Okay, so in this video, guys, we're going to be chatting about, sorry,
give me one quick sec, let me make sure that,
okay.
All right, so we'll say we're gonna be chatting actually about Queb.
So Steve B. found a really interesting idea that when we looked further into,
that we think there could be a ton of alpha.
So I just thought go through the process of how we found it,
what we think might happen and then why we think it's cheap or expensive.
So I got a message from Steve saying, hey, listen,
check out the longer dated vols on Queb. Okay,
so let me share my screen here and we will take a look together.
So can you guys see my screen?
All right, so Queb, we're gonna plot a couple of vols here.
We're gonna plot September, August, October, November,
because we traded November, but then we're gonna plot Jan 2023.
So take a look here.
One thing we noticed was if you look at some vols in terms of August,
September, you notice like,
so actually let's just look at August and September right now.
So the near dated vols. All right, let's take a look at these.
And you notice how initially you had a big spike, then cooled off,
and then it spiked back up to around the same level.
So it's almost like gamma is being priced in the same now as it was when the first
big move happened.
However, when we look, and this is also true for, let's say, November.
So we're getting a little bit further out,
but you can still see like November is back at its previous highs. All right,
now let's take a look at Jan 2023.
So what do we notice here about Jan 2023? Well,
it's continued to make, like there's a reach for vega here, right?
There's a reach for these long dated vols where we can see that the long-term vols
are making new highs, right? So what we might've seen,
if it was similar to everything else,
is we might've seen Jan 2023 around 3940 vol.
But instead we're seeing it at 46 and a half.
And when Steve first mentioned it to me, it was like 47 and a half.
But then of course we started selling and we might've brought the term structure
down or the January down a little bit.
So here we have Jan 2023 trading in line with options that are 90 days out,
60 days out. And so right off the bat,
that kind of tells us that maybe these long dated options are overpriced,
right? Maybe someone's reaching for vega and it's less liquid.
So it's likely that vols might be getting too bid out there. So we said, okay,
let's investigate a little more. Let's see what's going on.
And so what we actually started looking at,
what we started noticing or Steve started noticing was look at some of these other
names. Some of the stocks in the holding, that Queb is holding here. You know,
we got Baidu 43 vol, right? For Jan 2023. We got Baba 45 vol.
We got JD.com 42 vol.
So some of the biggest holdings here are trading well below the 47 vol that we were
seeing earlier. And so what we actually did was we said, okay, well,
let's create a sheet here.
Let's create a sheet and let's take a look at here.
Let's take a look at all the holdings and let's see what is being implied by the
correlation here. What's the implied correlation here on Queb?
So you can see what we did here. We did like 10 cent holding.
This is 11% of Queb and it's trading at 34 vol, right?
Alibaba 10% trading at 44 vol. We did it for all the stocks here.
Unfortunately, some of the stocks don't have options, they're not optionable.
So we put no data. The good news was a lot of these didn't have,
there was only 4% of the assets.
4% of the assets for this ETF that didn't have any data.
Luckily we had Bloomberg.
So we were able to use the volatility surface here to find what, you know,
what vols were trading in Hong Kong. So for example, the Hong Kong 10 cent,
right? We can see that the, you know, the December 2022 is trading at 34 vol,
right? At a hundred percent money in this. So we were able to input that there.
We go down the list and now we're trying to say, okay, well,
given all this information now, but what's the implied correlation of this ETF,
right? So the closer, you know, of course these,
these stocks are not going to move with correlation of one, right.
That'd be crazy.
And it's likely because the volatilities are a lot higher on these names that the
correlation is going to be a lot lower. Okay. Maybe 30, maybe 40.
And we're going to have to test that of course.
But the first thing we need to do is, okay, we need to say, well,
what's the implied correlation. So what we did was we pulled in the data. Okay.
We pulled in the data here and we said,
we're going to make, we need. So to calculate implied correlation,
we need three things. We need volatility. Okay. For all the components.
And then we need the weights for all the components. Actually,
let me just pause here and make sure everyone's following here.
Let me check the chat questions so far, guys.
Yeah. Tico similar to let,
I don't think we did an in-depth analysis on lit and when we should have,
but this one we're doing a lot more.
All right.
Okay. So here we said, okay, let's get the vols, which we have. Right.
We have the volatilities and we have the weights.
So we're going to get two vectors weights and applied vol.
So let's just take a look at those.
Okay. So these are all the volatilities, right? 10 cent was 34 vol Bob.
I was 44. And then let's get the weights. So here you go. Here we see 11%, 10%.
And then we need the implied volatility. Of the ETF. 47.
Now what we're going to do here. Is given all that information,
we can actually calculate. What the implied correlation is.
I'm not going to go into this formula too much.
Maybe one day we can go into it in depth. But for now,
we're just going to run it. Okay.
And we actually get an implied correlation of 76%. For two year options.
So this is crazy, right? To give you guys a general idea.
Of some other ETFs or some other indexes.
What their correlations are looking like. Let's go to.
Not my COVID test today, guys.
I don't know if I might have it not feeling great. A little bit of a fever,
a little bit of a cough.
Let's see. Alrighty. So here we go.
So let's take a look at implied correlations for a couple indexes here.
So here's the implied correlation across all of these indexes.
So we have Dow Jones. 41%. Okay. We have S&P 500. 30%. NASDAQ 37%. Russell 21%.
Okay. And just the other day. S&P was at like 23. Dow Jones.
I'm actually surprised to see 41. It's quite high in my opinion.
And then you can see in Europe here, like the Euro stocks, 50 is 39. FTSE.
And these are all the 30 day options. So let's actually go further out.
Let's go to the one year.
So here actually it picks up a bit. Okay. That's for another story,
but usually. Vols are more expensive in the back, right? You get that contango.
So the implied vol.
For the single names are usually not going to be in contango. But the,
the index is. Right. So it looks like there's going to be like more of a,
more of a premium in the back there.
So not, not really surprised to see that.
Let's see if we change this to three months. Yeah. Okay. Anyways.
We're seeing like anywhere between 30. And 45. For these indexes.
Hang sang index. So in Asia, we've got 34 and a half. And then in Australia,
we're seeing 40. What's this ESTX banks. This one's pretty heavy.
So this let's see what, let's see what's holding.
Let's see what's in this thing.
Okay. So it looks like. Not many stocks. There's only like what?
20 stocks here. 15 stocks.
It seems super concentrated. Right.
And these are probably all very low volatilities. Remember what you said when,
when vols are lower for the individual name, usually.
The implied correlations can be a little bit higher if they're the,
if they're the same asset. That being said though, if the index drops, right.
Or everything goes down. The volatilities increase.
And so does the implied correlations.
Okay.
So 30, 35 to 40 to 45, 30 to 45 is what we're seeing. Even 25 to 45.
And we're seeing 76. For these Chinese tech stocks. Right.
So we're trading the tech basket. And then we're seeing a 76.
So just like to put that perspective, NASDAQ is 45. Right.
So that's pretty insane. Right. And so the question we should ask is like,
okay, well, what, what do we think implied correlation should be?
And let's say, for example, we think implied correlation should be.
Let's just throw an arbitrary number out there. 45. Okay. 45%. Well,
if we change Ivy. So let's say 37. Okay. And we hit this. Well,
now we're getting 45. Implied vol. Now 45 implied correlation. So what,
what that's telling us is if the,
if the basket has an implied correlation of 45%.
Then the fair value of balls today is 37. Is 37%.
But right now it's trading at 47.
Now that being said though, is, is 45% correlation for value. Right.
And so what we need to do is we need to say, okay, well, let's,
let's plot the realize correlation.
Let's pull up the realize correlation for this ETF over time and see what it,
see what it is. I don't have that right now, guys, unfortunately.
I was working on it, but I didn't have enough time to finish it.
So I'll post it in the group. Next week. But let's just,
let's just quickly take a look here at SMP.
Let's see. We can plot this guys.
There's a function here. I don't recall what it is, but anyways,
three month realized vols for the SMP. Let's take a look at the realized vols.
Okay. The realized correlations. Look at this guys.
Russell index 12 SMP 26. Dow Jones 28. Right. All of a sudden now,
like usually we,
people usually say like ETFs are usually more expensive and that's because you're
getting this like implied correlation risk premium. Right.
So let's go six months.
So now all of a sudden we go from what was a correlation of,
let's say 25 to 45. From now let's say 15 to 30. Right.
For the realized correlations.
And so, you know, given all this information,
we could probably say that implied correlation of 76 is like way overdue,
but we need to figure out what it should be. Right.
And it's likely going to be something along the lines of 40%. Maybe even 35%.
And so, you know, if we were, let's say a humongous hedge fund, and we wanted,
let's say, let's say less risk.
What we could do is maybe do a dispersion trade where we figure out, okay,
well, what assets shouldn't,
can we buy here to kind of replicate the ETF invest with only,
let's say a handful of stocks.
Maybe we will want to only use 10 stocks and can we replicate the most of this basket
or most of the volatility of this basket.
And so we would do that by those vols sell the quibble,
which has a 76 implied core.
So basically we're buying realized core selling implied core,
and we're going to capture the spread between that.
But in this case, we're cowboys. You guys know we're cowboys.
And so we're just going to go outright short Vega and short the volatility.
Yeah, Tico. So implied correlation is usually going to be higher, right?
That's why there's usually a higher risk premium in ETFs.
And there is single stocks is because of that. So you wouldn't hedge Tico.
You would just let it rip, right? You're almost,
you're replicating the basket with these stocks and you're going to let them rip.
At least that's what I would do because it's super cost of like, this is,
that's probably a really good trade to do this, right?
But what we're going to do is we're going to see what the realized correlation is,
test it out, make sure that, you know,
realize the realized correlation is in between 50 and 90, usually. Right.
If that's the case and, you know, we probably don't want to be selling this,
but it's unlikely. It's very unlikely.
Okay. So that is what, that's really what we're going to be.
That's really what I wanted to show you guys today.
So you want to be a big seller so far. We're not a hundred percent. Sure.
Just yet. But a big seller of these quibbles.
Okay. And I think guys, so Jan,
2023 is usually a tree at 27 at the lowest point.
That's what I wanted to use as a PA terminal here to show you guys.
We plot the one-year vols over time.
We can see that this thing was trading at 27. It was trading at 28,
29 at a low at the lowest point during the debacle of the tiger cub vault went to
38. And now we're trading at 45 all. Okay.
So likely when things settle down, we're going to see vols.
I would say maybe drop, drop back down to 35, 33. If you're going,
if you're willing to hold it, which would be insane, right?
It'd be pretty insane considering all that Vega.
Actually, let's see Steve. Are we the only volume in Jan, 2023 today?
But we can't be though. There's must've been tons of buyers though.
Okay. It had almost no volume.
Interesting.
I wonder who buying it done.
There seems to be quite a lot of open interest here on the,
on these Jan 20, 23 calls a 60 strike like 10 K.
That's a ton of Vega monster size.
Yeah, no problem. No problem, Joey. Enjoy your swim, buddy. Okay.
That's going to be, that's going to be all for today. Have a good weekend,
everyone. Enjoy yourselves.
Take it easy and we will see you all back on Monday.