All right, everyone,
today we're going to be looking over a trade that came to my attention recently,
and it's VXX SPY relative value trade. I just thought I'd go, you know,
through my thought process with you guys and also, you know,
what the trade looks like.
And just like basically break it down for you guys to see like maybe what's going
on in my head sometimes.
So with that said, let me just share my screen and we'll jump right into it.
You should be able to.
All right.
So, the trade is VXX SPY. And first, you know, you guys probably saying like,
how did I come up with this? Well,
the first thing I did was I scanned for the most,
the highest implied vol for the one year options, which I was looking for.
So let me just write that in there. The thought process was implied vol,
one year, looking for the highest in terms of percentile.
So where is it right now versus where is it usually? And let me just,
I'll draw that out here. Let me just draw that out.
So if the implied volatility looks like this,
I scanned on the one year implied vol for options that are up here,
for implied volatility that's up here.
And VXX came on the radar.
So the first I did was I said, okay,
let me let me plot the implied volatility of the VIX, of the one year options.
Okay, so it came up my radar. So let me take a look at this.
And here's what we notice, right?
The one year implied volatility is as high as it was during COVID,
which is insane. It's insanity, but it's up there. Okay, it's at the,
it's at all time highs. And so I have a friend who, you know,
trades professionally in the VIX and SPX space. And I met, I said to him,
I said, hey, like, what's going on here? You know, this, I'm like,
this is extremely odd for me to see that the volatility of VXX is so high.
And we're gonna talk about that in a second. And he said, since the crash,
buying vol on VXX has been one of the most popular ways to get long volatility exposure.
Okay, so buying buying call options on VXX to get, let's say,
tail risk exposure.
And just so you guys know,
what we're looking at here is the one year volatility of VXX.
And VXX is volatility. So you call this the vol of vol. Okay, vol of vol.
I said, okay, well, you know, I wonder what the S&P vol looks like, right?
You know, there's really two ways that are popular to hedge. One, buy SPX puts.
Okay, two, buy VIX calls.
So I plotted the S&P, one year vol.
And you guys can see it's been trickling down. Right, which makes sense. Well,
you know, we're seeing the absolute opposite for VXX. Super weird.
So what I'm just going to do here is I'm going to plot the three month vol and the
one year vol in the same graph. Okay, so here's the three month. Here is VXX,
implied volatility. And for three months.
And here is SPX three month right here. So I asked my friend, I said, hey,
like, how should I structure this trade? Like, you know, I'm trying to,
you know, do you see anything, you know, going on here? And he said,
it's clear as day that VXX is actually the alpha leg. Meaning,
we want to get short vol on VXX.
But it's kind of hard being short vol outright. You know, things go sour.
You could be in big trouble. VXX can be explosive. So what he said he would do,
so he's taking the trade, is buy SPY vol as the hedge. Okay,
so now we're not just looking at VXX in isolation.
We need to look at VXX vol with S&P vol.
And one thing to note here, guys, is it's hard to view these graphs like this,
right? We don't even know if these are correlated. Like, it's hard to say, hey,
well, you know, our next step would be, let me write it down here.
Our next step would be, is SPX vol correlated with VXX vol,
right? At the end of the day, we're trading vol versus vol.
If these things aren't correlated, we could be in big trouble.
And it's hard for us to see if they are correlated from this graph. Okay,
so what we need to do is we need to scale the data. Okay, so basically,
we got to turn everything into standard deviations.
So that's what I'm just doing right here. I'm just scaling the data.
So now we can actually look at this and look how clean this is now. We can say,
okay, well, clearly, these two assets are very similar or correlated, right?
Would anyone disagree with that?
Would anyone disagree and say the volatility is not – vol of vol is not correlated
with vol of S&P? What do you guys think?
So I think we can all say, you know, it is, right?
And so now we say, okay, well, we know – it looks like VXX is overpriced. Okay,
that's our alpha like. And it looks like S&P is fairly priced.
So we can buy S&P against our VXX position and trade this. Now,
the last thing we need to do – well, not the last thing,
but an important step is to say, okay, well,
where is this relationship today relative to where it usually is? Okay?
And not just that, we want to see, okay, well,
where is the relationship of the 1-year vol, the 90-day vol,
and the realized vols? Okay? So because we need to decide, like,
are we going to trade the 1-year relationship?
Are we going to trade the 10-day relationship, the 90-day relationship?
What are we going to trade here?
And so that's what this last graph is going to do here.
So in green, lime green here, okay, this is the realized vol relationship.
So what is the realized vol of S&P? What is the realized vol of VXX?
Divide those by each other, and that's this green line. Okay?
And you can see that – well, like, that's what it is, okay?
We're going to get back to what we see.
The second thing is this red line here is the implied vol 90 days.
So IV 90-day of the S&P 500 divided by the 90-day vol of VXX.
That's this red graph here. And the blue graph is the 1-year.
So the 1-year of S&P 500 divided by the 1-year of VXX.
And so what we notice is the relationships are at the highs. Okay?
So Vega looks overpriced. Okay? Vega on VXX versus XPX looks overpriced.
What we also notice is that the realized ratio is much lower as well.
And not only much lower, it doesn't get much higher.
So what does this mean for us? Well, it means a couple things.
The first thing is vol is overpriced. Vega is overpriced.
And the second thing is it's going to have a positive carry,
meaning theta is overpriced as well. Okay? So when we put on this position,
it's going to carry theta. It's going to make money every single day. Right?
Should make money every single day.
And the second thing is we actually might get the vols to drop.
We might get Vega gains and theta gains. Very rare. That's a very rare, like,
trade to find. But it looks like this is actually going to have both. Right?
Which is awesome.
So before we go and actually structure this position, I have it on thinkorswim.
Does anyone have any questions about this?
Any questions? Any questions, guys? Like,
usually what we'll see is we'll put on, let's say, you know,
realized vol is going to be through the roof.
And so implied vol is going to be through the roof. But when you sell vol,
usually the realized outpace is the theta. Right?
The gamma outpace is the theta. But in this situation,
we actually might get both.
Let's go structure it out,
and we'll come back with any questions here because I'm not seeing any yet.
Okay, great. So let's go and.
Okay. So here we go.
So here is a paper trade of it just so you guys can see it.
So the way we're structuring this trade is going to be theta neutral.
And we're going to be doing the S&P 500 volatility versus the vol of vol.
And we're going to be doing them a strangle swap. Okay?
We're going to do one strangle versus another strangle.
And so this is what it looks like.
So here's our S&P. First thing to note, guys, we're going to notice about this.
So I put this on earlier today just to show you guys in this example.
You see how this is up $1,600. This is down $2,000. That's the whole idea,
right?
One gain is going to offset the loss or the gain is going to offset the loss.
And in the long run, we're going to make more money on the winning side.
Then we lose.
Okay. So here is the S&P. And the way we structured it is we're long.
So we're in September. We decide to do the 90-day vol. We just graph it.
We pull up the graph again. We're trading this red line here. Okay?
Because the red line is going to give us a little bit of exposure to realized vol.
And it's at the highs. Okay? The one-year vol has come in quite a bit.
Still high, but has come in quite a bit.
So the structure we did here is a delta 25 strangle. Okay? On the S&P 500.
So I bought 100 of the 380s and bought 100 of the 442 to give us a total theta of
$1,000. So every single day, this position is going to lose $1,000.
On the flip side, we did this VXX trade. Okay?
And we did it again with a little bit more theta because it's the alpha leg.
So we got 1,150 theta. Okay?
So theta neutral plus a little bit more theta because this is the alpha leg.
And then again, delta 25 strangle. And this is what the trade looks like.
We're short the 31 put and short the 80 call. So that's the trade.
And hopefully, you know, in two, three weeks,
this thing makes a bunch of money.
So now do we have any questions?
Any comments?
Will do, Ram. Just waiting for Jordan here.
Good? Okay. Ram's asking, can you explain what an alpha leg is?
I was going to make a silly joke there. But anyways, Ram,
the alpha leg is you have two things here, right? Now,
one of them is likely to be the over... Okay,
one of them is likely to be efficient.
And the other is likely to be over or underpriced.
The over or underpriced leg is the alpha leg.
This is the leg otherwise known as the error correcting leg.
This is the leg that you think should correct. Not this one. Okay? So usually,
there's two things. You usually want to get this leg on first.
And you usually want to trade a little more size. So in this case, Ram,
imagine we have two things here. Okay? They're trading differently. Now,
we think one of two things are going to happen.
This is going to come down or this is going to go up.
Or maybe they meet in the middle. But in this case,
we think that this leg right here is the alpha leg.
So what that means is we think this is going to correct.
So we want to get short a little bit more of this. Right?
Imagine Coca-Cola and Pepsi usually move like this together. Right?
They usually move like this. And then all of a sudden, Pepsi goes like this.
Okay? Now, Pepsi jumped up a bunch in terms of vol. Coca-Cola didn't change.
All right? Well, the question we need to ask is like, okay,
like assuming these should get more correlated or, you know,
come back together in some way.
Is Pepsi supposed to come down or is Coca-Cola supposed to go up?
If we determine that Coca-Cola is the one that's supposed to go up,
this would be the leg that we actually make money on.
And this would be the one that we have as a hedge.
Right? But this is the one that makes the money by coming up.
Perfect. So we've got another question from Adam here. Adam's saying,
so when you say collect Theta and Vega,
do you mean the extra 150 a day that you're getting on the short options?
Yeah.
Yeah. Like Adam. So that 150 is the Theta, the positive carry. Right?
So that's like the Theta gains that we would gain from putting this on.
The Vega gains would come from the position correcting, the vols coming down.
So it's like, while we wait for the vols to come down,
we actually don't have to burn money holding the position.
We'll actually make money holding the position.
So we kind of get to double dip in a way. So, Jordan,
maybe this is an important question to ask. I'm surprised it didn't come up,
honestly. How do we lose money here? Yeah. Good question.
So we lose money here if implied vol, if the spread continues.
Because remember, guys, we're trading this. I'm sharing my screen still, right?
Yes. Okay. So we lose money a couple of ways here.
Way number one, this red line here continues to go up.
We're short this red line right now. Okay. We're short this red line.
Why do we lose money?
This red line goes up and that means we're losing on Vega. Okay.
Implied vols are still moving.
The other way we lose is this green line shoots up.
We're also short this green line. Okay.
We're saying that we're not technically short this green line.
We're just saying that this red line is going to be higher than this green line.
So if this red line goes down and this green line goes down, you know,
we're going to be okay.
So that's another way we could lose money is if this green line just shoots through
the roof. AKA let's say S&P doesn't move. Okay. And VXX moves like crazy.
You got another question here.
How do you know how to size these two positions relative to each other? Yep.
You can. So in this case, Theta neutral.
So Theta neutral just means premium neutral. So think about it like this.
So there's two things, right? There's Vega neutral, which is notional neutral.
So you buy $1 million of the underlying of SPX and,
or SPY and a million dollars of VXX. Theta neutral means.
Imagine nothing happened. Okay. So this, this strangle. Nothing happens.
We realize the max loss on both of these. Okay.
It just means we wouldn't lose or make any money. They're premium neutral. See,
so for example, and this is. $138,000 is how much premium we have to output.
And this is going to be, it should be a tiny bit more. Or 138,000.
So they're both 138,000. They're premium neutral, AKA. Theta neutral.
And that's, you know, whether you want to do Vega neutral or Theta neutral,
that's for another conversation.
So we've got a question here. I'm going to jump in front of this one though.
How are you going to manage this position or is there any management required?
Well, I thought you were going to jump in front of it. No, no.
That's the one that I mentioned. I shared my question. That is my question. Oh,
okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Got it. How do I manage this position?
So this is a really good question. And as this thing changes.
So for example let's say we,
let's say implied volatility of VXX starts to collapse.
Then I'm obviously going to close out the position. If let's say the stock,
the S&P jumps up and VXX doesn't move. Well, I got to hedge my deltas. Right.
So it's really going to be,
there's going to be a lot of different combos that could happen,
but I'm really only caring. I really only care about two things. Okay.
Two things I care about. Delta and theta. If one of my legs get too high theta,
I'm going to neutralize it. If one of my legs get too high delta,
I'm going to neutralize it. And I'm always thinking about it.
I'm always thinking about this trade together, together as a whole. Okay. Yeah.
So I was actually about to add on there, Jordan. Where can someone look at the,
the whole portfolio?
Obviously you have, like if I just look at this one trade, it's not,
it doesn't look beta neutral. It's just beta neutral.
well how can I see the whole thing together?
Like what my total theta is on this and my total delta, things like that. Yep.
So your theta, you guys don't need to do any adjusting for it.
It's going to be right here. Delta is going to be a little trickier. Okay.
Delta is going to be a lot trickier. Because S S and P 500.
One delta of S and P 500 is different than one delta of the XX.
And maybe we can have another live on that,
but that's that's going to be a little bit trickier. Theta. You just.
It's just premium. Right. So you can just look at it right here.
So now for a serious question, You know, we always say, you know,
don't try to repair a losing trade. When are you,
when would you actually exit this thing for a loss? Yeah,
that's a really good question. And with this trade, it's actually really hard.
It's really hard to exit this trade, but you still have to, you know,
you still have to exit. So let me go back to our,
well, it's something to the top like this. Okay. And you look over,
let's say five years data. And it's at the top. It's hard.
As this thing keeps going against you, it's hard to say I'm wrong. Okay.
Especially with a relative value trade like this,
that has such a tight relationship. In this case, you have,
you want to have a PNL stop. So if I lose X amount of dollars,
I have to close the position. Okay.
Remember being wrong and having the right time are the same or having the wrong
time or the same thing. So have a PNL stop. And when you hit that,
you got to exit the position.
So we have another question here from Lucas, Lucas, what's going on, man.
He said, I'm not sure if he covered this yet,
but VXX appears to be made up 50%.
Front month contracts for VIX and 50% June contracts.
And then something he's pointing out about this is that the June contracts have
a lower implied vol than the may contracts. And what do we think about that?
So I think probably right now it's probably 50, 50, but it's, it's,
they're trying to find out what the 30 day volatility, the 30 day vol is.
Right. So let's say for example, so June right now is 44 days, I believe away.
And may is 18.
As we get closer and closer as June gets closer and closer to that 30 day mark.
Then VXX is going to start buying more and more of June contracts.
And in terms of June, having a lower implied vol,
that just means there's going to be a rollup. Right. So you can actually, if,
if, if, if, if the market's in steep contango,
Then VXX should start to trend down. Because of that roll down.
If it's in backwardation. Then as a,
as June gets closer and closer to the 30 day, right. Well,
think about VXX as a, as the ETF is selling high and buying low. Right.
So it's going to have a roll up. And. So how,
how does that affect this position? I thought about it and, you know, that,
that, that, that, that effect from the term structure.
It's not actually going to be as important here just because our position is so
wide. Right. If you look at our position here,
if you look at our position here. We get a 10% move in the underlying.
It doesn't really affect our position because we're a hundred days out.
So we're not really,
we're not really too concerned about those Delta moves for now.
We're more concerned about just the level of vol.
And. I keep in mind, this is also vol of vol. This is not.
This is not volatility. Right. The VXX is the vol.
And this is the volatility of that volatility. So it's called vol, vol, vol.
Any other questions? Yeah. I hope to answer your question.
Danveer. What's up, man? Good to see you here. I just noticed.
We have another Sean in the chat. Oh,
And I was like,
I thought it was maybe Jekka or someone playing a joke on me at first.
But then I remembered. We actually have another Sean. Is he Irish? Hello, Sean.
I spelt the Irish way. So probably. What's up, dude.
An imposter. Right. There can only be one.
So I guess I'll leave.
Cool. So if we have no more questions, I'm going to stop the recording there.