So, on tonight's live, everyone,
we wanted to just have more of an open discussion.
The reason is the big thing we're going to focus on this week is Coinbase,
right? Coinbase, super hype company, right?
Really difficult to actually like evaluate because it's hard to actually find something
to compare it to. And it's coming out with the options tomorrow.
So what we wanted to discuss with you is some of the ideas that we're going to be
looking at first thing in the morning tomorrow for pricing out Coinbase volatility
and trying to actually,
if there's a trade, right?
There's a chance this thing can open up really crazy levels of vol.
And we just want to make sure that, you know,
we have an idea of what we're looking at so we can, you know,
pull trigger if need be.
What do you think, Jordan?
So, guys, tomorrow,
Coinbase coming out with vol products or vol products coming out on Coinbase,
I should say. And we want to be the first ones there, right?
We want to be the first ones being able to value this product.
I was asking around some pretty smart people who are in the industry and asked them
like, how are you going to value this? And they said,
it's going to be tough because there's no comparables, right?
There's nothing that's comparable. So, you know,
Sean and I were chatting and we were thinking about some ideas on how we could value
this thing. And we thought, you know, as a team, we would try to figure it out.
If we can be the first ones to value this thing properly tomorrow, well,
you know, there's going to be a lot of money on the table, right? So,
I think it's good that we have this discussion today. So,
why don't we kick it off with some of our ideas to start, Jordan? Yeah. So,
the first thing I was thinking was like, okay, well, there's no comparables,
but can we take a blend of some stuff to try and value this, right? So,
the ones that I were thinking of right off the bat were Ethereum and Bitcoin vol.
And then also make, but, you know,
because it's a company also taking maybe some Tesla vol and GME vol and making a
blend. And Sean had a- Oh, sorry, dude, I muted you accidentally.
There we go.
No, no, I just muted you accidentally because someone came in with some noise.
Here, just unmute yourself.
Just now, right? Yeah, my apologies. No, no problem. So,
Steve B still heard me say happy birthday to him.
And he heard me saying happy birthday, right? All right. Yeah, guys,
just so you know, keep your mics on mute. Just until like, you know,
unless you have something just for background noise, things like that.
All right. So, yeah, Coinbase.
We try to take a blend to try to figure out what the vols are there. And so,
GME, Tesla, and Bitcoin and Ethereum vol.
But Sean also had a really good point there. Well, what about a brokerage,
right? Isn't this thing, isn't this thing like a brokerage? And so, you know,
we said, okay, well, maybe it's obviously not going to be as- What's that?
What's IBKR vol? IBKR vol is like 25. Yeah,
so it's probably not going to be that. Right. Oh,
Marcos is saying there might be a couple of comparables like FUTU and TIGR.
Yeah? What are these? What are these, Marcos?
Do you want to chat? Like, what's going on? Well, like,
what are these products? I think those are like Chinese digital brokerages.
Chinese digital brokerage. Interesting. That could be close.
That could be good. That could be really good. Digitized? Not like,
I don't think those are like crypto brokerage. Yeah,
these are probably going to be, I would say, more volatile than Coinbase.
What was the other one, Marcos, you said? TIGR. TIGR?
Yeah, because, so one of the things I was thinking, right? You know,
we could use like Bitcoin vol, for example,
but, you know, are their revenues really tied to the value of Bitcoin?
You know, like, you know,
I'm trying to think of what would be on like interactive brokerage because they
make their money off of commissions, right? You know, do we know,
are they taking the Bitcoin and investing it somewhere?
Or do they just hold it for their clients? Like, you know,
where are they really making their money? Yeah. Yeah,
it'll impact buying and selling for sure. But that's more like,
it's not like Bitcoin goes from $100,000 to $50,000,
their revenues are cut in half. It's not a one-to-one relationship like that.
Because maybe, like, do we know, does a dip in Bitcoin encourage more buying?
Do people just, you know, like,
on a surface level, it's like that's not their revenue, you know? Or is it?
I don't know a ton about them.
I think their earnings are going to be a lot more volatile than let's say a lot
of the competitor or like a lot of like, you know, regular brokerages.
And you have that retail hump, right? The retail pump.
Which is why I was thinking we put in GME as kind of like in the mix as well.
GME vols.
But this is going to be a tricky one. I was looking,
so the ones that Marcos mentioned are trading at about $100 vol.
Futu and Tiger are trading at about $100 volatility.
There's one to check out here as well. It's a Canadian company, VYGR.
It's a crypto exchange listed on the TSX. Really? That's what I'm seeing here.
These things went to the, this thing went to the moon. Okay,
but realized vols are only $35.
Because one thing we're seeing with Coinbase right now is, I'm sorry, guys.
Does anyone know actually? Oh, there it is.
The last two days, guys, it's been moving 3%,
right? So when vols come out, I would imagine this thing picks up a little bit.
You know, like, what if this thing actually realizes $50 vol or $40 vol,
right?
If I look at Tesla, for example,
so Tesla is trading at $58 realized vol right now. $70 implied. Okay,
we got GME realizing $100 vol.
And the one that Sean mentioned is realizing $35 vol. And IBKR, TD, Ameritrade,
they're all realizing $20 vol.
So Koa is raising his hand here. So I would say like anything above $80 vol,
guys, is probably a sell.
And we're going to be trading the longer dated vols.
That's what's going to be probably most overpriced is the longer dated vol.
And, you know, the GAMLA is probably going to be fairly priced.
It's that longer dated vol that's going to be over underpriced. So,
Micah had an idea. Eric, Micah, a few people have had ideas here. Actually,
lots of ideas in the chat.
So I'll start with Micah's idea here. He said,
what if we start by setting an upper bound on vol? Right?
Coinbase isn't more likely to be,
isn't likely to be more volatile than their first two to three days after their
IPO anyways. Really good point, actually. Really good point, Micah.
And the only issue is the first day was like 300 vol. Right?
But if we look after that, Micah, and that's a really good point, actually.
This range here.
It's only a 6% range. So I think, honestly,
I think that's actually a really good way to look at it, buddy.
Let's just do the math super quick. So I'd say upper bound, 96 vol.
Wow.
Watch this thing come out at 120 vol tomorrow. Like the one year.
I know Steve B saying the shorter-dated vol is going to be overpriced.
I actually, I would disagree with that, Steve.
And I'd love to hear your opinion.
Gamma is probably not going to be too expensive. Right? Like this thing,
this thing could get pumped so easily. And I think that the longer-dated vols,
man, are going to be through the roof.
They're going to come down like 40 vegas on a two-year option. You know,
in a week. Just like ARKX did.
Not 40 vegas, but 10 vegas. Koa has his hand up.
Maybe we'll see what Koa has to say. He's got,
he's always got a good opinion there. Yeah, Koa, just send me your mic. Okay.
Hi. So I read somewhere that the, how do you say? The exchange,
the centralized exchange like Coinbase, Binance, the number of like,
the percentage of trades are going down. And what's up is the,
how do you say it? Like SoFi,
distributed exchange where you don't have a centralized,
everything is like anonymous and decentralized.
So just to give you like the trend,
I think Coinbase is going to go up for the next six-month year,
but perhaps later, the trend will go like they will have to offer,
I don't know, decentralized trades because that's where it's hot.
Like the market is going there because if you have decentralized,
you have less fees, and you have more anonymity. Like you have better,
less government intervention,
less risk than going with decentralized transactions.
So what do you think about the vols though, Koa?
Do you think it's going to be like crazy volatile or do you think it's going to
start to really settle down? I'm actually surprised that it didn't double.
I mean, I thought it would double, triple in like Doge or something.
So I think the risk is to the upside.
Like the stock will go up if suddenly Bitcoin is going up,
and then everybody wants to FOMO and get into the coins,
whether Bitcoin or Ethereum or Doge or whatever.
So people will go in and want to be in the trade. So the volume will go up.
But I don't think they make money because they hold the cryptos.
Like if crypto doubles, they won't double their assets. I don't think so. Okay.
Maybe we could start by thinking about like how big this thing is, right?
If it's a huge company, right? It's going to be hard to move.
And if the volume is going to be huge, it's going to be hard to move.
So does anyone know how big this thing is? What's the market cap? What's that?
It's 11% of the crypto market. Dude, but how big is the company?
Like what's the market cap of this thing? How many shares are available?
It's like 61 billion. It's 61 billion? Oh, this is going to be a...
That should bring vols down like crazy.
Let me see. 185 million.
Yeah. Wow. 62 billion market cap. Shares outstanding. Almost 200 million.
So this is pretty big.
So to give you an idea, Binance market cap is 77 billion.
Okay.
So, guys, this looks like a sell. And they have 25.
Binance have 25% of market share.
And their value like slightly over like more than these companies at 11.
This has around. Like it moves, right? So the data is like it could be 11%,
I said. But it could be 14 right now or 9. I don't know.
Okay. Well,
just given that the market cap is honestly 65 billion or 68 billion,
that's huge, right?
This isn't like a GME $3 billion company easy to push around, right?
This is a lot of money that would take to move this thing.
So that's also, you know, if we see vols at like 100% tomorrow,
that would just be phenomenal. Phenomenal for us.
So, yeah, I think we're seeing over 100 is a sell for sure.
And we're talking about the one-year options here, right? Yeah, yeah.
The one-year options.
Because I'm thinking like it's got to be vols should be more than Tesla,
in my opinion. At least at the beginning.
Ryan's asking what is a what's Square vol when it IPO'd?
Let's see.
That could actually be a pretty good comparison, actually.
And Adam's mentioning it too, right? Two-year vol on Square right now is 47%.
Yeah. I'd actually say, guys, so I'm looking that up right now.
But as I do that,
I would actually say probably above like 75 vol is probably going to be a sell.
Let's see what Square was when it IPO'd. 60.
60 realized vol. The two-year was probably fair value is probably 45.
Question for you here. In terms of like time of day to sell it,
would you be looking to sell this right at the open?
Or do you think will there be like a lot of volume coming in throughout the day
that maybe it's worth waiting? I think you have your fair value.
I think for me, I'm going to put this at 70 fair value.
I'm just going off of like where Tesla is right now and also a 5% a day vol figure.
So anything that's a pretty big spread, I'm going to be selling it.
If this thing opens up at 100 vol, I'm going to sell it right in the morning.
I'm not going to put all the chips in the middle. But if it goes to, let's say,
120 vol, I'll get some more. And then unfortunately, if it keeps going,
I might have to get out of the position.
But I would be, I have my fair value and what vol I want to sell it at.
And if it opens up there, I'm going to have to sell it right away.
Got it.
Any other ideas? Steve B, you want to come chat? Birthday boy. Bring him in.
How's it going?
30. Wow, man, dude. How's it feel, man? It's almost your bedtime.
You're officially in the fossil gang. Me in the fossil gang, yeah.
I'll be like Jack, shout out to the fossil gang crew. Me, Dan, and uh... Right?
Anyways. Okay, I'll give my thoughts here. So first off,
I'd expect to see a lot of backwardation in the term structure, right, Jordan?
So just because if shorter-dated vols are 100, I don't think that's a sell.
Especially because it's an IPO, right? So 30-day vol, like that's a good point.
Like if people look at, oh, 30-day vol is 100, sell.
I don't think that's a good idea necessarily.
The other thing is there might not be super long-dated options.
So it might be only six months. So in that case, yeah.
They might not give you all the options up to 2023 and stuff.
And I think that's a really good point. Any ideas on how you would value this?
I think you guys brought up the good points for me.
The major point for lower vol is the market cap.
And the major point for higher vol is just the fact that it's an IPO.
And I think it's got a lot of challenging macro stuff that with Bitcoin regulation,
new players potentially entering the field fundamentally.
They've made a lot of revenue, but stuff's going to change, right?
So I wouldn't be surprised if it's half the price in six months.
So because at the same time, they just put out the IPO, right?
And people have to value this, right?
Just because it traded within a range for a couple of days,
I don't think that signifies that it's necessarily for sure going to be a lower
vol. But I was kind of thinking around the same.
If one-year vol was like at 100, to me, that seems conclusive enough.
So for six-month vol, what would that be like? It would be like 110, 120. Yeah,
yeah. But I wanted it to be, because I don't have a lot of confidence in that.
So if it's 110 on the high side, and I doubt it would open up low,
but if it opened up like under 50 on the,
like even the shorter-dated vol might be worth it.
That's kind of about the range I put.
So what do you think about Micah's idea that the second day of the IPO,
it'll only move 6%? What's your thoughts there?
And targeting that as the upper bound? Well, you're taking one day of data,
right? But it's like the IPO day. The IPO day itself,
it moved from 370 to 420 and then back down to 330. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Huge vol.
And I haven't gone, to be honest,
if I knew a little more about IPOs and everything,
but the earnings is going to be volatile as fuck. Yeah, exactly.
It always is for the, or potentially for these new listings, right?
So there's going to be some events of significant volatility.
I just think if it's super no-brainer, you take it, and then afterwards,
maybe we look at it and then look at the term structure and then see, well,
the term structure makes sense, right? Because there might be a trade there.
Yeah. So we look and see, hey, you know what? The term structure is flat.
That could be a trade, right? Exactly.
If this thing opens up flat vol surface tomorrow, and, you know,
it's 100 across the board, I think that's like a no-brainer easy trade. Yeah.
So like there might be a trade that comes up.
But I was going to approach it if there's something easy that comes up that I'm
like, this really makes sense. Like, I don't know.
Part of the part is when you sell like long-graded vol is, you know,
say it opens up at 75 and you sell, right? The six-month. What happens if it,
as you said, it goes up to 100, right? In that day. Yeah.
At the end of the day, you know, there's not going to be someone,
there might not be someone selling vol, right?
Like if it just has the right kind of combination of things.
And I'm not super sure how exactly, you know, it works. Like with ARKX,
it was a lot easier, right? Because you knew the volatility of the components.
It's not a- Exactly. This one's just so hard to value, right?
I do think that's where the, potentially there's obviously alpha there, right?
There's a ton, right? No one knows how to value this.
If you have a better dart, then, you know, at least for like a small position,
you could throw it at it, right? Right.
I think we're onto something too here in terms of like, you know,
the way we're looking at this,
the way we're trying to compare it to other things. What would be great?
And I don't know if we have information or data on it.
Does anyone have fundamental data on this thing in terms of balance sheet and stuff?
Because then we can start comparing it to other companies that have, you know,
similar characteristics. Like if this thing, imagine this thing,
we find out that it basically has all cash on the balance sheet and, you know,
revenues are pretty stable. I don't know. I haven't seen it. Well, you know,
this thing can't be volatile for too long, right? What do you think about that,
Steve? Mike is going to pull it up on his BBG. Yeah, he's a criminal. Yeah,
I agree.
But I do feel as though like I did read a couple articles and essentially like,
you know, they've been making all this revenue.
But the risk is kind of that they get squeezed out.
So it might not be as much like, like, I do think obviously the fundamentals,
if we can like more information, we get the better. Yeah.
You know, it's I think just tough. It's tough to value it.
Because what I was thinking of, like the way you value Tesla was so exact.
Right. And you should have all 20, you know, 20 points overvalued.
And you probably had a conference range of maybe five points on either side.
Right. Right. And in this situation,
like you have to have like a range of like 40 points, probably. So see,
let me ask you a hard question here. Gun to your head. What is fair value of,
let's say, one year vol for Coinbase? Fair value.
I'd probably say 60, but it wouldn't be selling it. Yeah.
Like if I had to sell it 60 or buy it 60, I'd sell it 60.
But I wouldn't sell it 60. Just because like if I think there's, you know,
10 points of edge, but I have no confidence in that, then I don't sell it.
Right. So you'd say 60 vol. And what do you think the odds are?
I would want to sell it a hundred.
And do you think there's any odds that this thing is actually worth 40 vol?
Um, yes. Me too. I actually, I do. Like, I think there's a chance,
but you can't be selling, you can't be selling vol. No, no, no.
I'm just trying to evaluate. Yeah, yeah, yeah. I think 40 is the lowest. Yeah,
yeah. If for some reason it opened like 40 vol, like,
like if it's opening similar to Snaps or whatever, then I think you buy it.
I don't know who said it in here, Steve, but if we think about it, like a,
like square, right. Square was kind of like a new technology when it came out.
But, but the only, the difference is, is that square had was,
was dealing with cash, right.
It wasn't dealing with like with the crypto space.
So maybe we could like say square plus some premium. Yeah. Yeah.
You got to have premium just because of the fact that you don't know. Right.
So it's like your margin of error. Right. Yes. I'd actually say 60 vol,
65 vol would probably be fair value. And we'd want to be selling at 85 plus.
Exactly. Yeah. For the one year.
So the one year is probably probably a hundred. Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
Really good point. Well, yeah, there's no way,
there's no way I'm selling 30 day at a hundred vol. Yeah. Because like, Christ,
I mean, just how we had on the initial day. Exactly. You know, you're done.
You're right. It's not a, not worth it. And yeah, we'll have a, have a look.
I'll be, I'll be curious. But the market may come like, you know, I haven't,
I haven't actually watched many of these single stock IPOs and I don't like the
ones that I looked at with me get a couple I looked at,
they seem pretty fairly priced actually. So got it. If it,
I guess if it comes out fairly priced, at least we did a good analysis.
Exactly. Exactly. Okay. Let's see what we got here. Let's see. We got,
we got some questions here for Steve. Potentially you can answer them.
Adam saying if it's flat, if it's a flat surface, can we do a calendar spread?
Absolutely. Absolutely. The issue is though,
Adam is that realized vol could be tough. It could honestly be very,
very tough to value.
And I think maybe just trading one leg tomorrow might be the ideal,
the ideal way to go.
Okay. So we got some, we got some earnings data here. Thanks to iPhone.
I think Eric's pointing out a good point there as well.
Yeah.
So Adam saying what happened with RBLX IPO vols were way overpriced, right?
So you could solve all there and it came down pretty quick.
And I think that's a tendency, right? Especially with these hype IPOs.
The only one that I haven't,
that I saw where like vol ripped like crazy was BYND, right? Vols came out,
they were priced. I think it was like 70 vol and the thing just ripped.
But other than that, they seem to be overpriced usually.
But BYND, like when it came out, did it have as much hype as like it became?
Cause didn't it like,
because what happened is after IPO just kept going up and up and up.
I don't know what.
Yeah.
Like that'd be a good one to kind of think of just like what could go wrong.
But that was a smaller market cap too, right? It was. Yeah. This is huge, man.
And I think that's a really good point, Steve. This thing's huge, right?
It's gonna take a lot of money to move this. But even look at Tesla, man.
We're seeing Tesla move at 60 vol right now.
Yeah. I was thinking of like a member of the tribute had,
didn't really work out on what was it? Chinese.
GSX? No. The one before it was before that. Was it ETF? No, Steve.
It didn't work out? Yeah. We got out of it pretty quick. Oh, lit. Oh, fine. No,
no, not lit. What was that one? I haven't traded any other one.
The one that got into the EV space. That was lit. No.
It's single stock. I can't remember the name,
but it was a large market cap and it ripped. I don't remember it. Baidu? Baidu.
Got it. Yeah. That was, that was pretty bad.
But eventually vols came down like crazy. Eventually.
After you got a margin call. Yeah. Like that selling high IV rank.
But even then though, right?
That thing was only moving five or 6% a day just because the vols I was selling
at 60 and it was realizing 80. Yeah. Like it wasn't that.
And it moved one direction the whole time. Yeah. Yeah. I think,
I think we can come to the conclusion. We are going to, we're going to say 65,
60 to 65 vol is fair value. And 85 vol and above for the one year.
We are huge sellers in.
I like that. I like that for tomorrow. If it opens up at 120, I'm shopping.
If it opens up at 120, it goes all in.
I have some fundamental data. Perfect. Thanks Tico.
So Coinbase revenue basically quadruple this year. So they, they,
they were making 1 billion and now they're making, oh, hold on. Sorry.
They were making 500 million in 2019. It doubled to 1.2 or something like that.
And now in the first quarter, they're making 1.8. In the first quarter. So,
so basically 7.2 for the whole year compared to 1.2. How about their earnings?
Do you have their earnings there too? Yeah. That's the earnings.
What about their, their debt to equity? Are they all,
what's their balance there? I like, of course, you know,
the first couple of days can be crazy volatile still.
Cause all the flows coming in, but if we're selling that longer dated stuff,
eventually that's going to die out and go towards its fundamental value.
So if we can get a good sense of what's up, what's going on on that side,
that's equity Tico. What do you got there? Hold on, hold on.
I don't have access. Oh my goodness. Tico. I thought you were the,
I thought you were the guy. I thought you were the fundamental expert there,
man. I thought you had all the data. I wasn't looking for that.
I wasn't looking for that. Debt to assets is 83%. According to this,
it's a 5.86 billion in assets and 4.8 billion in liabilities. Wow.
So it's positive equity. Is that all debt? Can you see or no? It doesn't.
I have no details. It's just a high level balance sheet. Got it. Okay.
So it has some equity, which is good. Just to give you an idea, Binance,
everything is double. Like revenue, like profit.
They're making 1 billion profit last year. Got it. And is there any vol on,
like Binance is not public, right? I don't think so.
Else we would have heard about it. Yeah. Tico, I got an idea.
What was this valued at a year ago? Right. You know how they did the IPO,
right?
And they have a valuation at the IPO. Like this was private before, right?
What? Coinbase? Coinbase. Yeah. Yeah. But it had a valuation, right?
So what was his valuation last year? How did that change from this year? Right.
So over the course of the year, how much did it move? Right.
I would say that would be an absolute extreme probably.
I know that Binance multiplied by 14, their valuation last year.
Like 2020. Multiplied by 14. Okay. So Binance has grown then, Tico.
Yeah, but Binance is 85 billion in market cap. Yeah. And it has grown by 14.
So divided by 14. And, oh, sorry. Coinbase is 85. What was Coinbase's,
like what would be their market cap a year ago?
Okay, let me check.
Because if it grew like 20X,
then that's obviously concerning.
I'm going to stick with my numbers.
I'm going to stick with that 60-65 fair value for the one year. Not even.
I'd say 60. 60 fair value for the one year, Steve. Yeah.
So 85, I'm a seller. 80, maybe I'm a seller.
Yeah. And if we get like something like in that maybe range,
maybe it pumps up a bit. Exactly, right? There's got to be some,
I might even put like a limit order in. Just get me in at 85 vol or 90 vol.
But we'll see how this thing opens up tomorrow.
Everyone's going to have the trigger ready. And see you all bright and early.
Yeah, see you guys bright and early tomorrow. Any other questions?
Let's see.
Eric's saying here that the shares were trading at $345 a share privately.
Interesting. What did this IPO at? Didn't it IPO at 345?
It IPO'd right around there, but then it shot right up.
It IPO'd at 380. Wow, I thought they would mark it up way higher than that.
The insiders were pissed. Yeah, I bet. I'd be living.
Okay. So that's the ideas we have for tomorrow.
If you guys have any other idea on what this thing should be trading at,
please let us know. Just to recap, we use Square Vol. Square Vol IPO,
Square Vol today. Tesla. We're not using GME.
We're using some of the brokerages right now.
We're using one of the brokers in Canada that are similar, Sean's saying.
And then a couple digital ones in China,
which are trading at around 80 to 100 vol.
And that's probably going to be obviously a little more volatile.
So anywhere above 80, that should be a sell on this thing. Okay?
Especially because the largest move after the first day was only 6%.
And it's moving 3% a day right now. So I know we don't have a lot of data,
but my best guess would be anything above 80 for the one-year option is a clear
sell.
Rising Bloomberg compares coin to some weird companies. Yeah,
let us know what the vols are there. Just post them in there.
Post them in the chat later on, in the Discord chat.
Any comparables you guys have there, let us know. The more information,
the better decision we can make.
Sleep well tonight because it's going to be a wild ride tomorrow. Yeah.
Imagine a blowout in the morning. I doubt it. I doubt it. All right, guys,
get ready. Before we sell. Mike, liquidate the other stuff, man.
Get ready for it. Yeah. Collect your $8 off of, what is it? ARCX?
Take those dollars and run? All my accounts in ARCX right now.
So liquidating that would be kind of difficult for me. Yeah, I know, right? Oh,
man.