Okay, so guys in this live,
we're going to talk about the JD trades start to finish.
Basically how this whole thing unfolded and you guys are going to be able to see
how like a great trade went from, you know,
like the whole process of how this happened.
So just so you guys know, this might be a little bit more advanced. So please,
there's no dumb questions. If you have a question, you know, don't hesitate,
stop, ask, and we will, we'll answer the questions. So I guess,
let me pull up the chat here.
Yeah, the trades, it's over now. It's over now.
So we're going to start this off. So this morning, I was already positioned,
right? Sean and I, we already had a position on, right?
So what we were betting on was we had a position on for quite some time now,
right? And it turned out to be very profitable.
So Neil actually did a live on this guys, where you can see,
so I think it's just two weeks ago. Yeah. When we initiated the trade,
Neil did a whole presentation on it. I just want to see who's on the live.
Is Neil on the live?
Yeah, he is. Okay.
So Neil, Kyle chime in here.
So okay. So we already had a position on, okay.
And if you guys want more information on how the position was structured,
you know, you can take a look at that live,
but what we're basically betting on was when the earnings date would be.
When JD would release their earnings date.
So we believed it's going to be on November 16th, okay.
Which is after the November 13th expiration. However,
the market was pricing in a November 13th earnings date. Okay.
November 13th earnings date, and we were betting on November 16th.
So we had this position on for a little while. So to structure this trade,
we had to create a calendar spread.
So what we did was we sold the overpriced volatility in November 13th.
Remember the market is saying,
this is where the volatility is going to be on November 13th.
So we sold that because we said, it's not going to be there, right?
If we take out that event vol, all of a sudden vol drops.
So we sold that and to hedge that short vol and that short gamma,
we bought the November 20th. Okay.
And so you guys can see the structure of the trade right here, right?
Short the 90, November 13th, long the 90, November 20th, right there. Okay.
That's what it looks like. And now it's going for $1.43, but funny enough,
actually, we put on this position for 35 cents, right?
We actually did the 90 and the 75 calendars for a total of 71 cents total,
all in. So currently the position looks something like this, right?
Obviously I exited this morning and we'll talk about why,
but this is what the position currently looks like. Right. It was extremely,
extremely profitable.
Yeah. So code saying, what about just being long only?
So you couldn't because the real mispricing was in the November 13th. Okay.
It was in the November 13th. You had to be selling that.
You couldn't just be long the November 20th.
Okay. So what happened this morning? So this morning, you know, had my,
had my little meeting with the, with the junior analyst Neil gang and you know,
here's the conversation, right?
So Neil mentions that I vol for the November 13th had dropped below the November
20 by a sizable amount, right? You guys can see from that graph right here.
So this tells us that finally the market said, okay, you know what, Neil,
you're right. The earnings date is going to be November 20th. Okay. So,
you know, so here I asked Neil in the morning, I said, Neil,
when you get a chance, please look at JD. There's a market pricing.
The market's pricing in November 13 because when I looked at the market earlier
this morning, it had November 13 above November 20, AKA there was still,
there was still a trade to be made. We should be getting more size on.
And then Neil comes back saying, okay, here it is, right? It's already,
it's already, we are right. We should take off the position. So I said, wow,
like I can't believe this just happened. So I told Neil, you know,
take off the trade now and, you know,
post the P and L to the group and explain, you know,
follow up with your video there so that people can learn.
So I got out of my position on that news.
However, Neil had it, Neil was wrong, Neil had a little,
I don't know what happened last night. Maybe he had a late night, long,
a little bit of a bender. But you know, midday, Kyle comes in and says, guys,
you know, November 13th is still bid. It's still above November 20, right?
He's seeing 57 for the November 20 and 56 for the November 13, right?
There's still, there's still an event being priced into the November 13. Okay.
So, unfortunately I was on my phone at the time I wasn't on,
I wasn't on a desktop, otherwise I would have checked. You know,
I took Neil's word for it and close out the position, but that's okay. We got,
we got back into it later on and here's Neil making a joke of it, right?
Saying I never gave the signal.
Okay. So, but you know, we can't be mad at, we can't be mad at him though,
because he was the one who initiated the trade at 70 cents and then we got it off
for, you know, well over, well over a dollar, close to a dollar 40.
Exactly. Right. Steven, it was Neil's idea. So, you know,
he did make us quite a bit of money. So we can't ding him for that.
So what happens? Well, the research starts, right? So we realized that, okay,
November 13th is still bid relative to November 20. We need to make a trade.
Okay. We need to make a trade here.
Something needs to happen because there's a complete inefficiency.
Like Neil's model basically said the chance of this happening is zero. Okay.
And if you guys want to learn about what Neil's model was,
he did a whole video on it and that's posted on our, on our YouTube.
Basically zero chance that it could happen. So we said, okay,
we need to start putting on some size if this is correct,
but why is the market getting this so wrong? So funny enough, guys,
while this was happening,
okay, so hold on before we get there.
So what I need to do first was figure out what was the fair value of the non-event
volatility. Okay. What was the fair value for this non-event volatility?
So what I did was I used the QQQ and BABA to try to figure out what should JD vol
be trading at if there was no event, right?
Obviously these are all correlated together.
We can get a sense of what JD vol should be trading at given BABA and NASDAQ don't
have earnings during November 13th, right?
So we're using the new terminal here. And what, so this,
this graph right here is showing us the NASDAQ vol minus JD vol and the average
is about 18%. Okay.
So at the time NASDAQ I vol for the November 13th was trading at 27%.
So we had 18% on that and we get 45%. Okay.
So 45% given NASDAQ should be JD vol. Also, BABA I vol was 42%. Okay.
And so given that information, right, we also look at the BABA JD spread,
right? Given that information, JD spread,
and we looked at the beta between JD and BABA should be about 46%. Okay.
Given what we just took from BABA and Q's,
the event, the non-event vol should be 45%. Okay.
That was the information we came up with.
Yet the JD non-event vol November 13th at the time was 55% implied volatility.
Okay. So we said, okay, something's up here, but we don't know what.
So we actually, you know, we started to go in very small, very light, right?
We got a couple of diagonals on.
Now at the time, so this is at 1.33. So at the time I get a message, okay,
from a PM. Well, XPM,
he actually used to be head of the derivative desk at JP Morgan.
And he's saying, what do you think of this,
of this long November straddle short 1.7 Jan straddle for BIIB. Totally,
totally different. Totally different trade. He's like,
I think that Jan vol is too high relative to no vol. Once, you know,
once this is gone, you know, there should be nothing left after March.
So I said, I'll have a look. But in the meantime,
JD will announce November 13th cycle tomorrow.
The out the money call should drop nine points. This is the research that,
you know, we were working on at the time. And he asked me like,
did investor relations tell you this? Like, how do you know this?
And then he says, Bloomberg has it confirmed as 1113.
So he checks his terminal and he says,
Bloomberg has it confirmed on November 13th. Right. So right off the bat,
I'm thrown for a loop. Right. I was like, I was like,
there's nothing on investor relations. Like why is this happening? Right.
How does Bloomberg have it confirmed? How's,
how the hell does Bloomberg have this confirmed? So I was like, holy shit,
I could be on the wrong side of the trade. Right. I'm selling this thing.
It's already confirmed. And so he's, he gave us an idea like, like maybe China,
maybe in China, they don't have to give a date. Right. You know,
who knows what the, what the, what the rules are over there. Right. And if,
and if that's the case though, so if it was November 13th,
we could come in there and buy a ton, a ton of vol November 13th.
It'd be the best trade. It'd be the best trade ever.
We'd make millions and millions and millions. Billions and billions.
How does he say it? Millions. You got the hand, the hand gestures down. Okay.
So, um, so I was like, you could buy November. I was like, if that's the case,
you could buy November 13th, sell November 20th, quasi ARB. Right. Um,
I was like, there should be 7% implied move. And then he takes a look at it.
I send him some information. He's like, nice work. So at the bottom here,
I'm going to start selling November 13th. Right.
And buy some obvious earnings in December.
So he's going to also do a calendar spread.
Sell November 13th and buy longer dated options.
Some similar to what we were doing. So here's Bloomberg. Okay.
So here's what he was seeing. So you guys can see right here where it says,
so it says like earning surprise snapshot under measure.
It says next announcement, 11, 13th, 2020, 11, 13,
but it has a C meaning it's confirmed. Right.
Bloomberg usually has an E if it's only an estimate,
but they have it confirmed November 13th. Okay.
So all of a sudden this makes sense, right?
Bloomberg people with millions of dollars who can actually move markets are seeing
that November 13th, this earnings is confirmed. Okay. And you know,
Bloomberg is never wrong. Right. So we must be on the wrong side here.
Bloomberg is going to be right. Right. We, how are we going to go against this?
So our two interns, Neil and Kyle, they start looking into this. Right.
So they started looking into this.
And so Neil comes up with actually a great idea. He says like,
so since JD is a Chinese company,
potentially they have a different website for their investors. And guess what?
Sure enough, they did. Right.
Neil actually goes and finds this on the Hong Kong stock exchange filings.
And I was blown away when he found this. I was like,
you gotta be kidding me here. Right. So he finds this and right at the top,
it says a board meeting. Right.
And we click on it and it's actually have a board meeting on November 13th to discuss
the future earnings. Okay. November 13th,
they have a meeting to discuss the future earnings.
And that is what Bloomberg was actually picking up on.
It wasn't the earnings date. It was a board meeting and they got that mixed up.
So big inefficiency on Bloomberg's end. Right. And a lot of markets right now,
a lot of brokerages, a lot of like earnings, whispers, all those guys.
We're starting to pick up on this. That is November 13th,
which is a complete inefficiency. Okay. Complete inefficiency.
Yeah. So Steven, that's, and that's what we thought about, right? We said,
we said, okay, well, this could signal, this could signal some type of like,
some type of all, some type of all right. We can't just go and say,
let's go solve all. Now we've got to learn more.
We have to understand our edge more. Right.
We have to understand this inefficiency more. There's the market smart.
We can't just go and blindly start doing stuff. So what happens? Well,
we find another day, right? The date of board meeting on August 4th.
And this had the exact same scenario. It said on August 4th,
we're going to have earnings. We're going to have a board meeting.
We were going to discuss earnings in the future.
And what happened was actually they confirmed on August 6th,
they came out on August 6th and said,
we're going to have earnings after this date, after this board meeting. Okay.
So this board meeting actually happened on August 14th. So August 4th,
they said,
we're going to have a board meeting on August 14th to discuss earnings just like,
just like now. Right. They're saying on November 3rd,
we're going to have a board meeting on November 13th to discuss earnings.
So what, so now we've got to keep going. We've got to keep digging.
So what I did was I went back to thinkorswim on August 5th. Okay. August 5th.
So right after they announced, let me go back a slide.
So right after they announced, right, I went back. And what do we see? Well,
we see that vol is still bid, right?
For the August 14th where they're supposed to have their, their board meeting.
Vol is still bid, just the exact same scenario as what we're having right now.
Right. Exactly. The exact same scenario.
But look what happened guys. Once they confirmed the earnings date, August 6th,
look at this vol for the August 14th.
So look at the August 14th guys. Look at the vol. No, let's do this.
Oh, it's this one. It's this one. Okay. Look at the vol here.
Are you going to change it? It goes from, it goes from 53 to 40.
As soon as they confirmed the earnings, the board meeting meant nothing.
Vol vanished.
Okay. It completely vanished.
And that's what's happening right now.
And that's what's happening right now. Right. So we said, okay,
that's all we need. We completely understand this edge.
We 100% understand this edge.
And literally the exact same scenario happened last quarter.
And it looks like in order to take advantage of this,
we need to start selling November 13th. And we need to do this in size.
We need to do this in size. So we started selling.
So here are my screenshots from today. Okay. So we started selling in size,
right? We've got hundreds of lots on. I mean, oops.
We just kept pounding and pounding and pounding. So I was getting in.
Sean was getting in. Neil was getting in. Kyle was getting in.
We just kept hitting this thing as much as we possibly could. Now,
what happened though? Right. We just, there's no, we can't just like, you know,
you can't just be making free money here. Right. And no one just,
no one notices. You know, it's like, um, uh, it's like the support line,
you know, you can just sell as many as you want at the support line.
You can just, you know, or you can buy as much as you want at the, uh, sorry.
You can buy as much as you want at the resistance line. Right.
The whole technical analysis thing. Like it's infinite fills.
It's not infinite fills. Right. So here, for example,
the market maker started catching on. So towards the end of the day,
the market makers were noticing that all of a sudden, all this, all this,
all these lots were coming into the market. And so they, they,
they took notice of this. Right. And so, unfortunately for me,
I had to pay a little bit of a premium. I, you know, I,
I let the guys get in prior to I did. And then, you know,
unfortunately I had to pay up a little bit and I was just coming in more size to
look at Jordan, the true Robin hood. Yeah. I know the trading world.
I know Sean and I have been the nice guys here and letting you guys look and letting
you guys come in first. Right. So, um, now,
so here we're going to look at some of the data. Okay. So here we go.
What are the guys saying? Stephen's making me laugh.
Yeah. So let's take a look here. Right. So this, this, uh,
this is today's implied volatility for the 90 call option. Okay.
For the November 13th, this is when Neil was sleeping in the red, right.
We could have got some pretty good fills there,
but then this green period is when we started researching and we started researching,
um, you know, what was happening. Right.
And then we started getting fills and you can see guys,
we just started driving that vol down. Right.
We started hitting it and just driving the vol down and the market maker started
adjusting. Right. They said, okay, something's going on here and we need to,
we need to adjust. We need to adjust.
So this is for the, that was November 13th. This is for the November 20.
You can see guys, it stayed bid, right?
The market maker actually wasn't pushing it too far up.
And you know why he wasn't pushing it too far up because it was already pricing
in the move. Right. Because we know it's like, uh,
it's most likely going to be November 13th,
but November 20th for sure has it priced in. Right.
And it was a lot more liquid, right? November 20 is the monthly,
a lot more liquid. So market maker doesn't need to, you know,
doesn't need to get too worried. Right. He's got a lot of options there.
And so we didn't drive up November 22 much, but you can see,
we literally drove, uh, November, uh, that's, that's the nineties.
And look at the, out of the money guys. Okay. We,
we were selling out of the money on the November 13th.
We absolutely crushed it, right? We absolute vol went from 62 to 54.
You made markets more fair, right? We, we, exactly. We provided a service,
right. But you know, this is,
this is a thing where we can't get unlimited fills, but we,
unfortunately we can't get unlimited fills and, you know,
by trading it's expensive, right. And by trading size, you know,
that's why we say there's some capacity constraint ideas.
I can't come in here with $20 million and do this. Right.
So a couple of things though, guys,
there was someone who came in with 550 lots around one 15.
It's funny that, you know, when I sent my, uh, you know, the guy, the message,
it was just before that, but wonder who it was. Yeah. It's funny that,
you know, someone came in here with some serious, serious size.
And you can see right here, guys, they hit the bid.
So they were willing to sell at the bid. They were being aggressive.
They're saying,
I know for sure that this thing is overpriced and I'm willing to hit that bid.
And they did with 550 loss. And I think that also triggered the start.
So if we got in a bit earlier, I think we could have got better fills,
but coming from these big orders. And then,
then I was coming with a hundreds of lots coming in.
It's just like the market can't do it. He just said, Hey, this is it. Yeah.
I might be on the wrong side here. I can't do this.
So, so that is, uh, let's see. I think that's the end of the presentation.
Yeah. So that's it.
So there guys is an example of going from start to finish for a trade. Well,
I guess, well, we still have tomorrow.
We still got to take off the position tomorrow.
You know, that's how, that's how this game works.
Okay. Let's, let's go into a little question period here.
I'm gonna stop the recording. That was awesome.