All right, guys. So in this live,
we're going to be chatting about some of the research that I've been doing and then
also the trade that I've been doing as well.
So I've actually shared this research with some portfolio managers that gave me
feedback. And funny enough,
they actually decided to initiate the trade as well. So it's, you know, it's,
it's worth the look for you guys to see like what's happening on the back end.
Sometimes, you know, some of the more advanced trade,
sometimes I might not share because, you know, for multiple different reasons.
So, you know, just going to give you guys some insight into that.
So before we actually get into the research,
I need to do an exercise with you guys, just so you guys can fully understand.
Is SteveBee on the call as well, Sean? I believe so. Okay,
because I shared with him the research and this is one of the questions he had.
So I think it's good that we start with this.
So I'm going to draw a graph here. Okay. And on the Y on the X axis,
we're going to have age. Okay, so this is age of a person. Okay.
And on the Y axis, we're going to have frequency. Now,
I was thinking frequency of, of wakeboarding. But what do you guys think? Like,
maybe, so something, something that people do when they're young,
not very often, when they're like 20s, very, very often.
And then when they're like 60, 70, not very often at all. Any ideas there,
Sean? Go to the club. Okay, nice. So it looks, so the distribution. Well,
you're saying there's one year olds at the club with this distribution? Okay,
hold on, hold on. Well,
because I actually have like the actual one that I wanted to show you guys already
pre-made. So I'm just gonna, okay, so something that. Yeah.
Okay. It looks like this.
Okay, where I think that's a really good one, Sean.
So this is let's say 70 years old. We're drinking in general, you know? Yeah,
drinking, right. These are the people drinking in grade eight.
That was you and I. We'll call this 30.
Okay, and here we have the frequency. Now, when we look at this distribution.
Okay, what are some things that we notice about it?
What are you noticing about this one, Sean?
Like compared to all the other distributions that we've shown?
It's a lot lumpier. Perfect. Right? It's a lot lumpier. Right?
There's like this, this bump here.
And then there's like, like this bump over here. Okay,
like this bump over here. Right? It's a lot lumpier.
And so this is called structure. Right? This distribution has structure.
And what this actually tells us is that there's different groups here. Okay,
there's different groups. So I'm now going to show you something.
And this should, this should all like make sense now. Okay.
So just take a look at this. We see the groups. We see like this.
There's these weird lumps. Right.
And what this basically telling us is that there's different distributions inside
this. Okay. So let me. Yeah.
Like there's probably a trait that makes all the people on the left more likely
to drink at age 13. Exactly. Exactly. So if I share my screen again.
Right. So if we, if we took that distribution and like looked inside of it,
we might see something like this. Right. Well, okay.
There's a little bit of a lump here. Let's say like it's a little lumpy.
And that could be because we have an underlying. Distribute.
We have different groups, right? In this case, we have the male.
Who looks like drinking much more frequently. Then let's say the females.
Okay. So this is called a structure and in trading.
If we can find the underlying structures. We can make lots of money. Right.
Just to, just to tie it back one more time to an earnings trade, let's say.
Okay. So let's say we're tying it back to an earnings trade.
Okay. When we dish and we graph all the earnings. All the earnings moves,
all the average earnings move for each stock.
We might see a distribution that looks like this.
Sorry. Actually look like this.
Okay. This is what we would see. So on the Y axis here, we have.
Size of the move.
I'm sorry. The X axis. We have frequency. My apologies. The Y axis here.
We have frequency. And on the X axis. We have. Size of the move. Okay.
Now, once we graph by, let's say sector. Okay. Let's say we say, okay, well,
let's take a look at the sectors.
What we might find that here is the consumer staple sector. And here.
Is the technology sector. And here.
Is the EV sector really, really skewed. And so now when we say, okay, well.
We have company XYZ coming up. Right.
We have company XYZ or let's say Tesla coming up. If we have Tesla earnings.
Well, we can say, okay, well, Tesla is part of the EV section.
So now we know that it's probably going to fall somewhere in this range.
It's unlikely going to fall somewhere in this range. And so that is.
The understanding of trying to understand the structure of the distribution and
finding the underlying groups. Okay. Any questions about that?
Because then we're going to move into the research.
Looks like we're okay.
Yeah. Okay. Good, good, good. Great. Great. Okay.
Let me get rid of this chat.
Yeah, I had the chat open, so you don't need to worry. Perfect. Perfect.
So here, here is, here's the research. So what I'm,
what I'm trying to do here is.
So just so you guys know how I came up with this trade idea.
I was listening to a podcast. It was actually the mark.
The mark F podcast I post in the group. Where towards the end,
for those of you that stuck towards the end. He said.
Tesla vault 75. Tesla one-year vault at 75.
And he was able to do some arbitrage with the, with the. Convertible bonds.
And I said to myself, Tesla vault 75. Right. So that was where the idea.
The idea spawned from was born from, right. It's just listening to a podcast.
Vault 75. It doesn't seem right. It doesn't seem right. So I said, okay, well,
let me, you know, So I looked into it a little bit more. I graphed it out,
right. I use the PA terminal graphed it out.
And I saw where we're implied vol was where it usually is. It's okay.
It's expensive. Right. It's expensive.
Now let's actually dive in and try to see, well, what is fair value here?
If it's too expensive. Well, then we'll obviously want to sell. Okay.
Spoiler alert.
So in this document, we're trying to. Evaluate it. Okay.
And it's currently trading at 75. But given my current estimate,
I think it's actually worth 55. Giving it a 20% premium. Okay.
And so we're using the data.
I'm not gonna go into the nuances about like why I'm using, let's say.
I'm not using all the data. I'm only using some of the data. But what we're,
but what we're basically using here is.
465.
Equities. Okay. We're looking at 465 equities in the universe.
And we're taking a snapshot of what they are right now. Okay. So for example,
The current market cap of Baba. Right.
The current market cap of bank of America. Et cetera, et cetera.
And then we're also using in our data set, a time series of Tesla. Okay.
So time series, meaning the vols through time. Okay.
So any questions about the data so far? So we're, we're,
we're taking a snapshot. Of the data for each. So we're basically going to say,
okay, well,
what is Tesla trading at relative to what everything else is trading at? Okay.
Let's, let's try to build a model here. Right.
A way to think about it is if all stocks are volatile, well,
Tesla's probably going to be volatile. We're also going to use the individual.
They're called target predictor variables.
We're going to use a variable to predict. The volatility, right.
Can we use a variable to predict the volatility of Baba and, and,
and bank of America and Bowen. And then if we can, well,
let's just use it to predict Tesla. Okay. Okay. So first thing to look at.
Okay. First thing to look at here, here is. IV 30 for Tesla.
Here is IV one year. And then here's the forward 31 year.
Let's not worry about that too much. Okay. So we can see here,
Tesla's trading at 75, 73.8.
And that's extremely bit. Okay. Let me just take away the IV 30.
That's extremely bit. Okay. Pre pre COVID. This whole, this whole scenario,
all the, all the WSB. It was trading at 45. Okay. 70 ball,
75 ball for a one-year option is extremely, extremely expensive. Okay.
You don't see that very often.
So I think my fans are going through the roof here. Okay. You don't,
you don't see that. Right. That's extremely, extremely expensive.
And I encourage you guys to go and look at a whole bunch of the stocks that you
like. And go check out the longer dated vols. Right. Even by do right now,
the longer dated vol is 60%. Tilray. Okay. Tilray is 95 is a hundred. Right.
And Tesla's in that range.
So it's just unbelievable how expensive this ball is.
And then, so what I also did here, and it's very important.
Is I graphed the contango. So you can graph it to contango in PA terminal.
Contango is basically how steep is that term structure? Okay.
How steep is that term structure? So if we, if we went on the PA terminal,
we would see something like this. Well,
we would see something that looks like this. Okay.
We would see something that looks like this.
The term structure would look like this. Okay. Where this is 55%. Right.
For the near dated implied volatility. And this is 75%.
For the far dated implied vol. Okay. So what the market is saying is,
is that as we get closer to expiration, volatility should decrease.
But here's the thing. Okay. Let me ask you guys this question.
If implied volatility is high. Okay.
Let's say implied volatility is extremely high.
What should the curve look like?
What should the curve look like? If implied vol is extremely high.
Anyone got the answer?
Inverted. Inverted. Exactly. Okay. It would look like this.
It would look like this. And what's the logic behind that, Jordan? Yep.
The logic is that the volatility is not going to last forever. Right.
It's going to imply a lot of volatility now. Volatility is mean reverting.
And so in the future, volatility will drop.
And we have lots of videos on this as well. If you guys want to go through our.
And like, you know, to, to just think about it logically, like, you know,
if we have like a big event happening,
you expect the market to correct price and see a big move now,
but that doesn't mean it's going to see the same size moves a year from now.
Right. The market's pretty efficient, right? So if something happens now,
we shouldn't see this huge tale of volatility for the next 10 years, right?
We should see it taper off and go back to some sort of mean or average volatility
for, for the asset. Exactly. Exactly. And I just, you know,
I encourage you guys to go look at GME vol during everything. Okay.
See how the vols look. So contango now if I have Ivy one year here, okay.
Ivy one year, what should this relationship look like? So this way. Okay. The,
the curve is going to get steeper. And this way it's going to get more.
Into contango. Right. Into normal. Right. Well, what should we see here?
What do you guys think? So as Ivy increases, what should happen?
What's it was Steve saying there down sloping to the right.
Okay. So as, okay. So, so. Yes. As Ivy gets higher. Okay.
We get more into backwardation. Okay. And as Ivy gets lower,
we get more into contango. Right.
And we should see a relationship that looks like this,
but right now Tesla is at the highest Ivy. Okay. One of the highest IVs.
And it's in contango. Okay.
So it would be like somewhere over here on this graph.
And if you scroll down a bit, you can get both graphs on the screen.
One second.
Right. So you can see that it's at the top of the range there for both graphs.
Right. But to this graph down here, what it did, what we did was, well,
we can't say we can't just plot contango and say, oh, well, it's steep.
You know, vol is expensive or it's low vol is cheap. We can't just do that.
Right.
And the reason we can't do that is because every time there's a lot of volatility,
well, there's going to be a lot of, a lot of backwardation. Right.
And every time there's no volatility, there's going to be a lot of contango.
So we can't just plot contango and say, oh, well, it's up here.
It's got to be expensive.
What we need to do is we need to divide it or normalize it by the level of implied
volatility. Okay. So we take contango,
we divide it by the level of implied volatility, right.
Because we should see that, you know, as implied volatility drops,
contango goes, starts to move into, into normality, right. Into contango. And,
but what we're seeing here. Okay. So once we do that, once we normalize it.
Okay. Which we have to do here, but we can see that we are at extreme,
at extreme highs, meaning implied vol is low. And contango is steep.
So that's a sign that maybe the back months are overpriced. Right.
It's extremely steep. Right. So it looks like this. When in reality,
it might look like this.
Okay. So that's what we're plotting there. And this being the back months,
this being the two year,
the one year options and this being the 30 day options. Okay.
Any questions there? Nope. We're all good so far. Okay.
Okay. So I was saying here, like, there's no surprise. Like it's obvious that,
that this is steep. Now as any good researcher, as any good trader,
you really want to understand what you're trading, right.
What the hell am I trading here?
So I really want to look more into this one eyeball one year. Right.
What is this implied volatility one year? Right. What does it look like?
What are the characteristics about it? And so I did a histogram of it. Okay.
You know, we have the frequency and we have the level of implied vol. Right.
So for example, level of a hundred didn't happen. Right.
But level of 70 or 75 happened actually quite frequently. Right.
And this could be a case that, well, if it happening quite frequently,
maybe that's the normal, you know, maybe that's the normal. Right.
And we're clearly seeing that here. Right.
We're clearly seeing that right here. Right. That's 75 vol. It's the norm,
but you can see when we graph this guys is that usually it's all the way down here.
Right. Usually it's at this 50 mark, which we're seeing this big hump.
And right now it's up here.
So we do some transformations and now we can see it extremely clearly. Okay.
We can clearly see these two humps. What do you mean by transformations,
Jordan? Yep. So we gaussianize.
So what that does is it basically tries to make these normal.
It tries to make these, this structure as normal as possible.
We give the inputs of, okay, well, what is the,
what is the general shape of it?
And then we use maximum likelihood and that shapes it to, you know, to, to,
to the parameters, to, to what we're, we're trying to make it look like. Cool.
And so here we have it. Okay. So now we have clearly, right? Like no one,
no one can say that there's not two humps here. Okay.
And so what that's telling us is that given what we were just talking about earlier,
right. Is that there might, there's definitely two groups. Right.
There's definitely two groups here.
Okay. And if we know, if we know that right now, Tesla given whatever,
imagine this group is like,
this group is March to June. Okay. Just like the, the, the months of the week.
Or sorry, the months of the year. And then this hump is July to Feb. Okay.
Just imagine that for a second. Well, we would, we could say that, well,
we're going into March.
So implied volatility should actually be around this 45 mark. Right.
If we can say that this ball is going to be part of this group,
we can increase our forecast drastically.
But if we could figure out what these two groups are, We'd be,
we'd make a ton of money. Right. And this, this happens in multiple fields.
It's not just in this, this is in a lot of different scenarios. Okay.
This happens to insurance, right. Or is he a smoker? Is he not smoker? Well,
given that we can make a distribution to distributions of life expectancy.
So.
Because I didn't have time. This research,
this research was done on Saturday or Sunday. Saturday, but, you know,
we had to, the terminal needs to get done as well.
So we didn't have a ton of time to, to really work on this.
And I thought the model that I built was good enough.
I didn't need to find out what these two groups were. Okay. But usually.
These two finding what these two groups are is very important.
Especially when they're so blatant like this.
I hope you don't have to eat those words. I know. Right. Okay.
So.
Yeah. So I was also saying here, like, usually I like to shrink the data.
Right. Which, which we just talked about, like shrinking it into the sector.
Right. So if let's say Goldman Sachs. Bank of America,
JP Morgan and Morgan Stanley all have an earnings implied move of 4%.
And then you have.
City group with a 10% implied move. Well, you want to shrink that. Right.
You want to shrink that back down to the average, to the sector. Right.
They do it a lot in baseball. Right. So.
I don't know exactly how it's done in baseball. I can't remember,
but they do a lot of this in baseball. I like what is your batting average?
And they would shrink your current, like,
if you want to know the batting average in the second half of the season, Well,
you would actually shrink your you're for the first half of the season,
you're batting average down to the average.
And you can do better by like shrinking it to the left handies or the size difference
or the size of the person, whatever it is, but it's very, very popular.
In gambling. Okay. So basically what I'm saying here is.
We can do a lot better, but, you know, given the time constraint,
give me what to put on trade tomorrow. You know, let's just make it happen.
And so what I did here was. So is everyone following along so far?
Did I put everyone to sleep yet? Oh, I think. I think everyone's so far. No,
no. A couple of questions, but we'll, we'll get to them at the end.
Okay. Good. Good. Okay. So let me zoom in here. If I zoom in on my screen,
Sean. Does it zoom in on your screen? Yep. All good.
Okay.
So here I have graphed the relationships between all our predictor variables.
Okay. So let's just quickly go back up to the predictor variables. Okay. So.
So here, for example, we are trying to forecast this one right here.
IV one year. Is what we're trying to forecast for given the data.
Can we build a relationship? Can we given the data,
can we find a relationship here? So we're trying to predict this IV one year.
And we might say, okay, well,
does the average option volume predict the one year?
So I'm going to ask you guys this question here. I want to,
I want to hear what you guys say.
What is the relationship between market cap. And implied volatility.
What is the relationship between market cap and implied volatility.
Inverse. Tell me more. What does that mean? What does that mean?
What does that mean? Highest market cap, less implied vol. Why, why would that,
why would that be the case? More difficult to move. Who said that one? Marcos.
Oh, man, my guy. My guy. So. Good try, Jacob. We need it. He said the opposite.
No, no, no. He was just a little late to the party. Okay. Okay. So, so Marcos.
So here's Ivy one year. Okay. And here's a market cap. So we go down here.
And it's right here. So this is the, this is the graph right here, Marcos.
So you can see here, if we graphed all those 465 stocks. Right.
We can see that. The larger or the smaller, the market cap.
The more of the implied volatility.
The lower the market cap or the bigger the market cap.
The lower the implied volatility. Right. So, but before we see the data.
We want to be able to say, we want to be like, why would we see this? Okay.
So let's do another one. Let's do another one. Implied volatility 30 day.
And implied volatility one year.
What's the relationship.
Co is saying inverse. Inverse. Co-op.
Does anyone want to agree or disagree with co-op?
Marcos and Steve disagree. Guys never bet against co-op. Don't you guys.
Don't you guys know this? Okay. You guys, you guys are right. It is.
There is a relate a positive relationship, right?
If implied volatility 30 goes up. So should the implied volatility one year.
And so we can see that right here. Right. It's, it's fairly obvious. Okay.
It's fairly obvious. Now keep in mind guys for this data, I'm not using Tesla.
I'm not using Tesla because that's going to contaminate the data. Okay.
We'll do one more. We'll do. Okay. Here's a good one. Okay. Here's a good one.
Let's see who gets this one.
Wait, actually hold on. Let me just see super quick. If it's. Okay.
The skew.
And the implied volatility 30 day. One year. So the level. The long-term skew.
Okay. The long-term skew versus. The implied volatility one year.
Higher skew lower IB. Okay. Was that one, Steve? Yeah.
You saw this one already. Cheater.
We should abandon. So it is right. So what we see here, right.
And what we should see is that companies that have high skew.
Are usually companies like biotechs.
They're usually companies that like are on this crazy runs. They're till rate,
they're game stop. Companies that have. Or companies have a lot of put skew.
Are companies like Walmart or companies like target or companies like.
Procter and gamble. Where the risk is to the downside. Not to the upside.
Johnson and Johnson. Has no risk to the upside. Okay.
So we can see that right here. Slope infinity, which is the long-term slope.
And the Ivy one year. Okay. So the more. The more calls.
The more types of calls are relative to puts.
Then the more, the higher, the implied volatility is. Okay.
So what we are just going to quickly take a look at our data set here.
Implied volatility one year. The Ivy 30 day is a good predictor. Okay.
The slope is the skews, a good predictor.
The market cap is a good predictor. Okay. Also. Contango.
So there's groups here again. We can kind of see the groups here.
Now I didn't have time to look into these.
But you can clearly see that there are like a couple of groups here. Okay.
We don't have time to look into it, but anyways, it is, it is.
It is a little bit predictive given by the red line. Okay. Also.
Realized volatility. What's actually happening is a good predictor. And lastly,
the borrow cost is a slightly, slightly a good predictor as well. Okay.
How much it costs to borrow the stock. Right. Hi.
Stocks with high borrow would have a high implied vol stock with low borrow with
that low implied vol. Okay.
And so we run a quick regression model and we get this. Okay.
We get market caps, a really good predictor. Okay. The skews a good predictor.
The Ivy 30 script. Contango is realized vol and the oral rate.
So we put it into the computer.
The computer starts looking at it starts to build these models and says, okay,
Hey, you know what? I can actually predict the volatility given these inputs.
But this one here, the volatility of volatility. That wasn't very,
that wasn't very, I didn't really use it when I was trying to predict it.
I didn't really use it. So I said, okay, great.
So what we did now.
Okay.
So now. What we did was we graphed it. We graphed hours. Okay. So now we said,
okay, okay. Model. Okay. Computer. Here is. All the information we have.
I want you to go and predict what. You think the forecast is. Okay.
I want you to go and predict here. Here's the, here's the model.
I want you to go and predict Boeing's or Boeing's implied vol one year.
I want you to go predict.
Apple's implied vol one year. Okay. So that's what we did.
And so this is what the graph looks like. Okay. So on the, on the X axis here.
We took, we took the log of it.
There's reasons why I did that, but I took the log of it.
And we can see here that.
It predicts very well. Okay. Now, obviously it's seen the data. Right.
It's seen the data.
But what we're trying to do is we're just trying to explain it.
We're trying to explain this implied vol one year. Okay.
And this is an extremely good, right. This is saying, okay, well,
I can basically give you extremely good confidence.
If you give me this information. Right. Which we just talked about up here.
Okay. If you can give me this information. I can predict.
What the implied volatility is going to be with really good accuracy.
And so. So what do we do? Well, now we gave the model unseen data.
We gave the model Tesla. We said, okay, model. Here's Tesla.
Here's Tesla's information. What do you got for us?
And this is what it's got for us. Okay.
So what it's got for us is that if we were to.
First of the forecast would be 54%. 54% for the one year. Okay. Now,
if I were to graph where this was. On this graph,
it would be right at the center point here. Okay.
This would be our predicted value value on the green line. Okay.
See this little green, see the green line here.
This is what our model would predict.
However, it's all the way up here.
Okay. It's all the way up at the 75% mark. Right.
When our model is saying this should be at 54. Okay. And. You know, Stephen,
for example, obviously this looks really expensive. Now, Stephen, for example,
has this belief. And I agree with him here. That eventually.
So Tesla has a lot of calls to you, even in the longterm. It's not, it's not.
It was a lot steeper on Friday, but starting to come back down.
But Stephen has this idea that. It's going to completely invert eventually.
And if that was the case, right. If Stephen's right.
And I think he's going to be right here.
Then our model would actually predict a 51% implied vol. Right.
Because remember, skew went into this. Skew went into the model.
It would predict a 51% implied move of 51% volatility level.
And so, you know, obviously this is crazy expensive.
So you got to short this thing.
And so I did short this thing and I am short this thing through. A January,
2023. Okay. So actually two-year volatility. Straddle.
And let me show you guys what this P and L should look like.
So this is the big moment. Okay. You guys can see. So,
so this.
We're actually a little bit higher here. Just to show you guys for this.
I'll show you guys what I have on. So this is what I have on. Okay. Now,
if volatility were to drop. Okay. To the 54 mark. Oh, you have too many.
On a 10 lot. Right. This would be worth a hundred.
The P and L would be $170,000. Okay. If this were to drop now.
You know, it's quite, it's quite, you know,
the straddle is going for 830 bucks. But eventually, you know,
we try to buy back for, let's say about 700. That'd be the fair value.
I've already priced it out. $700, $710. Fair value. Okay.
So on a one lot of these. Right. Which is actually not very margin intensive.
It is $30,000. Okay. Cause the credit is being used against the collateral.
It's 30,000. You would make 17 grand. Per one lot. Now.
This might take a while to, this might take a while to play out.
It might take a month. It might take two months. Okay.
Might take them tomorrow. I take a week. But.
Vols are extremely, extremely pricey. And I think that, you know,
this will go down. And conversely though, we always need to think about, well,
if we're wrong. Right. We're never wrong. I'm just joking. We're always wrong.
But, and what would happen if we are wrong?
Which I don't think we're always wrong. My apologies. When we are wrong.
If we are wrong. What does that look like? Right.
If we're not thinking about the downside, we're not a trader. Okay. So what,
if we're wrong, what would happen? And. We look at the data.
That I was showing you before the max, the highest point.
The Ivy one year has ever gone to. Is 81. Okay. 81. So.
That'd be about eight points. We would lose here.
Okay. So we would lose.
And let's say we stress it to a 20% move in the underlying. Okay.
So per one lot. You can lose between four and $10,000. You guys were thinking,
how the hell does a one lot cost that? Like. Make you lose that much.
This is the power. Or this is what happens. When you trade. Vega. Okay.
And when I mean Vega, I mean a two-year option. Like this is all Vega. Right.
This is how much volatility can actually cost you or, or have you gain. Right.
It's quite a bit.
So that is, so that's it, Sean. What do you think? I got nothing to say.
I think it's awesome. Yeah. Hell yeah. So anyways, long story short,
I'm short vol. For those reasons. I think we need to name PA Vega gang.
Vega gang. Vega gang. I like it, man. What do you guys think? Vega gang.
New generation of traders. Vega gang. I like it. We had a couple of questions.
Let's scroll up a bit here.
Where is it? I saw Red had a question here. What's up, Red? How goes it, man?
Red, where is it? Red, I've lost your question, man. Oh, here we go. Okay.
So back when you were talking about the level of implied vol on Tesla right now.
You said think or swim saying the IV percentile on Tesla is only 6.42.
And on bar chart, it's saying the IV rank is 7.6 and IV percentile is 18%. Yes.
Yes. So keep in mind, guys, there are many different options, right?
So if we take a look here, we take a look here.
Let me pull up the share screen.
Okay. Okay. So what those IV ranks look at is this, is the IV30, right?
It's very low. Look how low it is.
Look how low it is right now relative to the last six months.
It's at the bottom. It's at the very bottom.
But what we're looking at is the one-year option. And this is at the top.
And to make it even so you can do, for example,
I was talking to my buddy at Jefferies and he was saying that every two to three
weeks,
they see a huge number of calls coming in or they call upside vol coming in,
right? Buying Tesla upside vol longer dated. Okay.
And so when I was talking to him,
what he's ended up doing was a reverse calendar spread, right?
Where he's buying this cheap vol, right? And selling the expensive vol.
And what you get by doing that is you're trading the forward vol,
which is this green line right here. And take a look at how expensive this is.
This is at the top, right? So the way he structured this was, okay,
I'm going to buy some Aprils and I'm going to sell some Jan 2023s because he's hoping
for that reversion in the term structure, right? Or that he realizes, right,
he's saying that gamma is cheap and Vega is expensive.
So he's going to sell that Vega and he's going to buy that gamma. Okay. So,
yeah, that's, so Koa asked, can I sell the two year and buy the 30 day? Oh,
look at that Koa. Perfect. Perfect. Right. That's the forward one year. Right.
I wouldn't, I wouldn't buy the 30 day.
I look into April because the further you go back, right.
And the cheaper the vol, then the higher, the forward vol. So April, the April,
Jan 2023 is this line right here. And it's extremely, extremely expensive.
So, yeah, I feel like I talked too much for that Ivy rank one.
Moral of the story, Ivy rank is usually looked at the 30 day options,
which is very low right now. But in reality,
the longer data stuff is extremely expensive.
It's being overlooked in my opinion.
Blessings asking what's the worst case scenario here. Yeah.
So the worst case scenario is vols go up eight or nine points, right?
Obviously, you know, freak freak environment where vols go up,
let's say 10 points. But if they were to go up 10 points,
the stock would have to move huge in my opinion, right?
Like massive to push two-year vols up 10 Vegas. It would have to be huge.
So that's why if you buy those, let's say April's right. Those that gamma,
if you do get that huge move, well, you're going to get paid for it. Right.
You're going to lose on the, on the, on the gens,
but you're going to make a boatload on the April's. Right. So it's a relative,
it's a relative value trade. I did, you know, I'm more of a cowboy as, as,
as the guy from Jeffrey's was telling me. So I'm just outright short vols,
but I don't, I don't work at a firm like Jeffrey, so I don't really need to.
So if somebody wanted to take a long vol trade,
do you think that April vol is cheap? No. No. It's cheap relative to Jan, 2023.
Got it. It's not cheap in absolute terms. Cool.
We're going to, so Marcos is commenting,
saying maybe the market is expecting Tesla to have a very big down move.
Even the markets. It could. Right. But what we're seeing, so here's the thing,
Marcos, which is very weird.
And we believe that the back is coming from structured flow. Right.
So I think like this one,
if the market thought there was going to be a big down move, well,
then the near gated option should be expensive as well. But they're not right.
The market's in contango,
meaning that the market thinks vol is going to be extremely low.
It's just that it's so steep. Right. So instead of it,
let's say being like this Marcos, which is fair value, it's like this.
So yeah. Yeah. I don't think the marketing is going to have a big down move.
We would see something a little bit different. We would see more call skew.
Okay. Or sorry. A big down. I would see more put skew.
And we would see more volatility.
But the funny you say that though, Marcos,
because I was talking to a couple of people and they were saying that.
The Martin, I think the Tesla could have a huge sell-off. So. You know,
maybe the market is, maybe the market is. I don't know.
But at least some people are. I think it's going to be a big, big down. Tico.
What do you think? The only opinion that matters when it comes to Tesla. Yes.
$2,500. Okay. Got it. 25.
So any other questions there?
No, it looks good. Jared. Jared, are there any questions there? I saw,
I saw a couple of posts. Jared. Was it a question or how you commenting a bit?
Yeah.
Of course, dude. Of course.
I'm going to be coming back full swing, dude.
Let's get wrapping a couple of things up. Well, definitely be back.
Funny enough, actually Hutch. Maybe I won't be back, dude. I got, I got the,
I got the new computer back. And I don't have discord anywhere.
Cause I took it off my phone.
And so I don't know my, I don't know my password.
So I'm going to have to reset it.
I might have to actually come back in under a different handle. I don't know.
So we'll see. I could tell Jordan how to reset his password, but. You know,
I'm liking the efficiency right now, so I might leave it for a few more weeks.
Exactly. Yeah. He's getting a lot of stuff done, Jared. It's, it's good.
And when I come back is a broke PRNAV 3.0. Yeah. Broke PRNAV 3.0 diamond rank.
Yeah, exactly. No admin status, just diamond rank.
But yeah, Hutch, man, I'm still,
I'm still telling my friends about that Disney trade.