Gotta change your name on discord to the chemists the chemists love it Heisenberg
Okay, so Guys,
we're gonna be going over the NKLA trade that I didn't let some of you guys did
and we're gonna actually break down A pretty in-depth thought process behind this
I want you guys to keep in mind though. I'm not always right Okay,
this is how this is my thought process. This is how I want to you know,
express my view and my opinion I'm not always right So I actually encourage you
guys to you know question and also give your feedback and what you guys are thinking
Okay, but keep in mind.
This is a good example of the level of research that goes into a good trade,
right? So like whether whether winner loses, I think it's a it's a good trade.
Yeah, right. Yeah,
let's see what you guys Let me share my screen Jordan found the trade but I hopped
in for a few lots as well Yeah,
I actually so it was brought to my attention It was brought to my attention by talk
in our group to see what you saw Tico By Tico and then I looked more into it and
then I you know,
do a little more research And then I got on the phone with one of my one of my p
.m. Friends Bougie, you'll actually know him.
It's it's it's it's slay so got on the phone with him chatted with him about You
know some some some other type of trade,
but I brought this up and we chatted about it We did a little research and it looks
like a great trade so we're gonna explain we're gonna explain the whole reasoning
behind behind this in the thought process and How it actually went from like idea
generation to finally placing the trade and and getting involved Okay one second.
Let me uh All right, nice, okay,
okay so NKLA obviously is a stock that has been has been on the move.
Okay, it's been on the move Moving up quite a bit. In fact,
it actually went from 10 bucks all the way up to $60 a share okay,
and What I heard was and this was the original thesis is a whole bunch of warrants
are gonna be exercised So we think of it like this.
I'm gonna explain what a warrant is to start Yeah,
a warrant is like exactly like an option.
So and actually before even get into this guys,
it's Times like this where there's like a lot of attention a lot of volatility where
you can find mispricings Okay,
when there's a lot of people involved in trades like these you can find mispricings
Okay, we're trading we're talking about,
you know 40 million shares being traded on a daily basis or 30 million shares being
traded on daily basis Okay on a $60 stock.
That's that's pretty big and the stocks only I think a few hundred million in market
cap So, you know,
it's during these times where we can actually see a lot of inefficiencies You're
gonna go in-depth and chat about it and I would love your opinion You know me because
maybe maybe I'm wrong You have to talk about our actual a true signal towards.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Let's have a few few signals.
So There was in the market.
There was an article that was published saying These warrants are gonna be exercised
on July 3rd.
So what that means is During when a company starts out people a lot of times people
are awarded warrants Okay,
so let's say Sean and I Sean and I start a fund or not even a fund we start a company
and We hire Jim and Jim.
We don't have enough money to pay Jim So what we tell Jim say hey Jim, listen,
we're gonna go public with the stock soon And we're gonna give you a whole bunch
of warrants think of it. It's just like options. Okay,
they're long-term options And there's a few differences as well,
but we can think of it as a call option Jim We're gonna give you a whole bunch of
call options on our on our company If the company goes up like crazy you're gonna
be at a very low price Okay, so this is what happened with NKLA.
We got a whole bunch of warrants.
We gave it out for a $10 strike so think about like this a whole bunch of people
have the right have the call option on NKLA with a $10 strike and The stocks are
trading at $60 a share now what people are saying is on July 3rd You're gonna be
able to exercise your options Well, what does that mean? Well,
it means I can buy NKLA at $10 a share and sell it for the going price Right in
this case Let's say before today $65 a share and that's fantastic So you but what's
gonna happen is not only our shares Not only can I exchange it for the shares but
shares are actually gonna be created here Okay,
so a new new shares are gonna come into the market. Okay,
I'm not actually gonna have the right to buy I'm actually gonna be exchanging for
shares my warrants for shares and these shares can't come out of anywhere They can't
just come out of the air. So the company has to create them Okay,
so that that's that is what is happening here.
And so people are saying well 50 million shares are gonna enter the market on July
3rd. Okay, July 3rd funny enough. It's a holiday Yeah,
I don't know how they came out with this but July 3rd New shares are gonna be created
and Because of that the stock is gonna plummet. Okay,
the stock is gonna plummet people are saying $30 a share and this is like professional
articles. Some people are saying $30 a share Okay.
Now this news Didn't just come out today. It didn't come out yesterday.
It didn't come out five days ago It actually came out a long time ago Like I think
it was two months ago or a month ago it was quite quite a long time ago But as we
got closer to the date the news started to pick up.
Oh my god 50 million shares are about to hit the market and so people are saying
this thing's gonna get diluted It's gonna get screwed and there's a lot of articles
that were coming out started coming out So I've been getting messages saying you
know what like I showed you guys one of the messages for example for my buddy Saying
hey,
I wouldn't touch this with a 10-foot 10-foot pole because shares are gonna drop
Now let's think about this for a second. Okay,
before we even go into the technicals of what's happening.
Let's think about this. Okay? Everyone thinks shares are gonna drop.
Okay Why hasn't the shares dropped if the stock's trading at 60 and you know that
the stuff and everyone thinks the stock is gonna go to 30 Why are the why in heaven's
name are the shares trading at 60?
Right. First thing that doesn't make sense,
especially if it's tomorrow tomorrow,
July 3rd They're saying the stock is gonna reach $30 a share.
So why isn't everyone selling right now? Why is there more selling right now?
Why weren't they selling yesterday?
In fact The options market is implying a $40 at the money forward and we're gonna
go over this We're gonna break this trade down step by step But the options market
is saying the there's gonna be the stock is going 40 Why in heaven's name has the
stock been trading at 70 for the last three weeks?
Okay,
so that's the first that's the first thing that caught my attention Then what I
noticed was Ricky Gutierrez So I was talking to one of my one of my friends who
I wouldn't say one of my friends One of my mentors works at a firm pretty big firm
as a PM. I told him I said, hey guys Check this trade out. Okay,
everyone's betting on this thing going down and he's like These are these are times
where you can see huge short squeezes and we're gonna get into why this is gonna
be a pretty in-depth Talk here.
So I was like, okay, you know what? I know.
He's a really smart guy I'm gonna take a small bet.
So I took a small bet by 20 lots for a dollar 20 verticals for a dollar Next day,
I'm down. That's okay.
Then I see Ricky Gutierrez make a post So let me just pop it up here and as for
the questions everyone will address him at the end because we'll get into the flow
of this story YouTube here
it is NKLA warning S1 filing 70% drop coming soon.
I watched the video and when I after I watched that video I realized Everyone is
on the wrong side of this trade fade Exactly. Yeah mark.
I think it's for I think it's 400 million shares or 450 here Let's let's do a quick
search, even though I'm not a big fan of Actually,
this is okay Let's do a quick.
Let's do a quick look here mark But the thing is we don't even know if they're gonna
exercise the warrants we're gonna we're gonna do in-depth here NKLA Yeah, okay.
So 300 360 million. So,
you know over over over 10% It's quite a bit that's coming into the market Chicks
is asking does Ricky make decent calls Well in my opinion,
absolutely not Absolutely not. So There's I've seen it.
I don't know if I faded any of his trades before but there was one Where I saw I
think it was like by USO or something right when like that you but right when I
was Yeah, right,
right when I was shorting USO But a mark is like he is not a trader.
Yeah anyways,
I saw this video and He like went into super you went to super in-depth research
about why this thing is going down to Why it's gonna go down to 30 bucks There's
a couple of really good articles about why it's going down to 30 and I realized
holy shit Everyone's on the wrong side of the trade here.
In fact on stock twits it went from like 90% bullish to 75% bullish in no way.
Yeah, and Remember, everyone's usually long right?
You usually have a long bias.
So Seeing something like 73% or a drop from 95 to 73. That's serious.
That's a signal, right?
That's a you know retail trade are really getting out of the market here Especially
with the number of watchers that NKLA has because you look at something like let's
say for example vbiv You
know, it's a funny one. I'm thinking of.
Mm-hmm So when we're talking about retail sentiment,
it goes up like an elevator down like an escalator. Yeah,
it's the opposite when he comes to the sentiment They get stuck holding the bag.
They're bullish for life So you see like vbiv for example, you know,
you'll have stuff like this.
It has 98% people are bullish People are usually long bias So 60% bullish makes
sense because most people can only buy shares.
They can't sell shares So they're obviously gonna be talking their book and they're
obviously gonna be in a bullish manner So we dropped like okay,
so we're at 73 now, right and just last week. We were way above 80 Right,
so or sorry two weeks ago.
We were above 80 So the sentiment is starting to come down quite a bit here and
and you will see if you guys read through this Shares are being diluted.
I posted the thing in my in my in the traders chat.
We're asked my buddy I said, hey, what do you think of NKLA?
He's like dude shares are getting diluted.
I wouldn't touch to attempt football So right away,
I'm noticing a lot of people are bearish here.
Yeah now a lot of regular people are bear.
Yeah And a lot of people are bullish as well.
You guys saw right 73% But you don't have also noticing about the bullish people
They're all talking about like the new truck and stuff.
It has nothing to do with their view on what's happening, right? Right, right.
So the reason people are bullish is different than the reason people are bearish.
They're not it's not a You know like one or the other it's like the bullish people
are like, oh,
but they don't know about this new truck Everyone who thinks it's going down and
the guys who think it's going out like it's getting diluted Exactly,
so they're not even like really opposing each other now So what I noticed was the
borrow rate. Okay,
the cost to borrow the shares was 970 percent 970% what that means is if I let's
say Sean own shares. Okay,
and I want to sell those shares I want to short them.
I have to borrow it from Sean and sell them into the market and From borrowing from
it borrowing it from Sean is gonna cost me 970% a year Insane.
So what if the buy said something is wrong here?
I've seen it in a CB where it went up to like 200% But 900 900 970 and then in the
options market was at the time that we couldn't short any shares and if the option
market was implying I think a thousand and fifty percent Borrow rate. Okay,
so do you guys all understand what the borrow rate is?
It's the interest you pay on borrowing a share Yeah,
right so like think about like this when you want to short a share you borrow it
from someone and You you sell it into the market and then at a later date you buy
it back from the market and give it back to You borrow it from but why the hell
would I if I was the person you're borrowing it from why the hell would I do?
That for free So I chart it similar to when you take a loan what you were doing
is taking a loan of those shares for me So I charge you an interest rate and that
is the borrow rate And just to put in perspective to borrow Apple costs less than
the percent. Okay, and that's annualized annualized. Yeah, so Right away.
Something's wrong. I think your phone's going on inside.
Yeah Yeah That's turned off So what's happening here is the shorts are saying we
are so confident We are like think about it who in their right mind would be shorting
shares at a thousand percent a year Who would be doing that?
No one no one in their right mind.
No one sophisticated would be shorting shares a thousand a thousand percent a year
Because it gives you no room for error No room for error Okay,
and when we look at this stock when we actually see what's going on with this stock
There's nothing really like there's nothing bad about the company sure they're not
making money sure they had a crazy run You know,
the idea is great There's nothing really bad about it to be paying a thousand dollars
a share like even for Herbalife when Ackman was short It didn't go the bull right
didn't go past 15% a year Right and Bill Ackman was saying this is a fraud Yet people
are paying a thousand percent.
Just like let that sink in for a second to short this thing So what they're telling
you is I'm 100% sure this thing is going down and it's going down fast Okay.
Now they've been wrong for quite a long time. They look at the stock.
Okay, look at the stock here.
Oh Yeah,
I guess we're right here right the stock has been flat This whole time they've been
paying money out to the long holders and they're down quite a bit Who do you guys
think I want to get you guys your opinion here Who do you guys think is a hundred
percent confident on this trade who's 100% confident about this trade that's going
down Can someone get someone give me a Oh Mark that was in my interactive brokers.
We'll show you guys where it is at the end Just remind us because I chigs was asking
as well. Yeah, um Well,
the thing is I don't think anyone has interactive brokers here.
You have fingers I don't think you can see you don't think personally. Oh, no,
you have to call them.
You have to call them Unfortunately give thinker keep thinker summer call see where
it is So bougie brought up a good point. He said insiders. Yeah, okay.
Okay now we have an issue there though,
right an insider an insider is Probably not gonna be selling shares because or shorting
shares because that's gonna bring a lot of attention She made a lot of attention.
Hmm. So who do you think is gonna be shorting shares legally here, right?
Because if you're short these shares like and stock drops like you are good.
Like everyone's looking at this thing This is not like,
you know Some name that no one's looking at that if it goes down you you get to
profit and that's it But you walk away you are gonna be looked at Like why are the
hell is this guy paying a thousand percent a share?
Like that's pretty that's pretty blatant that you know something that no one else
knows So does anyone know or want to guess who is gonna be paying a thousand percent
to short shares?
Because I know no one in this group would I know for a fact no one in this group
would Robin Hood traders Okay.
Yeah, so so Danny to borrow the share so on interactive brokers,
for example You can write on the where the stock symbol is It'll say short of all
or not short of all and I'll tell you what the borrow rate is I don't I don't know
if it's on thinkorswim. You might have to call them,
but it's a thousand percent Oh when I looked at it last the options were implying
a thousand percent and I'll show you guys on thinkorswim How you can price it as
well.
So I'll show you guys But it's gonna be through a synthetic so keep in mind this
is a silver lecture Okay It's gonna be a little bit tricky to me a little bit challenging
You guys are gonna be better people on the other side of this better traders.
You guys are always already great people Cody saying mm's. Okay, so Okay,
the people who would be shorting these shares are the people who hold the warrants
at $10 a share It's the only people why because they're locking in their profit
No one in no one else in this world is gonna short these things at $1,000 a share
except for the people Who own the warrants?
Okay, do you guys understand that do you guys understand break it down? Yeah,
I have the right to buy Apple I have the right to buy this stock at $10 a share.
It's trading at 65 I can go and short the shares right now and Lock in my profit.
I'm locking it in I can have the right to buy them at 10 and I'm selling them right
now at 65 Yeah, exactly,
right because no I receiving that huge percentage because everyone's talking about.
Oh my god These shares are going down.
These shares are going down and think about it you think about you as an investor
holding these warrants and All you're hearing is these shares are going down once
I come and exercise my warrants Well,
hell I'm gonna go short it before before the warrants get exercised Right.
We're starting to get into the efficient market here, right?
People are not stupid I'm gonna go short this thing before it happens There's the
only people on this planet who are shorting at a thousand percent a year annualized
There is no room for error if it takes one month for the stock to go down 30% Guess
what? You've lost money, right?
There's no room for error and they're not getting squeezed out You guys you guys
notice that right?
We got the rally on Bullish sentiment and no one is getting squeezed out here because
they already own the shares They don't care if the stock goes up another million
points They own it at 10 and they're locking in their profit at 65 70 dollars a
share Exactly, right. So who's you saying? It's it's you know,
it's basically 3% annualized a day.
You're spending 3% a day Can you believe that there's no one on this planet who's
going to do that except for the people who are Guaranteeing who can guarantee a
profit.
That's the it that's it So coasting the company can can force repurchase of the
warrants sure,
but at the same time though They they still have that right to buy it at $10 a share
or whatever is $11 a share They still have that right even if they have to buy more
warrants,
they still have that right and they're locking in their profits right now So what's
gonna happen once all this gets exercised? Right.
Well all of a sudden I exchange for my shares.
I buy back my shorts and what happens we get a squeeze Is that does that make sense
you break that down a little bit? Yeah,
so I own a warrant So I own a call option to buy these shares at at $10.
They're trading at 65 So I said, you know what? Let me go.
I'm happy with with those profits. I'm gonna sell the shares at $65 Okay,
all of a sudden Shares come into the market.
I close out my my short position Everyone else closes out their short position Stocks
rally Because now there's no more news like you you guys are noticing here.
It's stocks trading at 57 bucks If this thing was really going to 30 it wouldn't
be trading at $57 today The reason why we had that down move Right is because people
are saying all this could happen.
This could happen and they're selling their shares So they're getting rid of their
shares, but also remember guys if I own shares Okay,
and Sean's borrowing them and I decide to sell them Guess what?
Sean's got to cover Sean has to cover his shares Right.
There's not there's not an infinite supply in the market here Okay,
so there's a reason why the stock is not trading at 30 and it's partly because of
the borrow rate, right?
People don't want to sell they're making a thousand percent a year.
That's partly because of it,
but a lot of it is because Everyone's already short. There's no more.
You can't you can't short shares anymore.
They're not available Everyone is already short.
So there's only one way up Is that making sense?
That's our view Danny. Yeah,
so our view is so the view that I'm taking is Once once this doomsday event comes
out So this has been going on for a long time guys And just like you know,
we always have to ask ourselves like if if everyone thinks this stock is going down
Why is it not down right? Why is it up?
And then once the news is over, right?
It's like we have to think about one step ahead What happens once this news is over
what happens everyone knows it's coming out.
Everybody knows it's coming out It's not like it's a surprise.
It's not like there's a there's a there's a ER call and they say hey,
we're dropping We're loading 50 million shares into the market. Now.
The market has to reprice This is a known event,
right and it's still still bit up here.
So what happens after the event is gone There's only one way up.
There's only one way to go and that's that's and that's to the moon So if I can
got our space suit on And we're hoping for a rally,
okay,
and then so I talked to one of my PM's and Not one of my PM's well One of my friends
who's a PM and he he looked at who owns the shares who owns the warrants He was
on the terminal last night.
He has access to Bloomberg even if he's not in the office so he was looking at like
who owns these things and a Lot of the board members own it, right?
We actually we actually might see a scenario where they don't even exercise it Where
they just continue to hold these these long-dated call options because it doesn't
look good on the company Imagine imagine I'm a CEO and I say I'm selling all my
shares. Yeah,
right and then not only that though Then there's then there's technical issues where
if I sell all my shares all of a sudden.
I don't need power anymore I don't as a board seat member.
I don't need more power Right.
So there there are going to be there's are some structural reasons for this Our
view is and my view is not right I'm just trying to explain it to you guys how my
thought process is how I'm thinking about it Is that this this moved down today
13% on a doomsday scenario? Are you guys still able to hear us dancing?
He's having some trouble with sound you can't hear. Yeah. Okay.
Nice It's so funny. Okay. Yeah,
I'm like so funny Dan's just like did anyone else lose sound and then I asked,
you know, did anyone lose sound and Or does it sound good? They all said yes,
so I don't know if sounds bad or what? Yes, but it's broken up a bit. Okay.
Yeah,
so That's my thought process guys in terms of Why we're taking this trade because
not one person I've talked to not one thing is going up thinks it's a squeeze Everyone
is short and everyone short in the markets not going up and there's not going down
What's going on? Fuck is buying this shit? Who's buying it?
Retail no way It's not enough.
There's no way Retail is saying that this thing's going down who is holding this
and then JPM's of you. J. J.
JP Morgan's neutral JP Morgan has a neutral price target on this thing But retail
are super bearish and to see Ricky like once I saw Ricky Gutierrez put that thing
up. I said, this is it You know,
this is in like putting in all that work all that in front like all that research
To come up with a conclusion.
I think It doesn't make sense it's all this this is already known like I'm trying
to I want you guys understand this,
okay I'm trying to get my point across here.
If the market knows it's going to $30 tomorrow Why in heaven's name is it trading
at 60 who's still there who is still there,
right? We really need to think critical about this.
The market's going to 30 tomorrow and this is my own information Would you would
you okay. It's like markets going to 30 tomorrow.
Would you hold shares at 60 today? And like this is known information.
Would you hold shares at 60 yesterday or the day before would you be holding shares
right now?
if if it was if it was a if it was guaranteed if it was guaranteed no one in their
right mind would and Especially because someone would start early on selling you'd
see the price starting to drop What when you like you're not gonna wait until the
day before right like um,
like well What's an example we can tie this back to in the stock market because
we talk about this all the time It's not tradable information. Yeah. No. Yeah,
it's not tradable information. This is not tradable information, right?
This is the game theory thing. Yeah, right,
right If you know that it's gonna be there I'm gonna start selling you're gonna
start selling because you want to guarantee your fill because you might not get
it if you wait Till the last day, right and then so the flip side is, you know,
as a trader, we always have thing about the flip side Well,
there are people still holding this because they're getting paid $1,000 a share
and then we gotta think well who's shorting this It's definitely no one sophisticated.
No one can be holding this thing at a thousand percent a year No one no one sophisticated
so people are short.
This is only the whore the warrant holders It's only people left.
So even if the 50 million shares come to market Okay,
it's not it's not gonna change.
It's not gonna change the It's not gonna change the stock price the stock trades
50 million shares a day for 30 million shares a day So I'm really thinking this
is gonna be a blow off the top squeeze and here's the other thing Because of this
view in the market right now We're not risking that much for potentially huge rewards
if we're right. Yeah, we're able to get on a great trade Yeah,
okay So Cole's asking how high will it go?
I'm not too sure but I really think it's gonna be below off the top like Maybe near
to new time highs. I know it's a crazy statement,
but this thing is a thousand percent a year There's gonna be a quick recovery a
very very quick recovery once they start filling those shares And we remember those
shares have to get filled Those shares have to be bought back They're not just gonna
stay short forever. Right there.
Those shares have to be bought back at some point at some point It's too expensive
to hold short shares So anyways, he's got a good thing.
He's asked that quite twice now. So it's oh, sorry. Yeah Yeah,
so if you add so let's take a look at this question first.
Yes for this video Okay, he's asking. Well,
how do short shares affect the price of the stock? Well,
Danny what they're basically doing is they're increasing.
So let's say you have a Million shares out. Okay,
and then all of a sudden I come in and put 50 million into the market Well,
all of a sudden everyone who owns those shares on a little bit less of the pie So
the stock is should should drop right because now it's not worth as much anymore
but in this case Right.
What we're seeing is People are holding the warrants and then shorting their shares
So this should already be reflected in the price because it's basically gonna be
a exchange Right,
they're shorting shares more and more things are coming into the market, right?
So we shouldn't see the stock coming down and once that news is out Everyone else
who is not part of the work the warrant holders and who are short these stocks Honestly,
I don't know who is skip mind boggles me a thousand percent.
They're gonna be buying back these shares So we're gonna get a huge move.
So we're gonna huge move We should we should at least see that and that's that's
my view.
So let's let's open up in the top Let's open up thinkorswim now,
that's only half of the pie That's only half that's only half the puzzle The next
half of the puzzle is let's let's set up a trade because if what do we do about
it? Yeah, because in my opinion if I'm only getting one-to-one here,
I'm not happy if I'm getting point five to one here I'm not happy.
I want one to ten.
I want one to five I don't want to have to be right with super conviction to make
money I just want to be right some of the time and if I'm right hell,
yeah Right, so that's how we got to think about this.
We have our hypothesis we go in-depth We try to think about why this should happen
Right.
Why are people wrong and then can we set up a trade where we have a good bet?
So let's first do well, we're looking at it.
Jake's is asking Have you ever seen a borrow rate this high before never never never
in my life?
I don't we're near not even close not even close But it only makes sense now Because
the people who are shorting this thing are 100% confident,
right they only got 10 bucks a share Okay, so if we look at NKLA here,
let's go to So let's say we want to bet on this thing going down. Okay,
so let's say we buy the the 59 and we sell so we're gonna buy a put spread so we
buy the 59 and we sell the Let's say 45.
Let's take a look at this trade.
Look at this.
Look at this risk reward to bet on this thing going down Does this make does this
make sense to anyone? Brutal, would you be betting on this thing going down?
Kyle Wow puts are so cheap Right, so I hope it was a joke You know,
so you wouldn't want to be betting on this thing going down at all because you have
to be super confident That this thing is going down.
So instead we have our thesis. We have our hypothesis.
Can we set up a good trade? Well, I think it's a blow off the top, right?
So what I did was I structured the 65 72s. So I did a call spread.
How do you guys like this? Right. Oh, baby.
We don't have to be we don't have to be right that often We were getting we're getting
seven to one here. We don't need to be right that often Right,
and I'm thinking I'm thinking I'm right 55 50 to 55 out of 45 here.
That's what I'm thinking This option is telling me I only need to be right 10% of
the time or sorry 15% of the time.
That's it So I think I have 55% chance of going up market's telling me a Jordan
you only need a 50 15% That's a huge edge. That's a huge edge for me, right?
So this is this why we decided to place his trade. We did it.
We did a few others, right?
We did the 65 70 for 60 cents Danny saying can this trade still be taken? Yeah.
Well, no, no,
it can't be anymore Danny because It should it should blow off the top for Monday
because it's coming into the market tomorrow Oddly enough But you should see you
should see the squeeze on Monday, so it's it's gone.
It's it's a it's a it's a make or break So so this is this is a huge position I
have on which is this 60 cents to win five Right.
I don't I only need to be right 10% of the time to make money Current stock price
is like 57 bucks or something. Yeah,
58 58 58 50 after hours 58 20 Right,
and it's strange because you you would think this thing's going to 30 bucks But
it's gonna hold and then all of a sudden you have all these people so we're gonna
have a shift now, right?
You have all these people who are short or who are think this thing is coming down
all of a sudden kill a black fly All of a sudden the shift changes you have to cover
boom Stocks gonna push so that's that's a that's the theory here So and the reason
why we can get this for so cheap. Can someone explain to me again?
Why we can get this for so cheap? Good question. Yeah, why can I get this?
For very very cheap.
No time to expiry. No, that's not quite Danny.
This is actually the 17 No one's buying calls 100% okay Skew not quite not quite.
I'm gonna be very impressed. Someone gets this one here Booze I booze. Yeah,
I know you know this man.
Oh, it says because everyone is buying puts Did he yeah, we're yep.
So everyone's buying coach puts but that doesn't make that doesn't make the That
doesn't make the calls cheap Everyone thinks it's going down Yeah,
everyone thinks it's going down. Right? Okay.
So the reason is because the borrow rate is priced into the options So remember
holding those shares you get a thousand percent a year to Cody. Just get it.
Yeah, okay Because of the interest rate to cover the borrow rate Cody.
You're a legend man.
So holding those shares Buying the shares you get a thousand percent a year.
It's the option, right?
So the options are gonna imply that as well and the puts are gonna imply that So
what what is that?
So we're gonna go into something called the implied forward and guys Sorry about
like this is a silver line.
Just want to make sure this gets a little too complicated.
This is a silver life Okay Okay,
it needs to be it needs to be talked about okay,
so the implied forward is where the where the Where the the premiums line up?
Okay. So for example on SP why?
Let's give it a second guys okay,
so SP why for example the implied forward is $313 you see how the premiums line
up here 525 20 Right.
So this is where the market in 15 days think that the average stock price is gonna
be at three hundred thirteen dollars Let's go take a look at NK LA.
It's actually dropping off.
I'm notice it dropped off a bit So the market is expecting it to be so you can see
here four dollars and sixty cents fourteen dollars and twenty cents That's that's
not right ten dollars eight dollars.
That's still not right 45 we're getting 13 and 7 so it's gonna be in between 45
and 50 so about 47 and this actually started coming off towards end of the day So
earlier in the day was like 45 44 So what the what the options market is saying
is the average price in the future in the next 15 days is gonna be 45 bucks Did
you guys see that Kyle saying is that row?
No row is the sensitivity to the interest rate?
Not not the borrow rate too fast, man. Okay, Danny.
We'll go over it again The options market, okay,
the option market implies a future price on average price, so let's say,
you know Okay,
so here's the stock right stocks right here the option mark is future looking it's
looking into the it's looking into the future It's an expiration is in 15 days.
Not tomorrow of 15 days.
And so usually you'll see a stock where The implied forward meaning what the options
market thinks it's gonna be in the future is gonna be in line To where it is right
now, right because the best price of the future is the current price Right.
Remember what we said guys if you think the stock is going up You would buy the
stock and you would do that until the stock is at your future value so the stock
price today is The stock price very close to the future.
Okay, is that making sense everyone? Let's actually take a two-second breather.
Yeah,
let's take it to say because this is gonna get doesn't get heavy We'll take it.
We'll take a two-second breather. Are you doing good? It's too much.
I think Maybe but it's okay. It's okay. Okay. It's just it's a trade breakdown.
Yeah, exactly Well, hope you guys are seeing like this is uh,
it's pretty interesting Yeah, it's good trade. Yeah,
let's give let's give it a second here guys everyone like, you know,
shake it off Would you like a Tony Robbins thing? Everyone up?
Yeah Feel the energy in the room.
Come on I need my boomsticks Everybody out of your seats Okay,
the options remember how so we're just talking here we said,
you know The current stock price today is very similar to the stock price in the
future Now what about for let's say 365 days into the future or let's say five years
into the future for the S&P 500 What do you guys what do you guys think is a fair
value? Okay for S&P 500 500 days into the future. Sorry about these lines.
I swear to God. I don't use them Every time you come to this page,
they're there guys So,
what do you think a good price for S&P 500 is 500 500 days into the future if it's
at 312 right now What do you guys think just like some brainstorm ideas?
What are you guys thinking?
350 Danny love that answer man,
or okay 400 might be a little bit too high But it's gonna be above 312 right because
equities on average go up into the future So you'll see here we go to SPY.
Okay, and we go to the leaps Okay,
three years into the future You'll see Actually,
you know what because of the dividends embedded in here Okay,
so something like QQQ Where there's no dividends Because dividends are also implied
in options, okay okay,
so I guess because a lot of people are still betting that the markets going down
the You can see that the implied forward is about two for not for Nasdaq.
It's about two 254 it's only two bucks. But if we look at something,
let's say let's go back in time here before this whole kovat situation Okay,
so you guys can see here that the implied forward is around 193 for two years out
right 193 192 in the stock trading at 189.
So four dollars up from from where it is And that's because on average stocks should
make money Okay,
so there's kind of like people already pricing in the long run this stock is gonna
go up and we take where Where the strikes line up where that were the the the option
prices line up, okay So you can see here at the money This is you know,
18 or let's say $19 and here it's only 14 of 16 or $17, right?
So these are cheaper than the calls and that's because the markets implying the
stock to go up in the future So let's go back to to NKLA when 15 days you can see
here at the Price of these options. Okay,
where they're equal is between 50 and 45 Okay,
that's where the extrinsic value or the the The option values are gonna be the same
both the call and the put it's the at the money forward Okay,
it's the forward price of the at the money. Does that make sense?
So in 15 days,
what's gonna be the at the money strike and so the market saying between 45 and
50 aka a 30% We're just over 25% drop in the market in the next 15 days,
that's the at the money forward That's where the market saying the future value
is gonna be Yeah,
so it definitely would be it definitely would be chicks so Can't remember was why
I got so off track now Okay. Anyways,
so what we can do is okay if we basically So this might get a little a little tricky
guys, but just bear with me here Okay,
we're gonna try to extract out the borrow rate from the options because the options
market is implying the borrow rate so bear with me we are going to buy the 59 and
Sell the 59 we're gonna sell the put by the call. Okay Now,
what do we have here? What is this? Get rid of this.
It looks like stonk to me Shh don't say the answer Guys, what is this?
It's one stock.
It's one stonk exactly But guess what guess what's happening here?
Can someone tell me what's happening here?
What's what's the difference between this and one stonk price? Yeah,
what else do you guys notice? What's the difference?
There's there's one difference between this and one stonk You guys got this here.
You know what? I'm gonna I'm gonna I'm gonna show one stonk. Okay,
it's not data Okay,
I'm gonna buy one stonk here that's a great word say stonks yeah here it is so here's
the here's the one stonk Okay, I'm gonna switch over to the synthetic.
This is called a synthetic. Okay,
I'm gonna do one more time synthetic stock stonk stonk Okay,
can someone tell me what the difference is the time? Nope. It's not the time.
It's not the time The leverage. Nope. Okay,
I'm gonna do one more time Spot price Okay, Mark's Mark's getting it.
Actually mark did get it.
Okay, mark mark got it. Okay guys Where's our break even on this trade?
It's 4482 4482 is our break-even here. What about for the stock?
It's at the money. It's the current spot price Right. So what's happening here?
We're getting paid To put on this trade we are collecting $1,420 to buy this stock.
Are you guys seeing this? Look the stocks trading right here.
The stocks trading at 58 and we when we put on this trade we buy it for 44 How awesome
is that? Right, and why is that the case? Co is saying so buy it. Okay,
so if that's the case,
right and the stock goes down we can still lose money here So why why is this at
$44 if you guys can figure out if you guys can tell me why this at $44 I'm gonna
be mind-blown. I'm gonna blow.
I'm probably gonna catch I'm gonna stop this life.
Yeah But now you've incentivized them to get it wrong.
Yeah So Bourgeois saying can you compare a naked long call with the vertical?
Yes. I'll do that. I'll do that after bourgeois do that after 58 14. Okay.
Yeah, 58 minus 14, right? But why are we getting paid?
Why are we getting paid to put on this trade?
No, come on guys.
Let's think that's really that's really thinking about this here.
Why are we getting paid to put on this trade?
Why are we getting paid to buy this stock? Okay, Dan 99.
He's getting that he's getting it. No, it's not. Okay.
It's because of the borrow rate Right,
if I buy the stock I get a thousand percent because I can lend it out to Sean so
if I have this trade then right I can create an arbitrage by buying this and Selling
the shares against it. Check this out. Okay,
so we have a stock and I'm gonna sell these shares So here's our here's our here's
our synthetic I'm gonna sell the shares boom all of a sudden you guys can see I
locked in my 13,040 but wait a minute. Wait a minute.
There's no free money here. Why is there no free money?
Why why can I not lock this in I hold the option? Yeah,
but why why so I can buy it.
So basically I can buy the stock at $44 You guys can see that right I can buy the
stock at 44 But I can go into the market right now and sell it for 58 aka locking
in an arm. Why is it not an arbitrage? Why is it not an arm?
This would be interesting to see if anyone gets chicks got it Yes,
because you're gonna pay the short interest on the short shares So even though you're
getting paid right now you're locking you by shorting those shares I have to pay
back that $1,400 in the shares okay,
so You know that was just I wanted you guys see how this synthetic works How the
at the money forward works and what the options market is implying It's implying
the stock going to $44 in the next 15 days That's pretty damn big That's a pretty
damn big drop. Kyle's got a good question, but isn't that 1,400 over a year?
But you're on a July expiry Right. So this is actually 15 days.
We're gonna collect this 1,500 We're gonna cut the 1,400 right now and in 15 days
We're gonna keep it if the stock didn't move we would keep that 1,500 bucks But
you got a thousand percent a year.
That's seven hundred dollars That's that's a ton of money the shares trading at
six seventy bucks or sixty bucks a thousand is six hundred So you're paying out?
600 times 100 that's 60 grand in a whole year But what that equals in 15 days,
which is our option expiration 14 is 1,400, right? So no ARB no ARB here,
right?
So what's happening is what what what we're seeing basically is that stock market
is saying? 60 bucks option market is saying $44 Someone's wrong.
Someone's wrong.
Someone's right either stocks are gonna go down or Stock market stocks only go up
stocks only go up, right?
So what we did was we said because the the call options are so cheap because why
we are Inherently getting the implied forward price we're buying this vertical spread
and we're getting this implied forward and that's why the stone the The vertical
spread is so cheap because think about it like this The options market is saying
at the money is $44 and we are buying a $65 call spread okay,
the options market is saying is $44 at the month and we are buying a 65 call spread
even though the stocks trading at 60 and that's why we can get seven to one on this
trade right if so code master saying Right.
So so Danny what we're saying is The options market is wrong because and even this
is okay Yeah,
I should have said the options market is different than stock market.
I should I shouldn't have said that my apologies The reason why the options market
is pricing this in is because of the borrow rate Right because people are shorting
the stock like crazy if no one was shorting the stock this wouldn't be we wouldn't
get a credit of $14 it'd be zero.
So because people are shorting shares so much it's pushing back The at the money
implied forward so that there's no arbitrage Okay,
think about like this if this was zero,
okay I wonder what you guys would do here you guys can tell me this Sean and I are
what do you want to do if they can tell me the answer here?
Okay If this was zero dollars, what is the trade if this was zero dollars?
What is the trade if we could buy this synthetic for zero dollars?
What's the trade?
I'm gonna freak out. I know someone's gonna get it here. Yeah,
then we got to wrap it up shit There's no way over but mm-hmm. It was good.
There's good talk. It's a good chat.
Come on guys I know you got this. I had polls for you guys, too,
but I had pull for you guys But I don't think we're gonna get to it.
So what do you guys think if this was zero dollars? What could we do?
What can we do?
Okay Okay,
who's that who said that code master code master super close what you would do is
you would sell this Super close you would sell this right buy shares and Collect
the 1,400 on the shares, right?
I'd lend I'd do that I'd lend I'd let my shares to Sean and collect the 1,400.
So because of that by people shorting the shares It's driving down the price of
the options market Getting mocked a because the people in the warrants are selling
and selling and selling that there's no more shares left and that's driving up The
cost to borrow and so what's happening is the options markets can Push down push
down at the money implied forwards game push down And so we can come in here and
be like, well, let's buy some call spreads For one to seven.
I've never seen that in my life. By the way,
I've never seen it that close to at the money I've never seen it.
So that is what's happening here Okay,
the markets are saying basically this thing's going to $44 in the next 15 days and
we're saying Probably not Probably not and not just that that that's only the first
step The probably not is only the first step.
The second step is what are the odds?
What are the odds you're giving me to be right? Oh,
you're giving me seven to one to be right here That's a rock and roll.
Let's do it. Let's let's play this game Okay,
so I hope you guys are seeing like so I hope you guys are like starting to see you
know Okay, so you guys won't do the polls real quick.
I think I had two questions. So let's do it. Let's just do it Okay,
let's just do it. All right,
and then we're gonna we're gonna finish it up there But I hope I hope you guys really
like this because this was like, you know,
I look at trades Sometimes not all the time sometimes when they come up.
Yeah when they come up these don't happen that often, right?
Remember I said guys play tight to the vest most of the time have your own systematic
strategy and then sometimes when these come up Take a bet man.
Take a bet and bet bet decent bet a good size Launch pull and so just yeah launch
pull and then actually I want to quickly go over.
I see lavelle's here So I really want to quickly go over a trade that she did that
was very similar Okay,
and that had huge risk reward because she was betting on the stock going up So betting
on this stock going up pays out big if you're right in this kind of a situation,
right? And if you're not blind, right and if you're wrong,
you're gonna you're gonna lose very very minimal Cody. You make me laugh,
man Co a send me a message if you found another art, but this is not an ARB.
There's no ARB here Just a good bet it's just a good bet Well,
yeah lay it on me dude,
or as Codemaster said lay it on us you know if you want to Stick around in after
dark for a few minutes. Yeah. Yeah,
we'll go hang out for a little we'll chat about it All right.
We'll give it ten more seconds Then we got to go get some beer beer and editing
down on the off the dock We'll put up some pencils for the bugs, you know,
dude, I'm gonna layer up like crazy. Yeah, perfect. Let's end the poll.
Boom Everyone almost everyone got it, right?
So It is true that short sellers are very confident,
but that's that's really not the reason why it's dry It's going down right because
the ball rate is high for example Bill Ackman,
right Bill Ackman was super confident that HLF was going down in the movie was called
On his Herbalife Herbalife the Herbalife movie, right? He was confident in it,
but he wasn't big enough To move the whole market borrow rate was only like 15%
Right,
but this is because the ball rate is very high and that's why we were able to get
a good risk-reward Okay, next one Pull two.
I guess this was a little too easy. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. How deep you went?
Yeah Yeah Okay,
so you guys get it you guys get it sick sick So so Danny high borrow rate actually
makes long-term investors More excited about holding their position because they
actually get to keep that premium.
So it doesn't necessarily make this stock go down But it does make the implied forward
go down It does make the future the mark because remember the market is just what
people think that's all it is So if everyone short the stock,
what does that mean?
It means people think in the future stocks are going down So that's what's gonna
happen options our future Spot is stocks are current, but there is you know,
some discounted cash in there Okay, super quick. Okay,
Bougie Bougie wants to know everyone got it, right, by the way Oh, yeah,
everyone got it, right. Great job guys Okay, Bougie quickly.
She wants to see not the money call They're still very cheap, right?
You can buy a $62 call super cheap You know,
it's $2 here at $17 Extrinsic on the put so these are super cheap If you get the
rip, you can make some huge money, right?
It's just I really like that leverage factor of nine to one on some of the trades
I was getting so I did decide to Do the vertical spread? Okay,
so Andreas is buying calls.
Oh, yeah. Okay mark. That's right.
I wanted to go over Lavelle's thing super quick So this is what Lavelle did she
did something like The 50-55 or something like this. So look at this.
Oops Okay You're collecting and I she got like some wicked price She did a $1 wide
and she got like 75 cents or something. So,
you know in these case scenarios Right as long as the stock stays above $51 you
get this If you oh, that's right, that's right Okay,
so Lavelle had this trade on and like when originally she sent it to me.
I said,
there's no way I said there's no effing way that she got this and So I was a little
skeptical about it I looked a little more into it,
you know we have there's a funny story about that. I'm not gonna go into it,
but You know if you guys want to hear it,
I'm sure Lavelle will chat with you about it. Okay. So here's her trade. Okay,
as long as the stock stays above 51 bucks She's gonna make 70 cents and the stock
goes below. She's gonna make 30 cents. So you guys can do the You know,
you guys can do it pretty simply your expected value right now.
Imagine if it's 50-50 Okay,
imagine if it's 50-50 what is her expected value on this trade?
It's pretty damn high, right? It's pretty damn high So this is just you know,
this is just one of the One of the trades that one of our members took so Lavelle
you guys can reach out to her So yeah,
you know Betting on the stock going up you are getting a crazy crazy crazy risk
reward scenario Right,
even in this case scenario for Lavelle's case the stock Can go down 10% 15% and
she'll still make money and not just money She'll make two and a half times her
risk.
Okay, so, you know,
we're all about finding these mispriced opportunities and it all started with you
know looking at some of these uh well,
actually Tico actually brought it to my attention.
He's actually in here It's cool actually brought to my attention and you know from
there just you go deeper and deeper down the rabbit hole you try to play out the
scenario you try to play out the story and Then you just have to fucking pull the
trigger Okay, okay guys,
oh why don't you buy the call and sell the put oh I see I see I see I Didn't do
it just because The stock could go down Right the stock could go down and I'm on
the hook and so went down to 30 Went down to 30.
I wouldn't like that very much So instead structure a trade where I can get huge
huge risk reward on time Yeah,
and on top of defined and on top of that more margin efficient I like to put up
a dollar and sixty cents for some of these trades sixty cents and then a dollar
for the Seven and ten wide with this. I'd have to put up a lot of money. Okay.
All right, dude Let's hop into the after dark for a bit. Okay guys,
we'll answer some questions there. Maybe hang out. Yeah.
Thanks Andres Well address.
I know you're just excited because you're gonna be buying some calls tomorrow.
You're like hell. Yeah Let's don't Okay,
guys, thanks first,
thanks for sticking around and I hope you guys learned a lot It was a little more
in-depth this one,
but I know you guys are getting a lot smarter So I got a I gotta step it up.
So these silver lives are gonna Warren Warren man,
Warren's in here Warren Cheers, buddy. What's going on man? Cheers Okay.