Well, hey guys, happy Thanksgiving to everyone In this live,
we're actually going to be talking about one of my favorite papers of all times
It's Aaron Brown and his sports betting model how he basically built a football
model that did extremely well over over a five-year period and what actually went
into his his model,
so Aaron Brown for those who that don't know is the risk manager at AQ are No,
no,
okay risk manager is the manager of the portfolio managers determines who gets what
capital what they can do yeah, so he's like the you know,
there's the If if you're if your hedge fund was a chess board, he's the king.
Yes.
He is the guy and now he He's finished with a QR now and now he is just on the board
of directors for for the firm But he is one of the best traders of all times And
here's the good thing about him not working there anymore He basically spends his
entire day on Quora answering questions and giving value and giving away secrets
as well Remember like he's um, he did he doesn't need any more money anymore,
right?
He's made hundreds of millions and So he can give back to the community now,
right and he actually probably it's a lot of joy out of you know Helping young quants
and he does that now, right?
He he is now a professor at University of Chicago and he He tries to help young
quants Turn him to traders. Yeah real traders,
right and and really and maybe not in that sense Like I want to make these guys
a lot of money,
but in the sense of I want them to build To help grow the financial world right
help grow the financial economy.
We can never forget guys that When a good trader comes into the market,
he makes the market more efficient Okay,
he hits he he discovers miss miss pricings and he makes the market more and for
me More efficient Meaning the pension the the person who is investing in a mutual
fund the person who is you know Buy and hold will always get a better price okay,
so By investing in really good quants.
The quant is gonna make a lot of money or the trader is gonna make a lot of money
But in doing so he's gonna make the market a lot more efficient He's gonna provide
a service for the person on the other side of the trade Okay,
and just a quick example of to see this is imagine there were no people trying to
take advantage of misinformation or inefficiencies in the market You know the person
who's investing in their pension fund Well that pension fund is gonna have to pay
a huge bid ask spread Right. So these people make the market more efficient.
Okay,
so with that said we're gonna jump into it and I'm just going to quickly show To
a little a tweet that I think I don't get a lot of information from Okay,
so This guy named Darren He's saying and remember guys I have nothing against these
people personally like I'm sure a lot of them are actually very good people But
at the same time when we're on Twitter or wherever we are We need to learn from
people who know what they're doing, right?
And this is why we're gonna go over go over Aaron Brown's paper today But we can't
always just be looking at Aaron Brown stuff We need to be able to figure out who
should we who should we be listening to? Okay,
so in this example This guy named Darren who's actually pretty popular on Twitter.
He said basically I'm always look like I'm looking for these Trade examples that
have an R squared of 0.9 Okay,
and what that really means is I can explain 90% of the variance I can really explain
S&P's price tomorrow with almost certainty. Okay,
and The reality is if that was the case,
you would be richer than Jeff Bezos in no time right in a very quick period So we
always have to be aware guys that when we see things like this We need to say,
okay Well,
who are they quoting who are they learning from and we can write those people off,
right?
One of the biggest things in trading is to be able to write people off and to listen
to the good people That's probably the whole the whole point not the whole point
But the whole battle in trading right if you're learning from the right people,
you're gonna get to the end goal a lot quicker Okay,
so I just want to quickly quickly mention that and we're gonna head over to the
paper, okay, so Aaron Brown wrote a paper about His football bets, okay,
so he started he was creating a model. What year is this? Oh,
this is recently 2017 He wrote this in 2017.
So he was doing it from 2012 to 2017. Correct? Cool.
So he wrote this paper in 2017 and Basically,
what he tried to do is explain How he built a strategy in in football that worked
for five years And The beauty about this paper guys,
and this is gonna tie back into well what I was just showing you about the r-squared
Okay,
so And we're actually gonna be talking a little bit a little bit about the r-squared
in this paper So slow me down guys if you think I'm going a little too fast a Lot
of people think in trading you need to you know,
be able to forecast the future extremely well Okay,
and the reality is you don't okay.
So an r-squared of 0.9 For example means you can forecast the future very well in
Trading in reality. There's so much noise in trading, right?
You only need to forecast the future by a very very small margin Okay,
extremely small you only need in other words You only need a really really small
edge.
And so what Aaron Brown did was basically create a system that only won 55% of the
time Okay, let's sit down for a second because let's really think about it.
Yeah Imagine a game where you bet one if you win you make one if you lose you lose
your one So risk reward is 1-1 and you had a 51% chance of winning. Okay,
is that not enough to get rich? Think about it.
Let's say you had a thousand dollars to start with can't you and you can bet as
frequently as you want.
Mm-hmm Can't you set up a system where that million dollar or one dollar turns a
thousand dollars turns into a hundred million dollars Can't we like actually statistically
come up with something that that happens. Isn't that what a casino does?
Because you know says we have a bankroll of a hundred million dollars.
We have 50 roulette tables running We have a 2% advantage right 52% chance of winning
We won the one risk reward and yet they turn it into millions and millions of dollars
We don't need to have that,
you know hearing that 90% hit rate and stuff That's a retail phenomena because it
gives people a sense of comfort and confidence when they can't explain the math
behind it Right hearing 51% chance doesn't doesn't sound like a lot of confidence
if you know,
it's 51 There's actually a lot of confidence And we really need to understand that
that's actually really good points like the tasty trade like Probability of profit.
Yeah, we're option off of probability of profit This is a retail phenomenon,
right? It's uh,
it's something that we shouldn't be looking at as a trader At the end of the day
as a trader, we don't we don't care about the probability of winning, right?
Why don't we just go sell lottery tickets?
We care about the expected value care about the expected value and selling lottery
tickets would actually be great money Well, yeah, it's not a lot of tickets,
but the probability of profits huge, right? Yeah,
you know probably profits you yeah So, what did Aaron Brown go and do well,
he created the system Okay,
that 155 and also if probability of profit was all that mattered long ball wouldn't
exist.
Exactly That's a very true right long ball as a strategy would not exist because
you you win very little Very little time. Oh,
you looked at it was probability of profit Even buy and hold equity might not make
sense Every year it's you know, you know, you make money most years,
but is it 90% probably not maybe it's a little bit higher Last ten years it has
been but that's a good point Yeah,
probably 70% It's that really good probability of profit So so Aaron Brown basically
did this one-to-one risk reward scenario in football where he had a 55% chance of
winning And he did extremely well with it.
Now the beauty of this article though,
and this article taught me so much When I started trading it the beauty of this
article is how we came up to this 55% So a lot of a lot of the time guys,
we will think like there's this one indicator That's gonna give us a 55% edge Okay,
there's this one thing that's gonna give us that 5% edge,
but in the reality There's not okay There are a few small indicators That when combined
give you a huge edge.
So do you want to maybe explain like the term factor based model? Yep Right.
So this is kind of like a factor based model that you're creating Yeah,
so you're gonna have let's say a couple factors right factor one is Okay,
let's use this as an example imagine you're looking at you're a car insurance company,
okay,
and you're trying to evaluate someone and You you you you look at only one factor,
which is Speeding tickets. Okay,
you look at speeding to how many how many speeding tickets does this person have?
Well,
you might have someone who's 50 years old got four speeding tickets when they were
in their 20s hasn't had a speeding ticket in 30 years and you're gonna be comparing
that person to somebody who's You know calling them equivalent to someone who's
25 and has four for speeding tickets or you know Someone who's gotten one every
10 years over 40 years,
but these people aren't all equivalent But number of speeding tickets might still
have some correlation with likelihood of a crash So what if you started to combine
more than one thing?
What if you looked at number of speeding tickets you looked at age?
You you looked at accident history you looked at the type of car they drive You
look at where you know, like a whole bunch of factors, right? well,
all of a sudden if you have one of them,
it's like we know that it's correlated,
but it's not like Everything we have all these other things But if you saw all of
them a certain way,
like the guys had five previous accidents is for speeding tickets He's 23 years
old he drives a Ferrari It's funny cuz I'm actually describing someone I know right
now. It's really funny but Describing us. I know describing us man But uh,
you see how all of a sudden we have a lot more confidence that this is somebody
who may not be the best Person to insure, you know what? I mean,
or we see the person's had four speeding tickets, but they're 60 You know,
they're 50 years old. They drive,
you know a Honda Civic they've had no accidents and You know,
all of a sudden it's two different pictures, right?
Also in something seems a lot more insurable than the other and what we call this
is a factor based model where we find a bunch of different things that are correlated
with What we're trying to figure out and we weigh them against each other To come
up with a better picture of what we're trying to look at So that's a car insurance
example,
and I'm assuming I haven't read this paper as in-depth as you but that's what's
happening here. Yeah,
and The better the factor the better of the model we're gonna better better the
factor the better the model Let's say for example right now nobody has figured out
that smoking causes more more car accidents Yeah, okay,
but as a trader or as a let's say a new a new pension fund you figure out that Smoking
causes car accidents. Well,
you can add that to your model now Right and now you can give better rates and that's
gonna make you more competitive and that's gonna be able to make you more money
Okay, so that's basically what we're gonna be talking about here.
This was huge huge huge in my growth So two things guys as we go through this I
want you guys to think of two two things.
Okay one You usually can't explain the outcome very well So very you can only explain
a very little bit of it You can a very little bit you can only explain very little
of it okay,
that's the first thing and then the second thing is the better the indicator the
better the result the more creative the Indicator and the better it is the better
the result. Okay, and Just to touch on when you say creative.
It has to make sense. Yeah,
right creative Is a good word like or like novel Right,
it has to be something a different lens that you're looking at it Maybe but it still
has to make sense. So for you know, for example,
you can't be saying the you know,
the number of forks in someone's cutlery set at home is correlated with their driving
record unless it's all knives in which case they might be crazy and you know bad
driver, but Besides that you can't actually quote, you know,
it needs to make sense Right. So keep that in mind too. So here we go.
So Quick quick summary 55% but each indicator only gave let's say 51% Okay,
I'm gonna add it all together you get 55 So first indicator over reaction,
okay So what he basically did was he said okay,
well Imagine guys Green Bay is gonna pit is gonna play I don't okay.
I honestly don't know football that well.
Can someone just comment to football teams in here?
No Ravens in Green Bay, you know the Ravens and Patters. Yeah, okay So, okay,
we were the guys are saying Cowboys and the Bears Okay,
so chicks don't kill me man.
So imagine the Cowboys are playing the Bears and they're playing tomorrow night
Okay,
and tonight We say that there is a 55% chance or let's say 70% chance that That
the Cowboys beat the Bears,
so let me just let me do a new screen share here So we can you guys can see what
I'm talking about here. What are you trying to draw? I'm gonna draw a timeline.
Okay Okay, so Okay, imagine we are here. Okay guys,
and this is this is today Tomorrow is game night. We'll call it GN.
Okay, and on GN we have the Bears vs the Cowboys okay,
and The Cowboys today We think is a 70% favorite.
Okay,
so we think tonight the Cowboys are a 70% favorite now Let's say the Bears win.
Okay, let's say the Bears win tonight So Bears so we have the night here. Boom.
Boom. It happens and Bears win.
So we'll label that Bears Well now in the future okay,
they're playing again and because the Bears won against the Cowboys The odds have
been shifted. It is now 50-50 Okay,
it is now 50-50. Well, we can say this there was an overreaction Okay,
meaning before before we saw this game it was 30-70 Okay before we saw that game.
It was 30-70 Once we saw the game The odds went 50-50 for the next time.
They're gonna play Well, we can say there was an overreaction Okay,
and this can be like in an earnings event. Okay,
let's say for example on average the company moves five percent Okay,
so let's say the earnings date so this is today and this is the earnings date Okay,
and we say well the implied move on for fair value should be 5% and then on earnings
day It moves 20% Okay,
and so because it moved 20% the next earnings date the implied move is 15% Okay
Well,
we could say that this is an overreaction and it is probably a lot closer to this
5% number Okay, does everyone understand that?
Does everyone understand that one? What was the cue?
the question oh It was just which Give me a football team. Okay,
so we all understand this one Let's keep going. Okay,
so that is the overreaction Right, he's quantifying that overreaction. Yes.
So he's saying, you know,
we're not gonna go over the quantum quantification That's you know,
that'll be for you guys to do in your spare time and I'll send you guys the paper
But basically like this right for example Suppose Green Bay play Chicago in week
7 before the games of week 6 We would have expected Green Bay to be a 3.5 favorite
But after the week 6 results Green Bay is now a 1.5 favorite.
Okay We're gonna guess that this is an overreaction. Okay,
and he's saying that this is a very reliable signal and It's basically because of
this. Okay, he basically says And this is a concept of shrinkage.
We're not gonna get too much into it today But we are going to talk a little bit
about it What he's basically saying is the the the spread went from here to here
Okay went from here to here and from it going from here to here Was two components
One component was signal. So yes, you know,
the stock did move 15% after earnings There should be maybe a little bit of a structural
change That's the signal but there's also an overreaction right and the noise the
extra bit Right,
and that is what he is saying here a little bit of a tricky concept if you guys
have any questions We'll chat about it a little more and Then there's actually a
lot more nuances in this paper if you guys want to read it.
It's really exciting It's very very very exciting. Another thing.
He says here basically is that the market makers, right?
They are going to overreact.
So if they get a whole bunch of Money being poured at them in one direction.
They're going to adjust their book even further Because you know,
they don't have to switch to the other side if they're wrong, right?
They can always just lean on this right and and that's the concept of this It's
a really good read guys, and I highly recommend you guys read it,
okay, so Here's this other example, right? Here's this other factor.
So we're going through factors. First factor is the overreaction factor. Okay?
so the second factor is Every reaction has a predictable overreaction Okay,
and this was okay,
this is a very cool concept and What Aaron what what is actually happening here
is we just so what's actually happening in the in this in this factor,
which is That every overreaction has a predict every what do you call it?
Every reaction has a predictable overreaction. Okay,
and what this is saying is that imagine guys Okay,
who is like a really broke football team or a really broke a basketball team?
Was the Raptors for a while, okay,
so imagine like two years ago Raptors was playing in in LA the Hornets They sound
they sound pretty much they actually sound super okay,
so Marcus imagine the Hornets were playing in LA Lakers Okay.
Now let now let's just think about the situation for a second you have a very wealthy
team Playing at home. Well,
there's gonna be a lot of money coming in betting on LA Lakers Right.
Everyone's going to the game. They're all betting on LA Lakers, right?
They they want to see their team win while they're at the game Right,
or they're you know,
they're playing at home Everyone's telling their friends are going to the bars and
they got the got the money on LA Lakers Right.
So what's gonna happen and what Aaron Brown saying here is there is this?
home-field advantage Okay,
I know a home-field advantage home field It's gonna be skewed too much Okay,
so if LA Lakers is playing the Hornets, right?
There's not a lot of money being bet on the Hornets, right?
who you know the I don't know where they're from, but the the team is broke.
They don't have a lot of money being behind them and so Who is gonna be betting
on those odds, right?
Who's gonna be pushing that not a lot of people yet All the retail everyone else
is gonna be betting on LA Lakers Okay,
so for that reason you're gonna have this skew Or you're gonna have this skew Pushed
into LA Lakers and so what Aaron Brown saying is bet against that underdog right
You know,
there's gonna be too much money being pushed into the home field Especially if it's
a wealthy team,
it's sort of like getting a one three two fly Exactly a super cheap bet with a high
payoff That's a really good way to say you only got a hit at 10% of the time Yeah,
so that that's another factor that he adds into the model. Okay,
so let's get back here. Let me share my screen again Okay,
so he calls this a power rating and he says it's It's basically it's this is what
he calls the home field advantage. Okay?
Okay, next. Okay. There's this rematch this rematch one where Okay,
this one we're not gonna go too much into detail What's it about what's the gist
of it?
It's basically like It's basically like what we talked about in the first in the
first In the first example,
but it's a little different I did it more specific for a rematch,
but you could do it for not for rematch,
but we'll so we're just gonna skip over it Okay.
So then what he basically does is he gathers a whole bunch of data? Okay,
and each predictor,
okay Is very small right it has about 51% edge but combined they got 53.5% probability
which is above his 52% for a single factor. Okay, so For a single factor is 52,
but when combined with those three we get 53 and a half,
but he keeps adding so this is this concept of Okay, this is actually okay.
We're gonna skip over a couple of the factors here guys You guys can read over it
a whole bunch of factors. Yeah,
I really like this one here So he basically goes from 53 and a half.
He adds a couple more factors and gets to 55 I really like these two guys.
So we're gonna go over this one and feeding the hungry because Okay,
because he and I really want you guys to really embrace these next two factors They're
really gonna change your mind on how on how you think about trading.
Okay, you know what?
We're just gonna go to feed the hungry because this one is my favorite Okay,
so basically guys If a team is consistently losing,
okay So let's say we're gonna I'm gonna stop my shirt stop sharing for a second
and we're gonna go dive into the factor We're gonna think of actually in terms of
the bookie I want you I really really want you guys to pay attention here because
this is trading in a nutshell This is trading at the highest level here. Okay?
I want you to think about yourself as a bookmaker Okay,
and you are making the spreads. Okay. Well, there's a guy Okay,
he has you know, he's got a wonderful family.
He's out in He's out in Missouri and he loves betting on football Okay,
and every single week he bets on his team. He bets on his team winning. Okay?
Now if that guy is losing all the time, he's gonna stop trading.
He is gonna stop Paying me commissions. I don't want that. I want him to win.
I want him to keep winning I want him to keep I don't want to keep winning.
I want him to win every so often so that I Can keep him coming back every single
day for more? Okay, and this is what the market makers do. Okay,
they're saying in this in this factor. It's called feeding the hungry Okay,
this guy every single week.
He's he's betting on the Hornets He's been on the Hornets every single week and
he's losing Because they suck I'm sorry.
There's a if there's any hornets fan here I have no clue but Marcos made it sound
like they they're a bad team. So I'm gonna go with Marcos You know,
they're not a good team.
And so I have to as a market maker shift those odds Give that guy sometimes some
juice Right sometimes some juice so that he can come back and bet more again Okay,
and I want you guys to stop for a second and think about all the traders out there
Who are thinking in terms of the guy from Missouri?
He's they're sitting there saying this is going up.
This stock is breaking out to new highs And on the other side of that trade is a
guy sitting there Saying I'm gonna let you win every so often.
I just want you guys to think about that for a second That is the game we play Okay,
that's the game that we play somebody is on the other side of our trade Saying no
problem. I'm gonna let you win every so often,
but I know That you're gonna lose all your money and the guy on the other side of
it of the table is Studying and trying to find those breakouts.
It's brutal Right. Just think about that for a second.
That is actually the game we play Okay and so that is that is what this factor is
what this factor is basically saying is After four losses if a team loses four times
in a row We're gonna we're gonna bet on them. Okay,
we're gonna if they lose four times in a row We're gonna bet on them because the
market makers are going to start adjusting it so that these guys have the odds So
there's actually book. Yeah,
that's actually a really good point You might want to clarify what you're saying
there so remember guys,
it's we're not saying it's it this is this is so crucial Okay,
we're not saying the market makers are gonna do this So this like this is the real
odds The market makers are gonna do this, right?
And this is a huge mistake in trading that like I'm gonna know for certainty or
I'm gonna know with 90% of the time Well, I'm gonna know with you know,
a thousand percent of the time. It's a little tweaks to the Eevee.
It's Exactly it's a tiny tweak to the Eevee and you know,
let's say not all the market makers are doing it but some of them are doing it and
it's just that tiny tweak to the Eevee because think about this like If you you
know a lot of people who they focus on risk management Well,
you know something I say to people who are I'm like,
can you risk manage your way to success at a roulette table? No,
all you can do is bleed out slower because you have negative Eevee So imagine there's
a really negative Eevee situation Well,
if you went in there and instantly lost half your money You'd you'd take the other
half your money and leave but what if I tweaked what I'm willing to offer you a
bit that gives you a little bit better Eevee and Keeps you in the game a bit longer
Maybe I maybe I end up leaving with 80% of your money in the long run because I
gave you a little bit more and You have winners Right,
one of the what is it we're excited We're doing some studying on what makes a game
addicting and one of the things was perceived skill a lot of near misses and winners
You need to have winning situations.
You have a lot of winning situations more losers than winners though You have a
lot of near misses like I just missed it like It was a false breakout Looking back.
I can see it now Perceived skill more chart time equals more money made Right and
and as the game maker,
right if I'm playing against that person and I have more knowledge and and more
skill I can set I you know,
like a market maker can change what they offer To keep it more intriguing.
Yeah,
and it happens It actually happens and if you even if it would make sense that it
happens if you look at the books as well there's actually a few few market makers
that actually Run the show think about this when we Back to the JD trade.
Mm-hmm if we came in and instantly dumped 200 lots on them the market maker gets
out so we sit there and go what can I do with this guy?
To increase my EV and to milk get more money out of this guy.
That's a really points Well,
right we do that when we are in the driver's seat when we've got the winning hand
We're trying to maximize our P&L and even if that means not coming in hard Right
easing our way into positions or even guys letting orders sit Yeah,
or even remember we talked about the Norwegian guys They would actually hit the
guy so he would back off and then come in with a whole bunch of orders on this side
Oh, yeah No, Kim,
right Everyone tries to do different things to get the most value out of someone
else and that's really what this is saying. Yep And then okay,
so let me just share my screen again And there's one more actually guys that we're
gonna go back to that.
You guys are really gonna like as well So that's that's the squeaky.
That's the feeding the hungry. Okay,
I highly recommend you guys go and you got a key You got to keep the suckers in
the game simply put because that's you know, like you know,
imagine you were like a really good poker player and you went into a room with like
a whole bunch of You know rich businessmen in Vegas enjoying a few drinks at the
table Well,
you're not gonna come in and fucking put your world poker to a bracelet on the table
You know, you're gonna try and you know,
you're gonna you're gonna you're gonna play a game with these guys Knowing that
in the long run you're gonna win and I really want this last conclusion guys to
really sit with you And this is what from one of the one of the smartest most wealthiest
traders of all times I'm really want this sync with you.
Okay And don't read it.
Let's listen to listen to the wonderful voices over here. Okay?
The point of all this that why he did this and why he did so well with this is that
it's easy to beat the Bookie or the market or the house or City Hall?
You use simple quantitative methods You don't need fancy math or inside information
or rare insights You get a small edge not the kind of certainty too many people
claim which we just talked about earlier But an edge that can produce Reliable profits
over a long period of time. Okay.
Now he now he does go and say you can build better models Let's say 58 59 percent,
but those require a lot of work. Okay, but it's easy And I wouldn't say easy.
It's I think when he says easy,
I think he means like it's not like it's not booty Exactly it's this is not black
magic. Yeah,
this is something that exists well within the realm of human capabilities it has
for a long time and it's There for you if you acquire those skills and apply it
to this game. That's exactly what he's saying, right?
It's easy to do well in a math test you study you listen in class and you come in
right? So that's it No, you're shit Go from there Right,
and I think this is a huge thing.
He says here the difference is quantity not quality Once you have the skills and
you know what you're doing Like there's so many different things you can try.
There's so many different indicators and there's creativity right,
but it's not like like think about for you like Looking for earnings factors.
Yeah, how many factors did you look at thousands hundreds literally hundreds?
Tested all of them back tested every single one found a couple found a couple.
That's not quality of work. That's quantity of work Yeah,
the quality is the skill set. Yeah,
the quantity is there are way too many combinations To think that you're gonna try
one and it's gonna work that's why I like, you know,
sometimes some guys in the group be like Here's an indicator that I used to use
back in the day or that someone told me about can you test it for me?
And I'm like before I even look at it I know it's probably not gonna work because
what are the odds exactly?
There's just the odds that it worked knowing that it's coming from a guy who?
Hasn't tested it. Yeah, what are the odds that it works?
Outperforms the market at least I remember when Sean eyes were helping people do
back tests back in the day every back test like we had to know anybody but yeah,
cuz I was like driving me crazy cuz like You give me a back test and like when you
gave it to me We'd be like and we each I would look at it.
Would you like it's not gonna work, right?
so That's one but keep in mind guys like like just to bring it home because you
know We got some newer guys in here. We are not saying this game is impossible.
We are actually saying That in the retail space,
you were probably one of the 1% that are actually on the right track here,
right? We're never gonna sugarcoat. We're never gonna say hey,
it's gonna be easy But what I will say is you are actually on the right track by
being here yeah,
and for the guys here that have been in other groups and You know gone through signal
services and read all the books and done all this stuff As you're a little further
down the road in the game You could you can speak to that that you've seen both
sides, you know, what's going on?
So I'm going to send you guys this this paper I'm gonna post in the group So Marco,
so you can definitely find TA patterns that work you should read a evidence-based
technical analysis Yes, by David Aronson, please read that one Marcos.
It's gonna open your eyes.
That is one book that opened my eyes is basically like technical analysis can work
if you remove subjectivity and you remove subjectivity and and Go a little deeper
like basically apply quantitative methods to your technical analysis and you can
do it Yeah, and it was his mind opening.
Okay.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna send you all this paper in the traders chat
Yep I will type the book into the traders chat as well just after this Yeah,
Johnny, you know, you might like that one,
too It's is it is it worth reading if you're not trying to learn all the math behind
it.
It's awesome read Anything by Aaron Brown is David Aronson Oh David Aronson.
Oh the technical analysis. Yeah. Yeah, that's good. Yeah. Okay,
it's good it's a I can't remember if it's like a union book where it's like,
no, no, no. No,
it's not math heavy at all It's a Johnny give it a read give it a read.
I think you will really really like it. It's not option-based at all Okay,
it's all about Delta one so buy and selling future stocks 4x,
whatever But it's basically bringing an evidence-based approach and when I read
it my whole a lot of my game changed David Aronson Evidence-based trading.
Okay,
David Aaron says it evidence-based trading evidence-based rating evidence-based
technical analysis. Yes He's an awesome guy. I've learned so much.
He's on Twitter, right? No, he's not on Twitter. Unfortunately. Oh, man. Yeah,
he's unreal guy He's really really really smart Okay,