Okay. Okay, guys. So in this, in today's live,
we're gonna be talking about risk-neutral densities. Basically,
what does the market think is gonna happen in the future?
What is the market telling us about the future? Right? Remember,
a trade only happens when we disagree with the market.
If we agree with the market, there's no trade because it's already priced in,
right? It's like this. If we think Apple is gonna go up,
and everyone thinks Apple is gonna go up, well,
it's probably already priced in, right?
So Apple's already fairly pricing the future return.
If I'm selling this phone for $100, and you think it's only worth $100,
and you want to resell it, what's the point in buying it, right?
Where's the money to be made? You're gonna buy it from me for $100,
and go sell it for $100? There's no money there.
Trade happens when I'm selling this phone for $100,
and you think it's worth $200, and you, well, this is a Samsung S9,
so it's only worth $50. So buying it would actually be a mistake,
no matter what I was charging you for it. But you get the point, right?
You need to disagree on the value of something in order for there to be a trade.
And when it comes to the option space, the cool thing about the options is,
the options are future forecasting tools, right?
More so even than the stock price. So we can look at the option chain.
We can extract some information out of it and be like,
what is the market telling us that these options,
and what are these options telling us that the market is saying is going to happen
in the future, right? Remember, depending on who's buying what,
what people are willing to pay for different things across the option chain,
and through time,
we're able to extract or create a prediction of what the market is saying is gonna
happen in the future. And then we can compare that to what we think,
and maybe find a trade. And then on top of that, when we are trading, remember,
guys, we're never trading with certainty, okay?
That's the most important thing. You know, when someone says,
buy this because it's going up tomorrow, that's wrong. They have no idea,
right? You are trading a probability-based game. It's like this.
You think there's a 60% chance that the stock goes up tomorrow.
Or let's say you're really, like, let's say you're a Forex trader,
and you think there's a 95% chance that the stock goes up tomorrow,
or that the Forex pair goes up tomorrow. Now, you need to think, okay,
what does the market think it's gonna go up tomorrow?
Maybe the market thinks there's only a 50% chance that it goes up tomorrow.
And so in that case, the asset is gonna be cheap,
and you can buy the pair and make money in the long run. Now, 5% of the time,
you're gonna lose money. That doesn't mean making a bad trade.
And that's assuming you have a good forecast, right? Remember,
Sean always says this.
A good trade or a winning trade is not always a good trade,
and a losing trade is not always a bad trade.
You're playing a probability-based game.
If you think there's a 75% chance the stock goes up, and it goes down,
you got unlucky. There's nothing wrong with that.
It doesn't mean the trade was bad. Right. Because if it came up again,
you should take it again. And doing that every time it comes up,
in the long run, you make money, right?
It's like looking at a downtrend in stocks, like in the S&P, and being like,
buying the S&P doesn't make money. Well, no. We know how much it makes.
It makes 8%, right? But you will go through these downswings.
If it only went up until the right, how would it make a lot more than 8%?
Renato, you like the hair. Thanks, man. Appreciate it.
And we're going to be talking about Sean. Sean got one, too.
We got a couple of nice, fresh cuts. Okay. So let's jump into it. Okay.
What we're going to do, we're going to do quite a bit here, guys.
I want you guys to give me— I'm going to share my screen.
I want you guys to tell me, first guy to say it,
a stock that you like that's liquid. Okay?
We're going to start with a liquid stock.
Give me a stock that you like that's liquid. All right. Apple. Apple.
Apple is first. Oh, we don't— Okay. We'll do Apple and MA, Marcos. Okay.
So— Oh. Okay. Here we go.
So let's— So I wrote some code here for you guys. So what we're going to do,
and I'm going to go step-by-step to show you guys, okay?
So don't worry about the code.
The code is just a tool to help us collect the data. Okay?
So what we're going to do is I pulled the option data, okay, for Apple.
So let's take a look. Okay. So here's Apple. Here's the trade date,
which is today. Here's the expiration date. So this is, you know, October 2nd.
This is October 9 options, October 16. We have the strike.
We have the call volume, open interest. We have the implied volatilities.
We have the option prices, everything. Okay?
So now what we're going to do is these options are forward-looking, right?
When you buy an option,
that person who's selling it to you has some view of the future.
Let's say it's a 30-day option. They have some view of the future.
So what we can do is we can actually take this option data,
take the implied volatility data,
and graph out what the market thinks is going to happen in the future.
What is the probability that the market thinks the stock is going to follow?
And guys, we are always trading this. Okay?
So even though if you don't know it, we're going to talk about it right now.
We're always trading it.
So let's look at the – which expiration do you guys want to look at?
Give me the expiration. I have the October 16 here,
but give me the expiration you guys want to look at.
Where's the chat? Chat, chat, chat, chat. There it is. Got it.
What do you guys want to look at? What's the expo? October 16, November 2nd.
What do you guys want to look at? Okay. Renato is saying October 16. Okay.
So what I did was I just took all the options for Apple from October 16. Okay?
Now, I created this model. Okay? That basically – it's called a dual gamma.
It basically tries to price out the – it takes the option data,
the implied volatility data, and turns it into a probability.
Probability density. So let's graph it out.
Okay. So here we have all the strikes. Okay? We have all the strikes here.
And here is what the market thinks is the probability of Apple going to those strikes.
Okay? So on the y-axis, we have the probability. On the x-axis,
we have the strikes. Okay? So here's an example.
The probability that Apple goes to $50 in two weeks is basically zero.
Make this a little bigger. Okay?
The probability that Apple goes to – and so each dot here, guys,
is an option contract. Each single dot is an option contract.
So the probability that Apple goes to 50 is almost zero.
Did you explain the y-axis? Yeah. It's the probability. Okay.
So this is what the market thinks is going in the future.
So if I actually graph out Apple's current price, okay?
So this is where Apple's current price is. So we can look at this,
and it really looks like the market is saying it's normally distributed.
It's random. It's going to be random going forward. They don't know.
They don't know if it's likely to go up, if it's likely to go down,
where the volatility is going to be. They're not too sure.
And it's slightly flatter to the upside. Ever so slightly. Over here? Yeah.
What do you mean flatter? Like it stays higher for longer. Yeah, yeah. So,
okay. So that's actually a really good point.
So this one doesn't really show it that well.
We're going to look at some other examples.
But we can see that there's actually a higher chance that the stock rallies.
Very slightly. Okay, very slightly that the stock rallies a lot, right?
So it's trading at 113. This is like 130. Okay, so there's a little bit of...
This is basically a call skew. And we're going to look into this.
They're implying like an 8% chance of it going to 130. And like, you know,
like a 6% chance of it going to 70.
So let's take a look at something like...
Let's take a look at something that has a lot of risk. Let's take a look at...
Here, you know what? Let's go to the terminal for a second.
It's so funny how you still use my login for the terminal.
Okay, so let's look at something that has a lot of skew. Okay,
so a lot of call skew. Sorry, a lot of call skew. Okay,
let's get this thing pretty liquid.
And we'll get price above 40. Okay, so this thing, Datadog.
No idea what that is. Kyle was chatting to me about this. Okay, so this thing,
if we look here, if we look at Datadog,
okay? If we look at Datadog, there's call skew. You guys see that, right?
There's call skew here on Datadog. So let's take a look at it.
So we're going to take a look at Datadog here.
Should be good. All you change is the ticker, right?
Okay, here we go. Check this out, guys. Okay, so if I plot the...
Okay, so you guys can see here that there's actually,
there's a higher chance of a huge up move. You can see how fat,
like there's not a lot of options for this one,
but you can slightly see how fat this is over here. Okay,
and then you can also see that these options right here at around $85 are a bit
overpriced, right? This line should follow down like this and come in,
but there's a little bit of clustering here. So these 85, 83,
82 options over here, these are slightly overpriced, right? Relative to,
let's say, this one right here. Okay,
so a market maker might come in and he would sell these and buy these options.
And buy around it, sell the overpriced individual contract.
But as a positional trader,
we're more interested in where is the overpriced option in general?
So what else can we do here? Well,
what we can do is we can actually graph the historical returns of Datadog.
Okay, we can graph the historical returns of Datadog. Now,
let's take a look here.
What do we notice about the actual realized distribution? This is Datadog.
What we realize is there's actually a fatter left tail. Okay,
meaning that the risk is usually to the downside.
The down moves are usually more frequent.
The big down moves are usually more frequent, okay, than the big up moves.
Okay, let me show you guys. Let me plot a line here. Let me plot a graph here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to put a line at negative 0.04. Okay,
and a line at 0.04. So 4% up versus 4% down.
Okay, and what we actually see here, guys,
is actually we're going to go not even that high up.
We're going to go right here.
Okay, so what we notice here, guys, is remember, y-axis is the frequency. Okay,
so there are usually larger down moves, right? You can see right here.
There are usually larger down moves than there are large up moves.
So what does this mean?
This means that there should be put skew rather than call skew.
But when we look at the data,
when we look at what the options market is implying, okay,
we can see that there's actually call skew, right?
The market's thinking that there's a higher chance the stock blows to the upside.
But when we look at historical realized distributions, we say, well,
guess what? No, it doesn't. Now,
this doesn't mean that there's not some fundamental reason that's happening right
now. For example, when Walmart was getting bid up for TikTok,
we should have a little bit of volatility to the upside, right?
But sometimes the market gets so unreasonable. Okay,
we're going to look at one more, SPY.
And then we're going to look at how you can price this without graphing this risk
neutral density.
Look at this, guys, okay? We have a fat tail. We have a very, very fat tail.
See that? Let me put a line right here for you guys to see it. So AB line,
let's do... So spot price right now, I believe.
I believe the current spot price is...
So S&P is currently trading at or was currently when this data was pulled is $334.
So if we go, for example, let's say we're going to go 10% down. So actually,
we're not going to go that far down. We're going to go, let's say, 5%, 4% down,
okay? And we're going to go 4% up.
Okay,
let's actually go a little bit more.
Here we go, boom. Okay, look at this, guys, okay?
So you guys can see right here. So here is a 8% move up.
The market's saying that there's an 8% chance of this happening over the next two
weeks, 8% chance, okay?
But an 8% down move actually has more of a 15% chance happening, okay?
That's what the options market's implying. It's saying, well,
there's actually a bigger chance that a large move down happens.
And there's a smaller chance that a large up move happens.
Steven, this is implied,
okay? And then what we can do is we can also graph it. Like,
does this make sense? Well, let's take a look,
okay? Well, absolutely, this makes sense. Absolutely, right?
You see some right around here. So if I did, let's say, we're going to say,
let's say, a 3% down move, 3% up move. Okay, let's do this.
Actually, let's do a little less. So this is on the daily timeframe, guys.
These are the daily terms, okay? There is,
it's more likely that we have a down move than we do have an up move or large up
move, okay? Not a, it's not a small up move. It's a large up move, okay,
versus a large down move. The chances are a lot higher. Now,
what we notice though,
what we're seeing in the implied versus the realized is that the difference was
huge, right?
And that's why they say selling out of the money puts is a long-term profitable
strategy because it usually implies more than what actually happens, right?
The implied skew is usually overpriced, right?
There's a lot of research on this.
And this is where you guys see it in firsthand, okay?
So how can, without having the risk-neutral densities in front of us, okay,
how can we make a decision? How can we say, well, what's the market implying?
Well, it's very simple. And we're going to go thinkorswim,
and we're going to price it out right now.
So you guys can see what is the market implying an up move versus a down move.
And just to be clear, guys, whenever you make a trade,
you always have a view on the distribution of the future, right? As soon as,
if you don't know for certainty, think about this, guys.
If you don't know for certainty, you have a distribution, you have odds,
you have probabilities. When you take a trade,
if you don't know for certain that this stock is going to go up,
you have a distribution of possible outcomes.
It is likely that the stock goes up, let's say 3%.
It's less likely it goes up 10%,
and it's not likely that it goes down 2% or 3%,
whatever your odds are when you're making your bet. That's your implied odds,
right? Whenever you make a trade,
you're actually calculating that in your head, whether you know it or not.
And if we graphed out all your thoughts and opinions about the stock,
it would look something like this,
okay? And this is what the options market is showing you here,
okay?
So let's see what's going on here.
So we said SPY had a lot of put skew, okay? We said SPY had a lot of put skew.
So what does that mean? So the market is saying that there is a chance,
the down move is a lot larger than an up move.
That's what the market is saying, okay?
So the down move is a lot larger than an up move. So what do you guys think?
Is the market saying that S&P is going to go down or the S&P is going to go up?
What is the most likely scenario for tomorrow?
Stephen's saying up slightly, okay? Does anyone disagree with Stephen?
Ains is saying down.
Okay, Stephen's right here, okay? Because think about it like this, Ains.
You're in a basketball. You are betting on a basketball game, okay?
And it's going to, like, actually, Ains,
what sport is like your favorite sport?
Because then it's more relatable and then maybe it will help you understand.
What's your favorite sport to play?
NFL, okay. So, fuck, I don't know any NFL. Okay,
so who's like the worst team and the best team?
Okay, Packers is worst team or best team? Okay, Packers best, Jets worst. Ains,
okay, Ains is saying Tampa's best. Okay, so we're going to mix it up.
We're going to say it's Tampa versus the Jets in Tampa, okay?
Tampa's playing the Jets in Tampa.
What do you think the probabilities of Tampa winning is?
90%, exactly, right? It's going to be huge. They should win eyes closed.
So what are the odds going to be on betting on the Jets, right?
You should be getting a huge payout if you bet on the Jets and they win,
but you're not going to get a big payout if you bet on Tampa and they win,
right? So that's what's happening here.
If the market is saying there's a chance of a huge down move, okay?
So the chance of a huge down move, aka the Jets winning, okay,
then you are going to get paid out big, right?
But it's most likely that Tampa is going to win. So if you buy the S&P, right,
you are most likely going to get a little bit of an up move tomorrow, right?
You might get a percent tomorrow,
but less likely you're going to have a huge down move.
It has to compensate for that, right? Imagine if it was like this, guys.
Imagine if it was more likely that the stock went down and it was more likely that
if it did go down, it would go down like crazy.
That would be like saying if the Jets win, or sorry,
that would be like saying if Tampa wins, you get paid out three to one.
That doesn't make sense, right? So the way we look at it is,
the way the market looks at it is, it has to be a fair bet, right?
If I'm going to buy equities, let's say there's two scenarios tomorrow. Okay,
I'm going to buy this stock.
It's either going to go up very little or it's going to go down a lot. Well,
in order for this to be a fair bet, the up move has to be more likely.
Does that make sense? In order for me to bet on Tampa, it has to be a fair bet.
And that also means that I'm going to get paid out less because it's more likely
that Tampa wins.
Okay, so if we see big put skew, meaning the risk from last night,
from last week's live or this week's live, the risk is to the downside,
meaning the big move is to the downside,
then most likely the stock needs to go up. Okay,
so we're going to look at that right now.
We are going to look at a 14-day option.
Okay, and how we're going to do this, so I'm going to go on SPY here.
Okay, and what I'm going to do is I'm going to price a vertical spread.
So S&P is trading at 334. Okay, that was the last close, 334. Okay,
so what we're going to do is,
we're going to go to the 334 strike and we're going to buy a 10-wide vertical spread.
So we're going to go 5 down to 329 and we're going to go 5 up to 339.
Okay, so far so good. We're going, the spot price was 334.
We're going 5 down and we're going 5 up. Okay,
so now we have a call spread 329, 339. So let's take a look here.
Okay, so here it is. Okay, so here is our bet. Now,
what do you guys notice here? So here's where the current stock price is.
Okay, let me just turn this into,
just make this a lot easier for you guys to see.
Okay, see this line here? This line is where the current stock price is.
What do you guys notice about this bet? Okay,
pretend this bet is the Tampa Bay versus the Jets. If I said this is our,
who are we betting on here, guys? If you had this payout right now,
if this was your payout, who would you be, who would we bet,
who would we be betting on here?
Okay, and this is, yeah. Who would we be betting on if this was the win,
if this was the winning side?
Rami said the Bucks. Is that Tampa Bay Bucks? What's the other team? Jets.
I have no idea. Okay, Mark was saying Tampa Bay. Okay, so, exactly. Why?
Why would this, why would this spread here?
Why would this trade be betting on Tampa?
Okay. Tell me more, Ram. Tell me more. You're on the right track. Tell me more.
Why? Why is this here? I'm going to make this actually 575. Why?
Why is it that this trade here is betting on Tampa? How do we know this?
How can we infer that this is betting on Tampa and not the Jets?
What do you guys think? What's going on here? Right?
Okay. Marco's odds are in our favor. What is,
tell me more about the payoff of this thing. Tell me more about the payoff.
The payout. Exactly. What about the payout, Ram? Tell me more.
I need to know more here, bud. It's not, it's actually not one-to-one. So,
if we lose, we lose 5,750. If we win, we win 4,250. The payout is less.
Exactly. Right? Because Tampa has a higher chance of winning,
we have to get paid out less. We can't get paid out the same. So,
and we're looking at this spread here. Okay.
The market's telling us that the most likely scenario is S&P 500 in the next 16
days to be up. Now, that's great. But what are these odds?
What is the market telling us here? What are the odds we're getting?
The odds we're getting is there's a 57.5% chance. So,
all we did was we took our debit and we divided it by the width of the strikes.
Okay. The width of the strikes. And that is 57.5% chance. So,
the market is saying that there is a 57.5% chance that in the next 16 days,
S&P 500 is going to be up.
Now, we have something to work with here, guys. Okay.
Imagine I just told you that. Imagine I told you this, actually.
There's a 75% chance that the market's going to be up. What could you do?
What could you do? Well, first off, you'd have to think to yourself, well,
that doesn't make sense. Right? That's kind of...
The market's telling me there's a 75% chance up. I've never seen that before.
Right? It's usually 55, 57 at best.
Right? So, what we could do is we could sell this spread.
Right? We could sell this spread.
Because this spread is giving us great risk reward. Right?
Imagine if it was 75% chance, guys. Okay? It'd be $7.50. Okay?
This is what we would have.
Now, this trade would be an amazing trade. This would be a beautiful trade.
Right? It'd be huge. Huge. Huge. Huge trade. When I said beautiful there,
I felt like I sounded like him. It's going to be beautiful. Beautiful.
Beautiful. Okay. So, if you put on this trade, right? Well,
there's a 25% chance. Okay?
Sometimes you can be wrong here is what I'm trying to say here.
Sometimes you can be wrong. And you might say to yourself, Oh,
this was a bad trade. No, this was a great trade. Right?
Because most of the time you're going to be right. Right?
Or this trade has a positive expectancy. Okay? So,
let's go back to our risk-neutral densities. You guys can see that. Right?
We're looking at, I think you guys are going to have a nicer perspective. Now,
when we look at this, Let me actually just take the logs of this. So,
you guys might be able to see it a little bit better.
Okay.
So, you guys see how fat this tail is? Right?
You guys see that fatness in the tail, right?
Okay. What this is saying is, So, the,
I'm just going to take a screenshot here. So, we're going to draw on it, guys.
You can use it.
Oh, nice. Okay.
Is this good over here? This box? Yeah, it's good. Okay. So,
I get a straight line. Okay. So, here is where spot price is going to be. Okay?
So, what is this telling us? Well,
it's telling us that the most likely scenario, Remember, this is probably,
You still have the, yeah. This is frequency. Okay? This is frequency.
The most likely scenario is this. Is a little tiny up move.
That is the most likely scenario. Now, if this was the most likely scenario,
We would just buy stocks. We would just buy stocks and make money.
Make so much money. Okay? We have a little bit of an edge.
We'd make a ton of money. But that's not right.
We can't just make free money like this. We can't just print money.
There has to be a catch. And the catch is, The chance of a huge down move.
Okay? Is higher than the chance of a huge up move. So,
we are being compensated for the small probability,
For the higher probability of winning.
Because of a larger probability of a large down move.
And that is called risk neutral. Because we are indifferent.
We are risk neutral. We don't care if we sell or if we buy.
Because it's a fair bet.
Okay? And that is what this is all about.
It's about graphing out what are the options thinking.
What is the option market thinking is the future. Now, we would make money.
If ours was different than this. If we thought the graph should look like this.
Okay? We thought it should look like this. A lot of positive call skew.
Something like this.
Sorry guys. Terrible drawing. But imagine our thing looked like this. Okay?
Well, we can make a trade. Because guess what? These options are cheap.
And these options are cheap.
Okay? So, if we don't have access to this.
Which we are all going to have eventually on the terminal.
This is... Oops. Ah, shit.
Okay? What we can do instead is price it. Using a call spread. Okay?
We can price it by using a call spread.
And we can actually price them using butterflies as well.
To get the risk neutral density. But call spread is usually enough. Okay?
You're getting the probability of an up move versus a down move.
This explains the skew.
Okay? So, we'll scroll to DDOG. It's the same thing here. So,
what do you guys think we're going to see when we price this call spread?
What do you guys think we're going to see when we price this call spread?
It's not very liquid though, unfortunately.
Okay. So, here we are with this.
So, $3.10 for this call spread. For 7 wide call spread. Okay? Quick maths.
3 divided by 7. Or, sorry. Yeah, we'll just call it 3. Oh, no.
I think it was 3. What was it? 3.10.
Okay. So, the market's saying there's only a 44% chance of an up move. Right?
But that also means what the market is saying is the volatility to the upside is
going to be a lot stronger than to the downside. So,
now you guys got to come and say, well, DDOG,
this thing is definitely not going down. And so, this call spread, okay,
is a really good trade.
Right? Because you think this should actually have a… Think about it like this,
guys. Right?
The way you can think about it is if you thought there was a 60% chance that the
stock goes up, well, it should be priced at $6. Oh, sorry.
It should be priced at like $3.70.
Right? Or 60%? What would 60% be? I think it's like $3.85.
Okay,
so this thing should be priced at $3.85 because you think there's a 60% chance that
it goes up, but it's priced at $3.10.
Cool. Cool. That's it. That's all I really have to show you guys today. So,
let's talk about one more thing here,
which is kind of what Jack is alluding to here. He's like,
so are we assuming it's not going down based on the distribution? No,
we're coming up with our own forecast to compare to it. So,
maybe we can quickly, for a couple of minutes,
talk about how they actually go about formulating their own opinions about these
things more objectively rather than just how they feel. Yeah. So,
one way you can look at it, right, is through the realized distributions.
Right? What actually has happened historically? Okay,
so if we look historically at S&P 500, let's say.
What does it actually look like? So,
an easy one to think would be we should never see call skew on the S&P 500 because
it's never shown call skew before.
It doesn't make sense for there to be call skew on the S&P 500.
The risk is not to the upside. It's to the downside. That's one way.
In that sense, you're kind of harvesting this risk premium.
The other way is situational. Right? So, Walmart was in a bid for TikTok. Okay?
Now, you're not going to be able to get data on this. Right?
You were in a situational position where this only happens once ever.
Walmart is never going to be in a situation where they're bidding for TikTok.
Right? This is a one-time thing. So, it's your job as a trader,
if you want to trade this, to be like, well, what are the odds? Well,
first off, if Walmart gets the deal, the stock goes up.
If they don't get the deal, the stock goes down. So, what do you do?
You go in and you see what the market is pricing.
Maybe the market is pricing 50-50. It's unsure. Okay?
So, what you need to do now is say, well,
what are the odds that Walmart gets TikTok? And that's research. Right?
Nothing beats good, old, hardcore research. That's your job as a trader.
And that's why you will get paid. Right? Okay? So, that's how you go about it.
You can either, for example,
sell vol on the S&P 500 because you can historically see that the skew right now
is a lot higher than what it usually is implying. Okay? It's a lot higher. So,
you would say, okay, well, I should be selling vol here. Okay? Now,
that's a risk premium that you're going to be harvesting. Okay?
But then there's a situational factor. DDOG. They just got bought by Microsoft.
People think the stock is still going up and the volatility is to the upside.
It's your job now to be like, what's actually going to happen here?
Let me dig in. Let me look at the research. Let me look at everything I can.
Let me get my hands on as much information as I possibly can.
Then I'm going to make a decision. I'm going to bet reasonably large.
And if I get paid out, it was because I put in the work. That's it.
Marcos, I agree. So, maybe next week we'll talk. Or no,
next week we're going to talk about stats, right? Stats. After next week. So,
two weeks from now, we'll focus heavily on research. Yeah.
Right. You got it, Steve. So, what they were saying,
the most likely scenario is Walmart doesn't get it. But if they do get it,
right? It's going to blow up. It's going to blow up.
Because if everyone's thinking, so, think about this, Steve.
People don't know for certain, right? So,
there's always going to be something priced in. So,
people don't know for certain. And so, if Walmart didn't get the deal,
the stock would come down, which it did. And that was the most likely event.
But if it did go through, it would catch everyone off guard. And so,
the volatility would be to the upside. So,
then it would be your job to be like, well,
what are the odds Walmart actually gets that deal? Right?
Maybe it's actually less than what the market's implying.
Maybe the market was implying, Steve. I think it was like,
it was actually a lot of call skew. It was a ton of call skew. So,
it might have been like, let's say, 45-55.
So, you know, 45% chance Walmart didn't get the deal. But remember,
it also had other things priced in. Like, if the stock market still went up,
it wasn't just the TikTok. Because obviously,
it wasn't going to be a 45% chance that Walmart got TikTok. But you might say,
well, if they actually don't get the deal, then even if the market goes up,
Walmart is still going to go down. Okay? And then you could be like, well,
it's actually like, considering everyone else in the race,
it's only really a 15% chance that Walmart gets the deal. So,
when they announce that it's Oracle that's getting the deal,
what's going to happen to Walmart? Right? And so,
you actually would be buying put spreads or you would be shorting the shares.
Okay?
So, that's going to be, that is what we're going to be talking about.
And that's what we're going to wrap it up here. Yeah, Steve,
I know you'd like this, man. It's a little bit more advanced stuff.