What's up everyone? So today I'm really excited to bring you this.
We're gonna be starting up in R and I think you guys are gonna be super excited
with this.
I've been so excited bringing you guys this it's probably a 30 part video with 5
to 10 minute videos in between and Every day we're gonna do a little bit of art
to get closer to our end goal of being able to back test to be able to scrape data
from the internet pull data wrangle data and make be able to create and Create profitable
trading strategies So with that said guys, let's get to it.
I am currently on a MacBook I'm gonna go over what it would look like if you were
on a Windows so first thing we're gonna do is we're gonna go to Google.
We're gonna type in download R so you're gonna have this thing right here if you're
a Windows user just click right here and Download this download this link right
here But for ours Mac users,
we'll go download R for Mac click on the first link and We are going to be downloading
this first package right here, so let's go ahead and click on it.
It's gonna download Excuse that it's gonna take about a couple minutes.
So I'm gonna skip this part now and and move forward If you guys are using Windows
just answer the standard Prompts that they send you as you're clicking through the
download function features Okay,
while this is loading we're gonna go download our studio.
So our studio is a place where you can code so remember R is just the The coding
language, but you want to have a nice HUD something.
It's called a GUI GUI something that you want to just be able to write code in like
a script like a file So that's gonna be called our studio So, let's go.
It's gonna be the first link. Oh sorry,
it's gonna be here download our studio click on that and Then we're gonna scroll
all the way down So Windows users are gonna be downloading this link right here
but for us We are going to be downloading this one right here secondly So let's
download that So now we have the two things running we have our and we have our
studio So before you actually open up the R studio,
let's make sure R is installed So it's gonna say just gonna say continue continue
Agree We'll install for all users And install Password,
okay type in the password for your Mac Okay,
we'll close and we're gonna move that to the trash. Okay.
Now we have R installed So this is what R looks like by itself,
so it's this thing right here bottom left So this is called the R programming language,
right? You can type in something let's say 4 plus 4 is 8 Well,
you see how ugly this like layout looks it doesn't look very clean doesn't look
very nice So what we want to do is we want to use R studio So let's go ahead and
finish.
So we click on the bottom left It'll start pop up And we'll just drag that into
applications oops,
and we will replace Because I already have R studio Downloaded but you guys might
not have this. Oh,
you guys won't have this All right So now I believe that is all so close this out
Now you should go to your applications And you will have something like this So
now guys we are officially ready to start our programming journey All right now
as quants Okay, so I already have a whole bunch of day.
It looks like Reinstalling it. It just opened up my previous sessions.
You guys will have a blank page here So you guys will have something that looks
exactly like this Since we're quants, we have to go dark screen Initially,
it'll be a white screen,
but you guys need to change that we are quants here so in In the Mac,
it's called view. I can't remember what it is in Microsoft,
but It's what it's one of the tabs that at the top here So you want to go to panes
and you want to go to pane layout?
We're gonna go to appearance We're gonna change our studio theme to sky It's gonna
change the background here,
but we want to change this actually to dark So what we're gonna do you can scroll
through the list here. This is the one guys tomorrow night blue.
This is the quant Background so we're gonna hit apply and then okay,
and here we are now.
We're ready So this is our studio and we're just gonna do Our first our first two
lines of code To get started, but you know,
this is gonna be a long process guys You know,
we're gonna chip away at it every single day and eventually we're gonna get there
so Are at the simplest form as a calculator, right?
So you can do something like four plus four and then you hit enter so on the Mac,
it's for me its command enter you hold down command you press enter and on a windows,
it's It's one of the keys either to shift enter or I think control enter it's one
of those Now run down here so now we have we output eight So this right here guys
at the bottom is called a console.
So this you could say four plus four eight But up here,
so whatever you type in here and press enter it'll automatically run, right?
but up here we have our script so you can write stuff here like Hello,
and nothing will happen right you can go to the next line.
Nothing will happen This is just it's like a Microsoft Word script But once you
press enter or command enter it'll run that script and you can also run the command
like this so let's say we have four plus four and We have eight plus eight We can
highlight these Press run and it'll run both.
It'll run both of them or we can just go command enter command enter so at its simplest
form R is a Calculator All right,
we can go 8 times 5 divided by 2 and Outcomes number 20. So this is our script.
This is our console Over here. We have our environment.
So in a programming language let's say we Okay,
maybe we'll get to this in a second.
Let's start off with our first function our first script Which is going to be to
print hello world and Command enter boom. We just have printed.
Hello world Now this print right here is called a function right,
so if you go question mark print, which just says Basically,
tell me about print and press command enter It'll tell us a little bit about the
function, right?
So you put in an object into the function which we said hello world and Out will
come Right, you can see examples Out will come Whatever you put in here, right?
It'll print it to the console.
So if we said print 10 It'll print 10 now Similarly,
you can just run 10 and I'll print 10.
So this is the most basic command now Let's say we want to save this variable.
So we're gonna store it. Okay,
so this is where our environment is gonna come into play let's say we do a or my
first line equals to print Hello world when we run my
first line It comes out to hello world Right,
and we actually don't even need to say print. Hello world.
We can just take that out Hello world Type it again.
And now when we take that out So if you notice it doesn't print it when we did it
when we said print My first line print hello world out came hello world,
but in this case,
we're just saying My first line equals hello world now we can say print my first
line Hello world, just so you guys can see in our global environment. Now.
We have this thing called My first line and what it's what its value is is hello
world,
right if we have let's say X equals 10 Now we have a new variable called X and value
is 10 And if you guys want to save your script you go you hit this button here save
You save it as my first Saving whatever document you want.
Let's say we save it in documents.
We hit save and now we can reference this by clicking on this little folder finder
Let's go documents Date modified my first are and there it is.
So now we can just run the code once again So I hope that was helpful guys in our
first session on our and our studio and getting started.