Welcome to part two in our R course,
so what we're going to be looking at today is something very exciting.
We're going to be pulling stock data from the internet,
so this is a very exciting time for me when I was first able to do this.
Something that I want to talk about first from the last video is that when we say,
for example, x equals 10,
what we're doing is we're saying this variable becomes 10. So we press enter,
and now when we look at our global environment, x is 10.
We could have said y equals 10. Now y equals 10, right?
So we're just saying that when we call this variable now,
when we print out y to the console, it's now 10.
And we print out x to the console, it's now 10. We can name this anything.
We could say, let's call it hey there equals 20.
And now when we call hey there,
we get the number 20. And remember, capitals do make a difference.
The first thing we need to understand is what a vector is.
So a vector is just multiple numbers, right? So x equals,
you have to use the word C. C creates a vector. C, so C 10, 20, 30.
We call x now, we print x in the console, and we get 10, 20, 30. If we go,
if we do x times 2, we get 20, 40, 60.
So what happened was 2 is multiplied by each number in the vector.
So they say R is built on the shoulders of giants,
and that is because you can have access to people like Jeffrey Ryan,
who's at Citadel, who creates functions and packages that we can actually use.
So what a package is, is a bunch of functions. So for example, if we say sum,
sum, and our variable x that we have here, what do you think we should get?
We should have 10 plus 20 plus 30. So that's going to be 60. So sum x,
and we get 60. So this sum is a function, right? It takes an input,
and then it gives us an output. So a package is a bunch of functions.
So let me show you an example. Let's say we look for the function getSymbols,
okay? There's nothing there.
So RStudio is going to automatically start looking for the functions that we're
looking for, and we don't have anything. But now we're going to do something,
we're going to install a package. So install packages,
and we're going to install QuantMod, okay? So this is built by Citadel Quant.
So once we install the package, we're going to...
So this means that all the functions now are in your computer,
but you need to bring them into R. So the way we do that is we go library,
and we go QuantMod, okay? And so we have to do quotes here,
but we don't need to do quotes here. So now if we say, for example, getSymbols,
it's right here. It's in the QuantMod package, getSymbols, right?
So we can hit that, and we're going to pull in our first equity.
So we're going to pull in the SPY. Now guys,
something you need to understand is when you put something in quotes,
it becomes a character, okay? So you can do class,
class tells us what type is this. So character. Character. If we go class, 10,
or let's say SPY, we're going to get an error.
And why are we going to get an error? Because SPY,
there's no variable called SPY. It'll only be a variable if we did like this.
SPY, so let's actually run this first. Object SPY not found.
If we did SPY equals 10, right,
what do you think the class is going to be here?
It's going to be something called numeric, right? 10.
10 is numeric. Okay. So now that we got that out of the way,
so there's a few classes, right? We have list, character.
So let us, so getSymbols is going to take a character.
So we're going to put in SPY, boom.
So now all of a sudden in our environment, we have SPY.
Let's take a look at it. Look at this. From 2007, we have the open, high, low,
close, volume, adjusted, all in one second. So now that we have that,
we are going to, we now want to plot it, right? So let's plot SPY, okay?
So plot's a function. We're going to plot it. And now we're going to call.
So here's SPY. We want to call, we want to say get, select, right?
So this dollar sign is the select, okay? So go to SPY, select.
We're going to select, we'll call it, let's do the close. SPY close.
So SPY.close. That's what it is. So SPY.close, there it is.
And let's plot that.
And look at that. There is our SPY chart, right?
We can change the color to red, all right? You can change it to blue, green,
yellow. If you guys want to do one of the charts that we do in our tools,
you have to load in this package called library high chart.
So we're going to plot it using the high chart package. Now remember,
everything is open source. Everything is online. So we can go online here,
type in high charter, type in this URL, it'll bring you to this.
So this is going to be all about the package now. We can go to high stock.
And if we want to plot this right here, I'm going to show the code.
So all we're doing is H chart and then our symbol. So H chart, SPY.
And there we have it. All right, so now we can play around with this.
It automatically goes from daily to weekly when you start getting bigger.
It's really cool.
So that's how we plot data and pull data from the internet for these stocks.
And in future videos, we'll get into web scraping, we'll get into forecasting,
we'll get into backtesting. But you can see how easy it is to just, you know,
these simple functions can really give us a lot of insight and can help us a lot
in our modeling and pulling data.
So that is a quick synopsis of plotting and pulling data in ForR.