Hey everyone,
so today we're going to be going another step further with functions.
We're going to be writing our own function,
and we're just going to touch a little bit on the last video as well.
So over here, the environment, the global environment,
that's where our variables are stored, right? So when we have x equals 10,
it's stored in here, right? And when we call x, what happens is R says, okay,
what is x? So it goes into our environment, our global environment, and says,
hmm, this is x, so that must equal 10. And so down in the console,
we print the number 10. Now when we do something like getSymbols,
so let's say we getSymbols QQQ,
it's still in our global environment. So now when we call QQQ,
this is the data.
So if we take a look at getSymbols,
you can see that there's actually multiple arguments, right? So remember,
the question mark says, tell me a little bit about,
tell me a little more about this function. So here we have our symbols,
which we did QQQ. We can do an environment. Let's not worry about these.
And then you can say auto-assign. So this is, see how when we say getSymbols,
it automatically assigns it here, right? If we did, let's say, getSymbols SPY,
it's automatically going to assign SPY in our global environment.
But let's say we don't want that.
Let's say we want to store it as X equals getSymbols SPY.
Let's see what happens when we do that. What happens is X becomes SPY, right?
But if we look at X, it's just the number, just the letter SPY.
So what we want to do is we want to say auto-assign equals false.
So what this is saying is don't assign it to our global environment without us telling
you what to do. And we're saying create it as the variable X.
So now when we run that, here X, we can go X, and now we get the data.
And something else we can do is we can say when we want the date for.
So from equals, let's say we want from 1995, 01-01. And then to equals today.
So sys.date is today, right? And the way you do it is you put it,
let's get down here, you put sys.date in brackets, right?
And that is because it's a function. We're calling a function.
If we were to do sum, if we were to say sum 10 and 20,
we have to put the sum in brackets because it is a function.
So here we're going to say sys.date. What is today? 2020-02-02.
So now let's do this. And if we call head,
head means so if we have a whole data frame, head means the top,
tail means the bottom. So if we said head X, we have from 1995 now,
S&P 500 data. And if we said tail X,
we now have the bottom part, right? So this is today's data.
Friday was the 31st.
So here's the top of our data and here's the bottom of our data.
A very cool feature as well is you can say, for example,
get symbols and we start a vector SPY comma QQQ and IWM.
And what happens now is we have IWM, QQQ and SPY.
And let's say we want to get it from 2009-01-01, two equals 2010-01-01,
right? Now we just have that data here. So view is another function that says,
let's look at our data. So capital V, view, IWM.
So now we have 2009 data all the way down to 2000, well,
since the beginning of 2010, right? 01-01.
As well, we can create our vector. So let's say stocks equals C, right?
We're creating a vector SPY, QQQ, IWM. And now let's take a look at stocks.
QQQ, IWM, SPY. So what we can do now is we can say get symbols,
stocks,
and now it pulls it in.
So we don't need to state right here that we have to pull these three in.
We can create a variable first, stocks. So that's where we're storing this,
right? This right here is equivalent to stocks, right? What are we saying here?
Stocks is equivalent to this. So get symbol stocks is saying get symbols this,
right? It calls it. We can just highlight that.
So that's what's happening over here. So this is a really, you know,
get symbols is a great function to pull in data and to take a quick look at our
stocks. So what we're going to do is we are going to create our own function.
And what this function is going to do is it's going to,
we're going to type in a ticker name.
It's going to add on to the get symbols function where all you have to do is type
in a ticker name.
It's going to graph the stock data and moving averages depending on the parameters
you want. And when I mean parameters, I mean like,
do you want the 10-day simple moving average or the 50-day simple moving average,
whatever you're looking for. So let's go ahead and start this.
So the way you start a function is we're going to call it a name, right?
So get symbols is a function name.
We're going to call this one plot underscore tickers. It could be,
and this could be anything. This could be predicting alpha.
This could be whatever you want,
but we're going to call it plot underscore tickers.
And we're going to say this is equal to, it's a function, okay?
So inside the function, we're going to put our parameters.
So our parameters are going to be, right? Just like remember, get symbols,
we have symbols, right? We have all these.
These are the parameters inside the function. So let's say for plot tickers,
we want to have the ticker.
So we're just going to look at one ticker when we do ours.
We're going to do ticker. We're going to have from date and to date.
And then we're also going to have moving average one parameter and moving average
two parameter. So this might be like the 50-day, the 100-day.
And then we do these curly braces to start the function.
And now whatever we write in here is what's going to happen.
So first thing we're going to do is we're going to say our stock, okay,
is equal to get symbols, okay, ticker. So this, whatever we put in here, right?
Let's say when we put spy as symbols, get symbols pulls it, right?
So we're saying whatever we're going to put in here, plug it in here.
So if we say, for example, we put spy in here, it's going to plug it in there.
And we're going to have from equals from, right?
From is going to get plugged into there. To equals to.
And auto assign equals false, right?
We are saying don't just put it into our global environment.
We want to save it as our stock.
What we're going to do next is we are going to calculate what we're going to do
next is we are going to create our first simple moving average and add it into our
data frame. So we're going to take our stock.
This is select, right? But if there's nothing to select,
so we're going to say select SMA slow.
So this is going to be our slow moving average.
So maybe the 200 day and the fast one is going to be like maybe the 20 or 30,
whatever you guys decide to choose.
What we're saying is go to our stock, select SMA slow. Now,
what's the problem here? So remember,
our stock is going to be the same as if we said get symbols SPY, right?
So let's take a look at that. And do you see something called SMA slow?
I see SPY open, high, low, close, volume adjusted. So there is none.
So there is none. So what this is saying is create this, right?
Because SMA slow is not an actual variable right now. It's not a column.
We're going to create this column. And this is going to be equal to SMA, right?
So in the quant mod package, which is also the TTR,
there is already SMA function. So SMA, we're going to say the close,
right? So close is another function. So if we did CL SPY,
it would just pull the close.
So we're going to go close our stock, right?
Because our stock is now saved as it was auto assigned to it.
So this is not SPY anymore.
So this is equivalent to SPY.
So close, basically, whatever our ticker is.
Let's say we're going to play around with SPY. And N,
so let's take a look at what the SMA function does.
So it has N. So N is the length, right? You want the 200 day, the 10 day,
the 50 day. And by default, it's 10. So we're going to say N is equal to M1.
So right here, whatever we put in here is going to get plugged into here.
Okay. Now we're going to say our stock SMA fast, right?
We're going to create this new column fast is equal to SMA CL.
Our stock N equals M2, right?
So now we're going to create this new variable with our fast SMA.
And we're going to be plugging in whatever that is here.
So now we actually have all the data we need. We have our closing price.
We have our SMA slow. And we have our SMA fast. So now we need to plot this.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to only select the three variables
we need, which is the close, the SMA slow, and the SMA fast.
So we're going to say new.dataframe is going to be equal to our stock. Okay.
And now we're going to do something you guys haven't seen before,
and that's square brackets. So when we look into a data frame,
we have two dimensions, columns and rows. So if we were to say SPY, right,
square brackets, this is how we access the data frame. We want to see row one.
Column,
so we should see SPY open. We should see this number right here.
So let's do it. And there it is, right?
We're taking the first column and the first row. So the first,
now let's go to the second row, first column. So we should now see 141.23.
So let's run that, 141.23. Now let's go find the third row, third column.
All right, so now we're over here. We're on the second row, third column.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to say if we want all the columns,
we leave it empty. So we'd say this, SPY, row two, comma,
and we leave this empty. This means give me all the columns.
And if we did the other way around, we said give me all the rows,
only on column two. We're going to want to see only column two, all the rows.
And there it is. So what we're going to do is we're going to say our stock,
give me all the rows, but give me only the columns.
We're going to create a vector here that are called SMA fast,
SMA slow.
And then we're going to say new.df,
close is equal to CL,
our stock. Okay, so basically we have our whole data frame now.
Once we do that, we are going to plot new.df.
And so it's going to plot every single point on our data frame.
Once we have that, we just press enter. This is our new function now.
So we go plot, plot tickers, SPY, from equals 2010-01-01,
two equals 2000, and let's go 20-01-01. And let's see what happens.
We get an error. M1 is missing. We have to plot those in there.
So let's go with 50. Let's do our 200, 50.
And there we have it.
Here we have just plotted our 200-day moving average with our 50-day simple moving
average and with S&P 500 over there. If you guys want to change the title,
we can go back to the plot. We can add main equals ticker.
So whatever the ticker's name is going to add it over there.
And then we're going to say,
and then we're going to run that. So we're going to hit enter again,
and we're going to do the same thing. And now we ran this exact same function,
but now we have SPY. And let's do it on another one.
So let's go plot tickers. Let's go QQQ.
And from equals 2010-01-01. And to equals, let's say, sys.date.
So that's today. And we're going to do a, let's go 10-day slow and 5-day fast.
So really fast crossovers. And look at that. You can barely even see.
It's basically trading with the chart. So maybe we'll go a little longer here.
Let's go with a 200 again. We'll go with the 200, and we'll go with a 20.
And there we have it. All right, guys, so that'll do it for us today.
I hope you guys are learning a ton through this.
I'm really excited about the community growing, and I'll talk to you guys soon.