Okay guys,
so welcome back to our part for the real part for last one was actually part three
We're gonna actually go over a few things today. So we're gonna do regressions,
but we're also going to use alpha vantager to pull in intraday data from an API
as well as Daily data and the reason why I'm doing this.
I'm showing you guys this now is because one of our members Enrique is having problems
with quant mod and And this is actually an uncommon problem But it's still it still
happens every so often where the way your computer is set up Depending on if you
have our curl installed you might have troubles pulling data in from quant mod So
I think you know the new ways alpha vantager.
I'm just used to using quant mod I think it's a little simpler,
but we're gonna go through this anyways so first thing is guys whenever you see
me library a package like library tidy quant and library alpha vantager This just
means that I've already installed it So you have to go and every time you see like
let's say library tidy quant that means you have to install tidy quant And then
once you do that you can now library it in so I'm gonna delete that You guys have
to both you guys have to library both tidy quant and alpha vantager it so Let's
go ahead So what is tidy quant tidy quant?
Tidy quant is basically the data frame version of Quant mod so quant mod is some
is in something called an XDS Okay, so it's basically a program.
It's basically are written on top of C++ So you can think of it like this right?
Let's say we did Let's say we should get symbols SPY
All right, and now we go class so class tells us. What is this?
What type is this right class SPY It's an XTS slash zoo This is a special type of
class written by a lot of the C++ programmers and are Who have basically integrated
the two?
But let's use tidy quant so tidy quant has a function called TQ get where it's very
similar to So here pulls in right here,
so we have to actually save this so we have to say Apple equals TQ get and now if
we go so if we do head Apple right we see that here's here's the head of our data
frame, but if we go class Apple we can see that it's not an XTS.
It's a it's a data frame So that's the two that's that that's the difference between
Between the two and there's actually some subtle differences It might be a little
easier to work with a data frame rather than XTS When we get to speed purposes for
like example backtesting we're gonna have to use an XTS So what we're gonna do actually
we're gonna start pulling in intraday data And then we're gonna work on some we're
gonna look at some regressions So to do this you guys have to go online And you
go to alpha vantage Co right here You click on get your free API today So click
on that and then just fill out the information here,
and I will come a code So what an API is is basically something your computer is
interacting with that holds data right so out there in the world is some data frame
and You want to connect to that data frame in order to connect to it your computer
has to connect?
To something to communicate with that data frame and that is what is called an API
So R is gonna talk to this API and then that API is gonna collect the data from
Alpha vantage and another thing guys is that R is only the best programming language
in the world because of its community When you have a question there is someone
who already has asked this question before you need to start using stack overflow
Okay stack overflow.
I want everybody to sign up today on stack overflow What this is is when you have
a question?
There were people there will be people who will answer it for you in fact if you
have a question Tag it in the group,
and I'll go and answer it for you So if you look at my profile for example I Asked
her let's see what questions.
I've recently asked so I'm a silver badge Which basically means that I'm a very
good programmer But I'm just not the best the best would be a gold badge And then
everybody starts out with no badge,
then you move up to bronze and then silver and then you hit gold So let's take a
look at one of the questions that I asked is How to separate on a first period So
I have a data frame and this data frame has two periods one here and another period
here And I want to split it on the first period All right,
so I asked my question.
I showed the code that I've tried I show what I want to happen and then Someone
will come and answer the question for me,
and now I can learn from them now so for example we have Akron who's probably one
of the best our coders in the world and He is here who's able to help me,
and this is such a good resource You're learning from a lot of the best programmers
in the world Okay, so once we have our API key.
We're gonna come over here a V API Key you're gonna put in your API key,
so my API key is you can get it Okay,
so we get our AVI we put in our API key once you put in our API key We can now start
using the code so if you guys have any questions about Alpha Vantager there's documentation
so the thing with programming is it is a little bit tedious, right?
But as you get better and quicker everything gets a lot smoother So you go to the
back to the home page API documentation examples boom Okay,
so here is all the stuff you can get you get intraday data daily data daily adjusted
data so for dividends and splits Weekly data weekly adjusted you can get 4x You
can get cryptos you can get technical indicators What else can we get here?
We can get sector performance so you can get all this stuff,
so let's say we go to We're gonna look at equities here,
let's what do you guys want to do?
Let's do okay because we're doing regressions. Let's do daily data,
but you can you can as simply get intraday data We're gonna go with daily data here.
Okay, so what we need to do here.
We have to put in these commands So let's take a look at our let's take a look here,
so question mark AV Get let's see what we need So
right here perfect,
so here's an here's our example right we're gonna have right here right down here
So we're gonna have a V.
So let's call it Microsoft is equal to a V get Symbol equals Microsoft AV fun equals
Okay, so this is where this comes in right?
This is this So function time series daily,
let's do that instead of Let's do that instead of intraday so and then
output size,
so if we just do compact so output size Equals full if we do compact.
It's just the first hundred rows, so let's run that Well,
I took a little while. I'm not very happy with that,
but anyways Let's take a look Let's view our data And here it is So here's our days
open high low close and volume for Microsoft With alpha vantage or you can't get
batch symbols, so you can't get three symbols at one call So what we're gonna.
Do here is we are going to First load in the package called tidy verse tidy verse
is a suite of function that's run on C and It's very good.
It's super fast for doing any data manipulation Because AV get will only pull in
one symbol. We have to run this twice,
so we're gonna run in we're on SP Y equals AV get Symbol equals SP. Why AV fun?
time series daily and output size equals Let's
do compact here Okay,
so if we look you over here in our environment We have SP Y which only has a hundred
observations and Microsoft which has five thousand observations That's because we
did compact here right if we look over here.
We did compact and we did full for Microsoft So we pulled in the full data.
I really pulled in a bit of the data for SP Y So we want to run a regression here
But what we need to do though is we need to merge these data frames together Right
how do we do that one is a hundred rows and one is 5,000 rows so it won't work right
if we did C bind SP Y and Microsoft which means column bind What's gonna happen?
We're gonna get an error because SP Y is not the same length as Microsoft.
They have different dates So what we need to do though now is we need to call inner
join so inner join says Take something on the left.
Let's say SP Y and only get the matching columns from another data frame So we're
gonna do this final dot DF equals inner join SP Y and Microsoft But by what by the
open the closed the high the low What we want to inner join is by the date so we
go by equals Let's see what the names are so we can type down here names SP Y time
stamp so by equals time stamp Boom now check this out. We have our final DF,
which only has the hundred rows from SP Y and It's added Microsoft So time stamp
right here This is all SP Y and then so this so are added because you can't have
the two columns of the same names So are said that these ones are called closed
X These ones are added added an X to the to the end of the variable and then over
here We added a Y to the variable for Microsoft So what we can do now is we're gonna
run our first regression So we're gonna look at the first we are going to look at
the own the first and only math equation That I'm ever gonna talk about in this
group, and that is linear regression equation the formula is Our prediction,
let's call it y hat This is what we think is gonna happen Okay Is equal to?
Alpha let me just add a thing here.
Okay alpha plus beta Times our Variable that we're regressing it with our independent
variable So we'll call that X plus an error term So what is this equation telling
us this equation is saying that our variable that we're going to predict Our Y right
our y-axis, so maybe this in our case what we're gonna.
Do is Microsoft is Equal to is equal to some intercept plus the change in SPY Plus
an error term because we can't predict it perfectly so there's gonna be an error
This is the linear equation, but first for you on our regression.
We need to turn everything into return space right now We're in price space right
if we look at Our final DF everything is in price We have Microsoft price.
We have SPY price So we're gonna call Microsoft price equals ROC so ROC is just
a way to change it which is equivalent to the return of Final DF Why close why and
we're gonna go SPY Oops, sorry guys.
We're gonna call it return MSFT return SPY Return equals ROC final dot DF close
X Okay,
and now so if we take it we have two vectors here now right let's take a look at
SPY return So it's not a data frame anymore.
It's just a vector So what we can do now is we can say We're gonna create a new
data frame so new Or let's call this one return DF Equals to data frame MSFT
return equals MSFT return so this is saying The column is called MSFT return,
and we're gonna fill it with MSFT return We have another column called SPY return,
and we're gonna fill it with SPY return And we're gonna hit enter and now let's
take a look at this And there it is here's our daily returns,
so we can now let's plot some of this stuff So first let's remove the NA see how
we have an NA here Let's get rid of it So we'll type in return dot DF equals NA
dot omit return Dot DF Okay So let's take a look gone We are going to Let's
plot one of them plot return DF MSFT we're gonna do type Equals line,
and we'll do call equals red color equals red okay So here it is right here.
You're the daily returns now in order to Make it look like Microsoft's price again.
We have to run the cumulative sum function so plot Come some right we're gonna do
cumulative some return dot DF Microsoft return type equals line and call and Call
equals blue Okay,
and there's Microsoft's return of the last hundred days now We want to know what
we want to do a regression,
so you know when you see what a company's beta is It's simply a regression it's
Simply this right in our in our Now we're a regression right now.
We're gonna be asking the question. What is Microsoft's beta? okay,
so That is going to be equal to this big B right here Right and think about like
this We have on the y-axis.
It's gonna be Microsoft is equal to Some alpha which is gonna be should be close
to zero plus the beta Times SPY so if the beta is 2 what that tells us is Microsoft
is going to move 2 times whatever the S&P moves so if S&P moves down negative 1
If beta is 2 then you're gonna have this would be the equation the equation would
be Microsoft move is Equal to let's say alpha is 0 plus 2 times Whatever S&P moves,
let's say it moves 1% Plus some error term because it's not gonna move exactly it's
gonna move has it's gonna move almost So that is the equation All right,
let's say there.
Let's say we can let's say we're we're magicians or we're 4x traders,
and we don't have any errors So let's do that,
and then you're gonna see that Microsoft move now For at the T is Equal to 0.2 right
S&P move 10% Microsoft's gonna move 20% So what we need to do first is we need to
plot the data so plot Return dot DF Microsoft regressed on to That and that's what
the tilde sign is the tilde sign is regress so think of it What are you this?
What are you regressing y-axis on so this is your y-axis on to what and in our case?
It's the S&P 500 Okay,
and let's say call equals blue So here it is so here is our first regression So
what do we notice here?
well We see that there's a strong correlation Right when the S&P return is 1% Right
Microsoft is gonna be around 2% When the S&P is down 1% Microsoft is gonna be down
1% so there's a clear correlation here But we're quants.
We don't we don't just say oh,
there's a correlation and move away We need to actually come up with a number that
says okay if S&P moves this how much is Microsoft gonna move?
So what we do is we have to we have to create a line a best fit And that is this
equation right here.
This is the ordinary least squares linear regression So what we're gonna.
Do is we're gonna say We're gonna add a line Okay,
and we're gonna add this linear model LM means linear model And we're just gonna
do Same thing return dot DF Microsoft regressed on to return dot DF SP Y and we're
gonna make the color equals Let's say red and there it is so this line is the line
of best fit it minimizes the error terms so now we have a line that says okay if
If S&P goes up 1% we just go up here,
and we say okay Microsoft should go up It looks like one and a half percent,
so we're gonna build our model right so our model is our first mod Equals to LM
Return dot DF Microsoft return regressed on to return dot DF SPY Okay,
so that's our model We're gonna go summary our First mod and we're gonna print this
to the console So what this is saying is that?
The p-value is basically zero what this means is that?
S at the S&P return Has a strong correlation, and it's not by chance.
It's it's almost certain that this is a real thing Okay,
that the S&P is correlated so in order to actually really dive deep into what a
linear regression is I think that's beyond the scope of this context because when
it comes to a lot of the statistics stuff There's so many good videos.
I explained a lot better than I will be able to explain it So if you guys want to
do that you know I'd highly recommend you guys go and learn statistics online But
we are gonna be specifically focused around Quantitative using taking that information
and using it for quant trading So what this is saying is here.
Here's our coefficients. Here's our intercept.
Here's our alpha remember we come over here Where do we have it right here?
So this equation is summarized right in here our equation is Microsoft return okay
is equal to The intercept which is our alpha so is equal to point zero zero one
six five six five three Plus our beta term 1.292 times our S
&P 500 move So let's say the S&P moves point zero two Plus some error term so in
our case.
We are going to just say it's zero So what we're saying is I have micro if S&P moves
up two percent Microsoft is going to move.
Let's take a look MSFT return Point zero two six three so if S&P moves up two percent
Microsoft is gonna move up two point six percent Right and we can change this so
let's say we want let's say S&P moves down one percent Microsoft is Gonna move down
1.2 percent plus minus right that's our error term error terms we plus minus and
we'll get into that into another video How do we get a standard deviation for error
term?
But this is our beta right so the beta over this time period is 1.292,
so we just calculated the beta for an equity So that is our linear regression guys
I Hope that made sense we'll go into more details about linear regressions and robust
regressions Because what happens if we have a huge outlier in this data,
so I hope this guy's made a little bit of sense This is just an introduction to
doing regressions for statistical statistical analysis,
and I'm sure you guys are already thinking well What happens if?
Microsoft moves down 10% and S&P doesn't move well now.
We're getting into something called pairs trading And this is an amazing topic that