All right, guys. So in this, uh, in this video,
we're going to be talking about when basically in this series,
we're going to be talking about building out a strategy.
We're actually going to be building out a strategy from scratch. Right.
And I think this is like one of the things that a lot of the members here have been
asking me is like, Jordan, I want to trade stuff outside of earnings. Right.
Um, you know, how can I come up with an idea, you know, on all this stuff?
And I think it's so important,
so important that we actually build out a strategy together and. You know,
you guys seeing the process, we'll be able to, to do it on your own. Um, one,
so one thing I will say is that,
so this strategy is earnings related only because I want to get into it in a certain,
a certain aspect. I think there's a lot of money to be made there. Um,
but the ideas are identical across the board. Okay. Whatever idea you have, um,
it's going to be the same. And also like throughout, you know,
in this first quarter, in this first series,
we're going to be talking about the different types of edges out there. Okay.
And what like an edge actually looks like. All right.
And one thing I'll mention here as well. Um, when you see an edge,
when you actually see someone like trade an edge, so let's say for example,
you go work at a buy side firm and you actually see like your mentor or you're the
portfolio manager trade out the edge. It's like crucial in your growth.
Like you actually see, um,
what it takes to be profitable or what it looks like to be a profitable trader.
Right. And that's so key. So, um, that that's why we're doing this.
I just think it's going to be very insightful for you guys. Okay.
So I'm thinking maybe next time I'm going to put this in PowerPoint,
but I wrote this down in R in the meantime. Oh, Sean,
can you make me host share my screen? Yeah. Okay. So I'll just down in R oops,
but I think I'll, I'll probably put it into a PowerPoint, uh, for next round.
So we're going to go,
I have a couple of sections here that we're going to go over.
So it's basically these three sections, uh, sorry. Uh,
we have about six sections to go through.
So the first one that I really want to talk about,
and this is where it all starts, right. Is idea generation, right?
This is something that a lot of,
I find a lot of our members are struggling with and it's,
it shouldn't be a struggle at all. In fact, this is probably the easiest part.
Okay. The easiest part is idea generation.
So the way you need to think about it is you want to pick something that you want
to trade. Okay. So for example, spy returns, pairs, trading ETFs,
relative value trades, right. If you want to do relative value vol trades, um,
you know, you guys can think of so many. Okay.
So that's the first thing is like, what do I want to trade? Right.
And you guys know all these different types of products.
Maybe you want to trade the VIX, right.
You don't need to think of it in terms of like, Hey,
maybe there's some complex system out there. Like, uh, I don't know.
Arbing synthetics in, in super ultra high frequency space, right?
You don't need to think about it like that. It's like, what do I want to trade?
Right. At the end of the day,
there's only a certain amount of products out there that you can trade.
So first thing is what do you want to trade or what do you want to investigate and
keep in mind guys, um,
as you investigate new things and new things will pop up. Okay. So first off,
think about something you want to investigate. Okay. You want to trade, right.
And, uh, you don't need to reinvent the wheel. Okay. It just, whatever idea,
you know, a profitable system is just going to be better than the average guy.
Okay. So you're just going to be better than the average person out there.
So keep that in mind. Okay. You don't, you know,
you don't need to make something. I've been thinking,
I got to create something that's new and fancy. No,
you got to do something that's simple and that, you know,
it's just better than the current guy making money. Right.
Think about it as an electrician, the guys out there,
a good electrician is making the money.
If you can be better than that electrician,
then you're going to take the money to always remember that. Um,
and hopefully that's already starting to give you some ideas about where you should
be playing. So, um, the reason why we're doing the earnings, uh,
the earnings for this, uh, you know,
for this series is because there's a lot of retail interest.
It's very hard to model. We're going to talk about that later on today.
And there's likely to be a very interest premium. Okay.
So those three things are why I want to investigate this further and why I think
there's a lot of money here. And also I should mention here, uh,
liquidity and we're going to go over types of edges here. So, uh,
so retail interest,
meaning there's a lot of like people who are not pricing this thing correctly.
Um, it's hard to model and there's a very interest premium liquidity. There's,
there's some other ideas, but that's why this is a good thing to investigate.
We don't know if it's going to make money, but we need to try.
It's an idea and we need to investigate it. So, uh,
just like in business in general, ideas don't make you any money, right?
You guys know that anyone who's in business knows that you always have that friend
that says,
I got an idea and he thinks he's gonna make millions of dollars off this idea.
It's the people that can execute that make money, not an idea. It's just, it's,
you know, it's, it's Fugazi. Everyone has a brilliant idea,
but you need to build a moat. You need to be able to execute.
That's what's going to build the business. Okay. So that's idea generation.
Any questions about that? That's the first section.
Is there any questions about that?
So could, uh, could an idea be as simple as like, like, like, uh, I want to,
uh, trade a short ball strategy. Um, no, no, no. It's gotta be more specific,
more specific. Like, like here's another idea. Um, so, uh, you don't, and this,
we're going to talk about this later. You don't ask why you ask whether,
so here's an example. Does, uh, is implied,
is the implied variance risk premium higher on ETFs than stocks?
Or here's another idea. Where is the,
where is the variance risk premium the highest across us equities?
If you just want to say, I want to sell vol that's that's too broad, right?
Where do you want to sell vol? I want to sell.
All you gotta do is just ask a question and then you investigate, right? Um,
if you,
let's say you want to do sell vol is selling vol on tech stocks and buying vol on,
um, financial stocks, a good pairs trade, right?
And then you're going to start to, you know, as you get become a better trader,
you've got to start asking better questions, right? So in this case,
what I want to investigate is, um, can I forecast, uh, the straddle PNL, right?
Can I forecast the earning straddle PNL? Perfect. Yeah. Steve's saying,
you know, it's a good point to ask questions and then, uh, you know,
try to solve for answers. Exactly. That's all it is.
Um, so let's move on to, uh, is there any more questions about that, Sean?
All good. Let's talk about, uh, characteristics of a good idea. Okay.
So we're going to be, you know, basically talking about the, you know,
asking those good questions. So,
and this is also like characteristics of a good idea,
but also like the business, right? The moat, like you,
you want to have a good business. So you want to have a good idea, et cetera,
et cetera. So data. Okay. So here's an, an, an edge basically, right? Here's a,
uh, I guess maybe I should say this is characteristics of a good edge. Okay.
I have a good business.
And the first thing is data.
So do you have access to data that others don't write? Imagine, for example,
the number of species in the Marianas trench, uh,
predicted apples move around earnings. Well, no one has that data.
So clearly if you had that data, you'd have more knowledge than everybody else.
And you'd make the most money because you have this piece of data that no one has.
And, you know, if this,
if the number of fishing in the Marianas trench told you that apple would move 5
% tomorrow, and you're the only guy that has that data, well,
you're going to make the most money, right? So that's, that's a,
that's one idea is you have, you have better data than everyone else. Okay.
And then, you know, this is the,
the huge thing in finance where people are trying to get as much data as they possibly
can. Um, so here's one in earnings, for example, that's really difficult.
So I found out that the guidance predicts the earnings move the best. Okay.
The guidance revision, the guidance surprise,
it's almost impossible to get guidance data. I haven't seen it.
I haven't seen historical guidance data anywhere.
So if you want to spend the time to manually get it, you know,
that's going to give you a huge, a huge edge. Okay.
That's just an example there, the skillset. So if you're playing in,
let's say a pond with, let's say there's not many teams,
but there's a single individuals and they don't have as good of a skillset to let's
say, pull in data, manipulate the data, transform the data, you know,
have good data science skills. That's an edge that you have.
And that's going to be a good business, right? Um, your network.
So do you have access to people who can give you good ideas, right? Um,
private equity, for example, we can't get into private equity, you know,
as an individual, sure. There's new things coming up, but you know,
if anyone has watched the movie, uh, too big to fail, right. The guy, uh,
you know, the guy from Goldman Sachs, when they're on the verge of bankruptcy,
first call is Warren Buffett. Hey Warren, can you please give us some money?
And I'll give it to you at like pennies on the dollar. That's huge, right?
Warren has access to people. He's the first call for many people, right?
And this happened with I think it was in Canada for Steve. If you Steve,
you'll probably remember it home equity, home, something home capital.
He was the first call to buy out all the mortgage at a 70% discount.
He made a ton of money right after that. Okay.
So do you have a network specialization? Are you a lawyer?
Can you like figure out mergers and acquisitions better than everyone else?
Right. I don't have any space in that. Are you a doctor?
Do you understand biotech better than everyone else? Right.
Are you specialized in this field? Uh, geography, right. In certain places,
you can't trade certain products. So if you are in a certain geography,
you might have an advantage over someone who's not, um, also that, that,
that also incorporates regulatory issues as well.
So being first, you know, being first is always, uh, you know,
being first to an idea. So that's like, I guess, reinventing the wheel there,
right? You can always do that, reinvent the wheel and make some money,
but that's usually a harder route, uh, liquidity constraints. So, you know,
you using your capital to your advantage, um,
and then higher barriers to entry. So for example,
we can't just go and start a high frequency trading firm or an insurance company,
right? The infrastructure for that is insane. Right.
And so that's a barrier to entry. So it's going to get,
that's going to build your moat. And then another one is risk tolerance, right?
Do you have a high risk tolerance and you could take certain trades that other people
can't. Okay. So those are, uh, characteristics of good edge,
good business and how you shouldn't be thinking about, you know,
ideas and things like that. So do you have any questions about that?
I am not seeing any questions right now, but maybe we'll give it a second.
Maybe someone's typing. Yeah. I'm surprised,
but I do think a lot of our members,
there should be at least one thing in this list that started to maybe speak to you
a bit. Exactly. Right. Something in this list, so I know a lot of,
a lot of you like are, you know,
specialized in your careers or live in places where maybe you have some geographic
advantage, you know, liquidity, you know, data science skills. Yeah.
Adam's saying risk tolerance. Exactly. Yes, sir.
But it should get the gears turning a bit, you know? Yeah.
I'm not seeing any questions, Jordan. Is this boring, Sean?
You think I'm putting the guys to sleep?
I think everyone here is trying to make money.
I don't think anyone's falling asleep. Okay, good, good, good.
We're gonna make some money here. Okay. So, so once we have an idea, okay,
we don't want to ask, we don't want to ask why does this exist? Like, you know,
why is there a variance risk premium?
We don't want to ask that right away because we don't know if it's true.
So we need to ask whether,
and we can't really ask whether without looking at the data, right?
And this is something that I see like so many people fall into.
So many retail traders fall into this. They say,
this sounds like a good idea because of this, this, and this,
I'm going to trade it. But we can't ask why until we ask whether. Okay.
So just always remember that saying.
So what we need to do now is we need to collect the data,
we need to inspect the data. So I went ahead, guys,
and we'll do another series, maybe on like collecting data.
But I basically pulled in everything from the terminal,
all the data that goes into our terminal and a couple other features.
So let's take a look at it. Okay. So here's our data set.
This is the raw data set. Okay. And this is usually how, how it works, right?
How, how, how the process goes.
And just, just remember guys, this is literally how I'm,
how I'm building up this strategy. Okay.
I'm not just like putting this together. I'm actually trying to build this out.
So we have, we have our tickers. So you can see like AA, like,
and we'll talk about how big this dimension is. We have our tickers, you know,
our earnings date, whether it was after market or before market open, you know,
the price of, you know, the volume. What else we got here? Okay.
We got the average move, the IV30, this IV60, IV90,
realized vol, skew, contango, implied earnings move, et cetera. Okay.
So let's take a little bit, let's keep looking at this data set. So let's,
what we're going to do is we're going to take a look at the dimensions of our data
set, say data set.
So you can see here it's 28,000 rows and 60 columns.
So we have 60 variables and 28,000 rows.
So going back over five years for earnings.
And also let's take a look here if we do.
So we're going to see how many tickers are in this data set. Okay.
So how many different tickers are in our data set here?
So we got 1800 tickers. All right.
Now once we have our data set and we're going to inspect it a little bit more,
of course, but once we have our data set,
we need to think about what are we trading?
And this is called our target variable. Okay. So like we said earlier,
an example of a target variable would be the S&P 500 returns.
What do you guys think? I'm going to put this question on you guys.
What do you guys think our target variable would be here?
So we want to trade earnings vol. Okay. What would our target variable be?
What would it look like?
What are the guys saying? So the target variables, I think we want to trade.
Nothing yet. Nothing yet. Okay. Give it 10 more seconds.
I was watching Ferris Bueller's day off yesterday and the professor, he's like,
anyone, anyone, anyone?
I feel like Okay. Robbie, Robbie saying implied move slash average move. Okay.
Yeah. Implied move divided by average move. Okay.
Sebastian saying the difference between implied vol and realized vol.
Crawford saying equities with liquidity. Okay.
I think you're going to talk about that. Yeah. So the real,
the target variable we should have here is our straddle, our straddle price,
right? The straddle price return. So we're actually trading the straddle,
right? We're going to be buying and selling straddles. So in order, you know,
so just like buying and selling the S&P 500,
our target is going to be the return of that. So our straddle P and L,
our straddle return. Okay. That's going to be our target variable. All right.
So let's go back to our dataset here. Maybe just define target variable. Yep.
So target variable guys is the thing that we want to predict. Okay.
It's what we want to predict, what we want to trade.
All right. Do you have any good example, like outside of trading?
Real estate prices.
Whether someone is going to have cancer or not.
The temperature tomorrow. Okay.
The body mass of a person given other variables. Okay. That's what a target is.
And every dataset is going to have one, right?
We got to try to predict something and that's going to be our target.
So straddle return. All right. So let's take a look at our dataset again.
And here I created it. Okay. Well, we have it in the terminal as well.
Okay. So here is our straddle return.
So you can see pre-event and let's look at this example here. Okay. Pre-event,
the straddle was $2.90. Post-event, it was $3.08. So the return was 5%. Okay.
Now, one thing that's important, guys, is, okay.
So does anyone have any questions about what a target variable is?
Chris made a funny comment here when we were listing off potential target variables.
He's like, a good one would be whether the live will be a good one.
That could be a target for sure. So Kyle asked,
why the straddle P&L instead of the implied move?
Well, are you trying to predict what the implied move is going to be tomorrow?
Or do you mean the actual move?
So I think having the actual move,
why don't we try to predict the actual move tomorrow?
And it's a really good question, Kyle. And maybe we'll do some more,
maybe down in the next series, we'll talk a little bit more about it.
But the reason is because it's hard to predict. So here's another example.
It's hard to predict the score between Chelsea and Manchester United. What? Oh,
sorry. No, no. That was a little too difficult.
It's hard to break the score between West Ham and Manchester United,
but it's easy to predict who's going to win.
So instead of having it as what the actual move is,
what we really want to decide is the bias. And in this case,
it would be the straddle P&L tells us that. What is the bias like?
Whether the actual outcome.
And also you can't trade the actual move. Or you can trade the straddle P&L.
And the straddle P&L would be equivalent to implied divided by realized.
Now, that being said, though, Kyle, there is a new technique.
I don't want to get into it too much because of this,
but basically decomposition and then recomposition.
But I'm going to stay clear of that.
So that could be something for you down the road if you want to explore.
So first thing we need to do, guys, is we're going to talk about priors now.
So we're going to spend all the rest of our time now on this target variable.
And we're going to talk about candidate variables a little bit later and then in
the next series. But first things first,
we're going to talk about our target variable.
So this is where the highest return on spent time is going to be,
is working on your target variable. So we need to start with a prior.
And this is basically going to be from our domain knowledge.
The reason why the engineer can't go,
there's so many people that go to university, get engineer's degrees,
learn about neural networks, learn about AI.
They go and try to figure out trading and they don't make any money.
Or they use an out-of-the-box system and then apply it to trading and they don't
make any money. And the reason is because there's craftsmanship here.
You can't just use out-of-the-box things. As a good data scientist,
you really need to understand your variables.
You really need to understand what the problem you're trying to solve.
You need to have a good domain knowledge.
That's going to make you a good data scientist,
is really learning about the problem at hand. So we need to have a prior.
So let's take a step back. Let's have a little, let's take a little breather.
Maybe getting a little too much information flow happening here, but a prior.
A prior is basically what we think about something before we even look at it.
Okay. So when I ask you guys,
straddle P&L. If I were to graph straddle P&L,
if I were to graph the 30-day straddle return for an earnings event,
what would it look like?
What would it look like? In percents.
Long straddle for an earnings event and after an earnings event.
What would the returns look like? Anyone?
Is each point an event or is it over time?
So the straddle return over the event, that's our target variable. Okay.
Our target variable is,
I want to make sure everyone's clear on this because we're going to be building
on this throughout the sessions.
Does everyone understand what our target variable is?
Let's do another one just to make sure we're on the same page. Okay.
So straddle pre, this straddle is going for $6 and 33 cents.
Tomorrow after the event, it's going for $6 and 53 cents.
So our target variable is 3.5%. The straddle return, 3.5%. In this case,
it was $5.57 pre-event then $4 post-event. So our target lost 27%. Okay.
The thing we're trying to predict lost 27%.
How are we looking? No questions. Did anyone figure out what our prior is?
Is that William Anderson Lawrence? No, this is less taken path, I believe.
Got it. Okay. I was calling him Lawrence. I'm alive now. Sorry, buddy. Okay.
So William Henderson saying a normal distribution, hopefully with some skew.
Okay. Does anyone disagree with William, aka Lawrence?
Does anyone disagree with him? Steve, do you disagree with that or no?
So it's not going to be normal distribution skew.
He's saying a skewed distribution. Do you agree with that or no? No. Okay.
What do you think it would look like, Steve?
Does anyone else want to take a guess at it? So far, William's the only answer.
So we'll say it's the best answer. It's going to be a skewed distribution.
Yeah. Steve is sweating hard, man. He's really sweating.
Yeah. Ned, please don't answer this or Jeka as well,
since we've talked about this.
Okay. Distribution will mostly be down slightly with some blowouts.
So I think we're still saying a skewed distribution.
What would we think the highest number would be?
And what would the lowest number be on this distribution?
Kyle, what do you think? What do you think in here, buddy?
And if anyone's confused, let me know. We can take a step back.
This is important. We're building the foundation of the series here.
I'm just going to give it a second here, Sean,
but hopefully we get some ideas popping off here. Yeah.
Okay. So how can we, so coin saying,
how can we know something before you explain what a prior is?
So our prior is just what we think this variable should look like from our experience
as traders, right? So, okay. So in Toronto right now, it's, what is it, Sean?
24? So knowing that we're moving in Toronto for all these years, it's June,
it's the end of May, it's 24 degrees today.
What would the highest day look like tomorrow?
What would the lowest day look like tomorrow? So Sean,
if I asked you that question, tomorrow's distribution.
So probably 24 is the high end. And what would be the low end?
Like 15. Okay. So come on, it could be higher than 24. The highest highest?
In May? Oh, maybe like 32, like back in like 1980 or something. Okay. Perfect.
So tomorrow would be anywhere between 32 and 19. And how did you get that,
Sean? By living in Canada. By living in Canada.
So knowing that we've known about earnings and knowing about vol trading,
because we're vol traders, and this is important guys,
because when we look at the data and it's not like this, if we don't know this,
we need to be able to say like, will this look normal or not?
Like if we don't know what an assumption would be, we're kind of lost.
And I'm going to show you once we decide on this.
So we've got a couple answers rolling in here.
Robbie's saying the highest is one, the lowest can be less than negative one.
Yeah. So we're talking long straddle here, guys.
So you guys are saying the highest is going to be a hundred percent gainer.
Kyle's saying some big blowouts, but mostly wins,
never making a hundred percent. Okay. So Kyle, think about the long straddle.
Long straddle we're talking about. Okay. Thank you, Stephen.
So five standard deviation returns. So we're talking in percents. So Steve,
you're going to say about 500 to 600% is on the high end, on the low end,
what do we got?
Negative a hundred. Thank you. Thank you, coins. Perfect.
So now we have a distribution where negative one is going to be the lowest end and
positive 600 is going to be the highest end. Okay. That's where our prior is.
And I agree with that perfectly.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to graph the data.
Now here's what distribution looks like. Okay. We clearly have some, you know,
at five and we have some at like negative three. Now,
if we didn't have a prior or we didn't have any domain knowledge, we might say,
Hey, this is okay. This is okay. Right.
And I actually cut off the tail earlier. This was all the way to 19. Okay.
This right side tail all the way to 19. And we do a summary. Okay.
We can see the min, the smallest number is negative 400%.
How can a straddle lose 400%, right? And the highest number here,
I cut this out. I shouldn't have, it was all the way up to 19 guys,
but the highest we have here is five.
So clearly we need to cut out everything below negative one.
I guess, Steve, but 19, no, it would never be 19. That's a 1900% premium.
Or I guess maybe actually Steve, but no, no, I think 19 is way too much.
19 is way too much, Steve. So what I did was I said, okay,
well let's basically use our priors, right? After looking at the data,
negative, negative one to 600. And that's what I did right here. Okay.
And now we actually have our target variable. Okay.
At least the beginning of it. So this is what it looks like guys.
And we can do our summary.
So let's actually learn a little bit about our target variable.
This is the important thing, right? Is actually understanding our data.
If we're not doing this, we're way behind. We're way,
way behind because someone that has domain knowledge is going to be able to come
up with new ideas.
And this is going to become extremely important when we get into pooling and candidate
variables and all that stuff. So let's learn a little bit about our data.
Okay. Something I did here guys, by the way,
is I took out the most illiquid names as well. So just like some liquidity,
just because with option data, you guys know how it is. It can get messy.
So I took out, I put some liquidity in there and yeah. Okay.
So let's learn a little bit about our data here.
Prior. What do we think mean outcome is? Mean outcome of Strata.
What's our prior on that?
Do you want to define prior again?
Yep. Our prior is what is our, from our domain knowledge?
What do we think before we look at anything, right?
Prior to looking at the data, what do we think it would be?
So if I calculate the mean of all the returns prior to looking at the data,
what would it be?
Yeah. You're saying zero or negative 0.1. Awesome. Awesome. Okay.
You guys are getting very close. So Kyle had a really good point there.
He said,
does the data below negative one make you worried about the integrity of the data?
Since it doesn't make any sense. So that's a really good point, Kyle.
And you're all in any data set you get, you're always going to have outliers.
You're always going to have something that went wrong. Okay.
So if we actually looked at this data, Kyle, negative 4.23, it was only,
it was only one variable below negative one, and it was this one right here.
So that gives us a good indication that, okay, you know, this was an outlier.
Okay. But yeah. So what I actually did was I looked at Apple.
I looked at a few names and I looked at the data. I actually looked at,
I went back on thinkorswim. I looked at the data on think back and said, okay,
you know, was this, are we getting the same data here? And the answer was yes.
So, but you need to make sure you actually have good data.
So that's a really good point, Kyle. If there was,
let's say a ton of variables below negative one or a ton of outcomes below negative
one, we've got a serious issue, right?
But we have 28,000 rows and we have one variable that's out,
that's below negative one or even below negative 0.8. So I was like,
this is definitely, it's okay. All right. So given our prior,
we would think that selling vol around earnings or buying vol around earnings is
going to be a net loser, right? That was our prior. So let's take a look.
And here it is. So blindly selling vol, okay. But blindly selling the straddle,
we're going to, we're going to net negative 0.2% after transaction costs.
So selling vol should net 2% after transaction costs, sorry,
before transaction costs. So that's another thing to keep in mind, right?
In execution, all that stuff, slippage is going to be negative 0.2.
So this is what we're trying to beat. Okay. This is what we're trying to beat.
This is like buying the S&P 500.
We're trying to get this number up as high as possible.
And if it can't get any higher than 0.023 during the course of this, you know,
the series, then we failed, right? Then we clearly haven't,
we clearly aren't better than the current guy.
And I actually want to take a step back here, guys.
I know this is a lot of information here,
but I want to take a step back here and really focus on our target variable here.
The straddle P&L means it's the best guess of the market, right?
This is the market's guess, right? The market saying, here's the implied,
here's the average. That's going to make, you know,
basically our straddle return. And, you know,
we can clearly see here that the market is a really good predictor of the earnings
move. They only get it off by 2%.
And that's usually because there's a variance risk premium. Okay.
So the market does a really good job, right?
This imagine this was negative 10%, right?
That would basically mean the market has no clue how to value vol,
but it's only negative 2%. So,
and we know the market's efficient plus or minus some variance risk premium.
Yeah. So Sebastian's saying, I don't get, it's not zero.
So basically what this is telling us, Sebastian, is that on average,
earnings moves, earning implied moves are slightly overpriced.
Volatility is slightly overpriced. And this makes sense.
So it's not, it's not an ARB, right? If it was an ARB, you couldn't,
you couldn't lose money.
But what this does mean is that if you sell vol in the long run, on average,
you're going to make money,
but you're going to have to deal with losing a 600% on a straddle. Okay.
Remember some of these straddles made 500%.
So imagine you sell a straddle for 10, for $10, you sell one lot.
So you sell $10 and you buy it back. So that's 1000 bucks.
And tomorrow you buy it back for six grand. Those are going to happen. Right.
And because of that happens,
there's some risk premium and we can see that right here. So,
so far everything's making sense.
Yeah. So everything's making sense.
The market is very efficient on predicting the straddle return.
So what this is saying is that if we sell a straddle for $10, AKA 1000, okay.
On average, the next day, we're going to buy this back for 90.98. Okay.
So if we sell a straddle for 1000, on average,
we're going to buy it back for $980 tomorrow. Or if we buy it for 1000,
on average, we're going to sell it back the next day for $980.
Okay. Does everyone get that? Let's take a look at the median.
What do you guys think the median number is going to be?
What do you guys think the median number here is going to be? Kyle,
what do you think it's going to be here, our median outcome of our target?
Three, positive, negative. What are we guessing? So coin saying 2.5%,
Crawford saying 3%. Are we talking plus, minus? What else?
What do you guys think?
Robby, love it. Love Robby's answer. Kyle, perfect. Perfect.
Because remember guys,
the mean is going to be skewed by these like huge numbers,
by these huge numbers, five, 600%.
The median is going to be the most frequent outcome, right?
And a characteristic we know about volatility as a prior, right?
Because we're vol traders is that you're going to have a lot of small winners and
a few large losers. So the median should be much bigger. So let's take a look.
And there it is, right? Almost negative 8%. So almost four times higher.
Okay. So that is that. And we took a look at our summary.
Let's look at it one more time.
Let's look at our summary one more time. And I guess what time is it here?
Okay. We're going to continue more in our next series,
but we'll go over candidate variables super quick, ending this off.
Okay. So let's take a look at our thing here. Our min is 75%.
That's our best winner, our worst loser. And we're talking long straddle here.
The worst loser is when we bought it for $10 and we sold the next day for 75 cents.
Okay. Or sorry, $2.50. And our best winner was we bought it for 10 bucks.
We sold it the next day for 50 bucks or $60. Okay.
So that's our candidate variable. That's our target variable.
And we're going to go into a lot more detail about this, because look at this,
guys. We need to break this down. There's grouping here. There's groups.
Look at this structure. There's humps, right? We've got to get rid of those.
We've got to figure it out. So that's going to be in our next slide.
We're going to really dive deep into our target variable.
But before we do that, we need to understand what a candidate variable is.
And then we're going to end tonight's slide. But this is important.
Target variables, candidate variables.
These are the variables we use to predict our target.
Our target is the weather tomorrow.
One of our candidate variables are going to be temperature yesterday,
month of the year, day of the month,
whatever. Together, let's brainstorm an idea.
Who wants to come up with a target variable?
And then we'll come up with some candidates.
Who's got some ideas here? Let's think of a target.
Who wants to talk about a target variable? Or Sean,
do you have an idea of a target variable?
And then we'll have the guys guess some candidates.
Let's do a straightforward one. Tomorrow's weather. Come on.
I did tomorrow's weather already.
Starting salaries out of university. Awesome. Awesome.
Starting salaries.
Why don't we just say salaries at 25? Salaries at 25. Okay. That's a good one.
Salaries at 25.
Degree experience. These are things I'm seeing so far. Location. Location.
Coins. That's actually going to be one of our targets.
It's going to be the actual value. That's our target variable.
We've got to be our candidates now. Experience, education, cost of living.
Love it. Let's look at a couple more here. Some unique ones. Field. Yes.
University attended. Net worth of parents. I love it.
Maybe a cool one could maybe be the median income from the area they live in.
Exactly. Here's a really unique one as well. John Doe said smooth talker.
He's saying if the person is a smooth talker or not.
What you would do is you have a candidate variable that was either a one or a zero.
If it was one, it means they're a smooth talker. If it's a zero,
it means they're not a smooth talker.
That would be an example of a candidate variable.
They can come in different styles. It could be a factor. What state they're in.
Florida. Ohio. Pennsylvania. Whatever. Then you could have numeric variables.
The numeric variables can be of different types.
They could be discrete or continuous.
Example of a discrete variable would be the number of goals scored in a game.
A continuous variable would be the amount of rainfall.
You have all these different candidate variables.
They come in different styles, different flavors.
These are going to help you predict the target.
They're going to help you predict the target.
Let's take a look back at our data set.
We're always going to be going back to our data set, always exploring.
I want to ask you guys a question. Here's our data set.
We know what our target is. It's the straddle P&L. Before I even look at that,
what do you guys think would be good candidate variables?
Market cap. Cool. Like it. What else? Event vol. Love it.
Average historical move. Past P&L. Hell yeah. These are good.
These are all ideas of candidate variables. Now,
a lot of times they actually won't predict. If they can predict,
then you're going to make a ton of money. A lot of times they can't predict.
Or they're already incorporated into the straddle P&L.
They're already incorporated into the implied move. Let's say, for example,
market cap was a really good predictor of tomorrow's move.
This is a key essential piece here, guys, when we're trading. Because remember,
it's a competition. If market cap was a good predictor of tomorrow's P&L,
everyone can see the market cap,
and they would change the implied move based on the market cap.
That's going to be incorporated into our straddle P&L. Remember,
our target variable is the market's best predictor.
We're trying to be better than that. All right. Maybe a way to think about it.
I'm going to say, just to add on there, make it really clear.
Remember at the start, you gave that example about the electrician.
There is an electrician there right now working on this problem.
Somebody's pricing this. They have factors they look at.
They have things they consider.
The blatant ones that are the super good predictors probably are incorporated into
what we're already seeing. We need to get a little bit more creative. Margin,
that's another reason why we don't want to use the actual return tomorrow as our
target variable. Because, for example,
we might see market cap is a good predictor of the move tomorrow,
but it's already being priced into the straddle P&L.
It's already tomorrow.
We're going to jump into predictors and also creating predictors,
creating these candidate variables. Just a quick example, guys,
of how you create a predictor or a candidate.
We have implied move and we have average move.
I created this new variable called implied average,
which is the implied divided by the average.
I created this new variable called dollar volume.
Price of the stock times the volume. You create all these things.
Then we're going to start together as a team. It's going to help me.
It's going to help you guys out.
We're going to create a whole bunch of variables that we think are good.
We're going to test them.
We're going to try to build up this model step by step.
It's going to be really in-depth.
We're going to go all the way from start to finish with this thing. Jordan,
before we wrap it up here, do you want to quickly give a recap of what we did?
Yeah. Quick recap, guys. Then John, when we get to that question,
I love that question. Quick recap. We talked about idea generation,
characteristics of a good business. We talked about target variables,
collecting data, and then candidate variables.
That is the start to our session, our series.
John's question was,
how likely is it that we would find a better predictor or a better indicator than
hedge funds that actually hire people full-time to work on these models? Yes,
100%. Let's go back to our characteristics of a good business.
One thing is going to be here, liquidity. Understanding where you sit,
which table you should be playing at. If you have $100,000 account,
you should never, ever be trading the S&P 500. You should never,
ever be trading Apple,
unless you're trading the balls and there's some mispricing happening there.
I traded Apple when all the retail jumped in and pushed it way past where it should
be. You are competing against the best guys. There's lots of liquidity.
If I have a $5 billion hedge fund,
and I have some of the best analysts on the street,
I can go and trade ball there. Why would I want to compete with them?
Just the first thing is compete where you think you're going to make money.
Earnings is not crazy liquid. It's not crazy liquid.
It's also extremely hard to model.
Something you'll actually note is a lot of these big hedge funds that hire top talent,
the top talent is actually not as smart as you think it is.
It's actually not as smart as you think it is.
If you look at a lot of the guys in the industry on the sell side,
it's all about providing customers ship products. Sorry, my apologies.
It's not providing customers ship products,
it's providing customers products and then hedging for cheaper.
That's literally the whole finance industry.
How can I sell you something and then replicate it for cheaper?
Think about insurance or think about... Actually, here's a really good one.
A PPN, Principal Protected Note. What is that? Well, it's just a call option.
The bank is going to sell you a principal protected note,
package it up like that, and then recreate it on their end.
They're going to have all this principal protected notes,
offset the risk by going into the vanillas and buying, let's say,
a call option. That's 95% of finance.
We're talking about the buy side hedge fund. They're usually not in this space.
They're usually not looking at this stuff. And when you go down the tiers,
the smaller the size, they're usually not as sophisticated as you get big.
As you make money, you grow and grow and grow.
That's why the bigger the hedge fund, usually the more sophisticated,
eventually their alpha starts to deplete. But you want to find areas,
long story short, you want to find areas where you can go, where not everyone,
where you're better than the majority. You don't need to be the best.
So you can compete against these guys as long as we go back up here.
Why do we want to trade this? Because there's a lot of retail traders.
A lot of retail trade earnings. And so for that reason,
if I'm better than most retail, I should be able to make money. Okay.
So keep that in mind. You don't need to be the best.
You just got to be better than most. John saying,
just to clarify that what we're implying is play a field that's of our size.
Example, find smaller cap companies that hedge funds wouldn't bother with.
Right. And even then you don't always have to be,
remember a hedge fund only has certain capacity. Look what happened to GME.
Okay. Everybody, everybody knew GME was overpriced at 400. Everybody.
I don't know one person that said, this is probably, this is very priced,
but it got, or sorry, even at 200 or 100, it was overpriced,
but it got to 400 because there's not infinite selling liquidity, right?
If there's too much demand,
it's going to drive price past where it shouldn't be.
So you just basically want to look for where might there be an imbalance between
supply and demand. And then you want to trade in that, you know,
you want to be part of that, you know, part of that place.
Yeah. Jared, that's a really good point.
Jared saying like there might be no liquidity, it's too niche. So you,
you know, you really got to make that, you gotta make that judgment call,
right? Where do you want to trade?
And is there enough liquidity for you to trade? That's what's important.
Okay.
Okay. That will be the end of this first session in the strategy series,
Jordan. I think that was super cool. Next week will be the next session.
So we'll be on Wednesdays next week, right? So moving forward,
these sessions will be held on a Wednesday.
Thank you everyone for your patience. We needed that extra day.
I hope it was worth it. Jared's got a good question here. Jared,
do you just mind elaborating a little bit more in this case of earnings though,
aren't we choosing red or black?
Do you just mind elaborating a little bit more there, Jared?
Right. We're just going to be going either short vol or long vol.
What we're trying to do, is basically say, at the end of this,
we're basically trying to say, okay, these factors predict straddle P&L.
If we can get that, and it's going to be very small,
we're going to have a very small edge. But if we can find at the end of this,
let's say,
get that number from negative two to let's say negative five or negative six,
that's humongous. And so that's what we're trying to do there.
Can we check the stock price chart? Yeah, definitely.
And we're going to talk more about pooling and stuff later. So Steve.
So we have like, let's get the summary here.
So third quantile is three and a half percent move. First quantile,
negative three and a half percent move.
Usually it's like close to zero on average.
And the max is 120 and the min is negative 67.
Hold on, Jared. I'm a little confused there.
You're saying like columns related to competition. In the case of earnings,
it's less important because we're really just picking a side.
So in this case, Jared, we're really trying to say like,
these factors tell us that there's going to be,
that there's a supply demand balance on one side or the other.
So these five factors will say that usually the straddle P&L is overpriced or the
straddle implied move is overpriced,
meaning that there's too much buying and not enough selling.
And then on the low end of these five factors,
it means there's not enough buying and there's usually too much selling.
So we might find out, for example,
that certain characteristics show us that vol is underpriced.
And that might be because people love selling calls before an earnings event.
Around these particular, let's say dividend stocks. I don't know what it is,
but that's the thing. I don't know.
So we're going to have to find out together. And that's the fun of it.
All right, guys, let's wrap up this live. Fantastic stuff, Jordan. Good stuff,
guys. Good stuff. We're going to build it out.