So, interesting, okay, okay, so we're good, yep, all good, awesome, oh yeah,
okay guys, so we're going to kick off where we started last,
and we're going to actually go another another layer here,
so remember how in last, just to get you guys up to speed, in last,
in our last video, we talked about what our target variable is,
what our candidate variables are, how to start thinking about this problem,
some ideas, some problems we can start thinking about, and, you know,
if you guys want to take on your own projects, right,
just some ideas to get you guys thinking, to get, you know, to get you started.
So I've sent everyone who asked me for sample data, for the data,
I've sent you guys a sample,
simply because I can't send more than five megabytes over Discord,
so everyone has about a thousand data points for this project to work with,
and so with this lecture, we're going to be going to our next step now, right,
which is going to be really getting into understanding, you know,
more of our data, and, you know, actually trying to test some things,
and learning a little bit more about statistics as we go forward,
and just so you guys know, this isn't going to be like a three-part course,
right, like the thing with building models,
it actually takes a long time to develop, right, it's not overnight,
if it was overnight, you just, everyone would be rich extremely quickly,
so these things take time, and it's usually really hard to extract some alpha,
but I think after this live, guys,
a majority of you are going to be miles ahead of everyone else,
so let's get started here, so I'm going to share my screenshot. Yeah,
are you going to do a recap of where we left off? Yeah, yeah, yeah,
a little bit, so let me share my screen here, dude,
okay, and let me know, guys, if I'm going too fast, okay,
we'll really slow it down, so to recap, our target variable, okay,
so we're doing an earnings trading strategy,
and our target variable is our straddle P&L, so what is our P&L for, you know,
if we were to buy a straddle today,
what would that P&L look like tomorrow after the event, close to close,
so that's our target, okay, really important to understand that,
and you can go back to the last live to, you know,
to get caught up to speed with that,
so we're just going to recap here, we're going to plot our target variable,
okay, and you can see here, actually, we're going to get a little bit,
a couple statistics about our target as well,
just so everyone's back up to speed,
okay, so here's our target, right, you can see our max move is 500%, okay,
so we make, you know, if we buy a straddle for $10,
we sell it the next day for $60, and our worst P&L is 75%,
we lose 75% of our straddle, the median is, we lose about 8% on average,
and the mean is negative 2.5%, and this is just the variance risk premium,
right, so on average, and we would expect to see this, on average,
buying straddles lose a bit of money,
and here is what the density plot looks like, right,
you can see all the way out here, we have, you know, our 500%, our 500% winner,
and then, but a majority of the time, right, so this is what white line here,
this is the zero line, so you can see most of our stuff,
the mode is to the left of the zero line, meaning that most of the time,
the median, we're going to be losing money, okay, and on average,
we're losing some money as well, okay,
so now that we understand what our target variable is,
we're going to start looking at our data, our target variable, remember I said,
guys, we want to spend the majority of our time on the target, right,
that's where the highest payoff is going to be,
a lot of people try to spend time doing the newest XGBoost model,
the newest AI model, okay, finding these new predictors,
the most return you're going to get is through working on your target, okay,
so we're going to jump into that, Sean, is there,
if there's any questions coming down to the chain,
do you mind just like letting me know? Yeah, 100%, I've got my eye on it,
I'll interject as necessary. Awesome, awesome, okay,
so I'm not bashing this guy, you know, I think he's really interested,
but this is a mistake a lot of people make,
and I think it's important that we really talk about this,
so Mitchell Rosenthal, he said, always impressed by how smart the market is,
especially when looking at predictive relationships, most times I come up dry,
something I found tonight had a lowish R-squared of 0.16, and big variation,
but still big enough to be considered, okay, so we'll take a look at this,
so just so everyone knows,
the R-squared tells us basically how much variance we can explain in our data,
okay, so an R-squared of one would look like this, okay, so let me just,
just so everyone's familiar with R-squared, because it's really important,
it would have a really high R-squared, okay, temperature today, okay,
and temperature yesterday,
so if temperature today is 30 degrees, okay, what is, what do you guys, sorry,
if temperature yesterday,
I guess most people are American, if temperature yesterday was 90 degrees,
what do you think the temperature today would be?
Marcos is saying like 90. 90, like 90, right, and then if it was like 80,
it would be 80, right, and so you plot these, oops, sorry guys,
and you plot these data points, right, and it would look like this,
it'd be really tight, you know, it'd be a really good predictor,
and if we did the line of best fit, it'd look like that, okay,
and what this tells us is that the temperature yesterday explains a ton of variance
in the temperature today, okay, and this would have a very high R-squared,
and R-squared, guys, okay, is, can only be between zero and one, okay,
where one means it explains a hundred percent of the variance,
and zero means explains nothing, all right, so this guy is saying,
and just to make sure, guys, I'm not bashing him, I think, you know, he's very,
he's very inquisitive, and, but, you know,
it's good to learn from some people's mistakes, right,
so he is saying he found R-squared of 0.16, okay,
so his target, he can explain his target with six,
he can explain 16 percent of his target's variance, so let's go back to here,
so everyone, does everyone understand R-squared,
okay, it's, and also, guys, it's also, if you, if you square this,
you get the correlation, so this also means,
R-squared of 0.16 also means a correlation of 0.16 times 0.16, I don't know,
like, maybe, maybe 30 something,
okay,
higher, way higher, actually, like 50 percent correlation, okay,
so does everyone understand that, are we good on that one, Sean,
what do you think? That looks good. So he's saying, hey, guys,
I found this R-squared, so on his x-axis, he has some variable,
and on the y-axis, he has some variable, and he's saying, like, you know,
I only found an R-squared of 0.16,
and that's humongous, right, that's actually, like,
if you could get an R-squared of 0.16, that's ginormous,
but there's something actually more important in this data set that's,
that's not very good, okay, that he's, that he's forgetting about,
and this is probably one of the biggest things in, yeah, in modeling, okay,
and when we're talking about our target,
there's groups here,
okay, there's lots of groups here, so you might have a couple regimes, right,
you can see there might be this regime right here,
there looks like there's another regime right here,
okay, and there looks like, maybe they're groups, maybe there's something else,
it looks like there's another one right here like this,
and actually there could be a third one here,
a fourth one that looks like this, okay, so we, as, when we're forecasting,
we're learning about our target variable, we first need to understand,
is there a structure in our data, okay, this is called structure,
and we're going to talk more about it, and then can we fix it,
is there a structure in our data, and can we fix it,
so let's, let's get back to work here, let's get back to our work,
okay, so when we look at, when we look at this,
when we originally look at this, it's hard to tell,
it's hard to tell if there's any structure in our data, like, do you guys see,
like, a structure in our data would look something like this, okay,
okay, it would look something like this, right, where there's like other,
there's other groups,
there's other groups inside this, okay,
there's other, there's a bunch of distributions mushed up together, all right,
and we want to, basically we want to try to, and pick out what these are,
okay, a really easy one to look at would be something that looked like this,
right, this is a bimodal, okay, so there's clearly two distributions here,
all mushed up to one,
and we need to be able to pick these apart, what are these two groups, okay,
and another thing, guys, actually, we're going to,
we're going to get to that in a second,
so that's, that's so important, guys, I see,
I've seen Chris Seville do this so many times, it drives me up the wall, okay,
I'm not, not just that, but like, a lot of people do this,
and as a good forecaster, and as a good modeler,
we need to be able to pick those apart,
we need to look at the structure in our data, we need to figure that out, okay,
it's the most important thing,
all right, so what we need to do is, we actually need to do a little bit of a,
of a transformation here to this data set,
because it's hard to tell if there's structure like this, and so we do,
what we basically do is, we, we try to make,
we try to make that distribution normal, we apply some mathematics, and we say,
okay, can we make this distribute, if this distribution was normal,
what would it look like, okay, and this is what it looks like,
so here's our target, let's give that a second to load,
I don't know why it takes long,
okay, I don't know why it's not loading there, that old,
that old distribution that we just saw turned into this,
and we can see there's tons of structure here, right, look at this,
here's a hump, here's a hump, here's a hump, you know, here's a,
here's you know, in the shoulders, we're seeing a little bit, right,
there's clearly, this is not something, you know, that's normal, right,
and there's clearly a lot of stuff happening inside this,
but the good thing about this is,
it means that there's going to be a lot of edge here,
if we can figure out what, what are these distributions inside this,
what they are, we can make a ton of money, okay, that's the good news, right,
if it was just normal, there would be, there would be barely any alpha, right,
it'd be extremely hard to find alpha, and just to prove it to you guys, okay,
just to prove it to you guys, what is the most efficient market we know, right,
it's the S&P, so what I'm going to do is, I'm going to get the S&P 500,
and I'm going to do the exact same thing with the S&P 500 returns,
the exact same thing, so imagine our target variable was the S&P 500,
look at this,
look how, look how beautiful this is, there's no humps,
this is like almost perfectly normal,
it's going to be extremely hard to find alpha into something like this,
right, to be extremely, extremely hard,
yet this is one of the most traded instruments by retail traders,
and like that's why we always say it's so important,
you want to find a game where you could actually generate alpha,
where you can actually make money. So Jordan, would you say that when you're,
when you're looking at, when you're trying to norm,
would this be called like normalizing your data? That's a different thing,
yeah, it's, we're trying to basically normalize it into a normal distribution,
it's not, it's not actually normalizing,
it's just we're trying to convert this using some techniques to make it normal.
Okay, so just to maybe make it clear, I'll try and put it in layman's terms,
when you're doing this to your data,
it's when you see those like humps and like lumps in the normal distribution that
you know there's something that's not like clearly understood or like that,
that hump is the opportunity that you want to try and uncover. Exactly, if the,
if the target that you're doing is tradable, so for example S&P 500 returns,
straddle P&L, right? If it's tradable and there's humps in the data, right?
That usually means you can find some alpha there, okay? You don't want it,
if it's perfectly smooth, it's going to be like,
obviously we can go more granular here and there is, this is not perfect,
there's not perfect distribution and you know,
you have some of the smartest guys in the world trying to pick those off.
Exactly, put it around them and stuff. Exactly, or they might trade,
let's say an option, because this is not the option data,
this is just the stock data, right? They might trade an option that, you know,
is not, is being, is not properly expressing the,
the distribution that they should, that they should see. Right,
so is it almost like you could say perfectly efficient markets,
this distribution would be perfect? Yeah, exactly, like exactly, right?
So if you're trying to delta trade the S&P 500, I wish you the best of luck,
right? It's gonna be extremely difficult to do. Okay, yeah,
I think this probably makes it clear, especially with that little explanation,
I think it makes sense. So Robbie's saying,
is it okay to assume that all distributions should be normal and smooth?
When you normalize them, if, so not all distributions need to be like that.
If there's groups in there, like obviously they're not going to be, but,
and like as we progress through these courses, you'll actually see like,
there are certain things where it's, it's not normal,
but you can find ways to like pick them apart and actually turn them into,
into normals, right? Once you try to, if,
once you try to normalize something into a normal distribution and there's no alpha
on it, it should look almost perfectly normal, like this,
it should look like this, right? Because if you look at,
if you look at what we're doing here, we are,
so this is called Gaussianize where it's a, it's a function in R,
but what we're actually doing is saying,
we're telling it a little bit about our data, right? Like in this case,
when we did this one,
where he goes in that load, okay, I'm just gonna plot it again, guys.
And we're looking at this one, but we're telling, so we're,
remember we talked about priors,
but we're telling our model here is that this thing has a fat tail, right?
And this is seen by this type HH. And then we're using maximum likelihood,
you know, a maximum likelihood estimate to try to figure out,
like try to smooth those bumps. And then if it's still coming out like this,
there's clearly like, there's clearly some alpha here, but with this one,
it's perfectly smooth, right? So usually, like,
I don't want to say in all cases, because I obviously haven't seen all cases,
but usually if your target's all bumpy, there's probably some money to be made.
Almost certain, there's almost certainly money to be made.
If your target's perfectly smooth,
a lot of people have already removed those bumps by trading the underlying asset.
Okay,
we'll take one more question here for now on this particular section and move on,
Jordan. Yeah. Arcorn's asking,
do you ever worry that some of the mathematics that gets applied to form your data
into distributions removes outliers that might actually be alpha,
but get normalized as noise? So I would say, I would say no, Robby,
just because we've already removed our outliers. So for example,
and I don't know if you were here for the last session,
but there were stuff like, let's say that were 19 times our target,
or not 19 times, 1900% winners. And so we kind of, and we,
we remove those from our data because we didn't think they were necessary.
And then all we're doing here is we're just trying to look at our distribution.
So we don't really care if some outliers are being removed here.
We're just trying to like look at it and like say, okay, well,
there's clearly some structure here. Right. So let's say for example,
like you can see here for this, I said, okay, only go from 0.6 to 0.5. Right.
If I maybe increase this, maybe there's a little bump in the tail somewhere.
Right. But I'm not really too concerned about that.
I'm really focusing on the meat here.
So, so now we know like basically, okay,
there's lots of groupings here and eventually we're gonna have to try to figure
this out. And just before we move into the next part, guys,
I just have some questions for you. Like, what do you think these could be?
Like, what do you think these humps could be here?
And also remember guys, our real data, right?
Our real data is actually going to be a bunch of these,
right? Our real data, it might be a bunch of these.
So what do you guys, what do you guys think? Like,
what do you guys think these, these bumps could, these groups,
these bumps could be?
So just to remind the guys, what data set are we looking at here, Jordan?
So here we're looking at our target.
We're always going to be talking about our target always.
And that's our straddle P&L,
right? So if we're looking at, if we're talking about our straddle P&L, what,
what kind of groups do you think there might be here?
Ned saying before market open or after close.
Ned, is this guy for real?
I literally had a call with him yesterday talking to him about this.
Sebastian saying people trading for different reasons.
Okay. I don't, I wouldn't, maybe like there's all,
you always got to try everything, right? But maybe I,
I'm not a hundred percent sure,
but I wasn't thinking, I think there's, I think there's easier ones,
different industries, different types of companies, a hundred percent,
a hundred percent like that one, right? Different tech, different sectors.
Maybe like the banking sector has a lot higher straddle P&L on average, right?
It could be like some fundamental, some fundamental factors, right.
Which would be like in the industry before market after close.
So that was one that I was kind of like working with and it was kind of,
it was showing some promise.
You know, you, you really want to think about this stuff.
So I can't stress this enough. Everyone,
the difference between someone who actually is going to make money in trading and
forecasting is actually going to spend the time to think about their data.
It's actually going to be an expert in there and in this field to understand like,
what should I pull out here? What should I think about?
What variables should I do? As you go through the forecasting,
you're going to see a lot of people doing high-end modeling.
You're going to see them doing the latest neural network.
We need to step away from that. Okay.
We really need to think about our data here, right?
Craftsmanship over whatever else is out there. Okay.
You really want to become a craftsman here and this is what's going to take you
to, you know, way above where everyone else is sitting at right now.
So yeah, you guys, you know, keep thinking about it. You know, Margin,
for example, Margin Kyle in our group, I always told him like, you know,
sometimes you're not thinking enough about this stuff, right?
You need to be constantly thinking like, okay,
what actually might go in here, right?
Instead of just like throwing everything at the wall,
you want to really think about this stuff over and over again.
All right. So onto our next step, we're going to jump into regressions here.
Okay.
We're going to jump into regressions and this is going to talk about or feedback
on the Twitter example we were chatting about.
So what I'm going to do guys is we're going to look at our first candidate.
Okay.
We're going to look at our first candidate here and we're going to look at the implied
move versus the straddle P&L. So what do you guys think about this?
If we increase the implied move. Okay. So if we look at stocks that,
let's say have a 20% implied move versus stocks that have a 2% implied move,
what do you think the straddle P&L would look like?
Do you think it would have a negative correlation, a positive correlation?
What do you guys think as we increase the straddle P&L or as we increase implied
move, what happens to straddle P&L?
Adam saying that if we increase the implied, the P&L should decrease. Okay.
So let's, and like how, if you were to picture in your head,
how would you think it would look like? Would it be a clear, a clear like,
would it be a clear pattern? Like would, if I showed you the graph,
would you be like, yes, this definitely has a correlation. What do you think?
And I just arbitrary arbitrarily chose implied moves. Adam saying probably not.
Okay. So let's plot it. Minimal correlation. Okay. Let's plot it.
So here it is. Okay. This is what it looks like.
So straddle P&L on the left side on the Y axis. And implied move on the X axis.
All right. So what do you guys think?
Do you think this is a good predictor or not?
Like I'm looking at this and I'm, I'm wondering like, should we even,
should we even consider looking at this?
Getting some nos, some yeses. Okay. So in this, in,
if we go back to what our buddy said on Twitter, he would say,
he would say definitely not. Right. If we do actual, if we actually do,
if we run a linear model, we run that model.
Okay. We get an R square, not even one, not even one.
And the person on Twitter was saying 16. That's too low. Right.
We don't even get one. Now the thing is guys in trading, this is a huge,
huge edge, but a lot of people are looking for these like monster signals.
Right.
But this is a massive edge and it's hard to really see it through this graph.
So what we need to do is we need to look at,
we need to really spend the time to look at this stuff.
Someone would have saw this scene on R square 0.004 and then moved on and said,
ah, you know, ah, this one doesn't work yet. This thing,
it could be the one of many pieces that makes you extremely wealthy.
So what we're going to do is we are going to take these implied moves and break
them into quantiles. So we're going to take 10%. So let's say for example,
we have implied moves ranging from one to 10. We're going to take one,
you know, and say that's 10% of our, of the implied moves.
Then two is another 10% and we're going to break them up into quantiles.
So let me just draw that out for you guys.
Okay. So here we have implied moves ranging from zero to 30, let's say,
but we're going to break them up into 10% chunks. Okay.
So we might say this is quantile, this is a quantile one, quantile two, three,
four, right. And inside each quantile,
this might have implied moves ranging from one to three implied moves ranging from
four to six. Okay. So we're going to do that right now.
We're going to take a look at this.
And this is,
I hope you guys are going to see like where some of the craftsmanship comes in.
So this is what we're going to do.
We're going to take all our implied moves and break them into 10 pieces. Okay.
And what we're going to do is we're going to look at, we're going to view data.
We're going to view our data here.
Okay. So let me just move this up here guys. So we're going to look at just,
for example, the first quantile here. Okay.
And you can see that these in the first quantile, we have like 1% moves,
2% moves, you know, one, 2% moves. Okay.
Let's see what we got in the second quantile.
We got like 3% moves, 2% moves. Okay.
And then when we get to the 10th percentile,
okay. Oops. These are the NAs.
Okay. Here we have like implied moves of 17, 18, 28, 16.
Okay. So now what we're going to do is we're going to say, okay,
let's make this bigger so you guys can, everyone can see.
It's a little bit tricky to see here, but I'm going to, I'm going to adjust it.
So, you know, we, we get, we get more insights, but I said, okay, like,
let's graph the PNLs now for each, for each percentile, right?
So if we look at, you know, percentile one with all the small moves,
that's this orange one right here. Okay. That's,
that's this orange one right here. And if we look at the, you know,
the ones with the biggest implied moves, that's this pink one right down here.
Now it's a little hard to see with these 10.
So what we're going to do is we're just going to plot the lowest,
the lowest implied moves and the largest implied moves. Okay.
And look at their, look at, look at their graph. So here we go.
Look at this monster, monster difference, right?
You can see that the stocks with the highest implied move clearly lose a lot more
often, like a lot more often. And stocks that have the smallest implied moves,
they lose, they, you know, they don't lose that much, right? Well,
sure they lose, you know, they lose often, but they got, you know, they don't,
they definitely don't lose as much and they have this big, you know,
they make more, they make more money a lot more of the time.
So monster difference,
but we weren't able to tell that by looking at that scatterplot, right?
We needed to look a little deeper.
And so what we're going to do actually right now is we are going to take a look
at this from a numerical standpoint. Okay. So bear with me here, guys.
Here are the largest implied moves. Okay.
Oops.
Here are the largest implied moves.
And then here are the smallest implied moves.
And look what happens as we go up the scale.
So this Med is our median P and L of the straddle.
And the mean is our mean P and L of the straddle. Okay.
So you can see here as the implied move increases, right?
Our straddle P and L decreases tremendously. It goes. So the actually guys,
if you buy the cheapest implied moves, you will,
you will actually make money barely, but you'll make money.
If you buy the most expensive implied moves,
you're going to lose 6% per straddle.
Okay. Now this is, this is substantial, right?
This is a humongous difference here.
So keep that in mind. All right.
Keep that in mind that this implied move is actually,
we're definitely using it. We're definitely using it in our model. Okay. This,
and remember in, in trading, you're never going to have a signal.
That's a 25% R squared, right? Think about it.
If you could find something that explained the variance by 25%,
you become rich extremely quickly like this. You,
all you would do is just always take the best trades and then it would just disappear,
right? Because you're getting bigger,
you're getting bigger and bigger so quickly.
You alone are going to remove that edge, right?
And that's why you're never going to see R squared of 0.25. Jordan,
do you think you can try and like, help, help us conceptualize why you know,
an R squared of a 0.25 is like not, it's not what we should be looking for.
And really we should be looking for things closer to what we found with this implied
move. Is there a way you can help us conceptualize that?
I'm thinking like they just been doing with you know,
things that do predict that well are already priced in because they're obvious to
everyone.
Maybe it's something along those lines and we're looking for something more unique.
And then if you can try to really help conceptualize why something so small holds
so much significance. So think about like this guys, right?
Okay. So first off a single edge,
a single indicator on its own is not going to be enough to make money.
You're going to need a couple of them, right?
So that's why the small ones are still going to be there because you can't trade
them on their own. You got to combine a whole bunch.
Now let's take a look at this. Okay.
Let's say I bet $50,000 every single trade.
So every single trade I sell $50,000 worth of premium. Okay.
Every single earning trade, I do $50,000 worth of premium.
And my edge is 0.0625.
And there's an earnings event during this earnings event or during this earnings
season, I can do 200 events.
So check this out during this quarter, during this, you know,
this one earning season, I'm betting 50,000 each trade.
I'm going to make $625,000.
Okay. Super tiny edge. Imagine this was, imagine, you know,
we got a signal and this became like 15%, right?
Where we're making $1.5 million. And you can see how,
if you actually do have a real edge and you're trading at a relatively high frequency,
you're going to make a ton of money.
And that's why these huge edges don't actually exist. Because if they did,
it would take you four quarters before you just totally erased the edge yourself.
And so if you're trading the S&P 500, you know, and you think you have,
let's say a good model that can predict, I don't know,
let's say adjusted 60% of the time. That's, that's insane. It would take maybe,
let's say two months or not even two months at 60%,
maybe like three weeks to figure out if you're actually profitable or not.
Okay. Because you don't need a big edge in trading to make money.
You need a very, very, very small edge.
All right. So does everyone understand that? What do you think, Sean?
Sean O'Toole Bill had a question here. You said,
can you add other candidates and do like a logistic regression without curve fitting
it too much? Yeah. So you can do, so logistic regression would mean,
would imply that your target variable is binary one or zero, right?
In this case, we have a, a non-binary, right? So it's, it's continuous, right?
It can be 3%, 3.111%.
So we're running regressions instead of a logistic regression.
Okay. So, okay. One more important thing here that I really want to chat about.
So, is there any questions about that?
Cause we're going to be moving on to a very important topic.
I think we're all right to move on here. Okay.
So what is something that I mean, actually extremely, extremely, and Ned,
please don't, please don't spoil it, Ned.
I'd be really impressed if someone knew what was wrong.
What is like really wrong with that, with that graph that we drew,
with this graph right here,
like what's really wrong with this data or in general,
what's wrong with our data?
I'll give it like one minute there, Sean, just for someone to take a guess.
I'll shout them out as they come in.
Like what's, maybe you're not wrong with our data.
What's wrong with our target variable? Like there's something inherently wrong.
Lucas is saying not as many data points for high implied moves.
Robbie's saying the P and L is calculated at the end of each day instead of right
after the open.
Okay. Arcorn saying need more data. Joey's saying we have different groups.
Who's okay. Joey's saying different groups. Yes. Joey. Perfect.
So first off we have a ton of data. We have 30,000 data points here.
We definitely don't need any more data, but Joey hit it right on the head.
Okay. Joey hit it right on the head. We have, we have tickers. We have groups.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to filter for Footlocker KO and Goldman
Sachs, three different moves. They should have different size moves. Okay.
And I'm going to plot their moves. Look at this guys.
Here's so blue is Coca-Cola's moves. Greens are Goldman Sachs.
And then red is Footlocker, right? The moves are drastically different.
And so we can't really compare a 5% implied move to Coca-Cola, Pepsi,
to Coca-Cola, Footlocker, and Goldman Sachs. We can't do that. Right.
There is basically no pooling. Okay. And there's no pooling until really,
this is probably the most important takeaway from this, from this live guys.
So we're have have a example here to really demonstrate it.
They do a really good job.
And then we're going to go into our data and take a look at it.
And we're going to actually do pooling.
And then we'll look into something called partial pooling and we'll save that for
next week. All right. So imagine, okay.
Imagine we are trying to predict the average reaction time of someone.
And then we look at the amount of sleep someone got. Okay. So,
and we looked at, let's say 400 people. And here I'm just showing you 20. Okay.
So we looked at 400 people and we just took a sample of 20 and we said, okay,
well days of sleep deprivation versus average reaction time.
So what do you guys think?
What would you guys think like the data should look like?
I know it's right here already, but let's, let's,
let's really talk about this and think about this, right?
As the days of sleep without sleep increase,
your reaction time should also increase.
It takes you longer to react to something. Okay.
But we can't just put everyone together and then run a regression.
On average, let's say Sean might be faster at reacting.
So he's going to have a separate model, right? And let's say Joey,
he's even faster at reacting. So he's going to have a separate model,
but that's going to, that's going to overfit. So let's take a look here.
So in the red, okay, we have no pooling. Okay.
No pooling means we just look at each individual's persons and run the regression.
Okay. The green line, the green model is saying, okay,
let's just put everyone's data together and run a regression.
Okay. We can't just do that.
And this is like one of my like big secrets of finance that, you know, I,
I spent a lot of time on this and I hope you guys are going to see the value in
it.
So the thing here is we,
it's not good to just pull the data and it's not good to just know,
use no pooling, right? So let's look at this guy's data here, Mitchell.
What's Mitchell doing here? He's just slapping everything together, right?
He's doing no pooling and he's trying to run a regression.
We're missing a lot of information there, just like in our data, our structure,
there's groups, there's things like that. And we need to account for those.
So in this dataset here, Sean and I, and Joey are still human.
We still have similar characteristics. We still live, breathe, eat, sleep,
do whatever. And so we want to get a mix of pooling and no pooling, right?
Let's go back to our earnings dataset.
We don't want to just look at the average move for each individual equity,
right? Because at the end of the day, they're all still companies. So,
but we don't, at the same time, we don't want to mush them all together,
which we were doing before, right? We want to say, okay, well, you know,
equities are still equity and they still have earnings calls and they still move
up when there's a big beat and they still move down when there's a big beat.
So why don't we use that data? We only have 14 data points for each earnings,
but we can look at someone else, let's say Footlocker and Macy's and say, okay,
well, this is how Macy's reacts. So let's use some of their data in our model.
And now we can get more data and that is partial pooling. Okay.
So what it would look like is we have this new line,
which would be this blue line right here. So it's,
it's kind of hard to see you guys. So green line is complete pooling. Okay.
So it's always going to be the same in every graph,
no matter what the red line, it fits only to this individual. Okay.
Only to that single stock. And then the blue line, okay. Uses a mix of both.
All right. And that is, that is the partial pooling. All right.
So you can see that right here. This is a zoomed in version. Okay.
And here's another way you can think about it.
And we're going to go a little bit more in depth here.
Here's another way you can think about it. If we look at,
let's say we look at the whole baseball season and we look at the first part of
the baseball season and we see someone hit, like,
I actually don't know baseball,
but let's say someone hit like an unbelievable amount of home runs. Okay.
And then we were asked to say, like,
what is this person likely to do in the next season,
in the next half of the season?
And a lot of people would go by the hot hand theory.
He's going to do just as good. He's on fire. He's killing it. Right.
But he's human. He's still a baseball player. Right.
So what we would do is we would say, okay, well,
what's the average home runs that we saw that we saw this season.
And we would say, okay, well, let's shrink him. Okay.
So he's all the way up here with like crazy amount of home runs and here's the average.
And we're going to say, okay, for the next bit of season. Okay.
He's probably going to be a lot closer to the average.
He might be still above because he's really good,
but we're going to shrink him down. Okay.
And that's what the partial pooling is.
We're using his data and things that are similar and pulling it in.
And we can get better when we shrink to something that is more reasonable or something
that's more the same. So for example, maybe he's a left-hander.
And so we're going to shrink him to all the left-handed batters.
I think that's what they're called. Okay. And the better. So for example,
instead of shrinking footlocker to all the stocks,
we shrink footlocker to all the stocks in that sector. Right.
And that's another reason, well,
obviously we're going to go more into detail about this strategy as we continue,
but what we're going to do now is we're going to,
we're going to do complete pooling. Okay.
We're going to do complete pooling here.
So what I'm going to do is take that data.
I'm going to take that data that we just saw there.
Let me just get it up here so we can look at it. Okay.
And I'm going to scale the data.
So basically complete pooling and we're graph it right. You guys,
here's what it looks like. So just, okay.
Just so you guys know what we're doing here is we're saying we're turning,
let's say so footlocker 10% move for footlocker is a two standard deviation move.
It's a five standard deviation move for Coca-Cola.
So we're putting everything on the same scale. Okay.
Boom. Okay. Now we have something that is complete pooling here, right?
So everything is on the same scale now, right? You can see, for example,
you know, here are the two standard deviation moves here, the two,
three standard deviation moves. Now we can model using this,
but there's obviously a better way. And that is the partial pool, but that's,
it's 855. That's going to be for our, our next live. Okay.
So just showing you guys some of the insights and like how we need to be thinking
about this data and like being,
being a craftsman here and not just like rushing into these things.
They take time, they take, you know, work and they,
you gotta be constantly improving. Brilliant. So Jordan,
a couple of questions for you here in the chat and a couple that I'm going to tack
on as well.
So we talked about a couple of different things that are more like data science
techniques in this rather than just the direct application to finance,
such as turning your data into a normal distribution, complete pooling,
partial pooling. And these are not necessarily finance specific, right?
These are data science specific things.
If somebody wanted to learn more about these things,
can they learn about it on online? Like, can they just Google these things?
Will they be able to find code in the language that they are trying to learn it
in by Googling them? Is this all a part of a package that you downloaded?
What's the deal? For sure. You can do all of this.
You can learn all of this online. A couple of good resources,
cross-validated Kaggle,
and then a couple of really good books from David Aronson that's directly relatable
to finance. It's not an easy read.
An easier read would be evidence-based technical analysis.
So that's a good one to start with.
Yeah. So I would say those three or four places to get your feet wet. Kaggle,
you know, type in EDA, exploratory data analysis on Kaggle,
where people actually get paid to forecast things and they show all their work.
See what they're doing, right?
And you'll see a lot of the times 99% is spent on understanding your data and learning
about it. Yeah.
I'm more so talking about just learning about the different techniques and actually
getting the code for them, so they don't have to maybe start- Oh yeah.
And all the codes on Kaggle as well. It just takes time, right?
Like if you want to become a good data scientist, it's going to take time,
right? But this is the stuff that happens at the top quant funds, right?
Where they bring in a bunch of quants and then they teach them finance and then
they say, okay, let's get some data. Let's get to work.
So Joey's asking, I guess, related to the partial pooling saying,
so maybe you would match them with their correlated stocks and create like little
baskets of stocks? Yeah, absolutely. Right? Absolutely. So sectors, maybe,
sometimes it's really hard getting your hands on good sector data.
You want to try everything, Joey.
You want to really think about it and then try it.
And then just to clarify, Tico was saying,
are you saying that like a 5% move is different for different stocks? 100%,
right? A 5% move for Coca-Cola is huge. A 5% move for Shopify is like normal.
Mm-hmm. And then Stephen B saying, can we backtest partial pooling?
Like in the baseball example,
can we test how well it worked in the past and how much shrinkage we should use?
Yes. So that's going to be for another day, Stephen,
but you can actually graph like over time how well your model is doing. Like,
is it getting better? Is it getting worse? And that's a good method to use.
Partial pooling is used in like some of the best sports betting models.
All right. So that seems to be all the questions.
We're going to end the session here, just before we do the good stuff. Jordan,
another great live and I will be posting this up shortly. Yeah.
And next live guys, we're going to start getting into more of our data,
learning more about our dataset and starting maybe in a couple more,
we're going to actually build out, start building out the model and testing it,
backtesting it across, you know, a walk forward analysis,
cross-sectional analysis, all that stuff is going to happen.
And we're going to build something out good. We're going to make some money.
Exactly. And then we're all going to get rich guys. All right.
See you guys on the next live. See you.