Okay.
Alright. So in this live, guys, we're gonna be talking about,
we're gonna continue on our series.
So we're gonna be going into part 3 of our series.
And this was for building our earnings model. So as you guys know, like,
I'm taking this pretty seriously. And as soon as AMC trade us off,
I'm gonna be basically going all in on earnings trades and trying to figure out
how much, like, how much alpha I can really make trading earnings.
I know some of the guys in the group are already doing a fantastic job.
And I think bringing, like,
a really quantitative idea to the group and with their domain knowledge,
I think we could build something pretty fantastic.
So we'll go through what I got so far for today's live. And then on Thursday,
we're gonna have a more in-depth live going over in more detail part 4.
Alright. So let's jump right into it. And please slow me down along the way.
Alright. Let me get full screen here.
So the first thing we're gonna take a look at, just so we can, you know,
get back to where we were, we're gonna take a look at our data frame. Alright.
So quickly, here are our variables, right? You guys,
I've already sent out a practice data set for those who have asked.
And basically, we have implied vol data.
We have contango and implied move earnings date.
We know the price of the stock, the volume, what time it was released.
We got event vol, non-event vol. And our target,
we'll go over all of these other variables in a second. But our target,
if you guys remember from the first live,
is our straddle P&L for the 30-day options. Okay.
So what was our P&L holding these options?
Holding a straddle from the close before the event to the close after the event.
Now, my first day at this,
my first day at trading the model or a super naive version of it,
I did pretty well.
I think it was a $13,000 day for me with trading the strategy.
But I realized something during that. So something to keep in mind, guys,
is when you're actually building something out,
a lot of it is going to be domain knowledge. Okay.
It's actually one of the most important things. So for example,
I thought like if we could get a P&L of 5%,
then we're gonna make a ton of money, right?
But one thing I did realize was I was paying almost 5% on some of the names entering
and exiting the trade. So our original thesis was, okay, VRP, right,
was about 2%, right? And let's just, just to show you guys again,
we can see here that the mean was about negative 2.5%. So on average,
if we traded over 20,000 earnings events, each trade,
we made 2.5% if we shorted this of the straddle P&L, of the straddle price.
The issue, however, is this is imagining if we had no transaction costs.
And in reality, the transaction costs are extremely high, right?
A lot of these names are liquid. The bid-ask spreads are large.
Not a lot of traders, you know,
not a lot of market makers want to quote a tight spread.
And so we're actually gonna, just in transaction costs alone,
we're gonna eat up all this edge. And so we actually need more than that.
And just from doing the trades last week before this whole AMC debacle,
I realized like it's gotta be a lot more than 2%. Okay,
so that's just some domain knowledge that I'm adding to this now.
Let me just pull up the chat here, guys,
so we can chat about this as we go through.
Okay, so now that we know that,
it's time to really dig into this and see if we can, you know,
start to produce something that is gonna be tradable.
And I think you guys are gonna find this really interesting today just to,
you know, get a sense of how this all works.
So what I'm doing here is I'm actually creating a whole bunch of variables that
I think are gonna be predictive. And this is from my domain knowledge. Okay,
so one thing is gonna be the event vol divided by the realized volatility.
So one, I read a paper years ago that basically said,
the larger the realized volatility before the event,
the larger the move is gonna be.
And we need to really think about this for a second because the intraday move,
right? Think about just like the intraday move alone.
It's gonna be what regular volatility is plus some order of magnitude more,
right? There's gonna be more volume. There's more information coming out.
So we could take what the realized vol is now,
multiply it by some number and come up with a good estimate of what the actual move
is gonna be. Okay, so that's what we're doing here.
What's the event vol divided by the realized volatility?
So I'm creating that variable.
I'm also creating this variable called the implied move versus the average move.
So our usual thing, if the implied move is 10% and the average move is 5%,
well, that's gonna be a ratio of two.
And then I have the implied move minus the average move.
So maybe instead of like, for example, four,
let's say the implied move is three and the average move is two. Well,
that's gonna be a huge ratio of implied move versus average.
But it's only one vol difference. It's only not one vol difference,
1% difference versus something,
let's say that's 20% implied move and average move is 11, right?
The ratio is not gonna be as high,
but the size and the magnitude is gonna be extremely big.
So we added that in there. And then I created my own contango variable,
which is just the IV30 day divided by the IV60 day.
And I created dollar volume, right? Because sometimes, for example, people say,
oh, this thing has a lot of volume, but it's only $23 stock. So, you know,
it's gonna be different than, let's say,
a $10,000 stock with only a thousand volume. So multiply volume and dollars.
And then this one here is implied,
just the implied volatility divided by realized volatility, right?
Because a lot of the time, for example, we're selling a 30-day option.
And let's say the realized vol is 10 and the implied vol is 50. Well,
after the event, it's probably gonna collapse. All right.
So these are the variables that I'm working with right now.
We've got a couple more coming down the road in this section here.
But any questions about the variables we just created?
Nope. Okay. So we're gonna keep on going, guys. So what we're gonna do is,
and this is, remember, guys, as we're building our model,
we really need to think through the process every step of the way, right?
It's what makes us different than, you know,
the engineer coming out of Wharton, whatever it is, right?
There's a big difference there. And that is our domain knowledge.
Our knowledge is a trader, okay?
So always think about the steps as we go through this, right?
Full understanding.
So what we're gonna do here, guys, is we're gonna plot the implied move, okay,
versus the absolute move. So we should see like some type of correlation,
right? Let's take a look here, right? As the implied move increases,
the absolute move increases, right? Would that make sense?
Does that make sense to everyone? As the implied move increases,
the average move increases, right? We're looking at all the stocks together.
And this is gonna be pooled, right? Everything's pooled together.
There's no partial pooling or no pooling, right? So for example,
Shopify implied move of 10%, of course, is going to, on average,
move more than let's say, Coca-Cola. But you guys can see like it's super,
there's a lot of volatility here. Like there's a ton of volatility, right?
So for example, sometimes the implied move was 30% and the stock pancaked,
right? Or sometimes there's a 5% implied move and then the stock moved 65%,
right? Maybe this is STNP, for example, when it got cut in half.
So there's no real correlation there.
But what we can do with this instead is we can say, okay, well,
what if we took the average absolute move and the average implied move and plotted
that, okay? And before I plot it, what do you guys think we should see?
We take the average move, okay?
And we plot that against the average implied move.
Yeah, Sebastian, how positive do you think that would be?
You think it would look like this? A little bit less variance,
a little bit more variance. What do you think?
Okay. Well, while you're thinking about it, I'm going to plot it here.
Less variance. Perfect. And in fact, look at this, guys. Oops.
There's a lot less variance, right? There's a lot less variance.
So what's this telling us? Well, it's telling us that the market is saying,
it's pretty good at estimating the average move, right?
But it's not the best at figuring out tomorrow's move, right?
So basically what we can kind of infer from this is that the market actually uses
the average move to price the implied move, okay?
And this shouldn't be a surprise to everyone.
That's probably one of the first things you would look at, right?
What's the average move? And then I'm going to price the implied around that,
okay? So it actually does a really good job, right? It does a really,
really good job.
So what we're going to do, so now that we basically know, okay,
the market is pretty good, right?
But the key thing that we can also kind of infer from this is if we just looked
at Apple,
we just looked at Apple,
we could see basically that when Apple's implied move percentile is the highest,
it's probably a good time to sell. And when it's the lowest,
it's probably a good time to buy, okay?
That's another thing we can infer from this exercise that we just did here.
So that's actually what we're going to do here now.
We're going to basically create percentiles.
So what's the implied move percentile? What's the skew percentile?
What's the curvature percentile? What's the dollar volume percentile, right?
We're going to start creating these percentiles now,
and that's going to be the no pool, okay?
So we just looked at a pooling example,
then we're looking at a no pooling example,
okay? So now that we have that,
let's just take a look at our data here so you guys can kind of see what's going
on. And we're going to go down to Microsoft or,
okay, let's go to CSX here. So we can see here, well,
basically what we did was we created percentiles, okay?
But they're called Z scores, the same thing. So let's take a look here.
The implied move, let's see what the biggest implied move was here. Okay,
looks like about 5.2%, okay?
So this is going to be actually a 5.2% move for CSX,
given all the other historical moves, is almost a two standard deviation move.
Yeah, sorry. Sorry, guys.
The implied move of 5% is going to be basically in the extremely high quantile,
okay? So implied move of 5%, you can see here,
is basically two standard deviations higher than what's usually implied.
And then let's go for, let's say, the biggest move, okay?
We'll go for the largest move and the smallest move. So look at this one here,
right? Negative 10%, well, that is two standard deviations,
2.2 standard deviations down move, okay? And if we take the absolute value,
it's a 2.2 standard deviation move, okay? So that's what we basically did.
We said, okay, well, let's look at the data and let's basically create,
for each individual ticker, let's create their own percentiles, all right?
And that's going to be actually very useful for us.
And I hope you guys are starting to see why we would do that.
And we're going to go actually dive deeper into that,
just to make sure you guys understand why we're doing this.
So what I'm doing here is I'm taking Microsoft and I'm saying, okay,
I'm saying, okay, let's pull Microsoft out of the data set only.
And we're going to look at a couple of things, okay?
We're going to look at the basically no pooling.
We're going to look at all the percentile data.
And we're going to also do it for a bunch of tickers, okay?
So we're going to look at Microsoft first. So let's take a look.
So we can see here,
as the implied move increases, okay, for Microsoft,
the absolute move doesn't always increase.
So if we were to look at this and say, okay, well,
where do we want to sell and where would we want to buy?
If there's no correlation here between average move and implied move,
we basically always want to buy the cheapest percentile and sell the most expensive,
okay? So when Microsoft is, let's say, 6% implied move,
we always want to be selling, right? Or 5%, we always want to be selling.
And when it's at 3%, we usually want to be buying.
And we can convert that to Zed scores or percentile. So you guys can see it,
what we're going to do later on here. Okay, so instead now,
all we did was convert these into the percentiles.
And you can see it's the exact same thing.
But this is going to come in very handy in a second.
So let me see the questions here. So just to make sure everyone's,
I'm going to try to explain this one more time very clearly and you guys can ask
questions. If we look at all of Microsoft's implied moves, and we say, okay,
what were the highest implied moves? And what were the lowest implied moves?
We are clearly wanting to sell the highest and buying the lowest.
Because it doesn't mean if there's a high implied move,
there's going to be a high absolute move. Okay, does that make sense?
We want to sell the highest percentile of implied moves.
All right, so let me ask you guys a question.
Let's say tomorrow Microsoft implied move is 5.
Are we a seller or are we a buyer?
Sell, right? Why? Because sometimes it implies 5 and then it pancakes.
Like look how many times it pancakes.
So you basically want to be selling the highest implied and buying the lowest,
right? Because sometimes, for example, you buy a 3% move and it moves 6.
Okay, so we're going to do actually a really cool exercise right now.
And I really need you guys to pay attention and really try to understand this.
This is very important. This is going to be crucial going forward.
So let's really talk about this, okay?
So here, what I did was I took all those stocks that we did here. Microsoft,
Netflix, Google, Facebook, Goldman Sachs, Bank of America, okay?
And each one is a different color, right? But let's just look at Netflix here.
Let me see if I can draw. Okay,
you guys are going to see why pooling is so important.
So here it looks like our Netflix is, this encompasses most of Netflix's data.
Okay, you guys see that? So let's take a look at one point right here.
This point right here,
this was a day where Netflix had an implied move of about 6% and it moved absolutely
about 20%, okay? In this case scenario,
it was implying about a 15% move and it only moved 2.5%, okay?
And we could say that the middle arena, the middle area,
the centroid is what it's called, is right around here,
okay?
And then we can do the same for Bank of America,
which looks like it's right around here, okay?
This encompasses like all of Bank of America, okay?
And you can see there's little groups throughout this.
Now, right off the bat, we can kind of see that there's no correlation, right?
That when the implied move increases, the average move doesn't increase, okay?
But at the same time, there kind of is a slight correlation here because,
okay? There's a slight correlation here because everything is pooled together,
right? Of course, if the implied move is going to be higher,
the average move is likely to be higher. But you know why?
It's because it's going to be part of Netflix's data. And of course,
when the implied move is going to be 1%,
the average move is going to be 1% because we're looking at Bank of America and
Goldman Sachs data.
So what we need to do is we need to put everything on the same scale to actually
come to a conclusion,
all right? So let us do that. And we'll go back and really talk about this,
guys, because I need you for sure to understand this.
Okay, so here's everything. Here's no pooling.
So now we converted everything to ZED scores for each individual ticker, right?
So what we basically did, we said, here's Netflix's data all the way over here.
Here's the centroid.
And we're going to shift that centroid to where everything is, okay?
We're going to... And Bank of America was all the way down here at centroid.
And we're going to shift that centroid to right here.
So now everything's together.
And we can clearly see now that there is zero correlation,
okay? There's nothing.
As the percentile for any given ticker,
as we increase the percentile of implied move for any given ticker,
the average move percentile doesn't increase.
Or the actual move doesn't increase, okay? So if we think about this again,
we have 10 different tickers and we say, okay, for each ticker,
let's calculate what the highest...
Let's rank the moves and let's rank the implied moves.
And then we're going to plot them. And there's no correlation.
So we clearly want to be a seller when the percentile is high,
okay?
So we're going to start... We're going to actually start...
We're going to basically get into our first model.
Our first extremely simple model that you guys are going to...
I think you guys are going to really find interesting here.
So does everyone understand this before I move forward?
We're almost coming to the end here. Does everybody understand this?
This is so important.
Like, don't feel... Like, let's chat about this.
I'm sure there's a lot of people who have questions. Okay,
there's no reason to be shy about this one.
Ned, ask, what's up, man? What's up? What are you thinking?
Okay, so here we go. So it looks like no questions. We're going to keep...
So what we're going to do is now we're going to say, okay,
let's take all our variables.
All the things that we think are going to be important.
So our quorum are saying,
what about bid implied moves on stocks with little data?
So do you mean like percentiles?
So in that case, Rob, that'll be tricky, right? Let's say you have stock with,
let's say, three earnings dates or let's say one earnings date. Well,
you can't really get a percentile. But the thing is,
that's not really going to skew our data, right?
We have 1500 equities and 20,000 events.
So it's not really going to mess around with our data,
but we are going to try to do techniques to make sure that it doesn't.
And in that case, Rob, we're going to have other variables. Like, remember,
we have all these variables here. And so if there's no implied move percentile,
then we can always basically use something else instead.
So here's all the things that are going to be accessible, implied move,
contango, skew, curvature, time of day. All right?
And now what we're going to do here is instead of doing the whole 20,000 earnings
dates, we're actually only going to randomly select 2,500. That's it.
Okay, we're going to randomly select 2,500.
And now, so we have basically... Let's take a look at our data, guys.
Here's what we have. We have the no pool curvature, skew,
no pool dollar volume. We have also the no pool implied move,
which we just talked about right here.
And I'm just going to convert the time of day to a one or zero.
Okay, and let's... So now let's take a look at our data here. So funny enough,
these 2,500 variables that we just... 2,500 events we just sampled.
So we just sampled 10% of the data. The mean risk premium is also negative two.
So that risk premium of negative two kind of looks a little stable.
And just making sure that the data is good. Okay,
so what we're actually gonna do, guys, for the first one,
we're going to run a very, very naive linear model. Okay,
and there's been a lot of issues with this because it's linear and our data is almost
certainly not linear. But we're going to run linear regression,
linear multiple regression.
And the reason why we're doing this is just to see like what variables might be
important here, right? What things might we want to see?
And I know I was talking about this. You can do random forest,
which takes a little more time. So we're not going to do it in this video.
To also get non-linear variables that might be important.
And let's take a look.
Okay, so super interesting. Super interesting.
We got just from running this on the sample,
we got two things that are really important here.
One is the no pool implied move. So this makes a lot of sense.
And I think this is actually one of the strongest variables out there.
So the implied move percentile, this is really strong.
And we're actually going to see how strong it is.
The other thing that's strong is this absolute average earnings move.
So it looks like the larger the average move is, the slope is positive.
The larger the average move is, the better our straddle P&L,
which is interesting, okay? And obviously, the higher the percentile,
the worse our straddle P&L. So basically,
just what we're getting off this from our first run through is that stocks that
have huge average moves, we don't really want to sell, okay?
So let's say if the absolute average implied move is, or sorry,
the absolute average move is let's say 4, and the implied move is 7 or 8,
that's probably a good sell, okay? But absolute average earnings move,
we actually don't want it big. But this is a super naive model, guys.
So we have to do more digging here. But let's take a look. This one,
I did a sample before the live, and this one also came out positive.
This one actually didn't. So let's take a look.
So what I'm going to do here is, I'm going to take our dataset,
and I'm going to basically break them into quantiles and say, okay,
let's look at the mean straddle P&L for the ones that have the highest percentile,
right? Let's take a look at that.
Look at this, guys. It's absolutely monstrous, okay? When we get into the 80%,
the 90%, the 100%, like the biggest percentiles, we start getting huge returns,
right? 7%, 8%, 9%. These are the returns we need for sure, right?
As we actually, as we go down the list,
we actually get into positive return area.
So buying straddles start to get positive.
So this variable, I'm almost certain,
is going to be a huge driving factor in our model,
okay? So implied move percentile. For each, for any individual name.
So if the stock is, let's say, 4%,
and the implied move percentile is the highest it's ever been,
so you sell that,
okay? So this, now this is just a naive model, guys,
so we're going to do more digging, but I'm almost certain,
just because I ran a couple of samples already, and this one always popped up,
but this is actually going to be a very strong predictor in our model going forward,
okay? So that's where I stand on this for today. It's 8.35.
Do you guys have any questions?
Robbie's saying, I was just thinking, if there's never really a correlation,
most newer equities would be overpriced with higher implied moves,
but that's a guess. If there's no real data, right? No real data. I'm sorry,
if there's no real correlation,
most newer equities with high implied moves would be overpriced. Yes, 100%.
100%, Robbie, or Rob, because something else that we're going to find,
I'm almost certain as well, is that the implied move,
the level of the implied move is usually a good predictor too,
right? Obviously,
like the data is going to tell us the most profitable trade is going to be a low
average move, a huge implied move, and a huge implied move percentile, right?
We're obviously going to find that to be the biggest, the best case,
but how many of those are we going to get a cycle, right? Can?
So we need more trades. And so we need to start, you know,
loosening the constraints and trying to get more trades in.
Is it moving, Rob? Don't tell me it's moving, man.
Yeah, so Ned's saying,
all these variables are created based on the realized move and not the jump.
So the reason is, Ned, is because I don't have open implied vol data.
I have close to close implied vol data.
So if I'm looking at the jump versus the close implied vol,
my data is going to be so biased, right? Because sometimes it takes, you know,
an hour, two hours, three hours for the vol to finally leak out.
So it's going to be, it's going to be tricky.
And also when you really look at like some of the stocks and you look at the opening,
a lot of the time, Ned, you'll see in earnings,
the stock doesn't gap at all because it just doesn't trade after hours.
It's too illiquid. And then the first tick of the day, it's up like 10%.
And that's not good. The open is going to still be basically flat,
even though the first second is going to be huge.
So the jump would look really small, but in actual fact,
you'd never be able to get out at that price.
Yeah, so all we're looking at this is from close to close.
We're not looking at the open. Now,
when we start looking at the open and we're looking at the close as well,
now we're taking a directional bias, right?
We're looking at the intraday move now.
And we can model that separately and get a small edge, right?
Because it's liquid to hedge in the morning. We might find, for example,
that before market open strategies or before market open times,
you want to do a hedge in the morning, right?
And these are the things that you can keep adding onto the model and get better
and better and better, right?
And that's why there's so much improvement you can do in earnings because it's not
really modeled that often. And there's a lot of edge there. It's hard to model.
And so there's going to be a lot of edge if you can figure it out.
All right, dudes,
everyone's all right? No other questions?
Anytime, Joey. Great seeing you hanging around.
So Ned has a question here and Steve says,
okay. So Ned's saying, well, vol drop can take 30 minutes to a few hours,
as you say, how can we account for the intraday vol? I.e.
we leave for a loss at 10 a.m. in the morning,
but it ended up being break even or winter end of day.
So that's the thing that you'd have to model that, right?
And you'd have to get the data. It's easy to get intraday data, super easy.
It's not easy to get close to open vol data, Ned.
That's going to be the tricky thing, right? You might find, for example,
it makes sense to close early in the morning, right?
So if we do model the move versus the jump,
the jump is always smaller than the move, right? It's not always small,
but on average, it's a lot smaller, right?
And when we can plot this here super quick for you guys. See,
I've already did it, but we'll just go like this.
I won't plot it because I can't remember the code for it, but okay. Oops,
yeah. So the standard deviation for the jump is 6%.
Standard deviation for the move is 7.9%.
So the move is usually more than on average in the jump,
but you would have to get that implied vol data, Ned, to model it. So for now,
we're going to do close to close.
All right, guys. Ned, if you have any other questions, hit me up in the DMs,
and I will chat with you guys later.
Try again, Ned, I'll be there. All right, see you guys. Thanks, Jordan. See ya.
What's up? All right, peace, bro. All right, peace.