So, you guys know where we left off.
We were looking at our straddle P&L as our target variable,
trying to basically create a system that can give us above and beyond returns over
that two and a half percent that we were seeing from the risk premium. So,
I'm just going to give a summary of our target variable so we can get back on the
same page.
So, as you guys can see, our mean is negative two and a half percent, right?
We're getting charged that risk premium for selling that risk.
But we need to do much better.
And this is one of the biggest things that I think might affect other traders is
not knowing how big an edge needs to be to overcome costs, right?
A lot of the time, when you have brokerage fees, you have commissions,
you have slippage, and that's going to eat away at your profits.
And most of the time, it's going to eat much more than your profits.
All right, thanks guys. Sean would have killed me there. All right, let's see.
Recording in progress.
So, we need much more, but how much more do we need? So,
what I thought was I was going to do,
basically, I started looking at my historical earning trades and I thought,
okay, well, what hurdle do we need to overcome?
And for some of the guys that are on here that are taking earnings to that next
level,
I'd love for you guys to actually input what you think the hurdle is that we need
to overcome. So, in this case, what I have is a 3% in, a 3% out,
and a half a percent in commissions, okay? So,
and this 3% is based on the straddle price, all right? So, let's say,
for example, in this case, let's say the mid of a straddle is $8, okay?
Because don't forget, we're working with the data,
and the data is going to be basically the mid, right? So,
if the mid of the straddle is $8,
we're going to be basically spending 20 cents getting into the trade,
20 cents getting out of the trade, and then about, you know,
five or 10 cents for the commissions. So, for $8 straddle,
we're looking at about 50 cents in commissions. And so,
that's a total of six and a half percent that we need to overcome,
okay? So, from some of the other guys on here, Marjan, if you're on here,
if you could just, you know, let me know what your thoughts on this are. So,
six and a half hurdle, and right now, without just blindly selling vol,
we're actually losing 4% per trade,
okay? And this is what kills the traders, right?
We see a nice two and a half percent edge, and we say, hey, you know what,
let's just go and sell vol, we're going to make quite a bit of money.
The issue is, you're actually in a negative spot. And this happens,
especially in options, because the bid-ask spreads are very wide.
And does anyone want to disagree with this statement?
Or does anyone think they have a better number here, a better hurdle number?
So, the next step we're going to do now is now that we know what our hurdle is,
basically,
anything above six and a half percent is going straight to our pockets.
So, what I first did was,
I want to make sure that this risk premium has always been there through time,
right? A lot of the times, maybe it just happened once, or, you know,
it happened maybe for a couple quarters, and then it was gone. So,
what we need to do is we need to make sure that it's actually happened consistently,
or maybe it hasn't happened consistently. So,
what I did actually was I got eight years of data. Okay,
so I know when Hutch sees this, he'll be pretty happy with it.
I pulled in eight years of data, and what I said was, basically,
only show me the data that has a tight bid-ask spread.
And that's why I call this liquid ER.
And if we look at how many data points we have,
we have 17,000 events over an eight,
almost 18,000 events over an eight-year period. So, what I said was, okay,
let's look at our straddle P&L, and let's look at that through time.
So, here's what we have. And this graph is gonna come in handy later.
And just quickly looking at this, you can see the zero line up here. Oops,
sorry, guys.
Sorry, guys, that was a little bit of a spoiler. So, here it is right here,
all right? Here's our straddle P&L through time. And you can see, so,
for example, on this quarter, like 2013, you know, we were making,
we were losing 6% per quarter. And then we started making, you know,
2% per quarter here, if we're long the straddle. And then,
but now we're at this period where it's like,
the P&L is just getting sucked out of these straddles. So,
I wanna show you guys a post from our buddy, Ben. Okay,
which I think is a little bit ridiculous,
but we're gonna take a look at it anyways.
So, can you guys see my Twitter screen?
So, let me know if you guys can see my Twitter screen here.
Okay, great. So,
here's Ben posting the variance risk premium in selling equity fall, all right?
And you can see, so, you can see the zero line right here.
And what Ben is saying is like, there's a downtrend. This is since 1992. Now,
I really don't think there's a downtrend, but what we notice here, guys,
is like, you can basically see the cycles of variance risk premium.
You get a crash, variance risk premium is negative.
Then for the next five to 10 years, we start climbing, right,
and all of a sudden, you know, short sellers got blown out,
short vol traders got blown out of the water. And, you know,
all of a sudden selling vol is a huge, huge profitable strategy.
And what we're seeing here is kind of a similar thing, right, you can see like,
okay, 2013, 2015 to 2015, like really profitable.
Then it got like not profitable. Then we had the blowout, right?
And now all of a sudden vol is becoming extremely,
selling vol around earnings is becoming extremely profitable again.
So, you know, we can almost say that selling earnings vol is cyclical, okay?
You're gonna have a lot of short vol sellers come back into the market again,
let's say the next few years, and that's gonna drive down the risk premium,
right? And we can see that right here. Like, guys, for two years,
selling vol was not profitable before even we look at the commission structure,
okay? So just keep that in mind.
Blindly selling vol constantly is probably not gonna be profitable because you have
a 4% hurdle or sorry, a 6% hurdle.
And on top of that, you get years where it's like positive returns.
So selling vol could be extremely, extremely difficult.
Okay, so now something,
so now we come to the conclusion that we can't just sell vol, okay?
We're not gonna make any money. We're gonna lose money,
especially on a something where the holding period is a half day cycle.
You're holding overnight. The commission structure is huge.
The bid asks are huge.
So what we need to do is, oh, what I found, and this was actually unbelievable.
And it was unbelievable and unbelievably simple, okay?
If there is a vol drop, you're gonna earn. Let me say it again.
If there is a vol drop, you're gonna earn. And so sometimes we'll see,
let's say the implied move or the IV30 day at 60, the IV, sorry,
the IV30 day at 60, the IV60 day at 57. And there's an earnings event.
We wanna sell volatility. Well, the thing is,
you actually might not get the vol drop that you were anticipating. Well,
let's say for example, realize vol is above implied vol.
And so after the earnings event, the vol doesn't drop. So check this out, guys.
This is very exciting. What I did is I said, okay, look,
let's create this variable called vol drop, okay? And this basically says,
what in percentage was the change from yesterday to today? So let's say,
so this was the formula. Vol drop equals IV30 divided by, sorry,
IV30 tomorrow minus IV30 today. Okay, and then we divide that by IV30 today.
So it's just the delta.
Okay, so we'll do a quick example.
Let's say today the vol is 50% or tomorrow the vol is 50%.
Yesterday before the event, it was 60%, okay?
So that would be the formula. So tomorrow after the event, it goes to 50.
Yesterday it was 60 and yesterday it was 60.
And so that would give us 10 divided by 50.
This would be equivalent to a 16% drop in vols, okay? So it's not in vegas.
It's in percentage.
So that's what that is. And if we actually take a look at,
let's take a look at this variable because it's very important.
It's actually extremely important.
Look at this, guys. Most of the time there's a vol drop. Okay,
so here's the zero line right here, meaning no vol drop. You know,
sometimes vol increases after the event, rarely,
and most of the time it gets smoked, right? The IV crush,
whatever the retail call it. But what we're saying here is, okay,
let's at least give it a 10% drop, okay? So for example, it was 23 vol before.
After the next day, it was 19%, right? On a 30-day option.
That means the event vol was 73%. And so the expected move was 3.5%, okay?
For this scenario, right? Sometimes, for example, it's, I don't know,
80 tomorrow and 88 yesterday, right? And you know,
you're still gonna get a similar, oops.
This one was a big one,
right? That was a big 10%. So you say, okay, let's at least have that.
And now let's take a look at our P&L,
okay? So here I plotted in blue without that filter over time.
One simple filter. And then I plotted the red. Red is after that filter.
And what we can see here is our P&L drastically increases in every single quarter,
okay? Now, I'm sure some of you guys are saying, well, hey, Jordan,
how do we know there's gonna be a vol drop, right? How,
if we know there's gonna be a vol drop, then our life gets a lot easier.
And so that's the next thing, right?
How do we know there's gonna be a vol drop?
And there's two things that I found are the most important for the vol drop,
okay? One, and the Hutch might not agree with me, but I think after this slide,
he might start agreeing with me. One, IV needs to be bigger than RV.
The implied move could be 10%,
okay? The implied move can be 10%.
If the RV is higher than the current IV or the current non-event vol, okay?
Don't take the trade, okay? We basically wanna make sure that after this event,
IV is gonna get crushed. And if you guys go back to my 100K challenge,
I traded DRI,
and there was an example where the stock moved 3% after earnings and vol didn't
move, okay? If I had known that, I wouldn't have sold vol,
we would have been a profitable trade. So that's the first thing,
IV or the non-event vol,
the vol that you think this thing's gonna collapse to after the event,
needs to be greater than the RV, okay? In this case, I just did IV over RV.
There needs to be contango. I'm sorry, backwardation, whoops,
okay? There needs to be backwardation,
meaning the front needs to be higher than the back, okay?
And the back needs to be higher than the one after that.
So now,
what we're gonna do here is we're gonna apply a simple Aaron Brown method,
okay? We're gonna apply a very simple Aaron Brown method. So actually, sorry,
not just yet.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna plot three variables on their own. Contango,
IV, sorry, IV versus RV. So how big is IV versus RV?
The ones we just talked about here. And then the size of the move, okay?
So here we go, we're gonna plot the first one.
So here, okay, we can see that.
So what I did basically was I took the backwardation,
backwardation here equals IV30 divided by IV60, right?
And I ranked all of them in our data set. And I said, okay,
let's break them out into quantiles.
So let's just view our data here just so you guys were on the same page.
But we went over this the last two lives.
Okay, so for example, this one here, the IV30 is 11% greater than the IV60.
And so this goes into our seventh quantile. And this is 26% higher.
So it goes into our 10th percentile, okay?
So basically what we can see here is the higher the IV30 is over the 60,
aka steeper backwardation, okay? The worse the long straddle PNL is,
okay? So we're gonna get back to that in a second.
I will answer all those questions there, okay? So the higher the backwardation,
the higher our PNL. And we're gonna do the same for IV versus RV.
I love this one, guys. I love this one so much, okay?
And the reason I love this one is because you can see here, it's pretty stable.
Like when IV is just slightly over RV or IV is equal to RV or IV is below RV,
it's stable. And then like, look how quickly that melts off, right?
So we could see that, okay, well, basically, when IV is a lot higher than RV,
we're gonna earn,
okay? I'll go back over that in a second.
Yeah, I know, I have my windows open and like it's a busy street outside.
Okay, just joking. Sean's on the loose right now. Yeah, Rob got it. Okay, good,
good. Okay, so that's why I really like this IV versus RV, right?
The next thing is the implied move. We already went over this one.
The higher the implied move, the more our straddle PNL is.
Now this can of course be improved upon because Walmart at a 6% implied move,
it's huge. Shopify at a 6% move is not huge,
okay? This one is great as well, okay? Higher implied move,
the lower our long straddle PNL is gonna be.
So just to make sure everyone is aware, I'll write these out right here.
Contango equals F1 divided by F2, okay? So IV30 divided by IV60.
This is IV30 divided by RV30 or RV20, okay? And then this is implied move,
right? This has to do with the concept of shrinkage.
So now, this is the beautiful part.
We're gonna use Aaron Brown technique, which basically says, okay,
small things, small factors alone don't make a lot of money,
but together they make a ton of money.
So I did it. Adam, I didn't do that.
I don't, like there's gonna be,
like these variables are gonna be constantly changing and there's so many we can
do, so many we can test.
I don't know how far we wanna go with this because like this alone,
as we're gonna see right now, is gonna be a profitable system, okay?
So what I did here was I said, okay, look,
give me, I'm gonna filter for,
so all my indicators on their own are not gonna make us any money, right?
It might get us, let's say negative 4% or negative 3%,
but it's not gonna get us past that 6.5% hurdle by themselves.
So what I said was I said, okay, look, let's take all our data set,
18,000 variables, 18,000 observation,
and I want the ones that have above average backwardation,
above average IB versus RB, and above average implied move, no,
above the average implied move number. Okay, like, so for example,
I was actually long vol on ADBE today.
Basically, it was $15 in debit and was able to offset all my,
basically get out at 17.50. I sold all my deltas when it touched 567.50,
just based off this simple model. And that was a long vol play,
not a short vol play.
So we're taking the above average for just the three variables that we looked at
here. And now let's take a look at this, guys. This is very exciting.
Our mean return now passes our hurdle, okay? Seven, negative seven,
the straddle, if we're a shorting vol, the straddle loses 7% on average,
which is half a percent higher than our hurdle,
aka this is a profitable system.
Now, one thing that we need to be concerned about is, well, what is our,
how many bets do we have? Right, well, what if we only have five bets?
So we can take a look here. We have 4,400 bets, okay?
So basically 25% of our quarterly bets, okay? And you can see here, if I do,
you can see here, if I do,
okay?
Check this out, guys. Let's do tail,
okay? Because we have less events to begin.
So we're doing about six to 800 bets a quarter, okay? Without any filters.
We add the filters, we're doing 25%.
So we're basically doing 200 bets to 150 bets a quarter. And of course,
you probably still wanna refine that, get that number up to 10%.
That's where I'm trying to head to.
Now, what we're gonna do now is we're gonna plot a P&L.
So the first one we're gonna do is we're gonna plot the PA straddle P&L. Now,
as you can see, this looks fantastic. This is without the 4% hurdle, okay?
If I took away the 4% or the 6%, let's see how I can do this here,
times negative one minus 0.06,
okay? There we go. Here is our P&L for the strategy, all right?
Now let's look at this one. Without any filters, we hit all the bets. Well,
this one makes like two times as much money,
but once
we take that out, once we take out that 6% all of a sudden,
this becomes a terrible strategy, right? And you can see our P&L,
when we filter for better names, we get a less smaller standard deviation.
And so our Sharpe ratio is gonna be much higher.