Yun, so actually,
this is one of the questions I've been wanting to ask you for a long time.
So I thought I'd start, kick it off with that.
So you mentioned in the group that you took, you shorted some ball on SRPT.
Yeah.
I was wondering how you structured that trade and why you structured it that way.
And then maybe if you can talk a little bit about the sizing for that trade as well,
how you sized it. Okay, so yeah. Okay, so I structured that.
All I had on was a short strangle in the, I can't remember the strikes,
but it was like, when I put it on, it was like 15 delta call, 15 delta put,
two weeks out.
The reason I did that is because the wings in particular were really elevated.
All vol in that stock was really elevated, obviously,
because there was an announcement scheduled to come up,
but the wings were very elevated.
And the reason I sold strangles is because I really, okay,
so I wanna say right now, nothing I say is going to be an absolute.
You can always come up with, what about this? What about this? But in general,
I think if you're gonna sell vol, sell vol. Most of the time,
the idea of doing an iron condor to cap your losses or whatever is just a waste
of money. Those kinds of hedges are very rarely done.
They're not useful in single stocks in particular. I mean,
this thing had like a 400 vol. I mean, I knew it was gonna move. I mean,
if it had gone to zero,
I wouldn't have lost much more money than I lost as it was.
So it really just does come down to sizing.
And sizing is tricky because it could go on, I could talk about it all night.
I started very much as a Kelly person.
I've evolved slightly in that regard now that I'm doing a lot more portfolio stuff.
I mean, this method is based on forecasting method that I did 15 years ago.
But 15 years ago, there were only about 100 stocks that traded options.
And now there's, I don't know, 5,800 or something.
And I think there's 500 that have weekly options.
So now you can just do the breadth.
So I just do tons and tons and tons of this. And I have really small positions.
And I try to keep the maximum loss on each one to a certain limit. I mean,
obviously, I didn't know,
that stock could have gone up twice as much as it did.
So you don't know what the maximum loss is, but you can sort of,
you can eyeball it. You don't have to sort of say to yourself,
how much would I lose if the S&P went up 8,000% overnight? Could it? Yeah.
But I mean, realistically, you can just throw that out, right?
So when people say, how do you know? Well, you don't know, do you?
But if you know enough to do a trade,
then you know enough to come to some sort of conclusion about that as well.
And if you literally can't, then you shouldn't be doing the trade,
because you don't know enough to do the trade.
Everything you need for sizing is also the same stuff you need to measure edge.
So don't tell me that you can't size something, but you think you've got edge.
It's the same problem. Right. Interesting. So in that case,
I remember when we did a GameStop trade for earnings one time,
and we were trying to stress the position. Do we stress it to a 200% move?
And if we do, we can barely get any size on this thing.
When you look at these trades that you're doing,
how are you stressing that position in let's say the SRPT trade? Okay, well,
let's do an easier one right now. Let's say you've got an earnings trade,
right? And you want to sell the front week vol, and the front week vol is 150,
and the second week vol is 80. So in this situation, I would say, okay,
I don't think 150 is the fair vol, because that's what I'm selling.
So I think it's lower than that. Let's say I say, okay, it's 120.
It's halfway between those two,
because that's the sort of realized premium you can expect in a variance premium.
So then I'll say, what's a 3SD move based on that vol?
And I'll just cap it at that. I'll just say,
I could possibly lose here 3SDs if this thing moves against me. Interesting.
I'll do 3SDs, but I'll also lower the implied vol back to 80,
which doesn't make a great deal of difference on a one-day option,
but in a one-week option, it can.
And is there a reason why you thought in that case,
Gamma was expensive relative to, let's say, Vega?
Where maybe you wouldn't be so sensitive to the moves if you were, let's say,
selling a Jan 2022, for example?
Okay, now leaving aside earnings,
because obviously that's a specific timed event. Almost always,
the variance premium, if that's what you're trying to capture,
is larger in the short-dated options.
And it pretty much increases almost linearly and monotonically.
The biggest variance premium you're going to find is an option right before it expires.
So typically, if you're going to sell options,
you sell them as short as you dare. If you're going to buy them,
you buy long-dated options just because there's less variance premium.
And I also think people don't like doing that because it's going to involve selling
an SPY daily straddle for like 80 cents,
and then paying 15 bucks for a six-month option.
And people don't want to do that. But the price doesn't determine value, right?
I mean, a Ferrari costs more than a Kia, but for a reason.
People get stuck on the price because that's what they're paying.
And you've really got to think about the value. But also,
the reason there's a variance premium is because the losses are realized through
gamma. And the options that have gamma are short-dated options.
And if you think about it,
if you've got an option with one week to go and a vol premium of three bucks,
and you've got one with two, sorry, three points,
you've got one with two weeks to go, vol premium of three points,
the amount of dollars that the shorter-dated one is going to accrue in a week is
going to be much greater than the other one's going to get from two weeks to one
week. So you're accruing dollars in those shorter-dated ones,
hence you're taking risk, and you get paid for risk. It's a general thing.
People acknowledge that the variance premium is a risk premium,
but then they don't want to take any risk. And it doesn't really work that way.
You've got to walk towards the fire.
In regards to that risk premium,
I know we're seeing right now with all the meme stocks,
like I guess some of the biggest risk premiums,
we've probably seen in a long time.
I know you mentioned you were trading a basket there.
Is that part of your basket?
So like basically selling a broad range of meme stock vols?
They pop up,
but I think this is actually a really big mistake that a lot of retail people make.
I don't know what your people are. I don't know if they're retail or whatever.
And I wouldn't say they're typical retail because they're on this platform anyway.
But often I get asked, how should I trade GameStop? And my response would be,
why do you want to trade GameStop?
What's so special about GameStop apart from the fact you've heard of it?
I mean, if it shows up as part of your normal process,
that it has an edge that you identify in other situations,
will you trade it exactly the same as you trade that? I mean, otherwise,
why do you think you have an edge in GameStop just because the vol's 400 and it's
gone up 300%? If you can't explain to me where that edge is coming from,
then there's thousands of other things to trade. You don't have to trade stuff.
Right, I think you mentioned that in your books, right?
That's the beauty of being a positional option trader is you don't always have to
have a position on.
Yeah, yeah,
and the great thing now is you can trade across thousands of underlyings.
The bid-ask spread is much smaller than it used to be.
Brokerage costs are way smaller, and it's much easier to monitor stuff now.
You don't even need any real software. You can just use IB, which is free.
And then you can just, I don't know,
do RDE links or RDT links or something to an Excel spreadsheet and do all your monitoring
that way. Whereas like 20 years ago, this would have been a major operation.
Yeah, what was it like trading back in the day? Like,
but you were a market maker, right? At Bluefin? Yeah, yeah,
I started as a market maker in the DAX and the Eurostops. Got it. It was,
you might as well be talking about,
the difference from then to now is probably greater than the difference from 1900
to then. I mean, it was just everything about the market was different.
Like,
it would take us 10 minutes to run a risk slide just to see what our risk was.
And we're using dot matrix printers and stuff. I mean,
it's just a totally different world.
No one could price American options in real time because it would take too long.
So you'd use European options prices and then just sort of wing it.
Like all these approximations we got taught for like how to price butterflies quickly
and stuff. I mean, you don't need any of that stuff now.
You don't even need to know what the Greeks,
how to calculate the Greeks anymore. I mean, it's all there for you,
which is why I think a lot of training courses are still hung up on that. Like,
this is the formula for Delta. Well, who gives a shit?
You should know what Delta is, but trading's not stochastic calculus.
You don't need to know how to derive any of these things.
Got it. Sean, is there any questions coming in there?
Because I think you touched on some points that Jens was asking in terms of liquidity.
So you said it was much less liquid back then, a lot more liquid now,
but would you say that there's more opportunities in less liquid markets?
And should, let's say,
a smaller retail trader be trading in less liquid markets to find maybe edges that
other bigger people are leaving on the table?
That's one of those, it depends questions,
because I think once something's a liquid,
there's a lot of reasons why it could be.
Sometimes there are genuine edges in the liquid markets,
but they're so small that the big people are literally just not even looking at
them. So that does happen.
The problem in that case, though,
is no matter how big you are or how small you are,
you still have to be able to put the trade on.
So if no one else is looking at you, how are you going to get into that trade?
If you have to pay that full bid ask getting in and out,
it doesn't matter what your theoretical edge is, you can't capitalize on it.
So sometimes there'll be edges in a liquid stuff because the big guys don't care,
but often things are just a liquid because no one cares and there's no edge anyway.
So the fact that something's a liquid on its own isn't an opportunity. I mean,
that's just a problem for everyone. Transaction costs are an absolute killer.
And I think everyone knows that intellectually,
but I don't think people grasp how big a problem it is.
I mean, apart from transaction costs,
you could just randomly buy or sell stuff and you'd break even.
It's the transaction costs that add up and because each one's so small,
you just don't notice each one. But at the end of the year,
if you write them all down, it's horrific.
Would you say,
is there a difference between institutional transaction costs versus retail transaction
costs?
Yeah, there is.
Institutions can negotiate lower rates at every step in the process.
They can't do much about market impact.
An institution's market impact is just gonna be bigger than retail traders.
But all the other things like ticket charges and clearing costs can be negotiated.
And there's also ways that they can become like a pro customer versus a customer.
They can route things to different exchanges which give them better rebates and
stuff like that. So they have some advantages in that regard,
but they also have the actual market impact,
which is probably a bigger issue for them at that point. Well, it is. Yeah,
my friend who works at a pension plan, he's saying like, you take huge cuts.
Like when they call up a sell-side bank or something and say, hey,
I need to get into XYZ,
they'll like take huge cuts off the table there for the market impact.
So I can imagine a lot different. Yeah, and I mean, so obviously,
that's why a lot of option strategies just won't scale.
Because when I say I can trade options on 500 stocks, I can,
but if I had a hundred million bucks,
I wouldn't be getting nearly the same returns. It just doesn't scale.
At a certain point, it just stops. So if you're doing the S&P,
you can trade as big as you like, but anything other than that,
and you've got real scaling problems, options just really aren't,
in most cases, they're not that big a deal in the financial world.
And how big do you think the vol community is relative to let's say people using
options for hedging or Delta bets?
I don't know. I really don't know. Yeah, I couldn't even put a number on that.
Yeah, I know in the last couple of years,
the average order lot has dropped to about a third of what it was say in 2018.
And that's really indicative of more retail people coming in.
And most of that retail flow is directionally speculative and most of it's on the
upside. So that has changed.
Almost all of the large like pension funds are using options as hedges or overwrites.
And so they are pretty much set and forget type things.
All the sell side firms are largely hedging because they don't really have prop
disks like they used to now. And everyone,
whether they say they are or not is basically playing that market making game and
just trying to get the spread. But how all those things work out,
I really couldn't tell you.
Sean, is there any questions from the lads there?
There's a more general one related to how retail investors and traders should be
looking at the markets in general in the vol space.
Do you think the name of the game in the retail space should be trading risk premiums?
Or do you think there is genuine opportunity to find some real alpha?
I think I would look at it like the food pyramid.
I think the basis of any profitable trading operation,
no matter what the size is,
should be risk premium because they're always there to a variable degree,
but they're always there.
And they tend to be large and they tend to be there for reasons that are fairly
obvious and well understood. So like the variance premium,
largely due to insurance and risk transfer.
So because you can kind of rely on it,
that should be the thing that you kind of,
that's your main thing that you structure around.
But then there's a lot of other little things that turn up occasionally.
And a lot of those risk premium trades don't take a lot of monitoring or a lot of
effort.
So they are the sort of things you can kind of just put on and then look for other
stuff.
I think it's unrealistic to think you can make a significant amount of money just
with the pure alpha trades because I don't think they turn up often enough.
And I think when I do find something like that,
normally it's got a sort of a significant risk premium embedded in it,
but I don't find it anyway. Or no capacity. Well, that's the other thing. Yeah,
I mean, a lot of trades are interesting,
but you can hardly do them either because they don't turn up very often or because
when they do, they turn up really small. So, you know, like, I don't know,
selling vol over non-farm payrolls. Yeah, I mean, that's a great trade.
You can do it 12 times a year. What else are you going to do?
Do you have any stories, where you saw something, you were like,
there's no way this is trading for that. And, you know,
you ended up putting it on and it worked great. Or maybe the other time,
where it was like, why is this here? You put it on.
And the next thing you know, you're on the totally wrong side of the trade.
Yeah, both.
But the one that really had the bigger P&L impact was the one that went against
me. Okay, so back in 1998,
Eurostox was a fairly young index. It had only been listed recently,
and they'd only just started listing futures and options on it.
And the Eurostox was originally envisaged as a pan-European index.
So they were going to have a geographical spread of companies.
So there were going to be some Portuguese companies and some, you know,
company from like, I don't know, San Marino,
or whatever the little countries in the EU bucket were.
And then after about three years,
they decided that they were going to completely rechange,
not just the weightings, they were going to change the methodology completely.
So it was going to literally be a different index with the same name.
And so they changed it to a cap-weighted index,
and they just chose the biggest European companies.
And that meant that the implied forward, I think halved,
because the dividend rate was totally different.
So I wasn't aware that they could even do that. I mean,
that's one of those things that when it happens to you,
because I had the forward on the wrong way, and like,
I got run over completely with it. And then two days later,
it was announced they were going to do it. Huh, go figure.
Somebody in the bank got the inside knowledge, really.
I didn't even know that was possible. And it's one of those things afterwards,
a lot of people were like, well,
of course you should have known that was possible. And you're like, well,
fuck you. It's like, back up your hard drive.
People only tell you that after the damn thing's crashed, right? So like,
Uvixy was like that a few years ago, right?
Where they changed the leverage factor from two and a half.
It's not at all clear they're allowed to even do that. I mean,
there's still class action lawsuits going on against that. Oh, wow. I mean,
but good luck, right? That is, they say, yeah, we can, we just did. All right,
it's up to you to litigate against it. You know,
so I got COVID in that one as well because I had a whole bunch of long vol.
It's my worst ever options loss, it was long vol.
So people tell you you can't lose a lot of money being a long vol,
they really just haven't been around long enough. Because, you know,
the vol dropped by, you know, from like 200 down to 150.
That's 50 vols worth of Vegas, not much fun. So how did you handle that swing?
There's nothing to come back to work the next day? Well, yeah,
there's nothing to handle. I just lost the money. It's gone. I mean,
I wasn't happy. I think I took the afternoon off. Kind of,
I can't remember what I did. I didn't, I wasn't happy. But yeah,
there's nothing you can do really, is there?
It's just one of those things you don't think can happen. But- Until it does.
Yeah, the world's, one of the reasons of,
one of the definitions of risk is that there's a lot more things can happen than
have happened.
So if you get,
if you blow up because of something that's happened in the past and you just didn't
pay attention to it, you're just an asshole.
But if you blow up for something that's never happened before, all right.
I mean, that's sort of forgivable.
Yeah, especially even like a short, since we're short vol traders, you know,
we always hear from the long side of people saying like, there's tail risk,
there's tail risk. You're always going to blow up.
You're eventually going to blow up. And like, in this group,
we're predominantly short vol. We really, I guess our foundation is from,
you know, how you think you,
and so what we usually say to those people is like,
that's why we're getting paid, right? It's to take on that tail risk.
So what's your view there in terms of thinking about how people say you're going
to blow up eventually because you're selling uncapped variants?
Well, you don't have to. I mean, it's like, okay,
so if you're like LJM partners who had this crazy position on where they were short,
I think 10 of the five Delta strangles and long one of the 30 Delta strangles,
right? So their P and L,
I don't even know what you'd call it.
The payoff diagram looked like Batman's head, right? It went like this. Okay,
that is just asking for trouble, right?
And they lost like $980 million out of a billion and they claimed it was over two
days. Realistically, it was over about 20 minutes. That's going to blow up,
but being short, you know, across 200,
like really fairly uncorrelated names with long spread in there as well.
I mean, you don't have to blow up. I mean, I haven't yet.
Maybe I'm just running through a firework factory. I don't know.
I don't think I am.
One of the other things is if you're going to have a philosophical argument about
this, you have to differentiate between say,
what happens between five Delta and five Delta because we've got enough stats in
that range to legitimately say, you know what?
There's an edge to being short vol. Not all the time, but on average.
But if you're getting out to the one Delta options, you know,
I would bet that they're overpriced, but I can't prove that. I mean,
Taleb can't prove they're not either.
We literally don't have enough information.
And so you're at the point where you have to make a lot of suppositions about things.
I think at that point, I don't know is a perfectly valid answer.
And I'm not going to go around selling one Delta options because in order to make
any money, you have to sell so many of them that your risk is enormous.
And frankly, your margin's enormous too. But you know,
I'll sell 10 Delta options all day.
I think there's a difference between those two. It's important difference.
Sean, any questions there? Yeah, there's a few actually, Jordan,
if you want to take a look through the chat as well,
but there's one that I think we should chat about.
It's a good time to bring it up.
I think it was today and maybe leading into yesterday,
you were having a chat in the group with some of the guys about earnings and looking
at historic moves as an indicator of future volatility. So,
a couple of guys just want to ask about that because one of the factors that we
use to, we look at when evaluating,
selling vol around earnings is historic moves.
And maybe we can split it up into a couple of different things if you think it makes
sense.
Looking at one-off moves that may have happened as an indicator for something versus
maybe an average move over a period of time or an average implied move over a period
of time, these types of historic factors.
What's your experience been looking into these?
Do you think there's any validity to looking at them and why or why not? Okay,
so in my first book, which was in 2008, so I guess I wrote it in like 2006,
I gave an example of an earnings trade where you look at say the last,
there's an implied move of 5% and the biggest move over the last two years was 4%.
So there's probably edge in there.
So I'm not saying I've never looked at these numbers either.
Then when I did look at them, I found that I did it in two ways, right?
The first one I just did was kind of a regression model where I'm like, look,
do these past numbers predict the future number at all?
Like what is the R squared from using these other things as predictors for this
one thing? And it was minimal. Now,
I think it was practically statistically zero. That could be,
we've only got like 12 data points for a lot of these things. And frankly,
that's another problem. Fundamentally,
companies change so quickly that most companies,
what they were doing three years ago isn't really what they're doing now.
So like there's the obvious ones like Tesla, right? Which was a startup,
a Bitcoin company, a car company that lost money,
a green energy credit spelling company. But like even something like GM,
things like its healthcare obligations change, its financing arm changes.
It's a different company.
I think the average lifetime of an S&P 500 company is only like 20 years.
So it's a really dangerous thing just to compare earnings,
which only come out every three months. But anyway, once I did it,
I just didn't find anything. And then I said, well, okay,
I'm only gonna sell options if the implied move is in a certain percentile relative
to the past jumps. So if it's like,
let's say the implied move is 5% and that's the 95th percentile of all the historical
ones. Okay, does that make sense? Well,
let's just say I sell it if it's above average for the jumps.
No matter what filter I put on and use that as a trading rule,
it just didn't help.
I'm not saying that you can't tease something out of it.
And there's this site that someone pointed towards some guy who does machine learning
on the earnings or something. I don't know,
maybe he's getting something out of it,
but I just know that the simple stuff that I did, it didn't do anything.
I've been looking at these earnings now for 15 years and I've sliced and diced them
in practically every way by like market cap and value and industry and historical
numbers. Oh,
and whether it comes out in the first half of the earnings cycle or the second half
or all of this stuff, anything I could think of, I never found anything.
So I just think there's an edge there in selling.
So pretty much just sell everything. Yeah, right? When in doubt, sell all.
I mean, for the last, this earnings cycle hasn't been very good,
but the last earnings cycle was fantastic.
So it's a very volatile way to go through life,
but that seems to be where all the edges.
So do you view it then just purely as like a risk premium play?
Like we'll call it like an earnings risk premium,
jump risk premium kind of thing? Yeah, I think so. I mean,
I'm not saying that if you, it's one of those things, right?
You could have a detailed knowledge of that particular company or that particular
industry. That's always possible, but I don't. I mean,
I've been collating this huge list of weekly options going through all the tickers
over the last few days. And I would say 80% of those tickers,
I don't know what the company does.
Like I didn't even know what the company was for most of them. I mean,
it's just three or four letters. I just, it really makes no difference to me.
So,
and I think it's also easy for people to convince themselves they know more about
this stuff than they really do. I mean,
the track record for fundamental based analysis on stocks is pretty poor.
It's actually unbelievable. Time and time again,
these like analysts we read from like the sell side research, it's like,
even though how much they try to understand the company,
they followed it for years and years, how many times they just get it wrong.
So, I totally agree with that. And yeah, I mean,
I remember when Apple was trading for 12 bucks and that was,
I don't know how many splits ago. And everyone said it was a terrible company.
It was bound to go out of business, you know?
And everyone thought Google was a pile of crap because it didn't make any money.
And everyone thought Amazon was garbage because, you know,
people were doing the spread where they'd buy Barnes and Noble and sell Amazon.
Probably didn't work out very well for them.
Yun, so if we were to, obviously like we could consult the data here,
but in your opinion, would you think that if we took,
let's say a company and we looked at the distribution of earnings for let's say
a five-year period,
do you think that same distribution would it be a similar distribution in the next
five-year period? I mean, who knows? It's only 20 data points.
That's one of the big problems.
If you could see the earnings as they accrued every day, then yeah,
we might be able to do a lot of stuff, but you just never have enough data.
To just sell. Vols never, it's never cheap. It's only less rich.
That's not true, but I mean, I always make sure there is a vol premium. I mean,
sometimes there isn't, right? Sometimes there's a, the term structure is wrong.
Sometimes the structure is flat. And so then I'm just not going to do anything.
I used to look at the dispersion of analyst forecasts,
on the basis that if there's a big dispersion,
you can't really have a surprise because no one knew what was going to happen anyway.
I don't know if that stopped working or if it never worked,
but now that I've got more information,
it doesn't appear to be working anymore.
So that was the only thing I found that ever did anything, and now it doesn't.
Interesting. I don't know if you have the data for it,
but something that was speaking to my interest is looking at the guidance data,
but it's just hard to get hands on good guidance data.
Even Bloomberg doesn't have it. Yeah, that's something that's changed as well.
There used to be smaller jumps because earnings data was leaked routinely.
And so people would trade on it and that would sort of take a lot of that surprise
away.
So this is one of those things where leveling the playing field has actually increased
the risk for everybody.
So we're talking about, I don't know when Reg FD came in, 2005 or something.
We're talking back in the internet bubble era.
And then the only person who did that after that was Steve Cohen,
worked out pretty well for him. Yeah, he got us too, good for him.
He got to buy the Mets though, that's his punishment.
You're not a big fan? Well, I love baseball for some reason. I don't know why,
because nothing ever happens, right?
It's one of the most boring sports on earth,
but it's kind of appealing as well. I just wouldn't want to buy the Mets.
That'd be way down the list of things I'd want to buy.
I know we actually briefly touched on this June,
but do you find similarities between baseball sports betting and earnings trading?
I think in general,
there are similarities between sports betting and trading in lots of ways.
In the way that, the sort of trades that we're talking about here.
I think in terms of the statistical analysis, just the general mindset.
In terms of the particular example you were giving, I don't know.
I don't think I've thought about it enough to know,
but I do know a couple of very successful sports gamblers who've transitioned to
being very successful options traders. And if you look at some of the real,
the OG option guys like Blair Hull, I mean, a lot of them were card counters,
sports gamblers. I mean,
he literally went from card counting to being a market maker on the Picos because
he thought he could make more money. That was it. I mean,
he thought of it exactly the same game.
As a card counting? Yeah, I mean,
he still talks about card counting when he's thinking about new ideas.
And one of his good friends is Bill Benter,
who's made several billion betting on horse races.
So he's done pretty well. Yeah, have you ever looked into horse racing?
I feel like that's actually really similar to earnings in some way.
There's not quite as much doping involved in earnings.
A business partner of mine in one of my previous ventures got really into it for
a while.
And he found it was very difficult because he was convinced that the races were
pretty much fixed in a lot of places in the US due to doping.
So, and also the rake in horse racing is ridiculous. You know,
I think it's like 18 to 20%. That's very tough to beat.
So I did a lot of baseball gambling for a while.
I was never interested in going into horses at all. Never.
I did some reading on it, but I don't think I've ever been on a horse race.
Got it. Yeah, the VIG's probably pretty steep over there.
Baseball gambling is interesting case though,
because of how it relates to trading.
Okay, so in the 80s, I'm told if you knew what ERA was,
and you knew how to combine,
if one team scores four runs and one team's expected to score three,
what the probability of each one winning is,
that was enough to make money in the 80s. When I did it,
I could just take the statistics of a player for the last three years,
average them, and then run a Monte Carlo simulation between two teams.
And that was, it was free money in as much as, if you,
the hard thing was getting the bets down. I mean,
I was just getting cut off from bookies.
And there was a 10 cent bid-ask spread then, and I was making tons of money.
And by the time I finished it, there was a two cent, three cent bid-ask spread,
and I wasn't making any money at all.
That market got really efficient really quickly. Wow,
I'm surprised they didn't go out of business. After Moneyball.
Once Moneyball came out, everyone started looking at the same stuff.
You're kidding. Hey, just one. Okay,
so that's actually an interesting question. Like,
do you think these publications actually really affect edges? Oh yeah,
absolutely. I mean, that's not, that's not an opinion.
That's a demonstrated fact.
There is such a thing called alpha publication decay.
When an article is published listing an edge,
the edge pretty much drops down to between 50 and 60% of what it was.
And that happens much more quickly now,
because it used to be that a paper would be written and four years later,
it would get published. Now it's on SSRN, you know, in a day.
So that's a very big real effect.
But I think people come to the wrong conclusion from it.
They come to the conclusion that you should never read any of these papers because
there's nothing in there. I mean,
60% of something that was really good is still really good.
So I don't understand that at all.
I think you should still read as much as you can because you get ideas from stuff.
I was gonna say all the time. I mean,
maybe one in 50 papers that I skim has a good idea in it, but it's still,
it's money. Right.
And that's actually leading into a question from one of our members here,
which is how do you come up with ideas? Like,
I think a lot of retail traders and traders in general have a hard time finding
new ideas.
So what's your process there?
I don't really think I have many new ideas.
I think it's largely a matter of learning slightly more about the stuff I've been
doing for a long time. So like the variance premium,
I've pretty much been dealing with it for 20 years.
And I think the way to think about it, before you even get into statistics,
right, and measuring stuff, you have to think about the phenomena, right?
You're not a statistician. Think of yourself more as a hunter.
You want to understand your prey. So you don't wanna sort of necessarily know,
if you're hunting ducks, right,
you don't necessarily need to know the duck's blood composition or its heartbeat,
but you wanna know where it feeds. You wanna know when it's gonna sleep.
You wanna know where it flies at certain times of the day.
And that's what you should do as a trader.
You should learn about the phenomena.
And then once you got the phenomena and it's a strong enough phenomena,
then you can start quantifying it. So I'm still learning about that phenomena.
I'm still like a birdwatcher who learns more about the duck every time I go and
look at it. So I don't think I've,
I think it's very hard to come up with a genuinely new idea.
There really aren't that many ways to skin a cat. You know,
sometimes you'll find a new product that has wrinkles to it.
Like a couple of years ago, there were all these specks, right?
Specks had a really predictable life cycle and that could be really easy to trade.
And that was speck related. So sometimes that'll happen. But like with options,
coming up with something really new, pretty rare.
I think I've maybe had two new ideas and both of them turned out that other people
had had them before. I guess that's always the case, right?
Someone out there is already doing it. Pretty, well,
I had to put a caveat in half my PhD thesis because I did it independently.
But then before I submitted it, I actually found out that 15 years earlier,
some guy in some journal I'd never heard of had done it. I mean,
it wasn't exactly the same, but certainly it was a big enough overlap.
So I had to put a little sort of disclaimer in there. So yeah,
it's pretty hard to have a real new idea. Got it. Sean,
actually I just want to mention one last thing before we see what everyone else
is saying there.
This kind of goes back to, you told me like,
I remember I used to try to bug you like four years ago, sending you emails,
try to pick your brain around earnings and stuff.
And you told me like specialization is very important.
And at the time I asked you, I said like,
can I really go deep into these earnings and maybe try to find edge?
And you said like that is going to be probably better for a retail trader to really
like learn about these earnings. And those edges could last forever,
or not forever, but for a very long period of time.
So- In general, that's good advice. In that specific case,
that was terrible advice because we now found out that there's really not much to
learn.
But I, okay. So I do think in general,
specialization is probably the way to go.
You don't get paid to be a generalist.
So the best way to make money is to know as much as possible about one thing and
then just hammer on that one thing until it goes away. Like it's,
a lot of people sort of like to bang on about traders who they're out of the game
now, who only traded for five years.
But I knew guys who only traded for five years.
And then they'd made so much money, they wanted to keep trading,
but they were pit traders, say, right? And the pit went away. Yeah,
their game went away,
but they'd made so much money that it wasn't really a disaster.
And that's way better than the guys who are like, well,
I'll just make slow and steady money, blah, blah, blah, keep on going.
And that's really, that's the wrong way to do it because nothing lasts.
Once you found something that lasts, you've got to pound on it. Love that.
Hit it while it's there, right? Yeah,
particularly if you think it's an inefficiency. If it's a risk premium,
you don't have to do that because you can make a pretty good bet it will be there
forever. I mean, they come and go. They tend to come back is what I'm saying.
Whereas an inefficiency, yeah, you've got to really whack it.
Even this earnings thing, it's nowhere near as good as it used to be,
mainly because liquidity in those front weeks has really got way worse.
And I don't really understand why,
but I used to be able to put down five times as much size as I can now,
like easily.
I think also some Aussie guy wrote a book about earnings trading and that kind of
give away some of the alpha.
I was going to say something about Australians, but I'll just leave it.
You can take it as implied what I was going to say.
Sean, any questions there, Sean?
Yeah, there's a few questions,
but I think we'll go to like maybe a more general one about learning about trading,
really. Obviously with,
there's huge influx of retail traders in the last couple of years,
maybe like three, four years tops.
And with that comes this huge influx of educational resources,
of all different shapes and sizes. And in the markets,
obviously signal to noise ratio is very low,
but it seems to be the same way in the education space now. And it can,
if you had to start over again, what sort of path would you follow to learn?
How would you go about it?
Yeah, okay. So when I started our training course,
and you've got to bear in mind, this was at a medium-sized market-making firm.
This was a market-making firm that had like 30 or 40 people.
So it wasn't like two guys and a clerk. This was, we went Susquehanna,
but it was decent.
The training program largely consisted of mock trading and telling us to read Hull.
That is not the most efficient way to learn anything.
The book that I wish I'd found really early on was Beard's book called Option Market
-Making. And it still holds up today. I think it was published in like 1994,
something like that. It's a great book. That's the one thing I wish I'd found.
Because a lot of the stuff,
I sort of had to sort of piece it all together myself and kind of learn it.
It was all out there. Like if you look at volatility trading,
I don't think there's anything original in that book. I mean, it was all there.
It was just a matter of putting it all together and putting it in a logical process.
Like this is how you do a trade. You start here, you do this, you do this.
And that took me, I don't know, seven or eight years to get to that point.
So I think from that perspective,
it's easier now for people because they can basically,
there's two or three books they could read that get them a hell of a long way along
that path. Of course, you can't just read the book and know it.
It takes time for stuff to sink in. They still help.
So I think that's the big advantage people have.
The disadvantage they have is there's a lot of option education stuff that's just
complete garbage,
like actively damaging horrific things that people are being taught.
Like, it seems like in the option education space,
having like one or two years worth of experience makes you somehow a veteran.
And I kind of thought one or two years of experience and a veteran meant you were
either an athlete or a porn star. I mean,
I don't really think that trading for a couple of years means you know enough to
teach anyone else. So I think that's the hard thing.
I think you guys are doing some good stuff, to be honest.
Most people aren't. Most stuff's just terrible,
like actively damaging horrific things that say things to people that are just not
true and will cause them to lose a lot of money. And I think in most cases,
it's because the people selling it are not charlatans.
I just don't think they know what they're talking about.
Interesting. So, okay,
let's say you're one to two years into your learning about trading.
How do you know if you're learning bullshit? Like, how do you actually take,
like, do you have an idea of how you can step aside and go, wait,
how do you evaluate it? Well, you don't know. That's the problem. Yeah. I mean,
you might know if you survive and then look back.
But, okay, so I was teaching physics for a year at university.
And sometimes when I'm teaching all these first year students who are only doing
it as a med prereq, not interested, right?
I'm not particularly interested either. And I was just thinking,
what if I just start lying to them? You know,
what if I just start making up stuff about electricity? You know,
telling them that electricity, I don't know,
consists of liquid flowing in pipes and the important stuff is it's green.
Just making crap up.
And they really wouldn't have known because you're teaching them something that
they don't know. So they don't know what they don't know.
So that's the hard bit. If it was obvious you were being taught crap,
then you'd just stop listening. I don't know if there's a way around that.
What we try to do is say, learn from people who are verified.
So we tell them to learn from people like you, Aaron Brown, Augustine LeBron.
We say, read what these people have to say.
And then it kind of trains your mind to be able to pick out what's BS and what's
legit. So I feel like that's been working for us so far.
But what are your thoughts on that?
Yeah, I think certainly with those two.
Okay,
so they're a little different because they're not really teaching you about the
specifics of trading. It's more about the philosophy of trading.
Like I think Aaron's book is kind of like sitting down beside the fire with your
old uncle and he's got his pipe and he's like, all right, listen,
this is how you do this. It's kind of general advice.
And Augustine's book is phenomenal book.
And it's one of the few books that I think I appreciate now with a lot of experience.
I don't think I would have appreciated it more.
I don't think I would have gotten as much out of it as I do now.
And I think it's very rare for that because it's pretty rare that I read something
and I'm like, wow, that's wow. So I think with those guys,
it's not so much that,
I think you're getting better able to pick out bullshit because with those guys,
you're actually learning stuff. So you're actually learning this is real.
It's not just,
you're not just taking it on faith that it's because Aaron Brown said it or Emanuel
Derman said it.
But yeah, those, I think Augustine's book's amazing.
I don't think it's a really good book about trading necessarily,
but I'm not sure really.
Because he says that there are lessons for the rest of your life.
And I'm always kind of skeptical about that. It's like people are like,
if you're a good poker player, you'll become a good trader. I'm like, no,
you won't. I mean, poker's poker, trading's trading. It's like golf and tennis.
Yeah, you're both hitting something with a stick,
but they're pretty different sports, right?
So I think generally that kind of crossover is anyone who tells you that is someone
who's a poker player who's trying to convince you they can become a good trader
just because of that. But I think with those books, it's really, yeah,
they were good.
It's funny, we actually have both you and Augustine, actually,
your books are like required reading for PA.
I can see,
his book's one of those ones I think I'm gonna read every year again.
Whereas I think with a lot of options, like fundamental books,
once you've got them, you've got them. Certainly with Hull,
I haven't picked up Hull for like 20 years. Do you read any David Aaronson?
Sorry? David Aaronson. What about him? Do you read any of his books?
I've read one of his books, I thought he only had one. I read it,
I thought it was quite good. The funny thing, so he writes this huge book,
it's about 600 pages, right?
And it basically goes through and disproves every single thing about technical analysis.
It turns out the guy's really into technical analysis.
I was on a mailing list that he was on for a while and he's always posting this
technical analysis stuff, like he's really into it. Interesting. Yeah,
so it's kind of like a UFO hunter, right?
Who's said that everyone else is wrong, but by the way, I still believe it.
I've got this little Greek man who lives down in my garden.
Yeah, his book's pretty good. You know what, actually,
you should give his book, it's called the TSSB Manual. It's really,
he built a software around backtesting and it's actually a really good data science
book.
I like a ton for that book and it was actually recommended to me by a strange,
from Sergey.
So yeah, really good book,
it's a good read.
Jordan, any other questions there you wanna ask? Yeah, definitely.
So Yoon, so you mentioned,
like we were just talking about learning from people and I'm curious to know who
your mentors were growing up and when you were learning this field.
And do you think like you would have been able to pick this up quickly if you didn't
have the right mentors along your journey?
I think everyone's got this idea that there is a perfect mentor for them that they
need. I never had that one person.
There were a lot of people who taught me various things along the way that I think
were indispensable. You know, and people are like,
what trader did you learn the most from?
And I feel like I'm always meant to say something like some famous person that they've
heard of. You know, and it wasn't,
it was just some guy who I sat beside when I was trading the DAX and he was the
one who sort of yelled at me every day for a year and a half.
And I learned probably the most from market making about from that guy.
You know, and he's just a guy.
So I think there've been a lot of people along those lines,
just along the way that I've sort of picked up stuff from here and there.
And you kind of need, at each point of your career, you need someone like that.
It doesn't have to be the same person all the time,
but you kind of need someone,
even if it's just someone to go out with after work and complain about something,
or when it's been a bad day and when some guy, he's like, come on,
let's just go and get a beer. I mean, that really helps a lot.
And I don't think, I don't know if this is a different job from other jobs.
I haven't had any other jobs, but I know in this job,
it's really hard to sort of do it on your own. It's really hard.
It would really be hard to just go and live in a little mountain cabin somewhere
and figure all this out on your own. I think there's just,
it would take you too long. That's probably true of everything.
And what you say trading is a craftsmanship and the money's in the nuances?
Yeah, pretty much. I mean, I think 90,
like I think 95% of stuff you can tell other people and it doesn't make any difference
to your P&L. So people will be like, oh, well, you've written all these books,
so none of that stuff can work anymore. I'm like, well,
I didn't tell you the stuff that I thought would ruin my life. I mean,
there's plenty of stuff that I didn't tell you.
There's plenty of stuff that I didn't put in the books.
But I think most stuff that you need is actually out there.
I don't think the secret sauce is nearly as important as people think.
It'll make a difference. It'll take you from being good to really good.
But most of the stuff is relatively well understood,
but it's just spread out amongst a whole bunch of different places.
So I think it is about the details.
Got it.
Someone shared me a really interesting post where the person went on a rowing excursion
with their father.
And they said the difference between the first place boat and the last place boat
was nothing really, like it wasn't something special.
It was just like the fine details that they did a little bit better. Yeah,
I think that's true when you get to like the Olympic level where you're dealing
with everyone who's just amazingly athletic.
I don't think that's true at like the high school level.
I played sports in high school and there were a couple of guys who went on to play
for New Zealand. And it's not one of those things, ooh, he never stood out. No,
he stood out. From the age of eight, he was just way better than everyone else.
When you get to international level, I think natural talent is pretty close.
I would say that it's like with intelligence. Do you need,
there's no correlation between intelligence and trading ability once you're a professional
trader. But if you don't meet a certain bar,
you're never gonna get to that point.
So there's no difference between someone with an IQ of 110 and 180.
But if you've got an IQ of 70, you're just not gonna meet that first hurdle.
Got it. I think.
Sean, if you don't have any more questions there,
I just got one last question for you that was asked by Jens. All right,
let's let it rip.
So what are you looking at right now? What are some things that,
some strategies that are in the works or that you're working on or other areas that
you're looking into? Are you looking into crypto, crypto vols?
What's really taking up your time right now?
I've just got this equity vol thing implemented across a wide enough number of names.
So that's something I've been working on for a long time.
I have been looking at crypto a little bit.
The problem with crypto is that it's still immensely decentralized to the point
where I think it's one of those things, unless you're really into it, I mean,
you can't dabble in it to the point where you'd get a Coinbase account and buy some
Ethereum or something. That's not gonna do it.
You have to be on all these blockchains that no one's ever heard of.
And you have to be trading these ridiculous coins and getting these stupid tokens
and farming them out.
So I don't really think it's one of those things you can just do sort of half-arsed.
Whereas I think if you're just gonna do something as sort of a hobby,
the US equity market's great because you just need an IB account and then you can
pull up something and click on it. You can't do that with crypto.
And I hate all that other stuff. Yeah. I don't know.
I don't know if I've actually come across the hurdle yet to put in a big portion
of my capital into a decentralized exchange.
I wonder if that maybe creates some sort of opportunity, right? For sure.
Some of the alpha or money these guys are making is just unbelievable,
or the inefficiencies they're finding. There were, for a while, you could,
I did this,
but for a while you could make 40% just by lending out US stablecoins.
So it was literally like lending a dollar and getting 40% back. I mean,
the basis spreads on these things were ridiculous,
but that seemed to go away very quickly. It was there for years, right?
But then it went away just like that. And now it's much more difficult.
I think the crypto guys I know now are making a lot less than they did in, say,
April. There are some,
I used to think if you found a really complicated product that you understood,
that could be an edge. I'm not sure that is true anymore.
I'm not sure just knowing the product is enough to do that on its own,
but there are some crazy Bitcoin options out there. They're like,
they're called inverse options, right? So they're, it's a,
it would be a Bitcoin option where the strike is in dollars,
but it's paid out in Bitcoins. So as the Bitcoin's moving around, the amount,
not only is the amount that it's in or out of the money changing,
but the amount that you would get is changing as well in dollar terms.
So the payoff becomes really weird and nonlinear. So that kind of fun.
I did a bit of consulting on someone for that,
but I've never tried to trade them. I think Deribit lists them,
and I think Deribit has like 90% of the Bitcoin options.
So that's kind of weird because an at the money option will have like a Delta of
like one. For some of those exchanges, for some of those coins,
like those smaller cap coins? No,
for the way they've defined the option payoff. Oh. I mean, it's true.
If you look at, if Bitcoin moves by a dollar,
the value of this option changes by almost nothing because a dollar in percentage
terms is minimal because Bitcoin's like, I don't know, what is it?
45,000 bucks or something. And that's what it means for a Delta. So yeah,
the Delta of an at the money option because everything's in percentage terms.
So that's kind of fun,
but I've never actually tried to make money trading them.
That could be interesting space.
There's like so many products that are being pushed out like almost every day now.
Yeah. Sorry, go on. What's up with that equity ball?
Do you mind maybe just chatting a little bit about it? Sure.
What do you want to know about it? Well,
you just mentioned like you're working to make equity ball strategy right now.
What's the basis of the idea? Okay. So maybe 15 years ago,
you could make money just by doing like a GARCH forecast of to forecast the vol
for every stock that had options on it.
Calculate what you thought the variance premium was, buy all the cheap stuff,
sell all the expensive stuff. And you'd make, you know, 20% a year doing that.
Now, I'm not saying it's impossible to forecast volatility,
but it's really difficult to the point where it might not be worth the effort of
doing it, even if it is possible to do it.
But the relative value of options is still all over the place.
So I'm not trying to forecast the level of the implied vol.
I'm forecasting basically the shape of the curve.
So I'd end up doing a lot of butterflies, basically.
And is that,
are you doing a butterfly across the term structure or across the expiration?
Across strike, okay. Yeah. So like, there'll be a lot of things where I'll,
you know, all the other way around,
like I'll be long at the monies and then short the 10 delta options. Got it.
Possibly in some sort of ratio, but that's sort of, yeah,
it's relative option pricing.
I think there's more edge in relative option pricing than absolute.
You've got to do a lot more. You've got to do a lot more things though,
because the actual edge, once you've got all these spreads on, is smaller,
because, you know, it just is.
And do you just mind breaking down what do you mean by better trades in absolute
versus, or better trades in relative versus absolute? Yeah,
I think it's very difficult now to value an at the money option.
Like if the implied vol of an at the money option is 18,
it's really difficult to come up with any better value from that. Look,
if you take out the variance premium, so you can actually do that, right?
You can say the average variance premium has been this.
There's a lot of work you could do on that.
But let's say the implied vol is 18. Correcting for the variance premium,
your forecast is 16. That's, the edge in that now is really small.
Those trades are probably not worth doing on their own in most cases.
Not all cases, but most. But certainly there are tons of cases where, okay,
so right now,
if you look at the NASDAQ structure,
NASDAQ is begging to have a trade put on where you sell the NASDAQ 10 delta puts
and you buy constituent 10 delta puts.
Because there's a ton of single stock options in there that basically have a flat
vol structure. So you look at something like Intel.
Intel puts are basically trading flat to the at the monies.
And there's a whole bunch of them like that.
Mega cap tech puts right now are really cheap. Interesting. Yeah,
so there's stuff like that. But normally I don't even do it across,
I wouldn't do it like a dispersion thing. I'll just do it within Intel.
So if I make that observation,
I'll just buy the at the monies and sell the puts. Got it.
I guess you could go the other way around. Sell the puts,
buy the at the monies. Because the term structure is flat, right.
I guess with those kinds of trades, you can get some pretty good size on,
right? Because it's super liquid and it's not too much risk to that.
What do you think about that? Some of these things,
I like to trade in the really short dated options for a couple of reasons.
We've gone into the edge reason, but there's also, you get better feedback.
Because if I'm trading weekly options, I'm doing like 52 trades a year.
If I'm trading monthly, I'm only doing 12.
So I get to know if I'm doing well or not much quicker, which is a huge plus.
So I would say there's maybe 300 stocks I can do this kind of trade on.
So that's pretty liquid. But there's still transaction costs,
but the other thing about weeklies is I very rarely trade out of them.
Just have them for a week and let them expire. Yeah.
Cool. That's one way of halving your transaction costs.
Sean, anything else you wanna add there in the week? Yeah,
I got two more questions for you here.
So coming back to reading SSRN articles and things of that nature,
do you think it's worth spending a lot of time going through that type of stuff?
And with the volume there and everything,
do you try to read every abstract or could you recommend like,
do you do like a certain keyword search, anything of that nature to filter?
Yeah.
Okay, so we were talking about shitty advice, like terrible advice.
There's one of the worst pieces of advice that people get told is you've got to
find a way of trading that suits your personality, okay?
That is one of the dumbest things I've ever heard. If you wanna learn golf,
no one's gonna tell you,
find a way of playing golf that suits your personality.
What you're gonna do is you're gonna get the best coach you can and they will teach
you how to actually play. Trading's like that as well.
If it turns out that the shit you like loses money,
you liking it isn't gonna change that.
So that's one of the problems people have with buying options. They're like,
I like to buy options. Well, that's great. You also like to lose money.
Do you not like money? Then great, keep buying options.
So I'm not telling you that I do this because it's the way that works for me,
but there's certainly an element of that involved in this as well, right?
So in the research process, I think you can say that.
I learn a lot from going through the archive in SSRN.
The archive less than I used to because now it's all about machine learning stuff.
And those papers just aren't very good to read because it's always like,
I tried to predict the fixed term structure.
So I threw all this data into a black box and then I got these numbers out.
You're like, well, what do I do with that? But anyway, yeah,
I look at SSRN maybe a couple of times a week and I look at the JEL classification
for general financial markets, which I think is J1, sorry, G1.
And I do a keyword search for volatility and for options and for trading.
And normally I'll look as a result of that at maybe 20 abstracts a week.
And of those, I might read the introduction and conclusion of five.
I'll probably only read one full paper every month or so. There's a lot of,
it's fishing. You throw a lot of lines out and nothing comes back,
but occasionally something does.
I'm sure everyone here knows about the Uvexy decay trade, right?
All that stuff on leveraged ETFs was published way before people were actually doing
it.
So there's a lot of great stuff on leveraged ETFs out there that's been published.
You know what you might find interesting, Yoon,
is there's like four and five X leveraged ETFs,
ETNs in Europe that I haven't looked into it too much,
but it could be a nice potential pairs trade for the decay.
I don't know if that's a real thing or not.
I was having a debate with my buddy. You don't know which bit's a real thing.
So let's say for example, going to short TQQQ and SQQQ. You know,
Delta hedging every so often. I mean, that used to work.
Actually,
TQQQ is about the only one that wouldn't have worked on because that thing's just
skyrocketed, but it works. If you put a portfolio together of long, short,
so you're directionally neutral,
it worked apart from when you took borrow costs into account and then it wouldn't
work. But in theory, that works. I don't know about these European ones.
It's hard to trade European stuff as a non-institutional customer. Yeah,
they have all those exotics over there that you can buy as a retail client,
but IBKR won't let you sell them. And like the edges on them are huge,
but just being sold by banks.
It's actually pretty easy to replicate a leveraged ETF of anything you want because
you know what they have to do.
So basically you just do the opposite because you're shorting it.
You do the opposite trading that they do.
And it all basically comes down to a sort of, that's complicated,
but it's an autocorrelation trade. It's basically a vol pump.
So you can do it yourself.
Like if you wanted to replicate your own 20 times leveraged ETF,
you could do it up to the level of what you can borrow from your broker.
But doing a three times leveraged one would be easy.
So you can do it on anything you like, really. So there you go.
If you're mad that Uvexy isn't two times levered anymore,
just do a bit of math and do it yourself. Yeah, got it. Got it.
Arshad, if there's nothing else there,
I got a lot of other questions here from the guys as well. Yeah,
I feel bad because I know there's like a hundred and something comments in the chat,
which I've only just noticed.
And we probably haven't got to most of those questions,
but I also feel that's somewhat inevitable. A hundred percent.
You and the guys love you, man. The guys love you in this group.
So if you ever have spare time,
we'd love to have you answer some questions in there. Well,
they might only love me because they haven't met me.
I think someone asked me once how you know,
I think my only differentiating skill is I'm pretty self-aware about what I do and
don't know. So, you know, the whole Dunning-Kruger thing,
I think I'm relatively good at avoiding that,
but I think that's the only thing.
I'm pretty good at saying something if I don't know it.
So I think that's my plus.
Got it. Let's do another one of these sometime. Yeah, a hundred percent. Yeah,
as soon as I get my air conditioning working up here next time. So I'm not...
Yeah, so you can take the pressure from all the questions, right? Yeah,
that's the excuse.
I just said the air conditioning was off and it's really just... So funny,
it's like next time we have this, Yun comes, she's shirtless.
I feel like I should have been. This is ridiculous. Thanks a lot, guys.
I guess I'll... No, thank you. I'll turn up on Discord again.
Does anyone like Discord? What a garbage platform that is. Oh,
you're kidding me. I think the layout and stuff,
I think Slack's better and I hate Slack as well. I gotta disagree.
I think it's the best chat messaging platform out, man. Telegram's all right.
Telegram's pretty good. Oh, you know, maybe I'm just old. Maybe I'm like,
I don't understand these kids with all their platforms. I was gonna say...
Why can't we just use SMS messages? I was gonna say,
you're not a fan of all the Pepe emojis and everything?
I just can't navigate the threads. Whatever.
That's where the best conversation's going down.
You gotta figure that part out. I haven't spent a great amount of time on it,
but it could be also...
I think inevitably you reach this age where you're just like, ah, technology,
fuck it.
It was funny today. I was telling Sean, I was like, hey,
I don't think Yoon really likes me that much.
He's never answering me in the Discord. And Sean's like,
I just don't think he understands how to navigate it. Well, and I also... Yeah,
that could be it. But I don't go on there that much either. I mean,
if people actually want to ask me stuff,
you're probably better off DMing me on Twitter.
That's probably an easier way to do it. Well,
I will say that I've gotten some DMs.
The guys really appreciate you when you do pop in and share your thoughts on their
questions, things like that. It's been good. Great. Well,
I'm glad I helped someone. You having a couple more beers tonight? Me? Yeah.
I haven't had any. You're the ones who've been drinking.
What were you drinking? That was like a LaCroix or something. Yeah,
it was just a water.
It looks like a grapefruit IPA, right? Yeah, as he said, the old,
it's not vodka, it's water trick. Okay.
All right, guys. All right. Well, thanks. Have a great night. Yeah,
have a great night. This was awesome. Thank you. See you, Sean. Talk soon.