How's it going, everyone? In today's live,
we're going to be chatting about the borrow rate and how to find it.
And what does it mean? What does the borrow rate mean? And also,
how to synthetically short shares when there's none to borrow. You know,
we hear this all the time. Oh, you know, I really want to short this stock,
but I can't borrow it. Right? And so, as traders,
we always got to try to find workarounds. Right? And so,
there's lots of ways that we can do that. So,
that's what we're going to be talking about in tonight's live. Oh, wow. Pulumi,
what's up, man? What's up, dude? Haven't seen you in a while. Okay. So,
let's jump right into it. So,
we're going to actually be talking about a couple of the hype stocks just because
we are seeing it there. Okay? So, let's jump right into it right now.
So, let's take a look at GME. Okay, here's GME.
And, whoa.
Sorry, guys. I haven't seen GME today.
Sean, did you know this? What happened? That it's trading at this high?
I didn't know it got to $3.80 now.
Okay. So, when we look at GME, guys, you know what's moving after hours.
We're just going to mess our data up. So,
let me just pull that up real quick and we can see it. Okay,
so GME closed at $3.45. Okay, so GME closed at $3.45. So,
let's go over to this. We'll go over to the 350 strike here. Now,
what do we notice about this 350 strike? Well,
one thing that I noticed right off the bat is that these puts are trading $20 more
than these same equivalent calls. Right? Do you guys notice that?
That the ask here is $1.87. The ask here is $2.04. The bid is $1.72.
And the bid here is $1.65. It's trading so much more than, you know,
the puts are trading so much more than the calls. Now,
let's take a look at something like Apple, for example.
So, let me just make sure Apple doesn't have some… Wow.
So, Apple closed at $1.42.55. So, if we go to $1.42,
well,
what we notice is that basically the mid here of this option is going to be very
similar to the mid of this option. Right?
We can see $1.42 trading at the mid at $7.95.
And the mid over here is trading at $7.70. Okay? So,
they're trading almost exactly the same.
Now, what is causing that? Right?
What is causing that GME to have such a big difference? Okay? Well, Jordan,
maybe, you know, we need to mention something here because… Well, maybe,
why is Apple so different from GME? Right? Why is GME the different one? Right?
What do we normally see? Yes.
What we normally see is that the Apple money strikes should be trading the same
extrinsic value. Okay? Why is that?
And if they weren't trading at extrinsic value,
there could be an arbitrage done. Right? You could basically sell the put,
buy the call, and then short shares.
And we're going to talk about that as we go through with the borrow cost. So,
here's a quick example. Let's say we want to put on this risk reversal. Okay?
So, someone might come in here and say, Oh, look.
What do we say? $3.50. Oh, look. There's an arbitrage. Right?
I can buy these for, you know, $170 and sell these for $200. Same strike.
Right? Let's take a look.
So, we're going to buy the calls and we're going to sell the puts.
I think there's some data really messing this up here.
Let's see if we can do it on AMC here.
Anyways, this will cost us about,
okay. What we can see here right away is that, look at our P&L. Right?
We are all the way back here. Okay. So, the stock's trading at $3.40. Oh,
that's why.
So, the stock's trading at $3.50.
Guys, you know what? We can't do it with this. The data is just too bad.
Do you want to try one more stock?
It's only with AMC and GME that we're seeing this. Plus,
it's after-hours data that's messing up the whole thing. Okay, draw it. Yeah.
Go forward in time so it comes off the graph. Or, go back.
Here's what you can do.
Go forward in time so that it disappears off the thing.
Oh, I like that. Good idea. Oops. Okay, keep going.
Okay, go forward again. Keep going. Will it disappear completely?
Alright, drop it to $0 for $0.01. I can actually increase it here.
You could basically come into the market here, sell the put, buy the call,
and GME's trading at $3.47, but our break-even is $3.25.
When we buy the stock, what does it look like? Right? When we buy the stock,
our break-even starts at $3.47.
Right? But look at this. So, if we buy Apple at $100 and it goes to $99,
we lose $1. But with this combo,
GME's trading at $3.47, but we can buy it at $3.25.
There's an issue here. Right? We could arbitrage this way, obviously.
We can just sell some shares and create a perfect arbitrage. Right?
Where P&L starts at $22,000.
However,
the reason why this is existing on GME stock is because everyone is short the stock.
Okay? Everyone is selling this stock. And so, for that reason,
the borrow rate is increasing. Right? The cost to borrow this thing,
it's getting hard to borrow. And so, if I'm going to lend my shares out,
I'm going to charge a huge premium. Because no one else is giving it up. Right?
So, if I give them up, I'm going to charge you a huge premium.
And that is why we see this in GME. It's because of that borrow cost.
The cost to borrow these shares. If I'm going to short these shares,
right? If I'm going to short these shares, well,
it's going to cost me $22,000 during that period. Right?
And that's why we're seeing this, you know, plus $22,000.
So, always remember that when we're coming into trading, you know,
people might say, you know, it's hard to borrow, I can't short the shares.
We can synthetically replicate those shares by creating this risk reversal.
Okay?
But instead, we sell the calls and buy the puts. Okay?
We sell the calls and buy the puts. But now, look at what's happening here.
We are now shorting the shares at $325. But the stock is trading at $347.
And that is simply just because of the borrow rate.
How the cost for you to be able to short those shares, right? Every single day,
if you're going to borrow someone shares, you have to pay them money. Right?
Every single day,
money's going to come out of your account that you have to pay the owners of those
shares. And this is what we are seeing here. Because that's, you know,
you're loaning them. Right? Whenever you loan anything, you know,
you're paying interest.
It's what makes it worth it for the other person to loan it.
Exactly. How is that rate determined?
It's strictly determined just by how many sellers there are.
It's simply the market dynamics. Supply and demand, right?
If there's 50 million shares to go around,
then I know everybody is trying to sell these things. Well, if I'm the buyer,
I'm just going to be like, well, you're going to have to pay up. Exactly.
Right? And so the more and more people that come and try and short this thing,
the more and more we're going to see this happening. Right?
Where it's not easy to short. Right? Think about what's happening here.
The market's telling us that they think the stock is going to go down to 325.
At least.
And it's a no-brainer that eventually that this stock is going to go back down.
Right? And so, well, everyone's trying to do it.
And it's just getting harder and harder and harder. Right?
I would love to go and buy these puts. Right?
I would love to go and buy some 260 puts.
Guess what?
They're trading at such a premium because of that borrow cost being embedded into
that option. Right? It's easier to buy a call option. Let's see, 260.
So remember, this is at, so the stock was trading at 350. Okay,
so a 260 call option would be equivalent to,
I guess because of the volatility. Oh, this stock is so,
it's really out of whack. But it'd be basically equivalent to, you know,
buying a lot closer option. Okay? In terms of volatility.
So I know the data kind of, you know, messes up a little bit here, guys.
You know, the after hours data, GME being down 50 bucks after hours,
kind of messed with the data. But if you guys have any questions about this,
maybe you guys asking me questions can help me, you know,
really explain this a lot better. Yeah, Jordan,
I think while we're waiting for questions here, without using the live,
like take off the screen for a second. Just like explain it,
like try and walk through like, you know, what we're looking at here, right?
And why it's a value to look at.
So what we're looking at here is the borrow rate. Okay?
How much it costs to borrow the shares if you want to short them. Now, yeah,
if you want to short these shares, right?
It's a no-brainer that in the long run, this thing is going to go down.
And you can do that through buying puts, through shorting shares.
But the issue is everyone wants to do it, right? You might, you know,
there might, you might think, oh, everyone's buying these call options,
but there are a lot of people betting against this stock, right?
A lot of hedge funds, a lot of big money, not the small money,
but the big money betting against this thing.
And so that's going to drive up this borrow rate,
especially because there's no shares. There's 50 million shares.
So for that reason, the borrow rate,
the cost to borrow these shares are going to be very expensive.
And we can actually determine that rate by looking at the synthetic short shares,
which is the same as selling the call and buying a put on the same strike.
You are creating short shares. Okay, there's zero difference.
If there's a zero, if there's anything more than a zero difference,
an arbitrage exists, okay? Risk-free money exists. So Jordan,
when you look at the synthetic short shares,
how do you use that to determine the borrow rate? So in this case, you take,
so let me just show an example here.
So in this case, let's say it was $25,
okay? When we added up the puts and the calls, we got a credit of $25, okay,
for going long these shares. Well, you take $25, okay?
You divide it by however much notional value there is.
So let's say for example, it was $25 for 10 contracts,
which is 10 times about 350,000, okay? But obviously in option terms, 3,000,
here, 3 would be 350. It would be 2,500 over 350,000.
And so this would give us a number like 8% or, Sean, do you want to go here?
Let me pull up the math super quick.
It wouldn't be 8%. You want to fix that 2? It looks like a 7. Oh, it's 25,000,
not 2,500. Sorry, guys.
25,000 over 350,000, which would be about 8%, okay? But this is 8% in 15 days.
So you would make 8% in 15 days,
right? Well, how many days are there in a year? Well, 365.
You just have to compound that out, right? So 365 divided by 15, right?
And that equals 2.
Sorry, Jordan. I can't help out. My phone's not in the room. That's okay, dude.
So equals to 24,
okay? So we have 24 periods of this 8%, right?
So we just do 1.08 to the power of 24.
Cool. It's saying it's 171.
So there it is. 171% to borrow these shares per year.
And I think it's a lot higher. The after-hour data isn't good,
but I think this number is actually a lot higher.
I think it's a lot closer to 3,500. 3,500 on a 350,000 notional.
So finish your thought.
I'm just going to follow up with some questions to dig a little deeper.
So it's going to be roughly about 250% a year to short these shares.
So how is it above 100%? Like what happens here?
In terms of how can it be above 100%? Oh, is there a spider on the laptop?
On the screen? Yeah, there is. It just crawled over the webcam.
One thing about these mosquitoes down here is they're fast, man.
They're so fast. Yeah, and dude, you're sleeping outside.
Do you have a mosquito net on your bed? No, this is where I'm sleeping.
You're sleeping in the jungle. Okay, I get it. Okay.
So when somebody just goes to short shares,
do they not typically know the borrow rate?
Do most people who short shares not know this? Yeah, probably not.
Probably not, to be honest. How are you charged it?
It's just going to come out. Comes out of your margin, out of your account.
Out of your account, right?
The owners are going to ask for it and the brokerage is just going to grab it from
you. Is it billed daily, weekly, monthly? Every single day.
Every single day money will come out of your account. Wow.
So is this the only way to see the borrow rate? Can you call your brokerage?
Like how would somebody who doesn't know about options go about figuring this out?
Some brokerages quote it. You probably have to give them a call and say, hey,
what's the borrow rate? You know, for example, Aria on E-Trade,
he said that he had to call them. Wow. Right? Yeah,
so you have to call the brokerage or some of them have it,
but you can always just get it by pricing out the synthetic.
So how do you put yourself in a spot to be shorting your shares?
Let's say you hold a bunch of GME shares and you want to put them up for short.
Yep. So some brokers will allow you to be in that program. I know IB allows it,
but the thing is though they take a huge, huge chunk out of it.
So if you want that borrow rate, well,
what you could do is you could create the synthetic long.
If you want exposure to the GME borrow cost, you know, the 250% annually,
which is fantastic. Well, you can just buy the shares.
So, sorry, sorry, buy the synthetic.
Okay. And then let's say someone's sitting here thinking, you know, okay,
shorting shares sounds pretty cool.
Why don't I just buy some GME and short it out and I can make some income?
Well, because the broker is going to take a huge chunk of that.
A huge chunk of that borrow rate. So if you want the borrow rate,
it makes sense to do the synthetic.
I'm just trying to think if I can ask you any other trickier,
tricky kind of questions, you know, messy out maybe.
Anyone else have a question? Any questions guys?
How can over 100% of the float be shorted?
That's a good question that I do not have the answer for. Ah,
you got him Steve. Yeah, Steve. I don't have the answer for that one, dude.
Unless, you know, a couple things that could be bad data. Maybe there could be,
you know, some prop bets happening.
I don't really know how you could short shares that aren't available.
But maybe there is one. Is the synthetic more risky than shorting the shares?
No, same thing. It's the same exact same thing. If there was any difference,
you could arbitrage.
If the synthetic was different from the shorting of the shares,
you could create an arbitrage.
And there's been times where like, you know, back when we were looking at NKLA,
for example, where it actually was there, you just couldn't get the shares.
Which is really, really interesting.
So, any other questions here? It's not a very long live tonight, guys.
You know, it's just, you know,
every night the goal is really to go over a topic. You know,
we're compounding out our knowledge here, right? So, you know,
I know we had a little bit of trouble with the brokerage that kind of put a wrench
in our demonstration of it. But, you know,
we still want everyone here to walk away with the knowledge about the borrow rate.
So, please make sure to ask questions here. We'll give it another minute.
But besides that, that is the lesson for tonight.
So, ask away.
Yeah, if there's no more questions. Back straight up against that.
Sylvain. Sylvain's asking like, is synthetic, you know,
is synthetics a golden topic? No, not really, Sylvain. I mean,
you guys do synthetics all the time, right? Maybe you just don't know it.
You know,
the iron condor that we teach about in PA is just a synthetic butterfly. Right?
Synthetic just means replicating with other things. Right? So, for example,
synthetic leather shoe. You know,
you're creating this leather with something else that's not leather.
If you look at a butterfly versus an iron condor that we teach at PA, well,
they're the same structure. One is just a synthetic. Right? So,
you can do a lot of things. Like, for example,
doing a covered call is a synthetic short put. You know, I always hear,
you know, one of the questions I love asking people is I say, hey,
when they sell covered calls, I say, hey, would you sell a naked put?
And they say, no, too risky. Because that's way too risky for me. Well,
the short put is the same thing as a covered call. Right? So,
we do synthetics all the time.
Maybe it's just a bigger word. But it's really we do them all the time.
Now, Kiko is asking, can we do the box with GME?
So, Koaw, always remember, dude. Always remember. If an arbitrage exists,
it will almost always be taken advantage of until it dries up. Now,
as we both know, it does happen.
But it's not going to be like the box is going to be a moneymaker going forward.
There's nothing special about a box. It's used for certain things. For example,
extracting out a dividend. It's used for getting the interest rate. Right?
Because an option has interest rate baked into the price of them. Right?
It's part of the Black-Scholes model. And so,
the box is a way to get that LIBOR rate. But there's nothing special about it.
And then Eric has probably the best question of the night, which is,
did you pay extra for the lights tonight? Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Or did you just find the light switch? Yeah. No, no, no.
I think one of the guys came back and they were on. Wait, what?
I just came back and they were working. Wait,
so they were there before they weren't working? No, you know what?
I don't think they were even here, to be honest.
Because now I just click on the switch that I use all the time.
And now it works. But the plumbers here are super nice.
And I think he just helped me out. Yeah, Eric.
I'm thinking it's all the rum as well. Guys, I didn't have one drop today.
I'm so pissed. I had one fucking drop. Right after this live,
I'm going to fucking chug a whole 60.
Yeah, you couldn't button switch last night. That's funny.
That's why the lights work today. Yeah, exactly.
Stephen's asking, what is the box? It's for a different topic, Stephen,
but super simple. You just do a vertical on either side of the market.
We can talk about that maybe tomorrow's live. Yeah, yeah, we can do that.
We can do it. No problem. I'm sure Stephen wants to look into it tonight.
Stephen, it's just like you can Google it.
It's just putting a vertical spread on both sides of the market.
So it looks like this.
All right, everyone. That is the topic for tonight.
Kalumi, it was good to see you out here, man. Lawrence, good to see you guys.
Kalumi's asleep. He accidentally dropped in. Slip of the finger. All right,
take it easy. See you guys.