Neil how's it going, buddy?
Good. Good doing good.
Um, I did a couple today. I did a couple today But nothing too exciting.
I Actually closed out on the BMO, but let's see here.
Let's see what we got One second, you'll just get this all set up,
buddy Okay Hey, you know, are you there?
Can you hear my screen if I if I press play?
Okay,
do you remember how to do that because I want to share a video that I made with
you guys Cuz it was during real-time hours Okay.
Oh Yeah, okay. I got it. I got it. I got it,
but I might I might have to exit I'll come back in after I show you the video Okay
Okay. Tell me if you can hear it now. Let me go.
Let me drop this down to level to normal speed here And crank that up. Okay,
tell me if you can hear Yeah,
perfect What do you mean I for discord yeah,
I had to choose a different setting Okay, guys, let's jump into it.
So Sean is not gonna be here today.
So it's just me hosting the lecture we're gonna be talking about market making microstructure
and You know try to give you guys more understanding of how this how the markets
actually working,
you know You're always in there placing orders buying and selling and if you can
understand how this how this whole thing is working Of course, you know,
it's so complex,
but if you can get a general grasp of how this thing is working Then you can do
better going forward right remember strategies change right markets change strategies
change straight change And so you have to be fully equipped to be able to take on
new events that come up Okay, and by understanding how markets work,
you can obviously be more equipped to do that.
Keep in mind guys This is a silver course. So a silver lecture.
So I'm assuming that A Lot of you guys already know what I'm gonna be talking about
some of the words. I'm going to be using and So for the bronze guys,
if you don't understand it,
that's totally fine These are all being recorded and you can work your way up to
to silver eventually All right.
So let's jump into it's great to see a nice little turnout here so what we're gonna
start with guys is We're gonna be talking about Working orders,
okay So I know sometimes you guys see me,
you know I've heard like a hundred lots and it's like I've been doing it all day
trying to get filled But I spent three hours trying to get filled and let's say
I'm trading an illiquid market it like takes up my whole day right or 150 lots and
There's a reason for it. Okay,
I'm gonna go over here and show you what usually I'm doing because so not all the
time I'm trading in liquid markets,
but sometimes I am trading illiquid markets and we're gonna go over why sometimes
I trade them and What's really happening with the market makers here? Okay,
so just wanna make sure everyone can see my screen if you can't see my screen Just
comment down below. I know we've got some new guys here.
Let me open up the Let me open up the live recordings Okay So yeah,
if you guys you have a question write down in the live record in the live chat Write
it down in the live chat just above this video and I'll be able to to see it there
Okay,
I usually have Sean checking that for me so if I don't get to it right away,
sorry about that guys So what we see here is here's an option chain. Okay,
so I'm in my interactive brokers account and here's an option chain I'm looking
at QSR and We're I'm getting quoted the bids and being quoted on the ask,
right?
So there's a market maker behind this screen who has a fair price for volatility
and he's pricing on both sides Okay,
so this is probably TD Bank right now Right,
so you can go in and see on the exchange who is who are the big market makers?
So,
you know in the in the equities markets is usually Citadel or Susquehanna But in
the Canadian market it is let's say TD. Okay,
there's actually only four market makers in in Canada Okay,
so here we're gonna see So if we're looking if we're looking right over here,
for example, the market maker is quoting.
So let's look at the 64 option He's quoting the bid at 35 cents and the ask at $3
and 30 cents So what that means is he's willing to buy at 35 cents and he's willing
to sell at $3 and 30 cents Now this is so wide.
This market is so wide and basically, you know,
my edge is gonna be gone If I'm trying to trade in this thing,
right if I think balls under price, for example,
my edge is gonna be gone So I have to try to you know,
I have to try to find find a way to get this in market maker to take my order Okay.
Yeah Yeah Sure, it's it's pretty much full screen on my end.
Let me see here mark. Let me see That's the best I can do Yeah,
that's good guys. Okay, perfect. Okay for some reason on my screen.
It looks like it's almost full screen I don't know why but anyways It's full screen
now. So We can see it.
We're all good so market makers quoting a bid and he's quoting an ask right and
What he's saying here is fair value is somewhere in between So this is a first off.
This is a very illiquid option chain very illiquid and he's saying Fair value to
him is somewhere in between this number Okay,
so if we're looking at the 35 cents and $3.30,
it's somewhere in this number and what he's doing is he's putting 20 lots on the
bid Okay, so if I put in a market order for 20 lots I'd get filled instantly,
okay, he has 20 lots there He also has 20 lots on the ask Okay.
So if I want to went to buy this I get 20 I get filled 20 lots right away And then
we don't know what come in behind that so this is We'll say this is one market maker
now. I Need to get a better film. Okay,
when you're treating an illiquid market, it's really tough.
Look at this We got the open interest is three Okay,
the open interest here is 19 Very illiquid.
So what you can do is You can come in and start pushing the market maker down.
Okay,
so I'm gonna do this live here for you guys So we're going to be trading the 72.
So the 72 is trading at $6. Okay,
so he's trading at six bucks So right now his ask is six Okay,
so I put in my order for $5.95 and he jumped me You see that he went from six to
five ninety and now he's quoting ten Okay,
so we're gonna keep it going So here he goes again. He jumps me again,
right and he's actually quoting his whole lot 20 lots right,
so this is think about it like The market maker is he's sitting there and he's saying
well if you give me 20 slices of pizza Okay,
like so this is the supply demand right if you give me 20 slices of pizza I'm satisfied.
I was craving pizza. And now I got 20.
I'm happy now once you're full the next 20 slices of pizza They don't taste as good
anymore Right.
So if I ding that 580 he all of a sudden he just ate the 20 slices of pizza and
now he's gonna move his market To show that right. He's gonna widen his spread.
Maybe he's gonna go 590 or $6.
So we're gonna keep bringing this guy down Right,
so we can just keep bringing him down bringing him down bringing him down until
there's a point There's a threshold where he's gonna knock him down anymore.
I Didn't do it in this video, but eventually he starts to join me.
So we go from let's say we go down to $5 now Instead of so let's say he's quoting.
Okay. So for example, let's say he's quoting 570 here.
I come in at 565 He's not gonna jump me and go to 560 Instead he's gonna join me
He's gonna join me at 565 Okay,
so let's say I quote a one lot and he's quoting 20 it's gonna go from I'm gonna
go at 565.
He's gonna join me So it's gonna be 21 lots at the ask and because I'm a retail
trader I get first dibs So if someone comes in and buys the option,
I would get first dibs on the sell before him Okay,
so this is this is this is how this game works So do you guys have any questions
about that?
Because we're gonna we're gonna keep going deeper It's because I'm a retail I have
preference It's just the rules so That is correct.
If you if you were in a market maker So let's say it's you and me Neil that come
into the market and you were there first you'd get first dibs over me Okay,
but it's I can't remember the rule.
It's a Mark my nose better than me if you still if he does it's um I'll find it
for you Neil and I'll send it to you. But there for most exchanges.
There's a rule where The client gets the order before you do Okay Gotcha.
Perfect. Thanks mark. Okay,
so you're gonna so you're gonna get filled first Okay, Neil Yeah And then yeah,
yeah jump in there Mm
-hmm.
Yeah,
and I think those are called A Price improvers because there's like there's sometimes
maybe not in super liquid markets,
but there's sometimes hidden liquidity where you get filled at the mid right Yeah
Mm-hmm.
No, no, no mark, you know, it's uh,
I think you have a little bit of your pretty knowledge on this Microstructure stuff.
So if you want to chime in go for it Awesome,
great So, yeah, so but if you guys can see here What's happening there? Right?
We have the market maker.
He's sitting on the bid and if I wanted to come in now for 20 lots I just got 30
cents better than when I first started right? It was five.
It's 570 rather than six dollars Now sometimes there is hidden liquidity that you
don't see But when you get into really really illiquid markets Usually there actually
is no hidden liquidity and I'm gonna explain what's happening here Okay,
so first off the less liquid you go the less market makers there are right thing
boys as um, if there's more competition Right,
and obviously what drives the competition is the volume but there's more competition
Then you're gonna have more market makers participating if you have less Competent
competition, right?
You're gonna have wider spreads and you're not gonna have people trying to get in
and out in between Right,
and so that's that's why we're seeing such widespread in In this market because
on this exchange really have four market makers that are you know Maybe not the
most sophisticated when we go on to something like, you know in the u.s.
Where we have extremely efficient exchanges with Citadel and Susquehanna running
the show over there, you know,
you're gonna have nice tight spreads And then also something in Canada as well is
that you can't have You have to be a designated market maker,
so you can't let's say I'm You know,
let's say I have enough money and I decide to quote both sides.
I can't do that Right.
I can't actually even apply to the exchange to become a market maker so I can quote
both sides of my broker but in the States you have a lot more competition and that's
why you're seeing like Let's like something on Apple. For example,
there's a lot of retail volume as well.
The spreads are so tight So when you guys are Eventually at some point in your careers,
you guys are gonna say like I wish I knew something about liquidity So this is why
we're going through that right now because it's so important,
especially if you find a stock that's you know mispriced Right option that's mispriced,
but the spreads are too wide. Can you work a better order?
Can you work in order to get a better price? Okay,
so usually was on something like Apple Amazon Facebook SPY You don't need to worry
about this stuff,
but when you get less liquid Right when you're trading a two billion dollar You
know company that only has a couple hundred lots traded a day.
This stuff becomes important Right understanding how micro structures working So
do you guys have any questions about that?
Okay, nice. So we're gonna continue here so Okay, so what's happening here?
So let's open up.
So let's get rid of this video here So what it what's happening here?
well We said the market maker We said the market maker can only have let's say a
few slices of a pizza before he starts changing his order Okay so Yeah,
oh That's right. Thanks, man. Thanks for that. Okay. Okay guys,
I think pop pop pop it right back in Okay,
perfect.
I'll set the other guys jump in give it a sec No, it's good. It's good.
It's good It's good Okay,
I'll give one more second and then we'll get to it So let's say you come into the
market And you want to buy this? 320 call Okay on on NVDA you want to buy this?
Okay.
So here's your call Here's your call on NVDA now How is that what's gonna happen
here? Right? How is the market maker gonna make money?
Now 95% of the time guys, we're gonna be interacting with a market maker Okay,
if you I'd say more than that 90 98% of the time we're gonna be interacting with
a market maker So it's under it's important to understand what's happening here
So let's say you want to come in and buy this now the market maker is gonna say
He's gonna have to hold this position if he can't find a seller right especially
in an illiquid market Okay,
pretend we're in a liquid market still He can't go and find a seller He has to yes,
he's gonna sell you this option.
So you're buying it He gets to sell you this option and now he has to hold inventory
Okay, that's that's not what he wants Right.
He wants to market maker wants to remain neutral at all times I know a lot of people
say like all the market makers are out to get me guys market makers are not out
to get You okay.
Their sole job is to provide liquidity quote the bid quote the ask and collect a
spread every time They love high volatility high volume scenarios, okay,
we're widespread and lots of volume they love it That's their sole job Okay,
they're not taking a view on volatility.
They're not taking a view on direction of the stock Okay,
they're solely trying to quote you and sure they can have alpha strategies in-house
But that that that's beyond the point and besides the point So you want to come
and buy this call?
now what the market maker is gonna do is If he can't find if he can't if he can't
buy it from you for three dollars and sell it to To Neal for three dollars and ten
cents if he can't do that.
He has to take inventory So this is what's gonna happen.
You're he's gonna charge you an extra five cents. Let's say Okay,
and then what he's gonna go and do is he is going to create that exact same call
through a synthetic Okay, so this way is what he's gonna do.
He's going to buy the stock Okay So just make sure guys,
here's our call Okay He's gonna buy the stock And then he's gonna buy a put Look
at that He just synthetically created our call. It's the exact same trade.
There's the call there's the call you just bought and There's the since that there
is the synthetic Okay,
so he now he has a riskless position and he just charged you five cents Extra Okay,
so you are because as a trader we're okay.
Sometimes giving up that five cents to make a trade Right.
Our objective is to make is to turn this $30 call into a $60 call Right over let's
say a week or two weeks or three weeks But the market makers job is to do this transaction
with with the person on the other side of the trade thousands of times a day So
all they need is five cents from you and you're you're you are okay with that five
cents So that's what's happening, right?
They're just creating the synthetic Do you guys have any questions about that?
Right, so They're actually selling the call.
So they're taking the opposite trade, but it's the exact same thing.
Yeah Right because you're buying imagine we were selling the call.
How do we say that imagine you were selling the call?
Then they would take on the exact same trade Increase synthetic and charge you five
cents for it Okay,
so they're not out to get you All they're doing is creating a market for you and
they're charging you a little bit but they're doing it thousands of times throughout
the day Does anyone else understand have questions about that concept?
So if you're looking if we're looking let's say at this call option here So I think
some guy will meet will meet talked about this It's mind-blowing how that guy has
like 500,000 Twitter followers Let's take a look at this option right here This
option is two dollars and thirty cents wide So his claim was don't buy this option.
It's too illiquid Okay, don't buy the in the money options.
They're too illiquid But they are just as liquid and in the money option is just
as liquid as an out-of-the-money put Because the market maker can synthetically
create that trade Okay,
so just because sometimes you'll see like super wide calls Super wide like let's
say you want to buy in the money call and you see a super wide spread Doesn't mean
it's illiquid the way you want to look at it is look take a look at the puts if
the puts are liquid the calls are gonna Be liquid because the market maker will
just synthetically create the put otherwise it's an art Okay And I'll show you I'll
show you what I mean by it's an art Okay, let's buy it.
Let's buy this call So we're buying this call for $88 Okay,
so max risk on the trade 88 let's do a one lot max risk on this trade is 8820 bucks
Let's go and create this synthetic What
do you mean because this is 99 Delta Because the extrinsic is the same right like
take a look here now. Here's the stock right,
and then we're buying the put and The extrinsic value is the same remember that
put call parity says Let's go here That the extrinsic value on the call strike for
let's say for the 270 call it has to be the same for the 270 put They have to be
the same. Otherwise, which I'll show you right now. You'll take a look.
So if we did buy this for $88 Okay, if we if we did buy this for 88 bucks,
okay,
so this is the ask on the option If you did buy this for $88 then the market maker
Could synthetically sell This one and look at this one only eight eight eight thousand
six hundred dollar risk So we're dropping our risk by two thousand dollars.
Now. That is such a widespread Okay,
and what that means is that it allows someone like even me or you to Come and make
an arb here So it becomes competitive Right,
and the market maker is only it only needs five cents So that's why the fair value.
So neil I want to ask you a question What is the fair value of this of our call
option here of the 260 250 call option?
given given this put Given this what is the value of the call option?
Right, it'd be basically yeah,
it'd be eight thousand because let's say the market maker takes five cents You'd
get filled you'd get filled at Eighty seven dollars not eighty eight dollars and
twenty cents Okay Are you sure you get it?
What's wrong talk talk me through because if you have questions everyone else has
questions Okay.
So let's say you come in you And you buy this So what does that mean for the market
maker?
What does it mean if you buy this What is he holding?
Right So this is what he's holding Okay So let's go add this position here riskless
trade he captures 125 risk-free Right here.
Here is his here is his position he has from you Okay,
he short the in the money call so if he buys If he sent if he sent so he shorted
in the money call and if he makes one synthetically then He has this position and
this a long call plus a short call of the same strike equals No trade no position
on Exactly, right. It's not a risk neutral. It's risk-free.
He he owns exactly Right,
they cancel each other out he gets the extra of for making that for making that
commission From for make that transaction perfect And then you also might think
well,
this is going to cost them the the dealer margin But the truth is so if he has this
position on He's going to basically have no margin for this So you can put on millions
of these a day Okay market makers get special treatment when it comes to that They
got amazing financing a whole bunch of really cool stuff that happens that goes
on in those firms Okay,
so he might have a million of these on and then as as the um As the order flow changes,
he starts laying them off. So now this is inventory.
So he has these this position on as his inventory Okay And now let's say let's say
joe from down the street comes in by and says hey, you know what?
I'm looking to i'm looking to uh to buy a call option Or he's looking to sell a
call option right then he's going to lay off this call And then he's going to close
out this position Okay So he remains he remains neutral At all times he tries to
not always he tries to So,
let's see what happens here When we are doing so we're gonna we're gonna see how
we how how he decides where to put his spreads So,
let's take a look here So here this is a this is a market maker. Okay,
most of the time guys this bid and this ask is a market maker Inside is fair value
Okay. So how does he decide that? Well, it's inventory,
of course but a lot of the times for especially for liquid stocks let me uh So the
market maker might say okay. Well, so he always quotes involved.
He doesn't quote in price. Okay.
He's always quoting in vol terms Market maker thinks the at the money fair value
volatility is 30 Okay,
this is what he thinks fair value is for those options So what he's going to do
is he's going to put an ask I'm, sorry a bid Okay at 25 Okay,
and he's going to put an ask at 35 So this is how he's going to start off Now this
is acb. Okay. We're talking acb now.
This is this is the acb so he's going to quote right in here all of a sudden you
have The retail community start hitting this They want it So he's now going to start
so now he's starting to get inventory Okay.
So remember one slice of pizza is not the second slice of pizza is never as good
as the first slice So he's not going to charge 35% anymore. He wants more.
Okay.
So now this is going to become 36 36% But guess what more retail traders start flooding
the market Okay, and nobody Nobody is buying Nobody is selling at the bid.
Everyone wants to ask So he's going to start moving this up 37 Okay,
this is how the demand supply is working in the market Now eventually there's going
to be so now this is before predicting alpha comes in and starts selling vol Okay,
and taking it off the market makers books. This is before that Okay,
eventually He's going to get so full Okay,
he's gonna get so full these acb puts That now he's going to start skewing his markets
So before let's say 30% was fair value remember And so we quoted 5% less and 5%
above Okay.
Now let's say fair value Is 35% That's his fair value now after all this retail
came in He doesn't want all this trade on the book, okay,
let's say it's 10 it's 10 Let's say it's a 950 pa terminal hasn't updated yet.
And we and we haven't taken the market makers left on his own in the market What
he's going to do is he's going to skew his book.
So fair value is 35% and what he's going to do is he's going to like this 34% for
the bid Okay,
he's going to go 40% for the ask Or let's say let's let's call it 42 Okay 42 so
now all of a sudden even though his fair value is 35 mid Is now let's say 39 He's
skewing his markets. He's making Sorry guys.
Let me make this a little more attractive here he's making This 34% look much more
attractive Than this 42 Okay.
So when we see wide markets guys Mid Does not mean anything When we see volatile
markets with ACB mid means nothing right when there's a lot of volume going on in
a stock but relative to what it usually is so not like I'm talking spy where there's
usually you know, it's very competitive and The volume is usually high.
I'm talking when you know,
ACB volume volume goes from 20 million to 200 million dollars 200 million volume,
okay Mid Markets get wide mid does not mean fair value anymore Okay so If we're
selling If we're coming in and selling The options to the market maker Sorry,
if we're if we're coming in and selling options and we're taking off So he has inventory
and now now pa comes in Let me erase this Okay,
let's go Let's go green Okay, so market maker, okay,
he's got inventory let's say he owns a thousand ACB calls Predicting alpha comes
in and says, you know what?
We'll take we'll take a hundred of those from you Okay,
he is gonna be more than generous to lay those off to us Okay,
we actually might get so his fair value was 30 35 percent Right,
we might actually get the mid here But at 39 right mid was 39 but a buyer won't
get the mid Okay, he's skewing his books Do you guys have questions about that?
Dude, do you see how are you guys starting to see how this works,
especially with earning season, right?
so RBC will have a desk that tries to Take take the blow when people are coming
in buying options Right,
the demand for options is way higher than the supply for options before an earnings
event So market makers are getting paid now,
right and dealers are getting paid to come in and and take on the blow and take
on the load Right.
So that's why a lot of the time guys like right like right but like around like
350 355 We get like these amazing fills right near the ask right,
not all the time,
but on something like Microsoft or Facebook like those stocks were just like it
tracks so much buyers We always get those nice fills but on something that's less
liquid and there's not a lot of buyers, right?
Like like you've seen us struggling with some of those less liquid names Okay.
So this is how this is how this is all working At a very high level right at a low
level, of course, it gets way more complex, but a very high level.
This is how The markets working with us and interacting with us Do you guys have
questions about that?
No questions. Well, I must I must have put all you guys to sleep you know,
I thought like For me at least like when I first learned about like how how markets
work. I thought like wow,
you know This is so this is so cool you know get to kind of like See how you fit
into the market right and who you're really interacting with So you sure you guys
don't have any questions there? Yeah okay, no, no,
so Just because it's a liquid doesn't mean you get the mid It's It's right.
So it's it Depending on where the where the market is skewing.
So in a liquid market, you don't have a lot of buyers In fact,
you have no buyers So when you're selling you're probably get way worse than mid
Because you like the market maker is literally gonna take on inventory for you But
if you look at right,
it's all about the demand supply so if you look at a stock where there's a lot of
volume and a lot of the volume is by orders Then you might get better than the mid
Right, or you might get the mid and the mid is not fair value Right.
Remember how that we said the market makers skews the book to make right so So we
have 35 and 43 okay, but the market maker says Fair-value is 36% Okay,
he's making the bid look so attractive So we come in mid is 39 we We might get this
But a lot of time we actually will get this Because he's more than happy to lay
off.
He has so much inventory is more than happy to lay off some inventory to us Okay,
and this is gonna happen.
This is this is really prevalent in Low market cap stocks that have like insane
amount of volume a CB One of some of the other ones that we traded guys like VT
IQ SPC all those names Where all of a sudden you get a whole bunch of order flow
and like, you know,
the market makers are scrambling You're gonna have them skew in there.
You're gonna have volatility go crazy,
which is why we saw ACB volatility 500% Right,
it's not because the market maker said hey,
you know what fair value is 500% It clearly wasn't like the market only moved a
hundred and twenty percent So clearly there's no way that the market maker is that
wrong?
But what happened was it was just so much order flow coming into the market That
the market maker is taking on inventory.
There's only one way flow happening It's only buyers coming in like who in heaven's
name is selling options on ACB after a 30% move Who is selling that on a low market
cap stock It's too small for big for big funds to trade it.
They probably can't even trade it.
It's like against their risk limits So you've no you've all demand no supply and
that's why Implied volatility was so high and so we're coming in there We're gonna
get we're gonna get the mid bids were bitten ask was wide But I remember coming
in there and like instant fill at the mid right and who knows Fair value on the
market makers book was probably, you know,
ten points lower and his forecast of volatility was probably a hundred points lower
Okay, but he's not trying to take him. He's not true.
He makes money neutral He's not trying to take a view on volatility.
He sometimes does right?
Especially if he's holding inventory But it's not all the time Okay Yeah Any more
questions about that?
We're gonna end it there we'll leave we'll open it up for if you guys don't talk
about anything else But 841 I will leave it there. I'm pretty sure that's uh,
We just double check my notes here Yeah Yeah so
One of our goals Maddie is We want you to understand how things work Okay,
because markets change strategies change,
but if you can get a fundamental understanding of what's going on You're gonna be
more confident and you'll be able to change your change your strategy quickly,
so The goal of this Maddie is to give you more confidence when you're trading be
like, okay I understand why I'm playing volatility is high It's because well,
you know,
there's a lot of order flow coming in and the market makers are probably Taking
on too much inventory.
So it makes sense for me to come in and sell and sell the options Another thing
you can do is when you're trading in liquid stocks, right?
You're not just gonna go in and try to get filled up the mid Well,
you're gonna try to try to find. Okay. Well, where is fair value here? Right.
I know on interactive brokers. For example,
they have something called the mark Let me see if I can pull that up here quickly
Okay, so you guys see this here mark? Yes, this is not Yeah,
can you guys see my interactive brokers platform here? Okay, so See this mark.
So this is so what interactive brokers does is they fit a spline? Okay,
so they try to find well What is the fair value of?
These options if we were if we were to say they were all the same volatility or
near the same volatility Okay, how can we fit the best fit spline?
and so It's 367 is there a fair value so if I come in here and I buy for 570 That's
ridiculous. I put an order for 570. That's ridiculous, right?
Or let's say mid here is $4 and 30 cents if I come in there and place more for $4
30 cents I'll probably get scooped up Right if there's some hidden liquidity in
here so One of the reasons I'm you know,
I'm doing this as well as so you guys can say well Maybe if I'm trading a liquid
stock don't just go for the mid Okay, try to see you try to see okay. Well,
where is where should this liquidity be?
okay,
and obviously there's there's techniques to do that like but it requires a little
bit of programming right you got to be able to take the implied volatility of Forecast
or something?
so that does take some programming but You know other than that you have to just
try to look at it and say well, where is where's fair value?
Right if you guys want to pick up programming,
I know Maddie starting to learn it, which is awesome You gotta be like,
okay Well, where do I think fair value is here?
Is it at mid or is it probably a lot less right if the spreads are wide?
Maybe I can start a lot a lot less than mid Okay Did that answer your question Maddie?
Awesome. Awesome Yeah, Maddie. I like I hope you know,
this also gives you a lot of a lot more confidence understanding. Well,
why is implied volatility high?
Okay Yeah Maddie
did you see the the where I was showing the video of me trying to pull down the
market maker?
Okay Yeah Yeah Right. Yeah super quick. So he's 570,
but he's actually willing to go less So I'm gonna go 565 drop him down drop him
down drop him down.
Then I'm gonna hit him Okay Yeah Just gonna hammer him exactly because We know that
his fair value is probably a lot less.
There's no way he's this So this tells you this tells us that he's not confident,
right?
He's not confident with his forecast or just liquidity is so bad so he's quoting
so wide and So we're gonna bring him down because we think that he's willing to
come down and we're gonna keep bringing him down until He stops coming down Well,
I will clear him up Yeah,
I'm telling you Maddie this is gonna come in super handy when you start trading
super illiquid stocks If you start trading them,
yeah now Yeah Okay. So Kel Kelly got question here,
so If you identified that it's it's illiquid Why enter into the trade in the first
place since there's probability that it'll be difficult to exit the trade 100% 100
% so It's not just let's get in and then we're done right it's we can get in and
then Well, we now we got to work our way out Right.
So we're getting dinged on both sides.
Now the reason why we would ever be trading in a liquid market is because There's
probably gonna be more mispricing Right think like think about like this if you
if there's no competition in that space Right think about like the super The micro
cap stocks Those earnings events are probably not gonna be priced efficiently right,
so you could come in and take a directional view because the stock the price of
the stock is not Reflecting something in the market, right?
If everyone's looking at all the analysts are looking at the stock then it's gonna
be priced a lot more efficiently I think about real estate. For example,
the real estate market is so much less efficient In the stock market because there's
there's no liquidity there So though that's the only reason why are we going into
a liquid illiquid names and that's to be finding opportunities Finding larger mispricings
that are gonna cover your transaction costs Right. I mean,
how many how often are you gonna find a mispricing in Apple?
Probably probably never well,
I wouldn't say never but probably not that often But if you want to the smaller
cap names all of a sudden You might find some opportunities here and there I'll
go answer your question Right, right.
The the more the more liquidity you have the more efficient it should be Perfect.
No problem. No problem Hey, bud Thanks.
I did the exact same thing it So it was six like it was it was it was a liquid market.
Remember it was like I can't remember how wide the spread was It's pretty wide Mm
-hmm.
So what I did was so you wanted to buy let's say it was 555 You wanted to buy here?
Okay, and the market maker was quoting you 655. So what I did was I said,
well Let me come down five cents and I came down five cents and he jumped me Right
came down another five cents. He jumped me and then you got dinged Right,
right. So remember it's a it's that pizza slice So he ate a peach.
I said I'm done Right,
maybe maybe maybe it was a small market maker at that point. No,
it doesn't always happen You know,
you can't do this on Citadel but that was an illiquid stock right,
and there's probably not the greatest market maker on the other side of the trade
and Remember, he's not losing money from that.
Like I guess in the sense that He's he's still he's still only gonna go down to
where he thinks he can still make money. So keep that in mind Okay,
so in this case scenario When it was six dollars,
he's making a lot of money But when we're down to 570,
he still thinks he can make money there Okay,
he's not he's not going into a losing trade for us,
obviously He's saying I can still make money at 570,
but we're just bringing him down a little bit Okay That's good.
No Do it like does that make more sense now?
What happened there and during that trade? Okay Okay, so we'll leave it.
We'll leave it at that guys So that was a little bit about market making some microstructure
and Yeah,
I hope you guys found that pretty pretty insightful I mean when I first found out
about how the hell the hell these market makers are working and how I interact with
them I thought it was like so eye-opening for me.
So I hope I did a good job explaining it to you guys A little bit eye-opening for
you as well Okay, perfect If you guys don't have any more questions,
we'll leave it at that This was being recorded and I'll put it up and I got yesterday's
recording that I'm gonna throw in right after this live It's all done Or two days
ago recording.
So I'll throw that up right now Yeah Right couple bucks couple bucks.
We got in there But yeah, okay guys So we'll we'll leave it at that Okay,
perfect. Cheers guys. Yeah, no problem guys. Yeah. Awesome. Awesome Oh guys,
just so you know,
the shit show is not gonna be opened right now because I sent Sean a message I can't
get in touch with him.
I Don't know how to how to open it up So we're going to we're gonna have to deal
without it today But what we will we'll be back at it tomorrow unless it's already
opened. I see someone posted in there. Ha Look at that. No,
you hacked the system, buddy That was it. Hey, don't kill me. Okay All right,