All right, where we are recording. Thank you, Eric So,
yeah that I've known about these for quite a long time I've never made much use
out of them That that also says guys Just because I don't make use of them doesn't
mean they're not useful, right?
There's things that I use that other people might think is useless For example implied
volatility right a lot of people think implied volatility is useless yet.
It's the way that I make my living so But I think I do have a pretty good grasp
on on how they on how they operate what they are And so I really want to break that
down for you guys All right, so we're going to jump right into it.
So I'm gonna share my screen and here we go So this is this interview not this interview.
This live is gonna be done in our however No coding knowledge is needed.
And if you want me to explain something, please slow me right down Okay,
please slow me right down guys.
Well,
I seem to get the chat going here Okay,
so I do have the chat live Please stop me along the way by the end of this guys
I want all of you to be well aware of what Vanna is what charm is and I honestly
think you guys are gonna be way ahead of the crowd in terms of this new buzzword
Okay, I'm monitoring the chat. So please ask any questions along the way.
Can everyone see my screen?
Okay Let me know if you guys can see my screen Awesome blessing.
How's everything?
Very cool. Very cool. Okay.
So as this as this thing is loading right here I just want to give a quick primer.
So right now we're seeing a big buzzword out there.
It's called Vanna Vanna and charm And what we're seeing on Twitter is a lot of people
talking about Vanna a lot of people talking about charm Seeing how you know,
they can apparently make money You know basically seeing the Vanna flows and when
they say Vanna flows what their meaning is Money coming into the market that is
creating. Let's say Certain buying and selling pressure. Okay,
or maybe I take that back. Actually,
it's not money coming into the market It's how the options are reacting That's causing
buying and selling pressure and that is a huge buzzword right now Everyone's talking
about it and Personally,
okay personally as you guys are gonna find out I don't think it is as important
as As these traders are claiming but you know a lot of the time guys,
oh actually and I want to say something else as well a Lot of people who are coming
on to Twitter and and and following these guys and you know talking these guys up
They actually don't understand what they're talking about right and and this is
actually coming from people messaging us saying hey,
listen I follow these guys. These guys are very cool.
I don't understand what they're talking about, right?
And I'm sure you guys can resonate with that as well Gemco song Chris video,
right?
These guys are talking about Vanna flows charm flows It's hard to keep up but because
of these fancy words,
we kind of get sucked in Maybe they know something more than us and we're just not
at their level yet And so for this live we want to really break that down.
All right, so First thing is Vanna Okay,
Vanna is and I'm gonna break this all down and if you guys don't understand this
We are going to break it down we're gonna go to the base layer We're gonna basically
take in this life You know this like foreign thing that no one can understand and
we're gonna bring it down to reality Okay,
so every single person on this life can understand including you Neil so Vanna is
the partial derivative of Delta with respect to volatility now I don't I don't you
know,
I don't need you guys to understand this This is how someone might explain it to
you Vanna is the partial derivative of Delta with respect to vol. Okay,
so Someone might say someone sees the formula like this. Okay,
so when someone might see the formula Okay, we're go line by line.
They might see Delta divided by vol divided by Vega or Sorry divided by vol IV and
they might see this fancy word there.
They might see this fancy letter So if I go on Google,
for example This might be a little bit of a longer guys a longer live probably an
hour Just because I really want you guys to understand this.
Let's see if they have it.
Okay, they don't have it here. Let's see Okay, here it is. Okay,
so This is gamma. Here it is. Perfect. So we might see it like this.
Okay The change in Delta,
so sorry you guys might see like this Delta divided by Vega Okay,
this is how some of us might see it Delta Divided by Vega or divided by implied
volatility But this is actually not what it is. Okay,
it is the partial derivative meaning the change in Delta with respect to the change
in implied volatility okay,
so what that means is if Volatility changes How does our Delta change? Okay,
if volatility changes, how does my Delta change? Okay,
it's not Delta divided by implied volatility or divide by Vega It's if the denominator
okay in this case implied volatility were to change How is my Delta going to change?
Okay,
does everyone understand that and Do please don't be afraid to say no Okay,
because we are gonna go step-by-step if I can't get everyone on this live to understanding
what Vanna flows are what charm flows are We're not gonna get it.
Thank you blessing So blessing and everyone else who also probably has the same
question because I know it's not just blessing Delta is the change in the option
price Okay with the change in the stock price.
So if the stock goes up a dollar Well, how much is my option gonna go up? Well,
if it's not the money Let's say has a Delta of 50.
It's gonna go up 50 cents a call option now what this is saying is if Volatility
was to change. Okay, if volatility was to change How would my Delta change?
Okay, if my let's say I have a Delta.
Let's say I buy out of the money call option it's trading at 30 deltas and implied
volatility changed Well, what would my Delta be if implied volatility changed?
So that is what Vanna is and we're actually gonna go in detail We're actually gonna
do examples of it to see and graph it out.
It's gonna be a very cool live guys I promise you. Okay,
we're all gonna be smarter after this. I hope I really hope so.
So that is what Vanna is Now we have charm. Okay, and Actually Steve,
I hope you're really paying attention here because I'm gonna be asking you some
tough questions Okay,
so I hope you're paying very good attention So charm is the partial derivative of
Delta with respect to time. Okay.
So what that means is the change in time So if we move forward in time because we
can't move back in time Unfortunately, if we move forward in time,
how is my Delta gonna change?
Call you're saying there's three definitions of Vanna. Oh, no,
I for that for those formulas.
They were just deriving it They were just deriving it.
It wasn't saying what what they exactly were So charm is the partial derivative
of Delta with respect to time so if time moves forward,
how does my Delta change? Okay,
and Delta is our sensitivity to the stock price.
A lot of guys are claiming to make money on this personally Personally,
I believe this is a fundraising Technique. Okay.
This is a fundraising technique If people don't understand me,
but they didn't think I'm making money.
They're likely to give me money Right if everyone thinks I'm making money and like
your friend tells you that hey Jordan's making money and I talk like I'm making
Money,
it's it's likely you're gonna give me money even though you don't understand me
I honestly think this is what this is what the gurus are doing But we're you guys
are gonna come to your own conclusions about this.
I don't want to I Don't want to influence you Okay.
Now these are the two that are popular Vanna and charm. Okay.
These are second-order derivatives Right.
It's the change it so Delta is the derivative The change in Delta is the second
derivative just like gamma right gamma is the change in Delta With respect so who's
got this one? What is what is gamma if we were gonna put it in these terms?
Okay in these You know in these in these terms right here. What is gamma?
Neil saying change in Delta with respect to Vega No, no, that's not what it is.
You know the percent change of Delta. No. Thank you.
Thanks chigs It's the change in Delta with respect to price Right,
so we have for example in this case Right,
we have Delta with respect to implied volatility now I just want to make it clear
guys for this live this live is not an alpha live.
Okay this live I'm not teaching you guys how to make alpha in this live We're explaining
what the hype stuff is all about but in explaining it I honestly think a lot of
you are gonna start to by the time we get to the end of this guys I think a lot
of you are going to actually I think there's gonna be some like You know some some
moments here So yeah,
so Delta is the change in price with respect to the change I'm sorry the change
in Delta with respect to the change in price.
That's what gamma is So gamma is a second-order derivative,
but it's an important one. Okay.
Now there's other derivatives There's other second and third order of this for example
Voma. Okay,
Voma is the network I'm not gonna talk about these but just so you got the night
guys know that they're out There is the change of Vega the change implied volatility.
Okay, then we have speed Okay,
which is the change in gamma for the change in Delta Okay So a way out of the money
option has very little gamma and very little Delta at inception And but it has a
ton of speed Right as the stock drops the gamma is gonna increase increasing the
Delta right and that's why you get those huge ramp ups Okay, you have color.
Okay,
and that's gonna be the changing gamma with respect to the change in time Okay,
then there's Zoma elasticity, you know, there's so many of these okay,
there's so many of these I've never used them personally.
All right. So let's have this guys. Let's have start having some fun. Okay,
I spent some time on this Let's get some let's have some fun going Okay,
let's make sure I didn't miss anything Neal saying can you give an example of Voma?
sure,
Neil An out-of-the-money option has very little Vega But as implied volatility increases
the Vega increases So this is what we talked about with those strangles versus the
straddles Remember when I told you to take a look at that, right?
You priced it out as the implied volatility increases the Vega increases So now
for every point of implied increasing you're increasing exponentially Okay,
so it's the increase it change involved in Vega for the change in volatility,
you know I'm actually I'm actually thinking about this or library.
I can't believe we're actually having this conversation like These people online
I've gotten in my opinion way too far. They've gone way too far. Okay,
so Greeks So what we're gonna do here is we're gonna look at an option with one
month to expiration Okay, the stock is trading at a hundred.
The strike is a hundred and ten.
The volatility is 30 Okay interest rate zero dividend zero and one month to expiration
Okay Does everyone understand that an option that's trading at the stock trading
at a hundred?
We're buying a 110 call with a 30% implied vol and 20 days to expiration Okay,
20 business days one month one month So here you
guys can see it right down here, right? You know what?
I'm actually gonna change my view here so we can all be on the same page Do you
guys see view pains pain layout? Here we go.
All right.
So here we go guys So let's look at a that that call option here Well that call
option is trading for 57 cents and the Delta is 13.88. What does that mean?
Okay, we're gonna focus on the on this Delta number right now. Okay.
What does this mean?
The Delta is 13.88 and guys if you stay to the end of this We're actually gonna
be going over a market maker example how he manages his book So I really hope you
guys find this live insightful. I'm gonna try to keep it exciting.
Just just comment Jordan You're not keeping exciting and we're gonna we'll we'll
try to you know,
which we'll try to figure it out Can someone explain to me what does this mean Delta
point thirteen eight eight Red I'm not gonna be talking about how you can infer
Vanna and charm in the PA terminal personally because I don't think it's useful
but we're gonna get we are gonna get to the end of that red and you can Come up
with your own decision and let me know me like Jordan I think it is useful and I
want I want this in the terminal and I will definitely work on it.
Okay Guys I can definitely add this stuff into the terminal. Okay,
I'm so you guys really want this in the terminal Let's let's let's finish this live
and then we're gonna then we'll talk. Okay.
All right Delta point thirteen eight eight. What is this inferring?
What is this inferring Delta of point thirteen eighty-eight?
I gotta make sure we're all in the same track here. Oh Man,
you guys fell asleep.
Oh I guess I'm falling asleep. So I thought you guys were pointing to red.
Okay,
perfect for every dollar the stock moves The option it will increase by third We'll
have a variance of 13 cents, right?
If the stock goes up a dollar this is gonna make 13 cents the stock goes down dollars
gonna lose 13 cents Now we're talking charm here. Okay,
we're talking charm So what we're gonna do now is we're gonna take that same option
same spot price spot price means the stock price But instead of 20 days We're gonna
do 19 days. So 19 business days.
So we are going to move one ahead one step We're gonna move ahead one step Steve
you still with me Steve? How's it? How's the live going Steve so far?
So we're gonna move ahead one step in time Okay. Now, what do we notice here?
What do we notice here? Well the option decreased But our Delta decreased.
Okay, our Delta decreased by point six Okay,
it went from thirteen point eight eight to thirteen point two two. Okay,
so our Delta Decreased Okay,
as we move forward in time our Delta decreases Okay to show you guys this I'm gonna
actually move forward five days Let's take a look. Now. Our Delta is now ten.
Okay,
so for every dollar increase in the stock We are only gonna make ten cents as time
is going by our Delta is Decreasing Okay, as we're moving forward in time,
our Delta is decreasing that is for charm for an out-of-the-money call option in
Chopper charm. Okay.
It's the rate of change of Delta with respect to time How is my Delta changing as
time moves forward?
Okay, and so for an out-of-the-money option,
let me ask you guys this quick trick question.
What about for an in-the-money option?
Stephen in the money option as time moves forward. What happens to Delta?
Thank you, Stephen It increases right it gonna approach one in the money.
It's gonna approach one. All right,
so that is charm Does everyone understand charm?
We're actually gonna graph all this out in a second. But so far do we get it?
Thank blessing good job with the with the with the increase Bless blessing saying
yeah, if blessing saying yeah,
we're good to go because everyone else Is for some reason afraid to ask He's afraid
to ask questions along the way now.
We're gonna go into Vama of Vama Vanna But I call it banana. All right,
so we're gonna do the same thing option $100 strike 110 volatility 30 days expiration
21 month. Okay, same option. Okay, and what do we see? 13.88 exact same option.
Let me erase this.
Oops Let me erase this so we're back we're back to we're back to the same page How
are you guys finding this live so far? Are we okay?
We are we is everyone doing? All right We're having a good everyone smiling.
Everyone's everyone's intrigued Perfect Trent as long as perfect dude blessing.
Is it good so far blessing? Let me know Okay, so Steve this was the question.
I wanted to ask you Marcos good stuff, buddy Steve this was the question.
I wanted to ask you. Okay,
this is putting Steve's big brain to the test If we drop vol so in this case now,
we're taking the same option right Delta 13.88 and remember Del Vanna is the change
in Delta with respect to the change in implied volatility We're gonna drop volatility
by one point, okay,
we're gonna drop volatility by one point out of the money call option What's gonna
happen to Delta Steve and why?
What is gonna happen to Delta and why and anyone can answer really? You know,
I I purposely when I wrote this one down, what do you think will happen here?
It was I was trying to I wanted to give Steve a little test Trent saying decrease
Okay Okay,
we're gonna drop implied volatility By one point what's gonna happen Steve?
Do you disagree or agree with Trent?
And I know you're using an option calculator right now.
I'm very upset about that Wow Steve man.
I will happen Okay,
yeah what's gonna happen to Delta blessing what's gonna happen to Delta when we
drop vols Okay, so by now Steven is definitely using an option calculator.
So chigs Trent you guys are 100% correct okay,
and There's actually Oh Neil see. Oh, wow. Steve's gone.
I guess he had I Guess it's a little boring for him. That's okay.
That's okay guys.
We're gonna keep it going here It's gonna decrease and it's not just gonna decrease
because the the chance of the big move decreases which it does, right?
but the reason I want I was hoping you guys someone would say is volatility is Is
synthetic time, right? So dropping volatility is like decreasing time Right,
and so you're 100% correct if we drop volatility, right?
You can see in that here now Delta goes from point one three eight eight to point
one three zero okay,
and if we drop vault by five points our Delta goes from point one three eight eight
to Nine deltas thirteen deltas to nine deltas.
So now we're now this is where it's really gonna get fun and really gonna get interesting
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to create a sequence of stock prices okay,
stocks gonna trade at a hundred and we're gonna create a sequence from sixty to
hundred and forty dollars and We are going to basically figure out what the Delta
is For each of these call options and we're gonna plot them and here is what our
Delta looks like You guys are not unfamiliar with this Okay Hundred
Okay, sorry guys,
okay my apologies if it's trading it if the stocks I thought this was strike price
It's spot price the stock trading at a hundred forty The Delta is gonna be one right
because we're buying a hundred dollar call option Right if the stock string at a
hundred you can see right here. We have a hundred as the strike price Right,
so imagine if the stock was trading at sixty dollars the Delta would be zero,
right you guys Stock trading at sixty Delta.
I mean the strike price is a hundred.
So the stocks I move $40 volatility of 30 Right.
The Delta is gonna be zero Now if the stock's trading at a hundred forty for a call
option, the Delta is gonna be one Right,
it's gonna be so far in the money that it's gonna be basically trading at one Red
saying can you just elaborate volatility synthetic time?
We did a live on it red, but you know,
we talk about it If you increase volatility,
it would be the same thing as if you increase time if you decrease volatility It's
the same thing as if you decreased the time.
Okay I think about this red you have a 30-day option and you increase volatility
Right you jack up volatility Well,
imagine nothing else to imagine it that actually didn't happen, right?
It would be the same thing as let's say if you if you bought or sold a 60-day straddle
All right. So as you increased volatility,
it's similar to increasing time and you can see that by doing we did a whole live
on it.
It was basically where we did a Tree diagram and we explained like how when you
increase time Right your your width gets bigger of the tree when you increase volatility
your width gets bigger of the tree I'll Sean if you can send you over that one It's
a Vega is not like theta Okay, but implied volatility is like time Okay.
So here we go guys. Here's our Delta everyone understand this Delta curve.
Does that blessing? What do you think?
I'm blessing I'm holding you Accountable for the whole group because you are the
only brave one to to let me know What's up,
we're okay perfect So this is the Delta curve.
This is a Delta of an option Okay,
an option at 100 is going to have 50 Delta and at the money options gonna have 50
Delta Right at the money option 50 Delta in the money option 100 Delta out of the
money option 0 Delta now What we're gonna do is we're actually gonna graph Tomorrow.
Okay, we're looking at charm Okay, what does the Delta look like?
Tomorrow and this is what it looks like.
This is what it looks like. Take a look guys. Here's the difference ready Okay.
Now Sean's computers a little slow.
So it gets a little black so what I'm going to do is What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
plot both of them side by side.
I'm gonna plot both of them side by side And here they are Oops, oops. Oops.
Oops. Oh, sorry. Sorry guys. We're looking at Vanna. My apologies.
We're looking at Vanna guys. My apologies. My apologies Okay,
we're gonna actually do Instead of 25 vol we're gonna do 29 vol.
So let's run that again So we're looking at the change of Delta with respect to
the change of volatility So I did one vol point change.
So if implied volatility went from 30 to 29 Okay,
this is how the this is the difference between the Delta. So red okay,
red is tomorrow's implied volatility and Blue is oh,
sorry blue is tomorrow's implied Blue is 29 vol red is 30 vol Blue is 29 vol Red
is 30 vol. Okay, and just so you guys can see it clearer.
I'm going to drop the vols to 20 Here we go blue is
20 vol red is 30 vol.
Okay, do we understand that right?
Let's take a look here guys a 110 call okay 110 call if Volatility is very low if
volatility is zero Right, then we're gonna have a Delta of one Right,
we're in the money with no vol it and zero vol basically means who's got it.
What's another synonym to zero vol? We just talked about it.
What's a synonym to zero vol?
No Thank you. Chigs. Thank you.
Thank you for paying attention chase zero vol would be equal to zero time Okay,
zero vol equals zero time So 110, okay,
so you can see here right if vol is less Right.
That's the 20 is is is a I don't know why I called it tomorrow.
My apologies guys This is 20 vol and this is 30 vol right if the vol is less then
we're gonna be you know a lot closer to one Delta So you can see how here's two
graphs guys with two different vol implied volatilities one day Okay is the blue
the next is what implied vols drop this is the Vanna this is the Vanna and To make
it clear to make it clear to everyone.
We are going to graph The Vanna and how do we graph the Vanna? Well,
we're gonna simply take the difference between the two. So this is Vanna Okay,
this is Vanna and we're going to talk about what this is as volatility increases
Delta Decreases. Okay.
It's going to decrease when we are Sorry guys when the Delta when the Vanna Decreases.
Okay when the Vanna decreases if the option is out of the money,
the Delta is gonna decrease The option is out of the money and volatility decreases.
The option is going to Decrease Delta. We just talked about it,
right and let me know if we if we need if we need some help here Margin,
welcome. Welcome to the chat. Mr. Banana one okay, if The volatility decreases,
right?
Well are out of the money option is gonna lose Delta but are in the money option
is going to increase Delta Here's spot price right?
Here's the $100 spot price Margin,
I highly recommend You know later tonight whenever you get time away from the girlfriend
you You take a look at the live from the beginning just because you know It's gonna
be hard to catch you up right right from here The out of the money option is gonna
decrease in Delta the in the money option is gonna increase in Delta So blessing
seeing we got a little bit lost So blessing let's go back here. Okay,
let's go back here.
Let's go back to Vanna here is a call option Delta 1388 Okay,
Delta 1388 for this call option we are going to Well, I was charm. Sorry,
we are going to decrease volatility blessing.
So let's decrease volatility here The out of the money call option lost Delta Okay
lost Delta now if it was in the money and I think you actually mentioned it because
volatility is decreasing It's going the Delta is gonna increase All right,
let me ask you this question blessing you got a hundred dollar call option,
okay, and the stocks trading at 110 stocks trading at 110.
You got a hundred dollar call option at Expiration. What is the Delta?
What is the Delta of that call option at expiration?
110 stock Hundred dollar call option at expiration perfect one.
What about a year from now? What's that call option a year from now?
Don't give me the exact number What do you think a year in time if that call option
was a year in time? What do you think?
So it wouldn't be a year and it wouldn't be one Right,
it would be something like maybe yeah,
like maybe probably probably actually less maybe 0.6 0.7 Right because it still
has time to be out of the money Okay,
so it's not gonna be trading out one but as time goes forward or as volatility drops
right volatility equals synthetic time as Volatility drops we're gonna start to
see this thing go in the money and that's gonna become a Delta of one So when we
look at Vanna Okay,
and I know guys it like it's a little bit a little bit technical right now We're
gonna actually into a practical experience at the very end as a market maker we're
gonna act as a market maker at the end of this at the end of this live and in the
money option as Time goes forward is gonna come closer and closer to one Now to
the money option as time goes forward or volatility drops.
It's gonna go closer and closer to zero Now we're gonna do the same thing for charm
Okay, we're gonna do the exact same thing. We have a 20 to 20 day option Okay,
we're gonna 19 day option 20 day 19 day and we're gonna take the difference in Delta
And I have a trick question for you guys.
I have a very trick question for you guys What is charm gonna look like?
So here's what Vega Vanna looks like What is charm gonna look like I think I think
I have to put this one on chigs chigs But seem to be getting the answer right chase.
What is charm gonna look like? Here's Vanna Perfect red the same. Oh,
you guys are awesome. Why are they the same?
Why do I can they why are they the same?
Why are they the same?
Perfect chigs Vol is synthetic time Perfect. So let's graph it So, sorry,
so first here is the Delta with change in one day time Okay,
here's the Delta with one day chop time tomorrow versus today Okay,
and if you guys want to see five days Change Okay looks very similar to when we
change volatility and when we graph it voila Exactly the same.
So any questions about that because now we're gonna go into a real-world example
of where you know These guys are coming from these Vanna guys these Vanna flows
these charm flows Coasting I'm having trouble with the two curves.
Yep These these ones call or or these ones.
So let's call this one and let's call this to Co he said the second then the first
Confusing me one or two one. Okay,
Coa Let's take a look at a out of the money call option out of the money call option
It has 30 days to expiration Okay Give me a Delta number.
Give me any Delta number out of the money call option 30 days to expiration What
Delta could have? 80 80 Okay, 20. Okay,
perfect at expiration Coa What Delta could it have out of the money call option
expiration out of the money call option?
So the option goes from 20 deltas to zero.
So what can we say about about the call option in respect to time?
It decreases every day it decreases Everything else else held equal.
What about in the money call? So that's this showing here, right?
So this is the zero line,
right and this is saying that As time goes forward in this case one step one time
step. Okay, this call option Lost about three cents. Okay,
the y-axis is the change in the Delta So this call option lost about point zero
three Delta for one at the bottom here for one time step forward Okay,
and then the in the money option is gonna be the opposite right one time step forward
it's gonna increase in Delta So I'm seeing that you said here got it this part.
So I'm assuming we're good Okay Okay, continue explaining. Okay,
so then in the money in the money option one day forward Right.
This option is going to increase its Delta by five point zero four Right because
and let's say in the money option today Cohen 30 days out is 80 But expiration it's
100 so we can say that as Delta as time goes forward or volatility drops Delta increases
in the money.
So in the money Delta increases out of the money Delta decreases Yeah spots trading
at a hundred.
All right So now we're gonna have a really fun example and this is where the practicality
comes in, right?
So so in the way I think about it guys is this is how a lot of people show you this
stuff These Vanna these charms But no one has anyone ever has anyone told you the
practicalities of Vanna?
Has anyone ever told you what happens to market makers when time changes?
What happens to market makers when vol changes?
Has anyone ever talked about it?
I haven't seen it I haven't seen it on Twitter and and I'm gonna show you guys why
that is. Okay,
I'm gonna show you guys What what the reason for that is let's say we've got a market
maker. We're gonna late. We're gonna label him Eminem Okay,
and he is going to sell a 110 call option stocks trading at a hundred stock is trading
at 100 So you are gonna go buy a GME call option stock trading at 100 and you're
gonna buy the 110 GME call option Well, and this is 30 vol. Okay.
Well our Delta Okay for the market maker is gonna be 13 deltas, but he's short.
He's short this call option. So he's short 13 deltas Okay,
he's short 13 deltas, but this market maker doesn't sell one.
Okay this market maker instead.
He sells 10,000 of these He sells 10,000 of these option contracts So we're gonna
have a market maker gonna multiply it by a hundred right because Delta is you know
times 100 and then we're gonna Multiply it by 10,000 because he sold 10,000 of these
contracts So let's look at this market makers book.
Let's take a look at this market makers book.
He's short a hundred and thirty-eight thousand shares He's short one hundred thirty
-eight thousand eight hundred fifty seven shares of this of this of this stock.
So what's he gonna do?
Now he's actually not gonna do this but for Twitter purposes.
What what is this market maker gonna do?
Sure, but I can send it over to you. No problem for Twitter purposes.
What is this market maker going to do?
Hedge perfect. How's he gonna hedge? What's he gonna do?
He just shorted a whole bunch of these shares to some punter 10,000 of these some
big retail whale came in and bought 10,000 of these he's gonna buy how many shares
is he gonna buy?
Oh shit. We're gonna go past nine here guys.
He's gonna buy a hundred eight thirty-eight thousand shares.
Perfect He's gonna buy a hundred and thirty-eight thousand shares and that's gonna
make him flat Delta now tomorrow in in three hours Okay in three hours Vol
changes in three hours vol changes and it goes from 30 vol to 28 vol Okay,
it goes from 30 vol to 28 vol and I'm pretty sure the way that Jim croissant The
way he does it is he does it through how the stock moves with spot price,
right? You know,
you have different volatilities for different different strikes And so let's say
vol drops 28 to 28 it drops to Vegas For goes from 30 to 28 three hours later Okay,
you're gonna get her support resistance zone levels on Twitter.
So now this market maker is only short 121,000 234 Delta he was short a hundred
thirty-eight thousand He bought a hundred thirty-eight thousand shares,
but now he's only short 121,000. But guess what? What's the issue here?
What is our issue here? Perfect perfect Eric now, he's long Delta. In fact,
he's long about 17,000 shares Vol drops two points and now he's long 17,000 shares.
So what does he need to do?
He needs to go and sell 17,000 shares and to be honest guys,
this is actually not what really happens in the market Rule number one about options
is hedge if you're if you're trading options hedge with options as a market maker
But let's go say he goes and he sells 17,000 shares. Well,
this is a resistance level right at because let's say for example Jim Cousin says
if this because remember vol and as the stock moves Volatility changes if it's for
example when the queues go down Well,
the queues are gonna be increasing volatility So deltas are gonna change but as
the stock goes up, well,
guess what vol is gonna drop And so that's gonna change the deltas.
And so that's where he gets those support resistance from I'm pretty sure is that
you know The spot of eyeball correlation plus the Vanna flows,
right if spot were to rally 1% Let's say or to this support level vols would drop
X amount Meaning the market makers are gonna have to sell X amount of shares Dropping
the stock price Okay, but here's our here's our problem guys.
Here's the big problem For 10k short options contracts,
we need to trade 17,000 shares 17,000 shares on let's say something like the SPY
Apple that trades a hundred million shares a day 17,000 shares.
I'm pretty sure Neil does this on a daily basis and Neil doesn't move the market
Okay, the practicality of this in my opinion is ridiculous Right,
even if we bump this up to a hundred thousand contracts That's a hundred and seventy
thousand shares on a stock that trades a hundred million dollars Hundred million
shares a day and we're not even talking about all the other flows But we're not
even talking about all these flows the VOMA the color of the Zoma If the market
maker short a bunch of call options as a stock rallies Well,
he's got you gotta buy more and more and more just from the gamma exposure But the
Vanna exposure is telling themselves so it's like there's not only Vanna exposure
in the market, right?
there's so many more and I honestly think in my personal and I've never met a profitable
trader that You know, like these are second-order, you know,
these are these are second-order derivatives Right,
they don't what about the first order?
What about just betting on the direction of the stock?
You're gonna make way more money betting on the direction of the stock than betting
on You know the second-order effect to figure out the Delta before you try to figure
out the Vanna Right the change of Delta with respect to Vanna try to figure out
the Delta first That's where the money is.
The money is not in this third fourth order derivative,
you know But it's a complex situation that not a lot of people understand.
And so for that reason it's easy to kind of in my opinion you know,
maybe not but I feel like you know,
it's easier to raise capital if you know people think you're some amazing creature
And no one really understands you and we Sean and I actually get a lot of messages
guys. Can you explain Vanna? Can you like how are these guys doing it?
It's because we don't understand it yet everyone, you know,
everyone's hyping them up And so I think it's a way to raise capital in my opinion
But this is this is Vanna this is charm in a nutshell Actually in pretty I'd say
pretty in-depth This is what Vanna and charm is and now you guys know so,
you know,
congrats now you understand Vanna and charm flows So right saying they're nonlinear
and so we need these second or derivative guidance So red I you know,
I would I would actually I would disagree with that just simply because as a trader
We want to we want to figure out where? Where can I make the most money, right?
You know,
there's a there's a lot of guys on Twitter For example trying to price these like
Delta five options or these Delta three options, right?
And and let's and let's take a look at it real quick.
So So let's say we're doing $100 stock and we're trading a hundred and twenty dollar
strike and Like I see this constantly, right?
I see this constantly and it's trading out Let's say point four vol for 40% volatility
zero interest rates and one month expiration Does anyone know how to I I actually
I have it as a hyphenation. Does anyone know how to change that to?
So I can have this like the slash again Or did I mess up big?
change keyboard You know what? Okay.
Actually I have I have an example right here.
So let's say we're doing $120 strike John's gonna kill me.
I'm not gonna tell I'm not gonna say anything.
He's just gonna come back and everything's gonna be apostrophes apostrophe Okay,
$100 strike $120 call option and we're gonna say 40 40 fall Right and a lot of people
are actually trying to price this they're saying hey,
the tails are super cheap The tails are super cheap. Okay,
so when we when we price this out It's trained for 27 cents.
All right train for 27 cents.
And if we think let's say it's worth 50 vol Right now we might get a big return
on capital Okay, we might get a big return on capital.
But the reality is is That it's hard to actually get size on in the wings,
right? This is the practicality side Right, so we go from 27 cents to 70 cents,
right?
So we're gaining we're gaining 40 cents here On an option that we think is 10 points
underpriced Now the reality is is that it's 40 cents, right?
You to get you know You have to get a crazy amount of size on right if you want
to let's say make four hundred thousand dollars You have to buy What is that a million
of these contracts?
You can't get that size on right and that's where a lot of the time when I see these
guys on Twitter It's like well,
you can tell who the who the who the academic is versus who the practitioner is,
right?
I'm trying to wish we are trying to get some serious money from dollars We're trying
to get how much dollars can we extract from the market, right?
And so, you know trying to price these wings,
you know using fancy words like kurtosis or you know,
other words is It's not from a practitioner standpoint.
Okay, so right I'm gonna get a second.
Let me just read what's going on here Chick saying Jordan who warehouses the risk
at the end of the day like even if market makers hedging where does the risk end
up? Yes,
really good question so The risk is gonna end up to the person taking on the risk
if I if I'm a market maker Okay, so let's say I'm going long Delta's Okay,
and I buy a call option Well, I'm not gonna be hedging.
Let's say I'm actually bullish on the shares I'm gonna buy this call option and
you know,
I mix I want that exposure I want that exposure to the Delta but the market maker
is actually gonna do is he's gonna sell me that a call option He's actually not
gonna buy shares What he's going to do is buy the option closest to my ex to my
strike Right, because why is it now?
Let me ask you that question chicks Why would the why would the market maker instead
of buying my option from or selling my option and then buying shares to hedge?
Why would he go and buy the nearest strike option?
What do you think?
One second guys. What do you think chicks?
Why would he buy the nearest strike option versus buying the shares?
Does anyone else want to help chicks here? What's it? She's gonna say You know,
you're the man, you know, you got it Obviously better than the spread Okay.
Okay chicks. Yeah, you're absolutely right.
Okay The reason why he would trade the options instead of the and this is this is
the rule, right?
The rule is if you can hedge with options head with a hedge with options don't hedge
with shares But for some reason Twitter things everyone had just the shares The
reason is because if the market maker buys those shares,
he just closes out his Delta's.
He didn't close out his Vega He didn't close out his theta.
He didn't close out his gamma and he doesn't want that.
The market maker doesn't want that exposure He's trying to remain as flat as possible
and just collect the spread Right.
So when he sells you that option You can try to buy the nearest strike option to
get rid of those exposures and whatever he has left Which is gonna be basically
zero theta and zero gamma and zero Vega right price two options right beside each
other The the Vega and gamma exposure is basically zero There might be a little
bit of Delta left over and so he might hedge that off But they might have other
stuff in his book that hedges that Delta So,
you know most of the time the guy is not gonna be hedging with shares now if you
let's say he goes into a Super liquid option you might buy he might you know any
and also guys another very important point as well He does the quicker he can turn
over his book the better So what that means is if he can sell you that so there's
something called like a zero tick rule And you know,
this is more like like higher finance,
which we won't talk about today But we can talk about on another life if he can
get rid of that option as quick as possible He's he is happy to do that.
So if he doesn't have to hedge and he can just offset it to someone else as quickly
as possible he's uh He's very happy.
And the other thing we don't know is what's in the market makers book For example,
the market maker might be super long Delta and so by him selling you those call
options He doesn't need a hedge with shares because he's already super long Delta
And in fact,
he wanted you to see he wanted to sell you that call option right to get some short
Deltas So there's a whole bunch of reasons and I think I think there's a lot of
marketing going on You know a lot of raising capital going on in this space,
but it's my opinion I think red has a really good post that we should we should
chat about here So red spent a lot of time ball or ballpark in the ranges for cross
Delta hedging Red as I type this if you don't mind explaining a little bit.
So first cross Delta hedging You don't mind swing that as I read more With more
precise guides I could focus more on trading without having to having to do so much
mental math and guesswork And not compromise how much size I'm using Okay,
so Red I spent a lot of time as well thinking about Delta hedging but I spent a
little bit my time.
I spent a little bit of time thinking about a little bit different the time I spend
on Delta hedging is Do I want to add costs?
Right every time we Delta hedge we add a cost right and there's really there's no
way There's no two ways around that when you trade it's expensive to trade you have
to usually pay slippage You have to pay commission not just coming in but going
out once you put a position on to Delta hedge You also have to pay that coming out
when you close out the position So when we trade we're really it's really a concept
of do we reduce volatility aka hedging?
by increasing Transaction costs and that comes straight out of the bottom line.
Okay, so When we every time we trade it costs money now,
that's always the trade-off variance reduction versus Taking money away from the
bottom line, right? Our expected value is gonna be the same.
So as we all as a lot of you guys are aware of Wow, this lives getting long.
Okay, we're gonna we're gonna we're gonna we're gonna cut it here,
but I'm gonna quickly Quickly share this Okay When we trade an option their path
dependent, right and this is because the gamma is not constant Oh, you know,
we're gonna obviously down the road Hopefully we'll talk about this,
but we might have our P&L go up here. It might go down here.
It might go up here Right.
These are all different paths that we could take but the the the expectancy Okay,
the expectancy of all these paths are right here Okay,
now we have a choice to make we can either one embrace this Embrace that one time.
We're not gonna make money one time. We're gonna make a lot of money Okay,
or what we could do is this we can Delta hedge Which would allow us to have a tighter
path Okay.
Okay variance reduction But because of our transaction costs we drop our expected
value to let's say right over here Okay,
so we reduced our variance But we increased or we decreased our long run expectancy
So I wouldn't be too concerned blue about You know,
when do I Delta hedge right if you if you're can if you're thinking when do I Delta
hedge? That is a totally separate strategy.
What that's basically telling you is that you can trade the underline, right?
If you are having timing if you are timing your Delta hedges You are trading the
underlying and so you there should you if you have an edge in Delta?
You shouldn't be trading the vol because you can make so much more in Delta Right.
So really embrace that is the fact that if you are gonna be Delta hedging due to
you know Some other strategy that you're implementing on top of your vol,
right? It's a second strategy.
And so you should really think about what can I actually trade the underlying on
its own, right? In that case, I think you should you know, and you know,
of course if you can add a vol component to it You know you get double the edge
But I can't speak to the actual strategy of Delta hedging itself. Okay,
I can't speak to and when I say The strategy I mean Treating it as a Delta one strategy.
Oh, yeah, right if you can post to all panelists,
I'd be great So Ram saying can you explain can you explain variance sure Ram so
here you can see Ram Let's take a look at the red paths.
Okay And if you go to the advanced chat I posted about this today,
so right now I'm actually experiencing this Right.
I'm experiencing this but if I Delta hedged I could have experienced this Right,
but that also means that I give up this so Picture this Ram as the y-axis is our
P&L.
Okay,
and x-axis is time Imagine this Ram you buy a you buy a straddle This is similar
what happened to me you buy a straddle and the stock goes up 10% down 30% up 70
% and then at expiration Closes flat closes at your strike. Well,
you're gonna experience this part right here,
right where you made no money But the vol was crazy now sometimes with the same
volatility The stock could have gone like this up 10% up 50% up 70% up 90% and then
you experience this Right where you made a ton of money because you never Delta
hedged so that's the variance in the P&L the day-to-day the variance right variance
meaning like You know is your P&L straight or is your P&L all over the place?
But the end result right the end result if you're let's say buying an option at
30 vol But it's realizing 40 vol. Okay.
Well your end result is gonna be positive But the path it takes could be up here
or it could be down here or anywhere in between Okay,
and the green line is if you decide to Delta hedge, well,
you're gonna reduce that variance You're gonna reduce that variance a ton Now the
more you hedge the less you the more you reduce the variance,
but the more transaction costs So that's why we always say right the transaction
costs come out of the bottom line no matter what those are gone So we have to decide
do we want to reduce variance Right.
So for example portfolio manager at firm is gonna reduce variance for sure But at
the same time he's also gonna pay up a lot of costs So
red was just saying, you know,
basically if you're short gamma you're trading against the market defensively But
if you could pick points to where you know, where's optimal hedging,
you know You're obviously gonna do better and which I agree, you know,
if you can trade Delta one and a vol spectrum You're gonna do phenomenally well
So red just saying like,
you know when you're when you're short gamma You got to be defensive or you got
a hedge like if the market starts blowing through the roof You can't be like,
you know, come on come back come back.
You got a hedge quick When you're long gamma,
you cannot you can you afford to let it run?
Okay guys Wow 915 that was a long one,
but I hope you guys I hope you actually guys got a lot out of this one you know,
I So basically what I what I really wanted you guys to really understand from this
life is you guys are trading the meat Okay,
you guys are trying to find where's vol mispriced is it, you know,
where is Vega mispriced and that is the first order Right, just like spot.
Where's the stock mispriced? Where can I get Delta?
That is the first order and that's where the meat is Right,
and that's where we want to be as retail traders Trying to get the highest return
on capital.
That is where we want to be high highest dollar return That's where we want to be.
We want to be trading that meat So don't worry too much about the third-order derivatives,
I know it's all online I know it's super pumped up and it's super pumped up for
the reasons. We've talked about earlier Okay, and as you guys saw,
you know Trading $100,000 trading a hundred thousand contracts barely changes the
changes the market makers book relative to the overall volume and We don't even
know if the market makers hedging Right, so you guys can see right there.
It's a You know,
it's for me at least I'm very very very skeptical about this Trick is saying can
we do a big live on VIX VIX and VXX chicks? We can definitely do that Koa,
how can I make money? You can't that's the whole part. Uh-huh.
That's that's the caveat to this live that third order Greeks second order Greeks
is Is You know, it's second order. It's third order, right?
It's All our lives cool on first order stuff.
That's where I think you're gonna make a lot of money Red we got it. We got it.
We got you, buddy Okay. Well guys, thank you so much for showing up.
I really hope you guys got a lot of that and And I'll see you later. Yeah,
Neil so you can make money with gamma. Yes,
but Neil remember we really only use Yes,
I agree with that no gamma is probably one of the only one of the only things that
You know,
we can actually Make quite a bit of money from and that's it's not You know,
I'm gonna have to do a whole live on that. Okay,
because it's actually it's It's not really the gamma Okay,
it's not really the gamma guys.
It's really the vol The vol which way the Vega right when you're long straddle you're
long gamma but you're also long the Vega and We'll talk about that in another live
meal I'm not saying guys at the the second or third order Greeks are ridiculous
I'm just saying that I think they're being blown away out of proportion.
Okay?
Awesome guys. I will see you Awesome awesome, you know,
thanks for sticking out guys. Thanks for sticking out. I know it's 920.
You guys are unreal.
Enjoy your weekend I'm gonna crack a beer I'm gonna crack a beer and And enjoy so
see you guys. Take care.