All right, guys. So in this lecture,
we are going to be chatting about our lit position that we took.
And the ticker is LIT. And breaking down the implied vols for it,
as well as building out how to calculate the implied volatility for a portfolio.
Okay, this is actually in the silver exam.
It's the last question on the silver exam.
I think only two people got the answer right for it.
So we're going to break it down in detail today. Okay, so without further ado,
let us jump into the terminal and take a look at this position here.
So maybe start with like how we, how you know, once again,
shout out to Kyle for signaling the trade.
But let's talk about how Kyle was actually,
how he found this trade to start with.
It'd be nice if he actually popped into the lives,
but he's skipping class again.
So the way Kyle structured this position or found this position was he basically
created a scanner for himself. So certain criterias he looks for before he,
to scan through, let's say a thousand equities, right? So he'll scan for,
let's say high implied volatility percentile, right?
Which is called high IV rank in the scanner.
And we're going to actually go over that, go over that scan for you here.
He's looking for liquidity, right? Is this thing at least a little bit liquid.
So when he gets into the position, he doesn't move the market, right?
A lot of the time people think, Oh, if I see an edge, I can just get in. Right.
And we actually see the opposite. If there's a big edge there,
it's usually going to be hard to take advantage of.
So we always need to remember that we've shown multiple times how when we start
scaling into positions, you just see the market maker start to back off, right?
So we really need to always remember that when we're taking these trades.
So he scans for liquidity,
and then he also scans for implied volatility over our forecast. Okay.
So let us jump right into the terminal and see how he did this.
So when we head over to the volatility analyzer, okay.
We'll go to volatility insights.
What Kyle usually does is he scans.
So he wants IV versus our forecast greater than one. Okay.
And this just means that the implied volatility is greater.
The market forecast of volatility is greater than what we're forecasting.
What he also likes to do is he likes to have IV 30 day greater than 30. Okay.
So he likes to have it. So at least there's some type of volatility. Okay.
There's some type of volatility. Average option volume. He likes to have,
I think he has it at 3000, I believe,
you know, I don't know if 3000 is going to cut it, but anyways, well, you know,
just, just for now, it was, but I think it was higher than 3000,
but just for now, we're going to bring that down to 1000.
So at least there's like a thousand options traded on this product daily,
daily. And then what I think he does lastly is flips for IV rank. Okay.
And he's going to start for, so now if we think about it guys,
we have implied volatility over our forecast.
We have at least implied volatility over 30 and we have at least some type of liquidity.
Okay. And right off the bat, these are probably, these are all bio stocks.
So he's probably not looking at that. But here we go right here, right?
Fifth one on the list is, is lit. Okay. So on the second page,
we see it right here and let's break down what's going on. Right?
So we've got the price above, we got the price at 56.
We have the average option volume at 2000.
So 2000 options are traded on average for this product.
The implied volatility is 1.4 times greater than the forecast.
We have the implied vol 30 day above about 48. And we see the realized vol.
So this in the last 20 days, right? The stock is only realized 25% vol.
All right. We see our, our forecast of volatility is 35 and you know,
nothing really else to take a look at here.
The IV rank is in the 90th percentile. Okay. So it's, it's quite high up there.
All right. So now let's, let's break this down.
So obviously stocks been climbing like crazy. We have implied vol 90 day. Okay.
Quite bid.
Oh, you know what guys we're at a, we're on a, let's go to ARK. Wait, why ARK?
Aren't we looking at lit? Oh, sorry. Lit. My apologies.
Do an entire breakdown on the wrong stuff. Could you imagine that?
You'd be like, this is why. Okay. So take this out guys. Right?
We're seeing implied volatility, both the 30 and the 90 day at all.
Like it's the only time it's been higher than this was during the COVID levels.
Right. And you can see that the realized vol it's, it's much further down,
right?
So the stock's barely realizing anything yet the implied vol is through the roof.
Okay. And we can see this here.
If we look at the volatility cone that these wave, you know, these,
these far dated options are extremely bid relative to what it's been before.
So let's actually zoom in on here. I'm going to remove the max. Okay.
And we're just going to look here.
So what we notice is the options that are 90 days out, right?
These 90 day options are a lot more expensive than,
or a lot higher than the third quantile. Okay. So what that means is,
so the third quantile below means that that's where 75% of the data is. Okay.
So if we look at all the data for, let's say a two year period,
which this looks at 75% of the time, it's below about 34%.
And right now it's trading at 46, right? So you can see this,
this is extremely, extremely good.
So I'm going to just going to show you guys one more thing before we start breaking
this thing down.
We'll plot lit here. So we're going to move over to the relative value tab.
We'll plot lit. Okay. Versus we're gonna plot the 90 day options. Okay.
Versus the realized vol. And we're going to see the ratio of that.
And what we notice is this ratio is near the highs, right?
Meaning it's extremely high relative to realized volatility. It's even,
especially if we look and compare that to the past. Okay.
The 90 day divided by the realized vol, the 30 days realized vol, we get this,
this structure. Okay.
You can see that this process looks like it to be mean reverting, you know,
and I wouldn't say it's stationary, but it's definitely mean reverting.
And you know,
we should probably see some type of mean reversion to maybe let's say the 1.1 level,
but we don't, we don't need to end our analysis there. Right.
What we can actually do is compare this to things like the NASDAQ.
Let's look at the NASDAQ 90 vol. Okay. Versus lit. And look at this guys,
right? We're seeing this thing extremely bid relative to the NASDAQ.
And it's funny because there's a few stocks and we're going to go,
we're going to break down lit in a second,
but there's a few stocks in lit that have that are in the NASDAQ.
So just so you guys know, lit is a lithium, a lithium ETF.
So it holds a lot of products.
And let's break this down further. What if we compare lit to let's say Tesla?
You explained Tesla's one of the big holdings. Yeah, exactly.
Tesla's one of the big holdings in lit. And look at this.
Lit is a lot higher in terms of historical ratio, right?
Where it is right now versus where it usually is. Okay.
So we're seeing this thing is just extremely, extremely bid on multiple,
multiple scenarios.
Okay. All good.
So, but with any, every trade guys, we can't just be like, Oh, you know,
this looks like a fantastic trade. Let's go and tell it.
What we really need to do is understand.
What we really need to do is understand this product, right? And Chris,
this might help you answer your question, right? Chris was asking,
doesn't that mean the market is expecting something weird to happen? Yes.
Maybe not weird to happen, Chris, but the market is expecting a huge move,
right? One of the biggest moves ever in the last two years. Okay.
Market's expecting something huge to happen.
So we need to understand what's going on in this product, right?
We can't just be like, you know what? Let's just take this.
It looks pretty good. I'm going to take it right at the end of the day.
We want to get some pretty good size on these types of trades.
And to be able to get size,
we need to be able to stay with the position and to be able to stay with the position.
We need to fully understand it. Okay. So any questions so far, guys,
we're going to be moving on and continuing our breakdown here.
Awesome. Awesome. Awesome. You sure even for the new people,
don't hesitate to ask any questions.
We're going to break it down for you and make sure that you are fully understanding
this along the way.
Yes, Danny. So we are going to that's what we're going to go to and do next.
But so far, guys, summary so far,
implied volatility is extremely expensive on different scenarios against realized
vols, against historical implied vols,
against other assets that are similar to it. Okay,
which we are noticing that lit is pretty expensive relative to everything we're
looking at. Okay. And now that gives us a signal to look deeper.
So we pull up lit and we take a look at it. Okay.
So here is the fact sheet for lit. And we're going to,
we're going to really look at this in depth guys to make sure we fully understand.
So, okay, perfect. So Chris is saying,
and maybe Danny's having this is asking this as well.
Understanding why is my biggest problem.
So I was actually talking to John about this. A lot of the time, guys,
the market is efficient, right?
There's not going to be a trade every single day,
even though recently it's been like that every day, every day, right? Yeah.
Over a year. It's not every day. Yeah. It's,
you're not going to find a trade every day.
If you're finding a trade every single day,
especially let's say on a daily timeframe or a weekly timeframe, the market is,
is being very inefficient, right?
There shouldn't be like this massive amounts of alpha in the world because there
are people like us, there are people like you, right? And when I say us,
I mean, predicting alpha as a team.
And there's people at Morgan Stanley and there's people at Goldman.
Every single day, those guys come to work,
they sit at their desk and they look for opportunities.
And so if there's an opportunity that presents itself,
it's usually going to be taken advantage of. So for that reason,
the market is going to be efficient most of the time.
So if we don't understand why, right, it might be because there is no reason,
right?
Or there's a good reason on why vol is so big or why vol is so compressed.
Okay. So let's take a look here. Let's see what's going on with this ETF.
So we find out, let's see if they have a little explanation about the company,
about the,
okay, here we go. Okay. So this is the global lithium and battery tech ETF.
Okay.
So that is what, that is what this ETF is.
And net asset values is about 1.5 billion. Okay.
Shares outstanding 20 million total expense ratio, you know,
unimportant for us and basically no, no yield, no dividend yield.
So let's jump into it. So what is in this ETF, right? What are like,
what would be driving the vols? And we noticed a few things right off the bat.
Okay. We have Tesla, 10% of the ETF is Tesla. Okay.
And I'm sure a lot of these other companies are pretty,
are pretty big involves as well, but 10% of this company is Tesla.
Now we saw this exact same scenario happen with ARK.
ARK caught such a bid because 10% of that was Tesla, right?
We are going to basically see the S&P 500 move up half a vol point or almost half
a vol point because Tesla is 1.5% of the index. Imagine scaling that by six,
right? And that's what's happening to this ETF. So you have Tesla,
which went from 70 vol to a hundred vol,
and that's driving a huge portion of the volatility for a lithium and, and,
and sorry, and not lithium, but the ETF. Okay. So when we're looking at an ETF,
we need to actually see what's driving the components here.
What's driving the components. So for example,
and I'll leave this for you guys to do, you can do research on this one, right?
What's going on here? What's going on here? You know, let's look,
if we look at the top 10 of top five holdings, right,
we're talking about 40% of the way of the ETF, you know,
so if you can understand these products right here, what's going on with them,
you understand 40% of the ETF.
I think something worth mentioning is half the ETF is in China. Yep.
Another thing to notice half the ETF is in China. So if we were like,
let's say, look at the Chinese ETF, does anyone know what the Chinese ETF is?
No,
no. It's does anybody know what the Chinese ETF is?
No, no. Going once, going twice, Chinese ETF.
There it is. That's the one. Thanks, Steve.
Vol should be up for it. So we see vols are down, right?
So if we really start to break down this ETF here,
we're actually going to start to realize that not a lot of this stuff is bid,
but Tesla is huge. Tesla is really driving the vols here. Now,
before we go and talk about pricing,
before we go talk about pricing an ETF and pricing the implied volatilities for
an ETF in a basket, let us,
let us understand why we actually liked selling vols on ETFs.
So one of the main reason we like to sell vols on ETF is there's no company specific
risk. Okay. Example,
this company or this ETF is not going to wake up bankrupt tomorrow, right?
It's not going to wake up probably down 10% in a day, right?
Because it has this diversification and we see that in the realized volatility.
Okay. We see this diversification in the realized volatility.
If you're selling vol on Tesla, for example,
the thing could gap down 10% tomorrow off some news about the company, right?
This, an ETF is not going to have that. Right.
And that's why we're not seeing this huge realized vol. So for that reason,
we like to sell vol on ETFs, especially, right? Especially when they're misbid.
And sometimes even driven just by one, by one company.
So let's head back to Lit. What also we know, so the more we diversify guys,
the less vol is the less the realized vol is. And we're going to,
we're going to show the math and the example behind it,
but the less the realized vol is, but look at this ETF where we don't just,
this is not the S&P 500 in the U S this is a global company, a global ETF,
right? We are not diversifying just by ticker.
We are also diversifying by country, right? And for that reason,
we get those compressed vols, right? We might have, for example,
China goes on a tear and USD falls. Well,
if the ETF is exposed to both China and U S well, that's also going to,
you know, that's going to offset each other.
They're going to offset each other, right?
And that's going to compress the vols.
So here we have a diversified ETF where implied volatility is a lot larger than
realized. We understand you, we understand mostly what's driving that vol.
It's the Tesla, the Tesla factor. And, you know, we know,
we understand why Tesla is so big. It just got into the S&P, right? We also,
we also did some research on stock twist. Everybody loves this thing, right?
We've got 20,000 watchers, 95% bullish, right? People are,
and also I looked at the call volume versus the put volume and we saw like 10 times
more calls being bought. So it made sense. This whole picture made sense to us,
right? We understood basically what's happening here. Okay.
Do you guys have any questions about that?
We understand the product. It's a, it's a lithium, a global lithium index.
We understand what our risks are, right?
We understand what we're exposed to Steve saying, but you have big realized,
Oh, can't go bankrupt. Can't be bought. Actually,
if a company's bought fall should drop. Yeah. So right. But,
but the realized vol will spike and we'll lose money.
So it can't be bought out. It can't be, it can't go bankrupt. Right.
And for that reason vol is compressed. Okay. So Marcus thing don't,
I still don't understand why it's so bad. Yep. So we're gonna,
we're gonna show that right now, Marcos.
Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Sometimes I still get a little nervous on these lives, man.
Especially when you get these big turnouts, 25 people. Ooh. Okay.
So here we go. So we got this ETF. Okay. We're going to call this ETF.
And before we go over the math, we're going to talk about it.
So this ETF holds two stocks, hold stock one. Okay. We're going to say Tesla.
Okay. And then it holds this Chinese stock. Now Tesla rallies 10%.
Okay. Rally's 10%,
but this Chinese stock drops 10%.
Well, what, what is this ETF going to do? Assuming they're equally weighted,
assuming they're equally weighted, what is this ETF going to do?
Right. It's going to be flat.
So for that reason, okay. If the assets inside this basket are not correlated,
okay. If they were negatively correlated, vol would be zero.
If they were not correlated, right. It's going to be some number less than 10%.
Okay. Vol is going to move some number less than 10%.
They're not a hundred percent correlated.
And that is, and that is the diversification power. Okay.
Let's look at a second scenario.
Tesla moves down 10% and Chinese stock moves down 10%.
Okay. Well now this ETF is going to move down 10%.
Okay. So having these assets uncorrelated is what we want in this ETF,
because that's going to drive vol down and having that diversification in multiple
countries. It's not just like two country guys. Look at this. Oops.
It's not just two countries.
We're talking like seven countries, eight countries, right? Sure. You know,
the top five countries make up the majority, but we still have some exposure,
you know, across the board here. So,
and these countries are very different from each other as well,
which is awesome. We have industry diversification.
We've got industry diversification. Exactly. Right.
So we have equity diversification, industry diversification,
country diversification.
So you saying, okay, to play devil's advocate, this is quite a specialized ETF.
This isn't the spy. A hundred percent agree.
So what we can do is we're going to do some,
we're going to do some raw coding here for you guys.
We're going to pull all of these ETFs. Oh, I need the,
we need to pull, we need to pull the tickers here. Okay.
Can someone look up these? So let's see, Steve, can you look at the,
up the tickers for, let's say these two and then Marcos,
can you look at the tickers for these two at the bottom?
And we need all these tickers. Yeah. And then let's say, who else is on here?
Gilesto. Can you look for, we already know Tesla. Okay. Let me just,
one second guys here.
We're going to do some raw coding guys.
We're going to build the correlation matrix.
Okay. Great. Good. Yeah. Okay.
Ready? Yeah. What do we, do we got them? Do we got the tickers in?
What do we got?
Slacking. Wow. Steven saying ALB. Okay guys, come on. Let's,
let's get the tickers in here.
Oops.
Let's get the tickers in here.
We got ALB.
What else we got here guys?
SQM. Okay. Let's keep it going. One of the top five.
And Marcos is saying GNE NF. I don't know if they're going to have this year.
Let's give it a shot.
If not, we're just going to have to look at the top three guys.
I think we got it. Let's see.
I think we got it guys. Oops.
Cool. Oh, so liquid. Oh my goodness. Okay.
Okay guys, we're in some raw coding here and it always breaks.
As some of you guys know, as soon as you guys know,
code always breaks in live demo.
Okay. What else do we got here? Triswati is having a good laugh at that.
I know, I know. She understands the hustle.
Okay guys, you know what? Okay. Whatever. Hold on. Sorry guys.
Let's see how big, let's see how much data we got for a SQM.
Okay. You know what? We're just going to look at, unfortunately guys,
we're just going to look at a three and, and KRW.
We'll do KRW because the other ones, they don't have a lot of data.
So it's not going to be great if we don't, no, no KRW. Okay guys.
So we're going to go with these ones right here. Tesla, ALB, SQM. Okay.
Unfortunately we don't have time to, to really,
to really extract all the good data here. Okay. So let's do it.
Okay. Let's just make sure we got them all. We got Tesla. You know what?
Let's do a 2018.
Okay. Let's see what we got here. We got Tesla.
You got ALB and SQM. We got that. Okay.
So what we're going to do here guys is we are going to create this new data frame.
We're going to, with Tesla's close, ALB, and we're going to do SQM. Okay.
And what we're going to do is we're going to calculate the returns for these ETFs.
Okay. So let's, let's take a look here guys. So if you take a look,
for example, these are the returns. So Tesla return,
ALBs return and SQM return. So now when we plot the correlation matrix,
okay, here we go. Check this out guys.
Tesla correlation with ALB at the daily level is only 27%.
Tesla correlation with SQM at the daily level is only 39%. Right. ALB with,
with SQM is only 66%.
So it's not like these stocks right now are super correlated. Right.
So now we need to calculate what is, what is the,
what should the implied vols be of this ETF? Okay. And the formula.
Assuming it would be those three assets. Right.
Assuming it's going to be those three assets. Which make up according,
thanks Josta for this. They make up 22% of it. Wow. Wow.
So right off the bat guys, these, you know,
if we add maybe one more of those Chinese ones that are like 30%,
we're at like 30%, maybe even 40%. Yeah. Right. Now that's,
that's like most of the index. Yeah. Top five was 40%. Top five is 40%. So,
you know, you just got to look at the correlation matrix plotting up, um,
put in the vols and out should come the, uh, the index. Right.
We have some form of correlation matrix in the, uh, we do,
we have the correlation matrix in, um, the watch list in the watch list tab.
Okay. So for those of you that don't know, just quickly head over there. Okay.
For those of you that don't know, you head over to watch list,
throw in the three tickers. I don't think we'll have those Chinese ones.
Oh yeah. We might. Let's see. ALB. We do. What was the other one? SQM. No. Uh,
okay. Let's test. Okay. So here we go. Boom. Boom. And the indicators, well,
let's just like IP 30. Okay. Price. Uh, and whatever,
whatever you guys want to choose SKU. Okay. And that, and here's the beta,
right? Here's that beta to ALB that 30%, that 30% beta that we see. Okay.
So here's the correlation matrix. Um,
for those of you that want to use the watch list tab down the road. All right.
That's fine. I built this one for Steven. He hasn't done it. He hasn't used it.
Hasn't used it even once. All right. Let's head back over here.
So we're going to do this. Um,
you're going to do this, uh, with the two asset portfolio right now,
but you could just add a third one is a lot is a lot. It's super easy.
I'm gonna let you guys do this on, on your own time for practice. Okay.
So we're gonna do a two asset portfolio.
And then for the three asset portfolio,
you guys can go and practice that one on your own. Okay.
And you don't need any programming for this.
All you need is a pencil and paper or a calculator. Sorry.
You need a calculator. You'll need a calculator. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
So the formula to calculate this is going to be, so it's going to be,
we're going to put this here. So the, uh, the ball of the portfolio. Okay.
So remember an ETF is just a portfolio. It's just like,
when you look at your portfolio, you have a little ETF, you have a little ETF.
It's like saying, you know, imagine you packaged it up.
You packaged up your portfolio and said, Hey, Sean, Jordan,
you want to invest in it? Want to want to buy this, right? That's what it is.
And seeing some of your returns, we would love to, I'd be buying it. Yeah.
Seeing some of your terms recently, we're going to be buying some of yours.
You look at, uh, Tico's portfolio breakdown. It's just Tesla. Yeah. One stock,
100%, one beta of one. Exactly. Beta of one to Tesla.
You got to change Tico's name to Tesla. I know. Right. Okay.
So it's going to equal to the square root. Okay. Uh, the weighting. Okay.
So we're going to call the weight of asset one. Okay.
To the power of two times the weight of asset two. I'm sorry.
Times the volatility of asset one to power of two plus the weight of number two
to the power of two times vol two to the power of two. Okay.
And then if you had a weight three B plus weight three, et cetera, et cetera,
et cetera. Okay.
Plus, okay. Plus two times. Okay. Two times the correlation between the assets.
Okay. So in this case it is, let's do Tesla and ALB. Okay. The correlation.
So 0.27 times the weight of asset one times the weight of asset two times the vol
of asset one times the vol of asset two. Now make sure guys,
you always square the first bit. Okay. You don't need to square the second bit.
Um, oh, actually instead of pie. And so I'm just going to put P okay. That's,
that's the correlation. Okay. So you would do the correlation of one by two.
Okay. Vol one, vol two, then the correlation of, uh, let's say asset two,
let's say SQM and Tesla times the weight of them times the vols. Okay.
And if you guys are so confused, I want you guys to practice this on your own,
give it a shot. And if you're still a little confused,
reach out to us and we'll do an example in the group.
But I really want you guys to try out, try this on your own first.
So here we go. Square root point. So we're going to,
we're going to put in the stuff now. Okay. So Tesla vol for example, is 0.90.
Okay. And the weighting is, um, we're going to say this is a 50% portfolio.
Okay. So let's say this is 50%.
So weighting squared times the volatility squared plus weighting of asset two squared
times, um, that, that volatility, which I have no clue.
If anyone wants to take a guess, we're going to go, we're going to say 0.5.
Okay.
Plus two times correlation 0.27 times 0.5 times 0.5 times 0.9 times 0.5. Okay.
So what do you guys put a V1 as 0.9? Do you have it as 0.5 there? Oh, no,
you don't. Okay. Yeah. Okay.
So what do you guys think the answer is going to be here? Yeah.
What do you guys think the answer should be? I'm curious. So we got asset one,
50% implied vol asset two, 90% implied vol.
What do we think the portfolio is going to be? There's a correlation of 0.27.
No one with their calculators, no cheating. Just, just our idea,
our thought here. What do we think the answer is going to be?
Steven's saying 60%. Why Steve? Why are you saying 60? Marco's saying 60.
How come guys, why are you guys saying 60?
Okay. Nice. Nice. Right. Okay. I like that.
Now let me ask you this question though. Okay. Let me ask you this question.
And you know, we're going to play around with different correlations.
What do you guys think it would be if correlation was zero?
What do you guys think it would be if the correlation was zero?
Well, Marco saying 75.
Okay. So it's going to be a lot less. It's going to be a lot less.
So let's run this one.
57. You guys were almost bang on. Okay. 57% with the correlation of 0.27. Okay.
Now we're going to drop this down to zero.
We're getting 51%. Okay. So what we're seeing is as we,
as we continue to drop this, as we continue to drop the correlation,
okay. The vols are going to get more, less and less.
Right. And if we increase, if we move this up to one, you get 0.70. Okay.
Which is just basically the average of both.
Okay.
Yes. So it can go below Tico. If this is negative one, watch,
watch what's going to happen when this is negative one Tico.
Imagine these assets were completely negatively correlated. Opposite.
Goes down to 0.2. And in reality,
we're going to see this thing a lot closer to zero.
The reason why this is only 0.2 is because these, the vols on this, right.
0.9 is a little different than 0.5. If we turn this into 0.5 instead, if we,
if we change Tesla vol to 0.5,
right, we're actually going to get zero.
Right. Big fat L.
So moral of the story here, we can actually price the implied vol for this ETF.
And it should be very, very, very similar. Okay. Should be very, very similar,
but we actually have two components here.
We have the implied vols and we have the implied correlation. Okay.
Implied vols and implied correlation. So we might think, okay, well,
the implied correlation is probably way too high on this ETF. Right.
What we could do, for example, is put in all the implied vols for this ETF.
Okay. All the implied vols for each component,
put in all of the realized volatilities or realized correlations, right.
And we can come up with our, our estimate of the portfolio vol, right.
Or we can also find out what this P is, right. Because think about it guys,
we have the weights, we have the volatilities.
And I want you guys to do this as an example.
We have the weights and we have the volatilities.
The only thing we don't have is this P, this P value.
And this is what we call in trading the implied correlation. So I bet you guys,
if you guys were to look at this ETF, okay,
this number is going to be like 0.6 or 0.7 right now. When in actual fact,
it should be a lot closer to let's say 0.2. Okay.
So that is another reason why I bet you this ETF is bid. Okay.
The implied correlation is being bid up.
So we came in here, we sold vol and we're hoping for it to, it to drop. Okay.
And we sold vol through a structure that looked like this.
Okay. Some of you did April. So we'll do April.
I know Pranav did April.
So here's the position we have.
Okay. And we're hoping for vols to drop about 12 points.
And this is what we're going to end up with if we're right. Right. Luckily,
this happened to us with ARK and fingers crossed. This happens to us with LIT.
Make for a nice Christmas.
Steven's saying, so how, so how do you see, how did you see that?
How did you see that? What do you mean, buddy? See what?
Oh, you can just, if you want, we can, you can just do it by hand, Steve.
So you just take the weights. So we know everything here, right?
We know the weights, right? We know the weights of every, every component.
We know the vols of every component. All that we don't know is P.
Now we can have our assumption of P, right? We can do a correlation matrix,
right? And find out what P is,
or we can just plug everything in and see what the market has it for P, right?
Does that make sense, Steve? In the ETF sheets,
do they share the correlation between their assets?
They don't know because there's no, there's no, yeah, they don't show,
maybe actually, I don't think they do. You guys can check.
It would make sense for them to show it, wouldn't it?
Like for an investor to look at. Yeah, I guess. If I want to divert,
if I want diverse, you know,
a lot of them preach like we have diversified exposure in XYZ field.
Wouldn't that be? Yeah, but you can just back out P.
And if you want to do an example, Steve, we'll do one in the group together.
If we can just get, I can't get all the data here for this live.
But if you want to do it,
we can do an example in the group and find the implied correlation.
Exactly, right? The thing is, there's no, there's no, well,
the thing is though, Steve, we actually don't need,
we don't need realized history.
We don't need, all we're putting in is the implied and the weights.
All we need is the implied ball and the weights,
and we can find out what is the implied correlation. Okay. So for example,
if you want,
if you want to do this as exercise let's get all the implied ball data for all of
the stocks in that ETF, even though we might not be able to get it all,
but let's see how much we can get and let's build it up. Okay.
I think it's like, it's like 40 stocks. Let's see if we can get it all.
And we'll build out, build it out and calculate implied correlation.
Cool.
Okay. Okay. That is going to do it for tonight's live.
Still does not tell why it's so bad since Tesla's not even close to all time highs.
Well, Marcos, do you mean all time high in terms of vols?
So Tesla is extremely high in terms of implied volatility, right?
And so that's driving a huge portion of the vol here.
And the other portion might be because of this implied correlation.
Remember Tesla is 10% of this thing. So if we're seeing Tesla at 90% vol,
that's going to be driving this quite a bit.
That's really going to be driving the vol on the CTF, right?
And we might even see some spillover, right?
There's some other lithium stocks that are getting,
they're catching a bid in implied vol terms.
Okay. So it might not be Tesla's at all time highs, but it's extremely high,
right? And that's driving the vol.
We saw one of the reasons why we were easily able to move into a lit is because
we had the same experience with ARK,
right? Everyone was trying to get exposure through Tesla,
either explicitly by buying Tesla or by buying the ETF surrounding it that have
big stakes in it.
Okay. Marcos, did that make sense? I guess to summarize it, Marcos,
we understand this product. That's the first thing.
We understand what this ETF does. Next, we see what is driving vol here. Okay.
And we could do the implied correlation breakdown,
figure out what's being implied in the correlation by the market. Easy to do.
We don't need any coding for this. You can do it pencil and paper.
And then we also know that one of the biggest components in the ETF is that 90%
vol, right? And we know why people are buying Tesla vol.
It's been working out for us so far, but once Tesla vol drops,
let's say below that threshold, that might be gone.
But a strategy that you could build out possibly is find out what is the implied
correlation in a whole bunch of these ETFs, whichever ones have the highest,
you could sell some vol there.
Tico raised his hand. Tico, you want to chat?
These guys are crazy. Okay. Okay, guys. Should we skew it topside?
Because it has the call skew. Oh, topside? Up to you, Tico.
It's really up to you, man. Remember,
most of our P&L is going to come from the level of volatility,
not from the skew.
So we have it like this, Tico. So the 55 is really at the money, right?
This is at the money, the 55. You can see that through the Delta, right?
You can see that the Delta here is about 58, 41. But we decided to sell the 60,
a little bit of upside, and then sell the 55.
Okay. So there's not too much call skew here, Tico, you can see right now.
So we're not too inclined to be selling those. Blessing had a good question.
Why do we do a strangle over a straddle? Yeah. Blessing,
there's no real at the money straddle.
Maybe just pull it up. So check this out, Blessing.
If I do a straddle here at the money,
you can see, Blessing, we got a little bit of negative Delta, right?
We want the stock to go down, right? Stock's trading over here.
We want it to go down. We don't really want that. No, we have no view on that.
So we tried to eliminate it. So we structured it to get rid of it.
And so we did this, right? So now we're flat on Delta.
And then also by going flat Delta,
we actually get to sell a little bit more call side vol,
because we think call side is slightly overpriced.
Okay.
Okay, man, these lives have been going for 50 minutes, 60 minutes.
They're intense. They're intense lives.
I appreciate everyone sticking to the end and I hope you're getting a lot out of
it. Some pretty tough topics,
but we're going to mix it up with some more fundamental topics as well,
just to accommodate for everyone who comes through. And yeah, guys,
we're trying to throw you guys into the fire a bit.
Some of the members here saw the most growth just by getting thrown into the fire.
So Mark was just saying,
I believe our most challenging issues is getting right what is going on.
I think so as well, understanding why this thing is bid, right?
Why is this thing so expensive?
But I think this one is a little bit easier to understand.
Everybody is long ARK, right? I was talking with Koa the other day.
He was telling me about ARK, right? He was telling me,
this thing's a great ETF. Sean was telling me about his friends buying ARK,
but it wasn't everybody buying ARK.
Everybody's like anyone I know who loves tech, they're like, oh, ARK, ARK,
right? So we kind of understand who's buying vol, right? It makes sense.
We understand the underlying components, right? In ARK, for example,
the top holdings were Roku, Tesla, CRM, Salesforce, work, right?
And so these are like the top stocks by retail traders,
right? Exactly. Stephen, it's like all the WSB traders in one ETF,
all their favorite stocks in one ETF.
And so it makes sense that the vol is bid,
right? And it's just, it was so bad that we got in there, said, fuck it,
let's sell it.
So there you go.
And also guys,
something to keep in mind a little bit more for those of you that are doing this,
that want to calculate the implied correlation.
When vols increase, correlation decreases. If it's not always true,
if we're getting, let's say, a down move in the market, you know,
usually correlation starts to increase.
But if the market's not moving and stocks increase in vols,
we usually actually get a decrease in correlation.
Koaw, you dog.
Who is it? This is probably someone who's on their team at ARK. And he's like,
she's not.
We don't know, right? With ARK, for example, it lasted one hour.
It was so funny. So we actually got in the position.
I went to go get a bagel and I get a message from Kyle, like, dude,
look at the vols, check the print. I checked the print,
P&L is already rolling in. So, you know, you have situations like that,
where it's like, it works better than expected.
And then you have times where it could last. Then you have trades like SLV,
where it lasts. A month, two months. Yeah, that was a two month trade, right?
Still printed, but. Took a while.
Okay, guys. Koaw, maybe you two should become acquainted. You can have nice,
long talks about Tesla.
Okay. All right. We're going to wrap it up there.
It was very nice seeing everyone. And we will see you tomorrow.
Have a great night, everyone. See you.