Hey guys, and welcome back to another silver video in today's lesson.
We're going to be talking about my personal favorite topic Which is relative value
now,
this is how I want you guys to think about this topic Imagine you own a $5,000 TV.
You look on Kijiji and it's being priced for $5,000 You then also go to another
website.
Let's call it Amazon and you see a very similar TV being priced for $3,000.
Well, what would you do?
You would sell your $5,000 TV and buy that $3,000 TV and this is how we're gonna
be thinking about relative value trading or imagine we're looking at Pepsi Pep and
this is how the stock moves.
Well, if I asked you, what do you think Coca-Cola would look like?
I bet you would say something like this Because Pepsi and Coca-Cola have the same
industry same market cap same underlying fundamentals They're very similar companies.
So you would expect them to move very similar with each other now imagine a scenario
where we wake up one morning and Coca-Cola trades like this but Pepsi Gets smoked
and is trading down here.
Well all of a sudden we have a relative value situation we can sell Coca-Cola and
Buy Pepsi and and hope for this spread to collapse in the future what we would be
betting on is for maybe Pepsi to come up here and Coca-Cola to move down here in
which case we would make money on our long from buying Pepsi and we would Also make
money from our short on selling Coca-Cola now,
it doesn't have to be exactly like this.
We could also see something Like this Coca-Cola shoots up,
but Pepsi Increases even more so even though we lose on our short position We make
more money on our long position on Pepsi and this is relative value Given one asset
What should this asset be priced at?
So this is what a lot of my trades are actually made of where we're trying to look
for relationships between Certain underlines this is something that is used in the
professional space all the time In fact,
almost all the big option traders use something similar to relative value.
They are Buying one asset and hedging with another asset a lot of professional traders
don't like to have Delta to the market meaning they don't like to lose money when
the market goes down and make money when the market goes up They want to be neutral
So these relative value trades can help with that We don't care what happens to
the S&P 500 the next day the S&P 500 you go up here down here sideways Wherever
as long as this spread closes,
we're gonna make money So these spread trades are not one-offs They actually happen
all the time if we were to let's say zoom in on this part right over here We might
see the spread So, let's say this is coca-cola and this is Pepsi,
right we actually might see this Where we are trading this spread when we get these
gaps in the market we can start buying the one that's moving away and selling the
one that's Remaining high and waiting for this spread To come back together now,
we can also do this in the volatility market Which is where we are trading right
now and we actually find much more inefficiencies and why is that? Well,
anyone compares trade coca-cola and Pepsi.
It's very liquid All the big fund managers are doing long short equity,
but not everyone is doing long short relative value in the volatility space So,
let's see what that looks like We would imagine that Pepsi and coca-cola have the
same amount of volatility And if Pepsi is moving 5% a day coca-cola is probably
moving very similar to 5% a day So we would expect that the volatility would be
the same for both the implied volatility for coca-cola so say IV for coke IV KO
is equal to 20% and Imagine we saw Pepsi implied volatility Was 60% Well,
there's got to be a mispricing here Pepsi should be moving very similar to coca
-cola. Why on earth are they?
expecting a 20% move or 20% volatility and Pepsi is expecting 60% volatility.
It doesn't make sense that the same underlying factors So what we could do here
is a pairs volatility trade We could buy volatility on KO on coca-cola Right,
and we would do this by buying a straddle and we would sell volatility on Pepsi
And we would do that by selling a straddle and the way we would think about it is
if anything were to happen in the market Coca-cola would pay out a lot more than
what we lose on Pepsi And this is what we call volatility arbitrage or stat arm
in the volatility space It's a very reliable way to make money one downside of this
is that To sell a straddle naked It's gonna cost quite a bit of margin So that is
why a lot of the bigger players love this trade because they get access to better
margin, right?
They get access to portfolio margin and you know retail trader might not be able
to get access to that So that's one reason why this kind of strategy is huge in
the professional space So the way you can make money and a lot of time the way I
look at trading is I like to use one What I mean is if Pepsi is trading at 60 and
coke is trading at 20 maybe fair value around here is 40% that is the fair value
for these underlyings right,
we would imagine that the implied volatility of Pepsi at 60% is still pretty efficient
and We would also say that while the coca-cola trade is also probably pretty efficient.
These are both pretty liquid names So what we would do is we would buy the leg let's
say in this case coca-cola and Just trade one of the legs so we would remove the
short straddle and Just buy the long straddle and hope that the volatility is somewhere
in between these So this is what I like to do a lot of the times Another way we
can do this is imagine we have two equities SPY and some illiquid ETF Maybe like
a small cap ETF and we see that the implied volatilities are 20% and 60% Well right
away we would assume that this Option chain is gonna be a lot more liquid.
It's gonna be a lot more efficient SPY is a lot more efficient.
There's more eyes looking at it. There's more liquidity.
There's more hedge fund managers There's more smart people trying to trade SPY and
if SPY is assuming 20% implied volatility and this small cap ETF is assuming 60
% implied volatility And it's very similar to SPY Well,
what we can do then is we can say well, let's sell an iron condor here,
let's sell volatility on this and Hope that This number is correct that the SPY
is the efficient market and that this is the inefficient market and so we can trade
one leg here and we would just for example sell an iron condor and realize this
20% volatility for This small cap ETF.
So this is a lot of what I do I trade one leg usually and I look for inefficiencies
like this in the market So now that we're all excited about relative value Let me
give you an example of a trade that I did and posted with a group and actually some
group members took last Week that was extremely profitable now that we're all excited
about relative value trades Let's actually look at an example that I took last week
with the group that made amazing profits I think we made 25% on this trade in just
two days Now a lot of you guys might be like 25% in two days whoop-dee-doo But that's
25% that we made off of inefficiency in the market.
That's real money This it wasn't a lottery ticket that we decided to you know to
go to church afterwards and start praying This was something that we saw in the
market We took advantage of and we had a high probability of actually winning and
making money So let's dig down and see what exactly we took so IWM was trading at
60% Implied volatility the options market thought that IWM was going to move about
4% on average per day I also looked at SPY Which is a very similar ETF.
It is the biggest 500 companies and the implied volatility was 29% Meaning only
about a 1.8% move on a daily basis now,
this is a huge discrepancy Now think about it guys.
These ETFs are very similar. They move the same.
You can look at it historically They move the same or very close to each other.
This doesn't make sense So what I decided to do was sell an iron condor on IWM.
I sold the 127 141 141 151 iron condor for a total of $7 what
I was betting on was this number 60% being way too large and the S&P 500 is the
most liquid ETF in the world I was assuming that this number was a lot more efficient
than this number So my alpha leg or the leg that would make me money would be this
one So I decided to sell 127 141 151. Oh,
it's not sorry 155 My apologies iron condor for $7 now the next day IWM went from
141 to 143 a $2 move right away This started dropping because the move was not as
large as the market was expecting So we took a little bit of profits on day one
on day two the stock dropped back down to 141 and which we were able to exit this
position at $5 So we sold it for seven and we bought it back for five within two
days Meaning we captured a profit of two dollars So it turned out that this market
the S&P 500 was more efficient than IWM and that this number 60% implied volatility
was way too high It should have been at something like let's say 45% and by doing
so we did a fantastic job of making Some money.
So I hope this real-world example is getting you guys thinking about how you can