All right. So in today's live,
we're going to be talking about volatility as synthetic time.
I know it sounds like a big word, but it's not. And also how that impacts,
okay, let's say us taking a trade before earnings, right?
So just to give a little bit of a backdrop,
we're talking with Ron in our group here, and he placed a trade on Netflix,
okay? He sold some vol on Netflix. And, you know,
he's sold quite a bit of VEGA, right?
But what happened was his P&L is barely moving day in, day out, right?
It's like up 10 bucks, down 10 bucks, up 10 bucks for, you know,
a straddle that should be moving hundreds of dollars, right?
And so in this live, we're gonna explain why that's the case, why that happens.
And I think you guys, it will open your mind. It will open your mind up a lot,
in my opinion. When I first learned this, it was like,
and this is maybe like two years ago when I first learned this. I was like,
wow, okay, wow, is what I said. So hopefully, you know,
everybody at the end of this live drop a wow in the chat. Yeah. Okay, guys,
so I'm gonna draw on the board here. Let me know if you guys can see.
Let me get a darker marker, actually. You know, dark black here.
I got it. You got it? Oh, no, that's a line. You know what,
dark blue should be good. Dark blue will be fine. If you guys can't see it,
just let me know and we'll change that. Okay, so imagine you have a stock,
okay? The stock's traveling like this, okay? And it stops right here, okay?
And let's say that this stock can only do one of two things, okay?
It can only do one of two things. Tomorrow, it can go up 1%, okay?
So we'll call that plus 1%. Let me do that a different color, actually.
I'll do that green. So it can go up 1%, okay? Or it can go down 1%, okay?
What volatility is this? Who's gonna tell me what vol is this?
If you go up 1% or down 1%, what's the vol?
Right, if the stock can go up 1% or down 1%, so the volatility would be?
The one-day IV. Yeah, or the vol. Let's say this stock is,
we're gonna look at it for 30 days into the future, okay?
And it can only move up or down 1%, okay? It's gonna be? Yes, someone said it.
Excellent, 16%. There we go, Stephen said it. Thank you, Stephen. Okay, now,
so this is gonna be the movement tomorrow, either up to 1% or down 1%. Now,
let's say we take this path, okay? We go up 1% tomorrow. Well, the next day,
okay, we can either go up another percent again, or we can come down a percent,
okay? So that's another plus 1, and this is a minus 1.
And we went down this path, right? We can either go up 1 or down 1, okay?
Now, if we continue this pattern, okay? We're gonna do four timestamps.
We're just gonna do four timestamps, okay? If we continue this pattern,
it's gonna look like this, okay? Another one, and then another one, okay?
So this is one path, okay? It's gonna look like a tree, okay?
Bear with me, guys, while I quickly draw this out,
okay?
Okay, you guys see this? This is all the different types of paths. One, two,
three, four, yeah, okay. We'll just call it this.
This is all the different paths that this stock can take, okay? Now, at 16 vol,
so realizing 16 vol, okay? These are the different paths.
So the stock might end up up 4%, okay? It might go up three, it might go up 4%.
Oh, one, two, three, four. It might go up 3%, then down one.
Whatever, we're just gonna go like this. 3%, yeah, okay, 2%, okay? Zero,
negative two, and 4%, negative 4%, okay? And obviously- Tree's not perfect,
we missed a couple of spots. Yeah, we missed a couple of spots.
Tree's not perfect, but anyways,
we're gonna be basically between 4% and negative 4%.
That's where we're gonna end up in four days.
Now, this is volatility 16%, okay? Four days, anywhere,
we're gonna be on this tree, okay? Now, what if we double vol?
What if we double vol to 32%, okay? So now, here's our stock, okay?
You want another color? No, that's okay, I got it. Actually, yeah, actually,
I got it.
So we double vol now, and vol is at 32, okay?
Well, now, what can this do tomorrow? What can this one do tomorrow? Okay,
someone says it perfectly. It can either go up 2% or down 2%, okay?
And then the next day,
it's gonna go either up another 2% or it's gonna go down another 2%, right?
And this could go down 2% like this, and this could go like this, okay?
Okay, we're gonna leave it like that, but basically, we'll call it this, okay?
So it's gonna be either plus 4% or it's gonna be minus 4% in two days, okay?
Now, both of these ended up in the same spot. One, however,
ended up quicker than this one, right? So what happened here? In this,
we increased time and dropped vol, and to get the same result here,
we drop time and increase vol, okay? So we can say here, okay, that volatility,
you guys, here's the wow moment. Volatility equals time,
okay? Increasing volatility is equivalent to increasing time, okay?
Increasing volatility is equivalent to increasing time.
So why do we wanna know this? So first off, is everyone okay with that?
Does everyone understand that? An increasing volatility, okay,
is the same thing as if we increase time, okay? Very cool, very, very cool.
So Eric's saying because it offsets theta.
So this is basically, okay, so what we just did here, guys,
is called a binomial tree, okay?
And this is just saying all the different combinations. Yes,
as we increase implied volatility, what happens to theta, right?
So as we increase implied vol, theta drops. And what's theta?
Our exposure to time, okay? Oh, sorry, guys. Yes, yes, yes, okay?
As implied vol goes up, our sensitivity to the decay decreases, okay?
But theta increases, like the actual overall theta in our portfolio, right?
How much the extrinsic value, not the theta, my apologies,
the extrinsic value increases, okay? So volatility equals time. Now,
why is this important, okay? Why is this important?
So everyone's okay with this? I'm gonna erase this.
Looks good. Okay, great.
So why is this important? Well, let's go back to Ronnie's situation, right?
Ronnie's situation,
Ronnie's situation was, he had a iron condor on, right? And here's today, okay?
Here's our timeline. And here's the event. Now, for an earnings event, okay?
Earnings event's right over here. Or sorry, let's say earnings event is right,
sorry. Let's say, so here's today, here's 30 days from now, okay? T plus 30.
And here's the earnings event right here, okay? Today,
earnings event right here. And well,
if we graphed out the implied move for every single day along this graph,
and let's say we're looking at Tesla, because Tesla's earnings coming up, okay?
It's gonna be 3% move here, 3% move here, right? Et cetera, et cetera,
et cetera. 12% move, 3% move, 3%. Okay?
This is what the option for Tesla is gonna be implying, right? Non-event vol,
non-event vol, big event right here. John, do you know if the glow? Yeah,
it'll be okay. Yeah, have you ever watched it like in real time?
Yeah.
Okay.
That's good. It is what it is. It is what it is, yeah. 3%, 3%, 12%, 3%, 3%.
So what's happening here, right? What's happening here? Well,
this event here is increasing implied volatility, right? Meaning,
what does that mean, guys? If implied volatility is increasing here,
what is this equivalent to?
What is this equivalent to?
Time. Thank you. It's equivalent to time increasing.
It's equivalent to time increasing. Implied vol goes up,
is exactly the same as if there was more time on the option, right?
And just to solidify it, if we have an option that let's say is 10 DTE, okay?
With implied volatility of let's say 30%, okay?
And let's say there's an option all the way over here with 30% as well, okay?
And 120 DTE, okay? Well, imagine this option, okay?
Imagine this option had let's say $10 of theta a day, okay? So every day,
it lost $10 of theta.
If we jack up the vols, okay? If we jack up the vols on this,
theta is gonna increase, okay? Because we have more to lose now, okay?
But the different paths that can go, right? It becomes larger.
It becomes larger.
Just like how this one is gonna have a larger move as well because of that time,
okay? Because of that time element, right?
Increasing the implied volatility here, increase the width it can move, right?
And if we go all the way to back 120 days, well,
there was already a big move like this implied in, right? Right,
so before it was here, like this is the possible tree combos.
And now it's like this, which is equivalent to something that was back here.
Okay, do we all understand that? So what happened here,
what's happening with Ronnie here is when this jacks up, right?
When the implied vol is jacking up, increasing the time, all of a sudden, okay?
All of a sudden, our daily theta, right? What guys,
what does a longer DTE option look like in terms of gamma, right?
What does it look like? There's like zero gamma, right?
There's zero gamma here.
Go out in time guys and look at a 250 day option, look at the gamma on it,
okay? Jack up the implied vols on a 10 DTE option,
and you're gonna see it go from this,
okay? To this, to this brown line right here. Okay, the gamma is gonna drop.
So what this is telling us here is our P and L is gonna be more flat, right?
If we have less gamma, right? We're gonna be, imagine guys,
a product that had no gamma and no delta. It would just be like this.
A straight line. And so that is what's happening with Ronnie's position here.
All the P and L, okay? Because of this massive event,
the gamma is so low and the theta ratios are so low for these parts, right?
That most of our P and L is gonna be dictated,
especially in terms of theta and gamma right here, okay? Right from this event.
Does that make sense?
Does that make sense? So our day-to-day P and L here,
this day and this day and this day, is gonna be very low, right? Of course,
if implied vol drops, we're gonna make money,
but we're not gonna make barely any money from our theta. Okay?
And definitely we're not gonna be making any money from our gamma,
okay? Because this implied vol basically created,
this huge move here basically created an option that would be equivalent to,
if there was no event here, a much longer DTE option, okay?
And so we have to now wait for this event, okay? Now, in terms of,
let's say an event like Tesla, where when we were short vol,
even though we were short February around the event, right?
It was because of this.
We saw a lot of P and L there because this is what was implied, right?
And we thought that these were gonna go down to let's say 3%, right?
The non-event vol was gonna get crushed. Yeah, exactly.
Maybe an easy way to visualize that is if you were to kind of graph what the implied
vol should look like for Tesla, right? Let's say this is Jan here, Feb here,
and then March here, and the event is right here.
Implied vol should look like this, right? Maybe something like this, right?
Or realized vol and implied. But then the market changed and implied this.
So the event became way more diluted in the individual day, right?
The non-event vol raised.
So the event vol became less significant in terms of what dictates your day-to-day
P and L of this two-month option,
right?
Does that make sense? And obviously- And then I guess to wrap that up,
if you wanna give me the brown one, actually. To wrap that up,
what we were betting on was not really this.
We were betting on this coming down back to a more reasonable level.
Just to wrap that up. But our theta here,
our theta and gamma for each day is gonna be minimal.
It's gonna be almost nothing because what's the theta and gamma of a 300-day option?
It's basically nothing, right?
So this straddle that Ronald has on is really only gonna make money after,
or lose money after the event, right? Or if non-event vol collapses, right?
Or increases.
But you're not gonna realize any P and L from the day-to-day movement because a
longer-dated option is not gonna realize any P and L from a day-to-day movement.
Maybe show how... Well,
the reason Ronnie took this trade is because he looked at the terminal and he saw
implied vol at 100, forecast at like 80.
So maybe talk about how this all goes together to formulate the implied vol that
you see. Yes. So we're gonna be averaging it and stuff. So volatility, guys.
Okay, so the volatility is going to be the average of these, okay?
So it's actually the averages of the variance, but we're not gonna go there.
You basically would squarely- Do like a four-day option to show it. Okay.
And you know what, guys? Here, here's another way to think about it as well,
right? As implied vol is volatility synthetic time.
We can take this 12% and break it up into two days, right? Where we now have,
let's say, two 6% moves, right?
So that's how we just broke down that 12% to two 6% days.
And just to solidify how volatility is equivalent to synthetic time.
That's good. So you can erase that out, I guess. Yeah, yeah.
I think that's good for the averages. Yeah,
but show how it becomes the annualized implied vol of the actual option. Okay.
Okay. Just to make sure it's solid. Super brief. Okay, so if we have,
let's say, 1% day,
then let's say negative 1%, or actually, sorry,
let's say every single day is implying for easy, yeah, I guess for easy. Yeah,
do no event and with event. Okay, 1%, 1%.
You gotta work on your way. Oh, man, I know. Okay.
Okay, let's say it's 1%, okay, for day one, okay? And then 1% for day two,
and then 4% for day three, okay?
The volatility for the formula for the option is going to be, right,
so the volatility here is gonna be 16. Well, first,
we'll take the average of these, okay? Let's take the average of these.
And the average is six divided by, so it's 3%. Okay, we multiply three by 16.
Okay, we get 48. Okay, so that's gonna be the vol of the option.
Okay, so you can see how this one big event here,
you know, changes the option implied volatility.
Yes, Brian, that is correct.
I said six divided by three was three.
Okay, there we go. Okay, so this is how we get the volatility, right?
And the trip up that people make is they sell this, right?
Like this is where it gets tricky, right? They sell 32%.
Let's say the market is spot on. Well, on this day, day one,
they only realized 16%, Paul. Day two, they only realized 16%, Paul.
And all of a sudden you're seeing the one, what the hell's going on?
This thing is way expensive.
We're not realizing anything and I'm not making money.
And the whole point of this demonstration and looking at that event in that 30 day
option from before is to understand that this is why, right? In that pricing,
that 32 vol is this 4% day, right? So sure, we've had 1%, 1%.
It's less than 32% implied vol, but we have this day that we need to really,
that things make a lot more sense once we're aware of it and its impact on the option.
We're all good for questions. Okay, perfect.
So do we have any questions about this?
We gotta get better topics, man. Everyone's falling asleep. Yeah. Once again,
co-hosting, how do I profit from this? Well, cool. You sell, if, cool, cool.
It's a good question. Cool. If this, let's say, you know,
let's say you think the implied move should be 10%, right? Well,
then you would want to be buying these options, right?
And if let's say it's 2%, you know, you think the actual, what it should be,
you can be selling these, right? And well, actually,
I think it's time to bust out the three circles.
We can talk about the three circles here. I guess. If you have a view, right?
Remember your three circles co-op, right? And then draw on the level, right?
We have event vol, non-event vol, and market vol, right?
Let's say we have an option here that vol looks like this, let's say.
But I'm gonna use my little graph, right? Let's say this is a 30-day option.
There's an earnings event here.
And let's say implied volatility looks like this,
all right? We're expecting a big move on the earnings day.
And this is the implied non-event volatility, all right?
If you think that volatility looks, should look like this,
well, it kind of makes more sense. You really,
what you think is inefficient is this.
So it makes sense for you to enter here and exit here, right?
You don't have a view on this, but let's say that implied,
let's say that the implied volatility looks like this,
and you think that it should actually look like this.
Well, now you don't just have a view on this.
You don't just think this is inefficient.
You actually think the non-event and the event volatility is overpriced.
Being short vol from today now makes sense because not only do you expect this to
come down or this to be less or realize less, you expect this to realize less,
this to realize less. And all of a sudden trading this 30-day,
even with this event in the middle makes a lot more sense.
This is what we did for Tesla, right? We sold a February vol back in December.
We sold February vol because we didn't think this was overpriced.
We thought this was actually overpriced and this was overpriced, right?
So we could sell a whole event, right? It depends what you have if you want.
Cohen, does that answer your question? And no, Bron,
so what we're saying is he was betting that the realized volatility,
he wasn't betting on the level of implied vol.
He was betting on the realized volatility being less than the implied vol.
But here's the thing, right? We'll go this quickly one more time, right? Well,
as many times as we need to, we'll make sure that we get it.
So here's the thing,
right? Implied vol looked like this, right? There's the event here, right?
This is Netflix. This is Ronnie's Trade here.
And because this move, so Netflix is implying like a pretty big movement.
I can't remember what it is, but they have this big move implied, right?
So let's say this, the non-event vol, the non-event vol would be 30%, okay?
And the event vol is, let's say, 70%, okay? Or like 100%. Well,
when we take all this into account, all of a sudden, the implied vol is maybe,
let's say, 45% or something. I'm making up these numbers, right?
Implied vol is 45%. So this is what is actually going into this implied vol.
But what Ronnie was seeing when he looked at the implied vol was this.
He was thinking that it looked like this because,
and this is what we went over on the call with him,
was that it doesn't actually look like this. It looks like this,
and this big day is giving the illusion of this at a first glance, right?
And then all of a sudden,
it starts realizing what the market actually implied for this non-event vol.
And Ronnie's saying, well, what the hell? It's implying 45, it's realizing 30,
and I'm not making money. So go back to your question there,
whatchamacallit, Braun. The event's not necessarily priced in.
The event just hasn't happened yet. And that's where, what is this?
Have a good laugh. All right, right, and this is, you know. You guys are,
you guys are fine. Okay, you guys get what's going on here.
Yeah, so this big event. This real big event. This big event here was, guys,
was basically skewing all the data, right? But do you guys see how,
when we broke that down into two pieces there,
what was actually being implied and what was actually being realized?
Okay.
Hey, Hutch, wow, I've seen Hutch here, amazing.
So that is what Ronnie was seeing for his trade and why he was like,
not understanding why his P&L wasn't coming in as much as he thought it would have.
Okay,
so any questions about time as a synthetic volatility or volatility as synthetic
time? And the non-event vol versus the event vol. Any questions about that?
Swati's saying, how does this change? If on a particular day,
the vol changes like today's, NVDA Neo News changed the vol. Okay, so Swati.
You wanna erase everything? Actually, no, I think this is good. So this is,
let's say this is today, okay?
So actually, we don't need the screen line here.
Okay,
so Swati, let's say this is, this is what the market was implying today. Okay?
Now, this could change tomorrow, right? This could change tomorrow. Let's say,
for example, a Neo event comes out, we get new information.
And so now the implied volatility of the option is gonna maybe change, right?
Maybe they pre-released the earnings. Yeah, maybe they did something, right?
Maybe something came out in this newsletter and now the market is expecting,
okay, well, now we're gonna probably see higher vol in the next five days.
Then it's gonna drop off. Then it's gonna increase, right?
And then it's gonna have a big day up here and then it's gonna drop off again,
right? Now, we only, this is the whole path that the market sees, right?
And this might, this changed from yesterday to today, right? But we only,
we only see an implied volatility of let's say 80%, right?
We need to dig deeper and look at the lifetime of this option, right?
What is gonna happen over the life of this option? Where are the big events?
Where are the non-events?
And a way to see that is by looking at different expirations, okay? Now,
you know, we're gonna quickly go into this, but this is a gold topic.
We're gonna quickly jump into this, okay?
Let's say, for example, Swati, okay?
Does anyone wanna take a guess on how we can kind of guess the path of the option?
Does anyone wanna try to take a guess how we could view it?
How we could find it, figure a way out around it?
By looking at premiums, not quite, not quite. How could we, you know,
some deep thinking here, right?
How might we be able to find out the path of this, of the volatility?
Yeah, Jekka, it's gold. What is it? Ned and Jekka, what is it? Stephen,
I know Stephen knows the answer.
Okay, so I'm gonna let, I'll save Jekka here, Stephen, this one time.
But Swati, this is,
the way we can do that is by looking at the other expirations, right? Because,
sure, this is today, right? This is today, and this is 30 days from now. Well,
what is the one-week option implied vol? What is the two-week option, right?
What is the three-week, and then what is the one-month? Right,
because the one-month option that we're trading might be, let's say,
80% implied volatility for NEO, okay? But the one-week might be 110%, okay?
So if we know that in one month it's gonna be 80%,
and we know that the volatility is the average, right?
The volatility is the average. Well, if this one's already 110,
then these have to be maybe like 60 and 70, right?
So that's how we can see what the path is, right? So in this case,
it would look like this. Lot of volatility right now, then it drops off,
then it picks up, picks up a little more, and then flatlines. And this,
for this option that sees this whole thing, is gonna be 80% implied vol, okay?
But it's gonna have different paths along the way.
Now, this might change, though, depending on what happened, right?
If it's NEO day, maybe the vol's expected to be very, very high up here, right?
And then drop. And you know what,
why don't we show an example of this in the real option market?
And we'll do NEO.
So then hopefully it'll solidify everything we're chatting about here.
We just need to open up Thinkorswim. Yeah, just give us one second, guys.
Good job, Steven. Oh, Ronnie got it. Good job, Ronnie. Good job, Ronnie.
That's other Ronnie. Good job, Ronnie.
I'll give it to- Good job to both of you, anyways.
I'll give it to Ronnie Squared.
Okay, give it a second, guys. Just booting up here.
You guys are crazy.
Okay, let me share my screen.
Let me make sure no technical analysis on that here. Let's see. Oh,
no technical analysis. There's always technical analysis on there, man.
Those are good. Wow. No technical analysis today, guys. So, Swati,
let's take a look here. Okay? So this one-week option,
we gotta deal with delayed data. Okay, so you can see these one-week options,
for example, have an implied volatility of about 120%.
So let's start graphing this out on the board, okay?
Let's start graphing this out on the board.
Okay, I'll flip it back and forth as we go. Okay,
I think it's gonna be very intuitive for you guys. Okay?
Okay, so Y-axis, volatility. X-axis, time.
We're gonna chunk it up by seven-day periods. One, two, three, and four, okay?
So, 120% for this one-week option. This week, okay?
That's the volatility the market's expecting. Let's see what the next week is.
Yeah.
111, okay?
I'll just leave it like this if we're going quick. Yeah. All right,
and then 29.
29, 110. So, before you flip back, before you show them that one. Yeah,
don't show them that one yet. Wait, is that the? This is the 29. Okay. Okay,
so let's see the last one.
Is this the last one here? It's the Feb 5th. So, 110, okay? So,
if we were to look, so here we go. We're gonna see 120 vol here, okay?
We're gonna see 115 vol here, 110 vol here, and 110 vol in this period, okay?
Now, here's the thing. If we only saw this, right? So,
if we only looked at this option, the one that sees the whole thing, right?
The February 5th, okay? And the February 5th we saw was 110. But the seven day,
right, was 120. So, we know that between 120 and 110, right?
Between seven days and 30 days,
it's gotta be between these two, and that's exactly what we saw, okay? Now,
tomorrow, some news might come out with NEO,
and all of a sudden the market's implying higher up here.
Let's say higher up here, higher up here, and higher up here. So,
that's how it might change tomorrow, let's say, okay?
Or it can come down as well. Does that make sense?
Sure, Aria, we'll do Bitcoin part two tomorrow. Now, you ready for it? Yeah,
I'll be ready for it. Okay. Awesome, Swati, awesome. Any more questions?
All right. So, in that case, we are going to wrap up the live.
Can we do Ethereum?
Andres. Andres, that's the one, eh?
That's the one we should have been looking at the whole time.
Yeah, we need to look at the Dogecoin, come on.