Okay guys, so in today's lecture first off, how is everyone doing?
Hope you guys are doing fantastic.
It's a wonderful day Wonderful day here in Toronto We're gonna be looking over two
things.
So I'm just gonna briefly show you guys what I'm working on right now and Also,
we're gonna be talking about the concept of forward volatility. Okay,
this is gonna be your calendar spreads These are two topics that we're gonna be
discussing today.
So let me just jump in I'm gonna share my screen so This is a really good paper.
I'm gonna link I'm gonna put it in the group That's what I'm working on right now.
And it is basically how to get more value out of a signal. Okay,
so let's say Let's say you have a predictor variable.
So your variable is 52 week high so what you do is you say well at every 52 week
high what happens to the stock afterwards and Let's say when there's a 52 week high
the stock moves up a week after you would say that the 52 week high is a good predictor
of The next week return. All right.
So every time you get a 52 week high you buy the stock and that that is your indicator
Now what this what this person has done his name is David Aaronson What he's done
is he has figured a way to get more value out of these indicators and this is what
I mean So he will take an indicator. Let me just pull it up here.
Sorry guys I'm gonna link the paper down below.
So he will take an indicator like this,
which is the basically the the AAI which is Okay,
I think it's like the investment association where they basically go around They
basically go around to investment advisors and they say are you bullish or bearish
on the market?
how bullish or how bearish are you on the market and they get a hundred or a thousand
investment advisors to give their opinion and They create a sentiment indicator.
So they say well You know 88% of people are bullish but it's investment advisors
It's professionals and they come up with this indicator now This indicator on its
own It's not actually that valuable and there's two reasons why One it's called
there is a trend right it there is um You can see kind of trends right kind of goes
up like this and then it trends down like this down over here So that's one the
other reason it has time varying volatility Meaning it might be more volatile here
than it was over here. So on its own It's not a good predictor,
but if we detrend it Okay,
and we remove the time varying volatility doing some you know,
some modeling we actually turn this indicator Into this indicator and what he finds
is once you actually detrend and remove the time-varying volatility for some of
these Assets or some of these indicators you actually can get a really good prediction
well, not really good because in the market, it's very The edge is very small,
but you can get a pretty good prediction on You know future stock returns.
Okay, so he does it for a couple things, right?
So here's the regular data and then here is it detrended and time time-varying volatility
removed Even does it on the VIX? So you guys might like that one.
Here's the VIX Once you detrend it remove the time-varying volatility,
but you guys can see there's no volatility here But there's a ton of volatility
over here you get this and we can actually use this signal now to get a better Indication
of where the markets going.
So that's what I'm working on right now I Show you guys that we need to join what
is on the the y-axis there Axis here is actually something called a zed score.
So it everything is now turned into How far how far did this thing move away?
Given there's no trend and The volatility is constant. Yeah,
so you turn it into a mean reverting asset exactly and it's these are standard deviations
Zed score is a standard deviation, right? So if we see number two here,
this is a two standard deviation move to the upside Or in this case two standard
deviations away from everything else right,
so we we create it into a stationary asset meaning volatility and the mean is the
same across time And there's something like super important When you're doing when
you're trying to quantitative modeling quantitative trading You're building out
your own products building out your own systems This is gonna be really helpful.
Took me a while to like really get into this stuff.
It's really helpful It's really really helpful. Yeah,
this is like you're two or three or five or never So let's jump into We're gonna
go over forward volatilities.
I think you guys are gonna find this pretty interesting Let me just log into thinkorswim
here guys.
Okay, so while that loads So let's go over to vol trader.
We're gonna look at This term structure here. Okay,
so we're gonna look at Apple Apple had earnings today.
So this is right before Apple's close So we're gonna be looking at data today before
the earnings announcement. What do you guys notice about this?
So this is the so let me explain this first.
This is the implied volatility term structure Meaning how is the why where's the
implied volatility through time?
Okay. So for example,
this is the 10-day implied volatility This is the 20-day implied volatility 60 90
120 to 52 So a really basic way to think about this for the guys that are familiar
with skew like maybe to conceptualize in your mind When we look at the skew graph,
we look across the option chain right,
so we look at like all the different strikes for one for like one set of days to
expiration and We look at how the volatility changes across that surface With the
term structure we're looking this way. So we're looking through time Right,
so one we're looking across all for a given time period and then we're looking at
given the set How does it change based on different sets as we go through time?
Exactly Just so just so what Sean's saying here if you guys want to see it on the
chain itself Co is saying like if you merge the two you get a 3d graph of the The
option. Yeah. Yeah, what ballast of that for sure, right?
No koa saying that actually yeah,
so you actually get a 3d So I'll show you guys what the surface actually looks like
I think we've pulled this up once before Yeah,
it was like a 3d model like a wave or no. We were looking at a Yeah,
I think I think we were looking at that. You're looking like can't remember.
Okay, so this is what the option chain actually looks like Yeah,
Neil those for Boma,
okay,
let's get a local vol model here instead Yeah,
well any any of these are right,
but I thought I saw one that was really good before Anyways, well,
let's take a look at this.
So this is basically gonna be I wish I could make this big guys.
So Here is let's say days to expiration on the on the x-axis here Y axis is implied
volatility. I'm sorry. The Zed act.
This is the Zed axis is implied volatility and This is the y-axis and this is the
Zed axis Okay,
and you can see this is exactly what Apple's what Apple would look like high implied
volatility at the front low implied volatility at the back and Then through time
we and then sorry through the skew.
We see that the calls are much cheaper than the puts Okay,
so this is what the 3d surface This is what the option chain if you were to put
every single option and plot it all this is what it looks like Okay,
and you guys are trading one of these So let's say you come into the options market
and you and you like this one right over here You sell this one.
You're selling this on the whole surface So here we have the y-axis is the implied
vol the x-axis is the days to expiration Why does can someone tell me why it looks
like this?
And I'm so upset. I poured some cereal It's soggy Cereal soggy, but whatever.
Okay. Why does the why is the implied vol surface look like this?
Let's see John do you freeze? Oh, no, I'm here. I'm here. Okay.
I thought you froze Let's just looking at something Okay Event ball in the front
exactly,
right there is a Event that's happening tomorrow and this option is way higher.
But let me ask you guys a question though Let's really try to think about this.
This option is gonna see the event But why but this option is also gonna see the
event why is this one higher Right,
if we look at the option chain this options these options are gonna see the event,
but so are these ones Events tomorrow. This is October.
This is gonna experience the event Why is it that this one we look at the implied
volatility is so much higher, right?
This is 98% and this is only 41 why is it code saying because people are rushing
to be a part of it? Okay Anyone else?
What do you guys think disagree agree with code?
Steven saying IVs calculated per day 10 days one event more than 120 days three
events The further ones are and then shakes is saying the further ones are exposed
to longer-term vol versus tomorrow's one with fall That is mainly because of earnings
Siddhartha saying earning or event vol is currently factored in but not for the
later months Okay,
I think Steve I think Steve hit it I think Steve hit it so let me just pull up the
whiteboard here You got it there So
we're gonna have our front our first week option one week option. Okay,
this option is gonna have five days Actually, we're gonna say three days Okay,
we're gonna call it DTE days to expiration.
You guys gotta get familiar with with the terminology three days to expiration We're
gonna have another option that has 50 days 50 DT Okay,
the implied vol for this Implied vol is gonna equal to 30% here,
but it's going to equal to Guys, I'm pulling up a notepad here.
This is not a big fan.
Not a big fan of that whiteboard What's happening Jordan? Sorry guys.
I'm gonna switch right? I'm not a big fan of that whiteboard.
I'm gonna switch over to white pages here One sec,
let's make that big so we can all see we got option one three DT IV is
gonna be we call it IV one is gonna equal to 80% option 250 DT IV
is good IV two is gonna equal to 30% so we have two options one expiring in three
days like Apple and one expiring in 50 days with only 30% and So some of you guys
are saying it's because everyone's rushing to buy these options Well,
if that were the case What we could do is we could sell these options and buy these
options and capture almost a risk-free profit Leave more like this if this Was was
this if this was factoring in a move?
But this wasn't we could just buy this sell this and we capture we'd capture a free
move Right.
So obviously the market sometimes it does that sometimes they'll give us some inefficiencies,
but very rare so we need to understand what's really happening here and Steve said
it great if you have an option with three days to expiration It's gonna be more
sensitive to that event. Okay?
Let's break it down one step further This option has three days.
It has a 3% move It has a 2% move priced in on day one a 2% move Priced in on day
two and then on day three it has the earnings event Okay,
now what is volatility it's the average of all the days It's the average volatility
of all the days.
So can someone tell me what is the What is the implied daily move on this option?
What is the implied over the next three days? What is the implied daily move?
Yeah, okay, yeah,
I don't know I just I don't know if I cut out or you cut out no no I was waiting
for the guys guys.
What is the what is the implied daily move with an 80% option over the next three
days?
Kyle said it 5% right Raph. Remember it's the volatility Divided by 16.
So in plot, so the implied vol is 16 is 80 we divide by 16 Okay,
and that means every single day the market is expecting a 5% move 5% move and a
5% move Okay. Now let's I'm gonna keep asking You guys questions here.
Does this make sense? Does this make sense?
Apple has earnings tomorrow and the market is 80% vol and it's implying 5% 5% 5
% Does that make sense?
No, it doesn't make sense Right.
It does that doesn't make sense Instead we said it's 2% 2% and then the earnings
event So if the average has to be 5, what is this earnings event?
What is the implied move here? Well,
this has this has to equal 15.
So the implied move here, right? We got five five five Right,
the average has to equal five. Yes, the guys are saying 11 11.
This has to equal 11 so it's 80% because the average is 5% and The missing number
here is the implied move number and that's 11% Costing why are there he's got it.
It's got three DT Now, let's look at a 50-day option Okay, actually,
you know what because 50 is gonna have too many numbers let's just do let's just
do eight Okay, let's just do eight. Okay now What happens if we did like this?
2% 2% 2% Right because these are these days these 2% days are the non event volatility.
It's the non event.
So 2% 2% 2% what we got here 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 And then we have the implied move which
we said is 11% Okay, sorry about this this IV number.
Let's get rid of that for now Okay,
so for the 30-day option or the 8-day option,
can we all agree that this is what it looks like?
Can we all agree that this is what it looks like?
we have seven days of non events and one day of the of the 11% both these options
have the 11% move if it has to be if this Was let's say 5% you could buy this and
sell this This has to be 11% So what's the volatility here?
What is the implied volatility for this 8-day option?
Neil saying 50 Let's see new two four six eight ten twelve fourteen 25 25 divided
by 8. What do you got there?
What's 25 divided by 8? 3.1 3.1 2 5. Yeah, 3.1 2 5 Okay,
3.1 2 5 times 16 Neil hit right on the head 50 the volatility for this option is
50% So it's not because this one's more expensive or people are rushing into this
one. It's because Volatility is the average.
Okay,
just the first thing we have to go with understand before we talk about forward
volatility So,
let me know if you guys have any questions about this Go ahead a very important
question. He's like, okay now, how do we make money with this? Cool I love it.
I love it man. I love your attitude. You always oh, well,
no your practitioner You show me the money. I Like it. Okay.
Does anyone else have questions about this because we need to understand this you
know, I didn't I didn't see your I didn't see your answer,
but it was because the Because it's more sensitive.
It has less days to expiration So the volatility of the event volatility has a bigger
impact on the option price Right, imagine this was a 1 DTE option. Okay,
what would the volatility be of this option?
If if it was a 1 DTE option first first guy gets get gets gets the money Well,
we're traders here.
We gotta be quick What's what's the IV of this option 1 DTE?
It has earnings in it Come on guys one color saying 15. No, it's saying 80.
Oh my goodness. Come on guys. We got this. Come on Really guys?
Are we just throwing numbers here?
Who said it Siddharth Steven beautiful.
It's 11% because it's got the earnings event and Only one day times 16, right?
This is it's just it's just this so the volatility would be 176% Okay,
so that's why you see that's why you see this on Apple.
Oh, I thought you were a mathematician dude. What happened?
only complex equations a no, uh No arithmetic. Okay.
That's why we see this That's why the 100 252-day option is this low still has the
event priced in it But it's it's it's not gonna move the needle when when the event
comes down It's gonna be diluted or it's gonna be diluted by all the other regular
day-to-day activity But this is gonna be the most sensitive So once we're up,
let me see I'm gonna give him one more second Just to make sure you guys understand
it fully any questions and then we're gonna go into forward ball Which I think is
really eye-opening for it was eye-opening for me. Hopefully, you know,
it's eye-opening for you guys Looks like we're good to go good to go.
Nice so What is this concept of forward volatility? Well,
let me ask you guys a question.
Let's go back to the white page Once let's let's say we're looking at this two options
here. We're looking at this One DT one DT option and this a DT e option. Okay,
we're looking at these two right here What is the market implying?
between these events So what happens we look actually we look over here what happens
after this After after this expiration is gone Where is this volatility gonna be
what's gonna happen to it? What is gonna happen once? You know,
even if it wasn't an event, but what's gonna happen once it's gone, right?
Let's look at the S&P that doesn't have this type of term structure Okay What's
gonna we know the implied volatility for the 60-day option and we know the implied
volatility for the 90-day option But what's gonna happen in between 60 and 90 days?
Right think about like this. So yeah,
I feel like Sean would explain this better But I'm gonna I'm gonna try to pull Sean
here and explain this real up explain this good You get to the whiteboard.
So here we are today Sorry, here we are 90 days from now.
Okay,
here's 60 and then here is the future So this is the 90-day option.
This is the 60-day option and this is Zero. Okay,
and let's say the IV for the 60-day option is 30 and this is 40 Well,
what is this telling us? Well,
this 60-day option is saying from 60 days until zero days we are gonna have 30 percent
volatility and this 90-day option is Telling us that from 90 days until zero days.
We are gonna have 40% volatility,
but what about the volatility between 30 and 40?
What is happening in here? Because if we think about it guys,
I should have done this in a different color. I mean Okay,
whatever if we think about it Rosie and then it'll erase the last line. Yeah,
or command Z Do you know how to change color?
Just do it at the top Is it format, uh-huh?
Okay,
so here's this the option now I'm gonna be blown away and be blown away if someone
can tell me What is wrong here? What's wrong here? What is what?
What is misleading between these two options?
I actually might use I might honestly I might stop the live.
I might stop the live and just say go go learn from this person What is wrong here?
Okay. Well while I think of that Sean should I grab my charger?
What are you guys thinking Um,
yeah Jordan go through an example that again Because I when you went away from the
computer, I may have paused the recording and not got that Okay, gotcha.
Gotcha So we got two So Sean, are you saying I should do? This is zero or no.
Yeah losing now. I'll be too confusing now. No, no, no go back Okay,
so here is zero okay over here we have 60 DT Okay,
and we got 90 and I'm not gonna draw as many lines on this this time guys So you
guys can maybe get a little more better picture of it.
So we got 90 DT Actually,
I'm gonna let you guys fill this in This option has IV of let's say 20 and this
has IV 80 so here this option is saying 20% volatility over the next 60 days 20
% volatility and This option is saying 80% volatility over the 90 days okay,
so I'm not gonna I don't think I'm gonna draw.
I think it's gonna be too much So if this is saying 80 IV and this is saying 20
What do you guys think the IV is gonna be in here in this region?
What do you think the forward volatility is gonna be in this region?
Call was saying 120 It's gonna be high.
We don't know there's a formula for it We don't know the exact number right now
Okay,
but it's gonna be damn high it's gonna be extremely extremely high and yeah I'll
do the I'll do the code super quick. So forward vol. Okay,
and guys is the forward vol It's gonna be coming on the terminal as well So you
guys can do calendar spreads is that no one was in gold and we haven't really talked
about it. So It wasn't in there.
But anyways It could be in the couple hundreds. Yeah, it's gonna be huge.
It's gonna be absolutely huge, right?
It's gonna be like and we have it or something. Yeah,
so we said how many 60 and 90 6 So it's gonna be a hundred and thirty five percent.
You can see right down here a Hundred and thirty five percent is gonna be the volatility
inside Inside this region.
Okay,
but over the average over the 90-day period It's gonna average out to 80 Okay,
it's gonna average out to 80,
but we're gonna see 135 here and we're gonna see 20 here.
So to answer Koha's question out. How do we make money on this? Well,
we would look we would say well,
let's let let's take a look at a stock Let's take a look at a stock Okay,
this is this isn't volatility,
but we can pretend this volatility Let's say this is realized volatility and we
notice that forward volatility is only 70 It's only point seven zero the forward
vol. Let's say between the 60 and the 120 option 70 well,
we know Once that option goes once once that one up once the first option expires
The back option is gonna be worth 70 implied vol.
That's what the market's saying Now, let me ask you guys a question.
Does 70% implied vol make sense on this graph Khoa's
saying it's cheap Cheap What we do? Yep. So what can we do?
We can sell the front we can buy forward vol Okay,
that's the answer we can buy forward vol But how do we do it?
We can't go to the market say hey,
give me some forward vol We have to create it.
So we can do is we can buy a calendar we can sell the front and buy the back and
Once this goes as once this gets closer and closer and closer and let's say this
falls off eventually This is gonna get repriced to let's say I don't know maybe
120 110 but you bought it when it was at 70 You bought the forward vol at 70 and
now it's 120.
Okay,
so that's how we can trade calendars to make Make good cash to make good money,
right? We gotta find that inefficiency in the market Obviously,
I'm sure you guys just think just for me telling you guys this is like how do I
do this? Right,
and that's why that's why it can be done right because you can't just go out and
do it You can't even use think or swim to do it. No,
no one's looking at forward vol.
So for that reason You can definitely make money on there,
right it's a relative value play But you're selling the back buying you're selling
the front buying the back you're buying forward volatility for the future So what
do you guys think was I was that eye-opening? Was that really cool?
What do you guys think? You guys think it's really cool Yeah,
the guys are liking it. So it's still a little confused Okay. Well,
that's why we're here. That's why we're here. What are we confused on?
What are we confused about? Yeah,
and like I also get like that sometimes with concepts like this you need to sit
in them for a bit yeah, you know,
it's not like you're gonna like you're not gonna walk out of this lecture and You
know have it down pat But what I do recommend is I'm hoping that all of you have
a paper account at least on the side Try to think of an idea Right.
Let's chat about this tomorrow during the market See if you can find anything and
if there is Then uh, you know,
maybe try and start will help you try and structure trade.
That'll be the easiest way to learn But also Jordan what I was just thinking was
if you want to go back to the terminal and show them Are you able to see this in
the term structure?
No, it's gonna be it's gonna be in the new one. You could bring up the new one.
Yeah, okay Yeah, it's gonna be the new one.
There's actually gonna be a forward full column.
It's gonna be different But there's different forward falls, right?
there's forward vol between the 20 day in the 30 day between 20 in the 90 day between
the 30 day in the 60 between the 60 in the 10.
There's so many combos And so we're gonna have a whole bunch of combos we actually
have a forward ball section for calendar spreads But quickly guys,
what is the you guys take a guess?
What is the forward vol between the 20 and the 50-day option here? Okay,
we're looking at let's just look at the calls here Yeah,
let's look at the calls and let's look at the okay.
What what do you guys think the forward vol is here?
Between the 20 and the 50.
Okay, so is this still the whiteboard guys?
Dude, how the hell did Neil see it then?
Yes You have to be kidding me Nellie took a guess and you got it, right man.
Don't kill me, dude I think I've been sharing.
I think I've been talking sharing my screen sharing the wrong screen for quite a
while Actually, I didn't know you had anything else open. It's so funny.
I thought we were just chatting Okay, fuck you ruined it.
I gotta get a new one. I can't leave That's hilarious Okay. Okay 20 and 50-day.
What is the what is the forward vol here guys between the 20 and the 50?
We're just looking at the calls for the Nasdaq You'll
say 20 again. No, because it's not 20 at this time. Neil. Haha.
Nice try bud Think if thing you can fool me twice a What's the forward vol here
guys super quick?
52 no to pricey 30. Yeah, so Siddharth saying closer It's gonna be above 24,
right because think about like this We're saying this 50-day option is saying this
it's gonna have 22 out of the 50 days It's gonna have 22 days that are 22 percent
volatility meaning in order to get 24 We're gonna have to have something bigger
than 24 for it to average out 22 plus something bigger than 22 has to average out
To 24 and so the forward vol here we just do it super quick and I can send you guys
the code if you want it So we got 22 24 20 50 it's gonna be 25.2 Okay.
So now you ask yourself the question You ask yourself the question in 20 days When
this is gone, do you think the September volatility?
So when it's at 30 DTE now,
do you think it will be 25.2 if your answer is yes There's no trade if you think
it's gonna be 19 Then you'd want to sell the back by the front if you think it's
gonna be 45 You would sell the front by the back.
Okay,
so that is the forward volatility Hope you guys hope you guys learned a little bit
about it So it's you know,
and then you just so let's say like let's say we thought it was cheap Okay,
we come in we buy calendar spread and you guys can see how this is gonna go through
time So let's say yeah, let me just cancel this. Okay,
so you guys are gonna see how this is gonna actually move So let's say we get closer
and closer to expiration.
Okay closer and closer and closer and closer and closer and closer As we get closer
the market starts to reprice that forward fall,
but what's gonna happen back is gonna start pumping up Backs gonna start going up
going up going up. Let's say we think it's 30 vol Should be 30 forward fall.
That's gonna start pumping up pumping up pumping up and we end up with something
like this Okay,
and this is why gold calendars are gold because they're so multidimensional You're
so multidimensional Cool,
so we're gonna leave it at that Hope you guys enjoyed you guys enjoyed this You
know when I first learned about forward volatility, it was very cool for me.
Hope you guys find it cool as well Can you so Koha saying?
Okay, Koha. I'm gonna get back to that then. Okay,
cuz that's gonna be for the end.
Oh wait George Why can't we use term structure for this?
Why can't we use term structure?
This is the term structure to give me a little more info there This is the term
structure, right?
This is this through time volatility through time if you mean like why can't we
use the forward ball?
Okay So you have to be able to calculate the forward ball.
So what I'll do I'm gonna put a forward ball a forward ball calculator So you can
for example have the calculator window right here And then you could see well What
is the forward ball between this and that so you type in the numbers and then that
would come the forward ball?
Right you you can look at it here But I don't have the actual calculator in there,
but I can put it in no problem,
right I'm just guys reminder like this terminal was originally built To get people
excited about trading get people to get into trading right away and start making
money, right?
That was the original Idea behind this terminal the new one though. Yeah,
I wasn't to overwhelm you That's gonna you guys will you guys will be finding new
stuff out about it a year from now Okay,
and then koa saying Koa saying can you explain why vol went from 68 to 42 in seven
days and then jump back to?
Then jump back to 82, so let's take a look Let's take a look real quick,
isn't it guys how amazing is it though that Amazon is Dominates the Nasdaq it dominates
the Nasdaq so much that the move move the whole Nasdaq Yeah The Apple jump to that
right? Yeah, it's unbelievable Well,
it would've been such a good long vol trade guys, and it was cheap.
We should have bought some but We love being short gamma.
Let's take a look koa and actually I'm gonna show you guys how much money you can
make selling vol Okay,
you guys are gonna be blown away blown away Let's take a look.
So koa I never actually jumped backed up and never jumped back up.
It stayed low.
Let's go back to Let's go back to this date Jan 13 Okay,
I know everyone's excited about price and a lot of you guys here now are starting
to get excited about vol I'm gonna get a little I'm gonna get a little more exciting
for you guys. Okay,
and make it a little bit more exciting Okay,
let's see what happens when we sell vol at a reasonably high price on Tesla and
we sell let's say Let's call it November fall just like we're doing with SLV.
Let's say we sold a straddle Okay,
so we have no theta so you can't say realize volatility was low. Okay,
we're gonna be looking strictly at implied vol Look at this guys Look what happens
here?
Our straddle goes from seven hundred and seventeen dollars all the way down all
the way down to five hundred and ten bucks You lose two lose Was it 40% of the straddle
in two weeks in a week and a half a 40% of a $750 straddle in two weeks.
That's that's huge Right.
Obviously you have to put up a lot of money for this But it's just if you're on
the long side Let's say you are you're buying vol you can make 40% on a number longer
dated options have a lot They're a lot more expensive.
So if you make for example on our on our SLV trade We're already up 15% on a six
dollar straddle way back right on a $21 $20 stock So you can make a ton of money
on implied volatility a ton unrealized vol on volatility trading you make a ton
of money It's there There is a lot of money to be made and not a lot of people are
looking at this All right,
you guys know that it's just our group John anything you want to say I'm gonna end
the live there at 650 No, it was good stuff,