All right, guys. So in this video, we're kind of going to go and talk about...
It's going to be a build on from last night's live.
We're going to be talking about the term structure a little bit and how volatility
is actually... and build forward volatility, right? You know,
a lot of us are starting to sell these, let's say, 90 DTE strangles,
180 DTE strangles. And I was talking to a portfolio manager last night,
and he really gave me an idea here.
So I think we should chat about those just because a lot of us are selling these
Vega positions, okay? Right. And remember, the point of these lives...
It may change a little bit down the road,
but the point of these lives is to really immerse yourselves in the world of option
trading and volatility. And that will mean taking on challenging concepts,
sort of understanding what's out there, right? Always remember this.
Things that you're...
It's better to be exposed to these things than not because there's somebody out
there trading them.
There's somebody out there looking at this and making better decisions off of it.
The more information we can gather,
the more we can immerse ourselves in this world,
the better we come out the other side. So as we go through this,
if some of the concepts are a little tricky, two things I'll say, number one,
make sure to ask questions, right? If you have a question,
there's a really good chance that someone else does. And even if it's,
you know, an entry-level question,
that's okay because maybe it leads to a better question from you,
a more advanced question down the road, right? We have to start somewhere,
all of us. And the second thing I'll say is,
don't worry about getting it all this second.
You keep coming to these sessions, you keep watching the recordings.
And over time,
you become the person who just is familiar with these things and you start to see
them, you start to be able to trade them, you know,
and that's really when things will start to click. Yep,
and I think it's very relevant right now, the situation just because...
So one thing we're gonna be talking about is we're gonna be talking about some of
the term structures that we're in right now. So for example, LIT, ARK, right?
Versus let's say another term structure, like it's component Tesla, okay?
Or S&P during good times and during bad times. And really talk about, you know,
how volatility should move, you know, as for the longer dated stuff, okay?
And what the term structure can really tell us. All right,
so there's no questions about that. We're gonna jump right into it. You know,
Sean and I started like to use a, kind of enjoying the whiteboard. You know,
we did pay for the paint job here. So might as well make some use out of it.
Cool, okay. So imagine we're trading something.
Imagine the S&P 500 is in a pandemic, okay? It's in a pandemic.
And we're looking at the term structure, okay? So here's our graph, right?
This can be found in the PA terminal, okay? And over here, we have IV,
implied volatility. And down here, we have days to expiration, okay?
And where this is, let's say, zero DTE. And this is one year, okay?
So these are the one year options. And these are the zero DTE options.
And what we might see during a pandemic is something that looks, well,
what do you guys think, right? If we're in a pandemic, right?
We're seeing a lot of volatility.
What might this term structure look like and why, okay?
So really start to think about that. What might the term structure look like?
And why might it look like that, okay? Not much backwardation. Perfect, Steve.
Okay, so what Steve says is backwardation,
meaning that the near dated options are gonna be really high in terms of implied
vol.
And the longer dated options are not gonna be as high in terms of implied vol,
okay? It might look something like this, okay? Now, why might this be the case?
Why wouldn't the term structure, so let's say this is the 10 days, right?
This is the one year. And this is the, let's say, 20, 30, okay? 60, 90,
et cetera, okay? Why might the term structure not look like this, let's say,
okay? And when I say term structure,
what I'm talking about is the implied volatilities at different expirations,
right? So for example, right now we have the January expiration, the February,
the March, the April, the May, the June, okay?
Why might it look like this during a pandemic,
during a crisis and not like this, where it's flat, where the IV is the same?
Let's say IV here is 60%. Okay? And IV down here is, let's say, 40%.
Why might it look like that? And what is it really telling us?
Kyle, I don't want to ever hear that word again in this chat, okay?
Okay, people are worried about it right now. Okay, interesting. What else?
What do you guys think, right? You know, someone says, hey,
implied volatility is 45, right? Well, implied volatility of 45, well,
does that really tell us a lot, right? What expiration are they talking about,
right? Do we usually see it like this? Do we usually see it like that?
What's going on here?
Marketing desperate times, so there's higher uncertainty. Okay, yeah.
What else, guys? What else? Okay, okay, it's diluted, yeah.
So one reason for this, right, is volatility is mean reverting, okay?
Imagine we're seeing this in implied volatility, okay? Let's say, for example,
or let's say we're looking at realized volatility.
And realized volatility is looking like this, okay? Now, up here, okay,
we'd say, well, this is at one of the highs here, right?
And we know volatility is being reverting.
It probably can't stay at 60 for very long. In the long run, right,
it's going to for sure come back down, right? So we could sell, let's say,
a longer dated option, right, at, let's say, 60 vol, and make a lot of money.
But the real issue is that markets know that as time goes forward, right,
sure volatility clusters in the short term,
but then eventually it's going to come back down and mean revert, right?
So the market knows this, okay? The market knows this,
that there has to be some, there is some mean reverting function, right?
So as we go through time, volatility should come back down to normal.
We can see this clearly by just looking at the recent crisis in 2020,
and also 2008, 2001, all these crises, right? We get huge vol,
and then eventually in the long run, it comes back down, right?
It's pretty easy. Just like when vol is at nine,
it's pretty obvious that in the future, at some point,
it's going to be above nine, right? So that is a main driving factor, okay?
That volatility, as we go through time, eventually is going to come back down,
okay? So that is why we don't see this,
but we're going to come back to this because we are seeing this in certain areas,
and I want to get everyone's opinion on it, okay?
So just a quick note about this mean reverting characteristic of volatility.
This does not apply to stock price, right?
So I spoke to a couple of members recently who had shared that, you know,
I'd asked them like, if today was a 5% up move,
what move are we likely to see tomorrow? And the response was, you know,
a 5% down move because mean reversion. And I said, you're half right.
It's likely to be a 5% move, but we have no idea if it'll be up or down, right?
From just the vol characteristic of mean reversion.
The mean reversion is not the direction, it's the magnitude of the move, right?
So just to be really clear on that, these are vol characteristics,
not directional characteristics of the asset.
And so we're going to come back to this.
We're going to come back to this because it's going to be very interesting when
we start breaking this down a little bit.
We are now going to look at it when volatility is low, okay?
So this is when volatility is high. This is when volatility is up here, okay?
And you know what, just to show you guys, why don't we look at a stock?
Why don't we look at,
can we get the PA terminal up here?
Why don't we look at the actual term structure during the pandemic?
Okay,
so we go to volatility analyzer and we look at our term structure.
We'll go to S&P 500 and we'll go back to, what was it?
We'll go back to March of 2020, okay? March 20,
okay? So here is the S&P 500 term structure, right?
You can see that it's inverted, okay? It's called backwardation, right?
It's very high,
very close to expiration and it's much lower as we go out through time, right?
It goes from 80 all the way down to 33 for the one-year options, okay?
Do you guys see that? Let me just make sure. Let me check the chat.
So Eric's saying, so if the vol is at the bottom,
the market is for sure going to overprice vol due to no way to accurately predict
it. So vol is at the bottom. So low vol, I guess. Okay,
so we're gonna get to that in a second, okay?
We're gonna get to that in one second. Okay,
so we saw how the volatility was during that period, right?
It looked like this, okay? Because volatility mean reverts, okay?
So let us...
Okay, let's say now, okay? We're looking at the volatility here.
It looks something like this. And right now, VIX is at eight and a half,
the lowest ever. The lowest ever, eight and a half, okay?
Mark's asking just what asset were we referring to earlier? Oh, S&P, S&P 500.
S&P 500. SPY, to be specific. So let's say VIX is at 8.5. We're right here,
okay?
So the near-dated option, right? Is gonna be very close to the realized vol,
right? The implied and realized are gonna be very close to each other, okay?
So that's gonna be, let's say, somewhere right here, the near-dated option,
okay? What is the far-dated option gonna look like? Who knows?
Who knows what the farther-dated option is gonna look like?
What is the implied volatility gonna be?
High. How high? How high are we thinking? How high are we thinking, Eric?
Let's say the bottom here is 8.5, okay? And the max here is 80.
And the recent mean is, let's say, 15. Okay, that's the mean, let's say.
The recent mean is 15. How high do you think the one-year is gonna be, Eric?
Near 50.
Stephen's saying 13. Eric, how come you're saying 50?
Mark's saying it depends on the macro environment. 100%. So let's say, okay,
let's give a little more context here. It's 2017, okay? It's 2017.
There's no elections coming up in the near term.
Everything seems to be pretty good, okay? And we've been realizing, let's say,
7 vol, okay? And right now, VIX is at 8.5.
What do we think it's gonna be one year from now? Stephen's saying 13.
Ari is saying 20. I like it. I like it, okay? It's gonna be somewhere like,
you know, volatility mean reverts, right?
So if we look at volatility in the long run,
it should be somewhere near the mean. So it's, you know, as Mark said,
it all depends on the global environment. But for now,
we're just gonna use the mean, okay? So it's gonna look like this,
something like 15, okay? So it's gonna look like this,
okay? And then this implied volatility is gonna be here.
This implied volatility is gonna be here.
And that implied volatility is gonna be there. And this is called contango.
Okay, and so what is this story telling us? Well,
it's telling us that the market thinks in the future, right,
volatility is gonna go up, okay? In the future, volatility is gonna go up.
Because if we look at it, we're down here, right?
And if we know volatility is mean reverting, it should eventually rise, right?
Now, that's not always the case, right? A lot of the times,
volatility clusters for a long period of time, right?
It clusters for a very long period of time. So we might have, for example,
2017, where there's a full year where vol stays at 7.
And these that you could sell, for example, at 15,
eventually roll down to 7 vol, okay? So that's called contango.
The other one we showed was backwardation.
Okay, so now that we know this,
we're gonna dive a little bit deeper and to see,
we're gonna talk a little bit some trick questions, okay?
Some trick questions to really get you guys thinking,
really get the brain flowing. So is everyone okay with this?
Chart is not to scale. Is everyone okay? Because you have 60 on. Oh, Eric. Oh,
yeah, sorry, Eric. Yeah, let's imagine it's 15, okay? It looks like that.
Anyone have any questions about this?
And here, let me just show you what it looks like, okay?
So why don't we go to today? I think vols are low today.
Only got two years pumped in here. So actually, let's go back to,
let's go back here. Okay, so you see that, guys?
See the shape of that term structure there, okay? This is the S&P 500 on 2019,
November, okay? In the future, you know, the market thinks vol is gonna rise,
all right?
So these options out here are gonna be sold or bought at a higher implied volatility,
okay? Now, that's not necessarily bad, right? Because, you know,
volatility does mean revert. But it's something we have to be aware of, okay?
And every single day, right? Think about like this, guys.
Imagine if nothing changed, right? Imagine this.
It's not gonna happen this time. Okay, imagine this. Imagine nothing happened,
okay? Well, this, imagine we sold, imagine we bought this, okay?
Or let's say we bought this one right here, three months out. Well,
nothing happens in one month, right? This is not gonna go here, okay?
It's actually gonna roll down here.
It's probably a bad idea overlapping colors, eh? No? Why?
I feel like it changes the color on this one. I think it's fine. Okay,
this is gonna roll down here.
So we're actually gonna lose money from the roll down, okay?
And there's actually a strategy out there where people sell the front months during
contango, okay? Because then every day it rolls down.
And they buy when it's in backwardation because every time it rolls up, okay?
So that's a strategy that some people use.
Yeah, so that is, that's that. Now, let's get, so everyone's okay with this?
Can someone give me a yeah? We're okay with this?
Yeah, yeah, really good point, Mark. So people, Mark's saying, you know,
selling this, right?
Just going up and blatantly selling this can be quite dangerous, right?
So what people usually do is they do a calendar spread where they'll sell this and
buy, let's say, something back here, okay? So that if there was an explosion,
right? First off, it's not margin efficient. And secondly,
if there was an explosion, well, even though,
remember we talked one of our lives how the term structure moves,
even if there's a blowout, right? We're going to be hedged with the back month,
okay? So that's what Mark is talking about there. Great, great,
okay. So now let's talk about what this term structure implies.
So we're going to go back to,
we're going to go back and visit in backwardation just because some of the stocks
we're trading right now might or might not have backwardation,
but I think it's something we should really talk about here, okay?
So here is a company or a stock that's in backwardation, okay?
Let's say, guys, this 30-day option, okay, is, let's say, 60 IVOL, okay?
And this option, which is, let's say, 60 days out, so this is a 30-day, okay?
This is a 60-day, is 40 IVOL, okay? It's 40 IVOL. So far, so good.
Everyone understands this. We have two options here. One that's 30 days out,
one that's 60 days out, okay? So what is this option?
What is the volatility that this option is going to see over the next 30 days?
It's implying it's going to see over the next 30 days,
okay?
What is the volatility that this option thinks it's going to see over the next 30
days?
Excellent, excellent, Steve.
No, 60. This one is going to see 60 IV, okay? This option right here,
expiring in 30 days, is going to see 60 IV.
That's what it's thinking it's going to see, okay? Now,
what is going to happen to this option though? Okay, so we're trading,
let's say, the longer-dated stock, okay? We're trading the 60 DTE option here,
okay? We're selling the 60 DTE. We're selling the 90 DTE, okay?
What is this telling us here, right? This is very important, very crucial,
okay? Because originally, right, we might think that, okay, in 30 days, right,
this might still be, if nothing changes, okay?
I'm going to go by this super slow. In 30 days, and this is a misconception,
just to make it clear. In 30 days, if nothing happens,
this is still going to be 40 IV. Okay? In 30 days, if nothing happens,
it's going to be still 40 IV. What's the issue with this?
What is the issue with that thinking?
Thank you, Steven. Steven is saying, that's incorrect. This will fall, okay?
And what did, how can we really see this? How can we paint the picture here?
Okay, so let's go back to our graph that we did yesterday.
Let's go back to the graph we did yesterday. And at the end, guys, you know,
stay till the end of this because it's going to all tie back into a couple positions
that we have right now. And how, you know, it's acting very strange.
Okay, let's go back to our thing here. Here, so here is today.
Here is 60 days from now. And here is 30 days.
We know that the IV from today to 30 days is going to be 60. Okay,
we're going to call it 60.
Okay?
And we know that from 60 to today is going to be 40, right?
This option here is going to see 40 IV. So we're going to say 40 here.
Okay, it's going to be 40. But here's the thing, or sorry guys,
the whole life of this option is going to be 40, okay?
The whole thing is going to be 40.
From 60 or from today to 60 days is going to be 40 implied volatility. Now,
here's the thing. We are seeing 60 vol here. We're seeing 60 vol here.
So once this is gone, remember volatility is the average, right?
It's going to be the average. So once the 60 vol is gone, this should drop,
okay? Once this option is going to realize 60 implied volatility,
and then it might realize 20 implied volatility,
giving an average of 40, okay? And this number here, this 20 number here,
is going to be called something.
It's going to be called the forward volatility, okay?
And that's the volatility.
So we have this as the life of this option right here.
We have this as the life of the option here.
But what about the life of the option between here, right?
Between 30 and 60 days? Well,
that's called the forward volatility between the 30 and the 60.
So what we should see once this 30 days are over is that this option that's trading
at 40 vol is actually going to drop to 20 vol,
okay? And so on and so forth of these. Does that make sense? If not,
we're going to go back.
We're going to make sure that everyone understands this concept because we're going
to show you afterwards something that is very funky in the market right now,
okay? So everyone gets it. Are you sure? Is everyone sure?
Please don't feel free to speak up and ask, right?
There's nothing wrong with asking, right? These are very difficult concepts,
right?
I'm sure you can't turn to your friend or your family and talk about these concepts,
right? They're very difficult concepts. So if you have any questions,
please ask. Okay, I'll run through one more time.
Okay, I'll run through one more time.
Okay.
Okay, you know what? I'm going to draw. I got a good way to draw.
I got a good way to draw.
You have two options, okay? Option one is going to see 30 days or option one.
Let's start over. Let's make this nice and clear. Option one and option two,
okay?
Option one is going to see 30 days. Option two is going to see 60 days. Now,
we know option one is 60 implied volatility.
And we know option two is 40 implied volatility.
We also know that option two is going to see what option one sees.
They're both going to see 30 days.
So option two is going to see 60 IV for these 30 days, okay?
So this is going to be 60 IV for this option as well, okay? Now,
what's going to happen the next 30 days after this expires,
right? And this number right here is what we call the forward volatility, okay?
Between these two options.
And because volatility... So there's actually a formula for it.
And maybe it's good that we calculate it right now.
So forward vol is going to be equal to square root. Doing some code.
Doing code mode. Square root, okay?
Volatility one squared times days to expiration of number one plus volatility squared
of number two times DTE number two, okay? Divided by, okay,
DTE one minus DTE two.
Okay, so this is the actual formula for calculating the forward volatility,
okay? If we plug in these numbers here,
we're going to be able to get this number, okay? But for simplicity,
it's going to be very close to the average of these, okay? So this right here,
Jared, is going to be 20 IV. So this option here is 40, right?
This option that's going to see 60 days is going to be compiled of two areas.
One area, 60 IV, the first 30 days. And then the next 30 days of 20 IV.
Does that make sense?
Okay, great. Great. Okay. Excellent, guys. Excellent. We're getting there.
We're getting there. We're getting there, okay? Stay till the end.
We're going to have... We're going to show some of these crazy, crazy markets.
What retailers are... What retail traders are doing to the market, okay?
Stay to the end. It's going to be very important.
You guys can use your analysis right away starting tomorrow. Because I know,
Tico, you're about to ask that question. How can I make money? Okay.
How are we doing for time here? 830. Okay. IV.
And...
Okay, yeah. So let's drop it. Let's draw it again. Super quick. This is 60,
right? This is 40. And this is like, let's say, 20, okay? Once,
when we're looking at this, what we can say here is that once this...
There's something here. Something... There's something happening right here,
okay? Something big. Now, once this is over, this should drop, right?
This should drop once this is over. And so we can actually assume, okay?
We can assume when we see something like that, this,
that if volatility does drop, right? If realized volatility does drop. If,
you know, if nothing really happens over the next 30 days, that these,
if we sell these,
we're going to make a ton of money because the vol is going to drop down 20 points.
It's going to drop down 20 points. So we can assume, right? That, okay,
as soon as whatever the market's thinking is going to end, right?
As soon as volatility drops or if nothing really happens,
we're going to make a ton of money. We're gonna make a ton of money on vega,
right? Now, obviously, if the market blows out, we're short vol here.
It might not work like that, right? We might end up losing money.
But we know that once volatility is gone or slows down,
that this is going to lose a ton of money, right? After these 30 days expire,
this is going to go from 40 to 20,
okay? Now,
let's take a look at something very interesting in real life happening right now.
And I'm going to show you guys on the term. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm going to show you guys on the terminal here,
okay? Let me show you something very interesting right now.
Are you sharing screen? Yeah, I'm going to, and here we go.
Bless you. Okay.
Let's check this out, guys.
So look where we are, okay? We are at the top of the range.
So here's the current, right? Let's get rid of some of this stuff here.
Let's get rid of the max.
So we are at the top of the range in implied volatility.
You can see that right here, right?
But look at this. The term structure is flat. The term structure is flat.
And if we had 120 DTE, it's actually flat across the whole surface. Actually,
we can see it right here. Let's go to term structure, okay? Let's type in lit.
We're seeing this on arc, okay? Okay, this is the 252,
which we don't have the data for it. But you can see here,
all the way up to the 120 DTE, the term structure is flat.
We get a 1% kick down going out in time, out 120 days, right? Let's do an arc.
So what is happening here? Oh, arcs, oh, well, it's a little bumpy, right?
But even then, look, we're going from 55 to 54, 120 days out, right?
So this is pretty damn flat, right? And we can see that here.
If we go to volatility insights, we type in arc, okay?
We type in arc and we're pretty flat, right?
You can see that when we're at the max, at the peak,
we get into some backwardation, right?
Does anyone have a stock that has earnings coming up soon that we can look at right
now? Just to show you guys. Stock that has earnings coming up.
Does anyone have a big, it has to have a big implied move,
big implied move priced in. Who's got it?
Hachi on live? Netflix. Thanks, Mark.
Okay, so do you see that, guys? Do you see it?
So let me just remove third quantile here and max. Okay, so you can see this,
right? The market's saying, okay, there's some volatility here, right?
The event. But once this event is gone, right?
Then we should go back to normal, right? This is going to certainly drop,
right? And we see that, right? The reason why this is 53 is because it has,
it's going to see 62 and then it's going to see something maybe like 40, right?
So that's going to drop after the event. Now, but look, let's go back to lit.
Okay, let's go back to lit.
Here we are seeing flat. It's completely flat.
So what is the market telling us here? The market is telling us that vol,
that this is going to be relatively the new mean, right? Now, not perfectly.
There's other things going on that are in this. But, you know,
in a general sense,
the market is telling us that this is going to be the new mean. Vols at 57.
Okay, vols at 57. That's going to be the new mean. This is happening for arc.
This is happening for lit. Okay, instead of seeing something like this, right?
Remember, right now we are seeing insane volatility.
Look at volatility getting pumped up here. Okay,
look at vol getting pumped up here. Actually, let's go back. Let's go to arc,
actually. I'm actually curious. So this will do this real time.
Let's take a look here. We're going to do this in real time.
Let's see what arc was when we started getting this big vol here,
right around September 15. Let's take a look.
Arc.
Oh, whoops.
Let's go back to September 15. Okay, let's see what it looked like there. Oh,
sorry, guys. I'm on skew analysis with trim structure here.
Oh, it's kind of flat too, eh?
Well, you know what it is? It's the zero mark. That's messing it up.
But you can see we don't even have that much. You know,
we don't have too much backwardation there,
but it does drop off to 47 at the end, right? So let's go back to our tab here.
So right now we're flat, right? We're almost completely flat here.
So the market's telling us that this volatility that we're seeing is going to be
here to stay. Now, what do we think about that, right? Realize vol,
if we look at the graph on the top right here,
we're starting to approach the highs, right?
We see volatility is mean reverting. If I had a longer graph,
we could see that it's mean reverting.
But we're seeing that it's mean reverting.
And right now we're reaching the highs, not even. And vol is looking like this.
So what the market's saying is,
there's no mean reverting feature on this, right? This is the mean.
If the market thought it was going to be mean reverting,
we'd see it come down like this. But we're seeing it flat.
So the market's telling us, this is probably the long-term mean right here,
right? The vol we're seeing right now is going to be the long-term mean.
And so the way that I think about it is, I think this is way too bid.
I think these are way too bid out here, right? In my opinion, 5%, 5% days,
that is the long-term mean. I can't see it.
I can't see how this should be priced to the same vol of this, right?
If anything, we can maybe do a calendar spread where we take advantage.
We take advantage of the realized vol that's happening right now, right?
That's clustering. And we sell some of this stuff, right? We do a, you know,
it's not the greatest in terms of margin, right?
Especially for a T-REC account.
But what we can do here is take advantage of that.
By offsetting it by some quite expensive theta back here, okay?
Like we sell these and buy this. Now, we decided just to sell these, okay?
And that is because we think this is not the long-term mean. And instead,
this should be way down here at 40, maybe 35.
Okay, now we were right, we were wrong, sorry, on lit. But even now,
we're getting back into it and starting to sell some.
So what do you guys think about that? Let's see.
So Mark, I mean, Eric,
I wouldn't say that they don't know what to do with them.
They're just pricing it at that, right? Like Stephen said, had an idea.
The market's saying this is the new vol regime. And, you know,
this is going to be the mean going forward, right?
ARK moving 5% a day is going to be the new normal.
So let's see what else. We've got a couple of statements here. Yep,
so Stephen's saying the market's entering a new vol regime.
That's what they're thinking.
I wonder what it was like in the tech bubble. They don't have,
ARK I don't think was around during the tech bubble.
I think it started in 2015. I was looking at some of the data for 2018.
Parth's saying, when did the market solidify this?
This was my thesis for VIX long. Okay,
so I'm not too sure what you mean by solidify this.
This is just what the market's expecting right now, right? Tomorrow,
for example, well,
at least what we think is going to happen is eventually the market is going to realize,
as soon as realize vol starts to be like, let's say 2% a day, 1.5% a day.
As soon as that happens again, the market's going to realize, wait a minute,
this isn't the mean. The mean is down here, right?
And so this is going to drop, right? That's what we're estimating, right?
As soon as, so you saw today, for example,
vol was 1.5% or the move was 1.5% today. And if that continues to happen,
or it's 2%, if that continues to happen,
we're going to see this drop down substantially.
So I don't know what you mean specifically by,
is that the market solidify this?
And Mark's saying, another way to look at it is even if you're wrong,
the risk should be low as it would be hard to have sustained average vol much higher
than this, right?
Like imagine sustained volatility of an ETF with stocks like Roku, Salesforce,
Tesla, CRSP as the top holders, right? Imagine a sustained vol, let's say 60%,
right? And that's also including the correlation,
like this ETF had zero correlation, was carrying zero realized correlation,
right? So imagine something that's sustained at 60 or 65, right?
It'd be extraordinary. And so that's what Mark's saying.
So it could be a good risk reward trade here.
I think you have Stockholm syndrome. Could you explain to me? I've never,
I've never, do you know what Stockholm syndrome is?
You fall in love with the person who like kidnapped you. Yeah.
So they say like,
the stock burned you so bad that you now like are obsessed with it. Oh, well,
Mark did us really well. Lit did us pretty well. We cut lit.
So it wasn't as bad as it could have been. It could have been disastrous.
So blessing saying,
would you not normally sell front month on a calendar spread? Okay.
So I wouldn't sell it in this situation, right?
The reason why I wouldn't sell it in this situation is that realized vol is actually
quite high, right? Realized vol is actually really, really high.
So this actually might be justified, right? This actually might be justified,
but we think that the term structure should look like this,
where sure there's a lot of vol now, but in the future,
we should get back to normal, right? So I don't want to be selling really here.
I want to be selling over here in a calendar spread. Sure,
you could do it like this, but usually you don't want to be,
you don't want to be by a calendar spread when it's in, when it's in contango,
when it's in backwardation like this,
you want to be doing it when it's in contango. Okay.
Where the front month is dropping, right? The front month is dropping quick,
right? It's, the realized vol is a lot lower than implied.
And so selling that front month is going to do well. In the back month,
it's going to stay a bit. Okay. So this is, so Aria is saying,
but if retail are the ones moving this market here and they just keep buying,
won't it stay a bit? Yeah. And Aria, it's been happening for quite a while,
man. I actually couldn't believe when I saw lit go to,
when I saw lit go to 60 vol in the back, it blew my mind. But that is true,
right? And eventually though, eventually like retail can't,
like it's not infinite money, right? Eventually they can,
so the market can remain rational,
irrational longer than you can remain solvent, right?
And so surely can keep buying, but eventually the buying has to stop, right?
So we need to position ourselves where one, we hope it, you know,
we hope it doesn't last, let's say six months, right? So, but two,
we need to be able to withstand some heat, right?
We need to be able to withstand, let's say vol picking up another five,
10 points. Okay.
So how long would you hold a position like this for like on average,
do you think? Obviously it's until the vol drops or when you're wrong is when?
When I'm wrong is when let's say realized vol continues to shoot up like unbelievable
amounts, right? Because then if we see,
let's say realized volatility moving 10% a day again, right?
Then we can be in serious trouble here, right? Because the reason I ask is,
and I was kind of thinking about this too, right? If you,
if you think you could be holding this for three weeks, how, Ko was asking,
how would you, you know, hedge, what do you wanna call it?
You said things are moving. How would you protect from like a price increase,
right? So like, you know, if equities on average trend upwards, right?
This is a ETF, it should on average move upwards.
Would you maybe structure your strangle a little biased long Delta or would you
just hedge your Deltas? Yeah, so Ko, it really depends on your view, right?
If you want long Delta, then I'm not into the strangle, right? If you want,
so the strangle can give you short vol, short Vega and long Delta.
You just shift the body or the middle up. Yeah,
so it really depends on your view. And in my case, for example,
I'm probably gonna be hedging.
I'm almost certainly gonna be hedging if we get too much in the move.
And Mark said something really good here. So I just want you, blessing,
great seeing you. Oh, sorry, that was Bron. Bron, great seeing you, man.
Have a great dinner.
Oh, a blessing saying it's when you feel sorry for someone who's kidnapped you.
Yeah, or like you fall in love with them or something. Aria,
if you can maybe elaborate a little more on that.
Okay, so Ko, that's a really good point.
Ko is saying ARK can go up another 50% in six months. So 50% in six months,
if you break it down, that's quite a bit of vol. But if you're just going like,
let's say one, like half a percent a day every day, well,
that's gonna be easy to hedge.
And then we should earn money as well because the vol wasn't that high.
And vol should drop, right? If it's only realizing half a percent a day.
So Mark had a really good point here, guys.
The thing we should talk about for a second. You know,
this is in response to someone's question, right? Somebody said,
if retail are driving the market, retail keep buying. If they keep buying,
shouldn't this just stay or get higher? Then Mark responded and said,
sustained buying doesn't increase vol if it's not a sharp jump in prices.
Vol will eventually decline in the midst of sustained moderate appreciation.
So here, this is a really good point. This is a really, really...
And I actually just learned this during the crash of 2020.
So this is a really good point here. So check this out, guys.
During the crash, okay? We all know that when stocks go down,
fixed usually goes up most of the time. And if stocks go down a lot,
VIX goes up. But guess what happened at the very end of the financial crisis,
okay? Of the COVID crisis.
VIX, so S&P was going down, okay? Down, down, down.
And VIX was going up every single day. At one point, okay?
I think this is on March 20th, this happened. VIX, right before March 20th,
VIX was at 80, let's say, okay? And S&P was at 200, okay? The next day,
the S&P went down 4%. Huge move down. But guess what happened to VIX?
It also came down, okay? And that's because,
and I'm sure there was a ton of buying here, right?
I'm sure there was a ton of buying here,
of puts as the stock continued to move down. If the realized volatility, okay?
Remember, VIX at 80, right? Is implying like a 6% move a day, right? Or sorry,
a 5% move a day,
okay?
So even though we realized only 4%, right? And stocks went down,
VIX dropped as well because it couldn't sustain that.
It could not sustain that level. Even though there was a ton of buying here,
right?
We need an enormous amount of money coming into the market to be able to push this
up higher, right?
It's a lot easier to move VIX from 10 to 12 than it is 80 to 82.
It's a lot harder, right?
And I think I just learned that during this crash of 2020, right?
So we always learn something new,
but I think that was a really fantastic point that Mark mentioned.
Oh, no. Okay, here. Oh, not again, guys. Yeah, not again.
Just explain it quick. Okay, yeah, super quick.
The VIX came down even though the S&P went down.
And that was because the VIX was implying an extraordinary move, right?
At 80 and the market didn't move enough, right?
It's a lot easier to go from VIX from 10 to 12 than it is from VIX from 80 to 82,
okay? Or percentage moves. So what's that? 80, 96.
It's actually a linear product. VIX is actually a linear product.
Just because the volatility, the vol of vol increases to the upside,
it looks like it's exponential, but it's actually a linear product, right?
There's actually no convexity there,
okay? So it was a big topic, big live today, guys. All the way till nine, wow.
Wow, these lives are getting intense, man. Yeah, the whiteboard.
It's the whiteboard. These are lectures, guys.
Oh, yeah, Mark? Hey, Renato. Hey, thanks, Mark. Mark, I think you actually...
Mark, were you here for the Bitcoin one?
I think that was a fun one too to chat about.