Hey, guys. So in this live,
we're going to be chatting about how volatility moves through time,
how to calculate forward volatility,
and how to actually trade these calendar spreads. Now,
we're not gonna go in detail on this one on how to trade the calendar spreads because
it is going to be, you know, quite a dense live.
And we're going to start from the basics, right?
We can't start all the way up here until we really set a good foundation here.
Okay. So let us jump right into it. Oh, Dylan,
nice to see you out here as well. Which Dylan is it? Robinson. Oh, Dylan,
what's up, man? Okay. So let me share my screen.
So as you guys are in, you know, bronze, silver,
you guys are really not focused on volatility through time. Okay.
So when I say volatility through time,
I mean volatility at different expirations, right? Guys, think about it, right?
There's, you know, most of the time we're looking at, you know,
we pick like how far out do we want to trade? And then we, we,
we pick the chain that we want to look at.
And then we're looking across the strikes within that chain. Well, you know,
there's gotta be something that can be done with the fact that there's all these
different expirations, right?
How can we take advantage of the fact that different chains expire at different
times? Is there money to be made looking across that?
And that's what we call looking across time, right?
Most of the time we're looking across, we're looking across the chain,
but now we're looking across chains. So like we said, advanced topic,
but nonetheless,
this is stuff that you guys need to know at least at a later stage of your,
your trading career. So let's hop into it.
So we're going to start with explaining how volatility actually moves. Okay.
And so how we're going to do that is I'm actually going to, um,
we're going to price two different options here. Okay.
We're going to price this straddle. So this is what straddle,
this is November 20 at the money, at the money. Okay. November 20 at the money.
And we're also going to price a 238 day option.
So in June, 2021 option. Yeah. So we've got two positions here. Okay.
We have a November straddle and we have a, um, June straddle. Okay.
Now some of you guys will say like, for example, around an earnings date,
you guys will say, Oh, you know, why would I,
why would I sell something that's further back?
It only has let's say 50% implied volatility when I can sell something that's five
days away with a hundred percent implied volatility. Okay. Well,
let's see what happens here. Let's see what happens.
What I'm going to do is we're going to start with this straddle right here.
Okay. The November and we're going to drop volatility by 10%. Okay.
So volatility is going to come down 10% for the November expiration.
So remember guys, each expiration has a different volatility level. Okay.
Why do they have different volatility levels? We're going to get into that.
Yeah. Because different things might happen during different times. Okay.
And we get into why they're also a little bit different. And yeah,
remember that. So volatility is always quoted annually.
So even though these are two different expirations, one is a, you know,
a 30 day option and the other is a 230 day option.
Both will be quoted in annualized implied volatility terms so that we can sort of
compare apples to apples in a sense, right?
Because if we just looked at the price of these two,
the price would be drastically different.
And that would skew our view on what's going on.
We need to think about it about what is this price of this option actually implying
for the stock between now and the expiration.
The way we do that is by looking at it in terms of the implied volatility.
How much is the market implying the stock is going to move in that expiration period
between now and that expiration period. Yeah. So we're going to drop November.
Okay. By 10%. Why are you picking 10% and why are we dropping this? Yep.
Just random number. So we're just gonna say if volatility drops 10%,
what happens? Yeah. So most people will say, well, you know,
if it drops 10% in the front, I'm going to make, you know,
maybe the same amount of money as I am in the back. Okay.
So we dropped this by 10% and you can see, we make $2,500 on this trade. Okay.
Assuming stocks trading here, vol drops by 10%. We make 2,500 bucks.
Let's do the same thing, but in the back month, we're going to drop vol by 10%.
What's happened here. We've made $7,300.
Okay. We've made $7,300. Now we've clearly made a lot more money.
That is because this option has a lot more Vega. Okay. It has a lot more Vega.
So what would be an equivalent implied move change to get an equivalent dollar figure?
So let's see. Maybe if we drop this by, let's say 3%,
we get about the same amount of money.
So the front month needs to drop by 10% in order to be equivalent to the back dropping
only 3%.
Okay. And this is because of the Vega exposure for each of the options.
I think we can explain this really well using the whiteboard draw two timelines.
One that's 230 days, one that's you know,
20 days and show like with the earnings event there and like the whole,
like dividing out like the volatility for each day and getting like how you actually
make up what the volatility is for that option, the daily moves. Did you, Oh,
I see what you're saying. Um,
I think we're gonna do one more thing before we get there,
but we're definitely gonna get there. Okay. Perfect. Okay.
So what's happening here and why is this the case?
Price slices on. Yep. Yep. No problem. Yeah.
Okay. So here is, um, option one. Okay. The 20th, the 20th,
the November 20th Vega is two 58 and here Vega is neck is a 730.
So we get three times more Vega. Okay. Now what we notice here though, guys is,
um, so, so why is this happening? Right. What's, what's going on here? Well,
what we find is that volatility doesn't move linearly or linear, right?
And what that means is if the front month volatility goes up 10%,
the back month doesn't go up 10%. Right. So I'm going to draw this out.
You can just switch it up quick whiteboard.
And just keep in mind guys, this is gold level stuff. So, you know, don't be,
uh, don't be, um, uh, discouraged. Everyone's going to get here.
So let's say we have the term structure. Okay. So here is November.
Here is December. Here is January and here is may of 2022 21 or June or June.
Let's say there's a big, uh, big bang. Okay. Something, something, uh,
president Trump says I'm dropping out of that election. Okay. Well,
what's going to happen here?
This term structure is not going to turn into this.
Okay. This is not what's going to happen, right? This, they all don't move up.
Let's say 10 points. Okay. The volatilities don't all move up 10 points. Now,
why is this the case? Does anyone want to tell me why this doesn't happen?
Okay. Just to make sure we're all on the same,
let's make sure we're all on the same page here. Who can, who can tell us why?
Trump says I'm dropping out of the election.
Why doesn't the whole surface move up the same amount? The event is diluted.
Okay. You want to expand on that? Yeah. We need some more.
We need some more guys.
Neil, what's the answer, man?
Okay. No, no. That is true. That is true. But that actually, that is not true.
That's actually not true.
Dylan.
Okay. Dylan got it. What did Neil say? The news is now not the whole 300 days.
Okay. Guys, volatility is mean reverting, right?
Volatility is mean reverting in the long run. Okay. Volatility looks like this.
So when it's up here, every imagine guys,
when this level right here is up here. Okay.
Everybody knows that in the future, volatility is going to come down.
So what are you going to do as a trader?
Imagine if this went all the way up here as well, the two year options, well,
you would go and sell it knowing with a lot of confidence that you're going to make
money, right? You would go and sell it because volatility is mean reverting.
So what happens is the front month will move up.
So this is what will actually happen. Guys, the front month spikes 30 points.
Okay. Then the back month right here, and then right here, and then right here.
And we look something like this.
Okay. Now we need to keep something in mind.
This option is still going to experience the same.
It's still going to experience the event.
This option right here is going to see the exact same event as this. Okay.
And what do we, what do we mean by that? Imagine from Trump's,
the Trump saying I'm out of this, I'm gone guys.
The next week implied move was 20%. Okay.
The next week implied move was a 20% move. So Trump says today,
I'm out market say next week, there's going to be a 20% move up or down.
This option right here is still going to see this event, right?
Let's think about it. We have a timeline here, right?
Option one expires here. Option two expires here and option three expires here.
All three of them see what's happening today. Right guys.
And then this is where Sean was saying what's happening though,
is that this is being diluted. Okay. This option right here is being diluted.
And what do we mean by dilution? Let's do this.
You can drop here. Nice. Imagine we have, okay. Imagine we have,
imagine we're looking at this option right here and it only has three days until
expiration. Actually, let's say five days,
five days to expiration and the market thinks that the moves are going to be 5%.
Okay. On day one, 5% on day two, actually let's go 10% on day one,
10% on day two, then 5% and 5% and then it starts trickling down. Okay.
Back to let's see what the average is of 2%. Back to the average. Well,
this member volatility, just the average of the daily moves. Yeah.
Like here's a like a real world example to think about how it is, right?
Coronavirus comes out, everyone panics.
There's no toilet paper in the supermarkets,
but today you can go buy toilet paper. What happened?
Initially there was huge volatility. Nobody knew what was going to happen.
Things got crazy,
but then eventually people went back to a relative normal life, right?
There was a curve of like from normal, normal, normal, extreme panic.
And then it slowly trickles back down to no panic.
Neil, can you get, can you get the calculator up quick?
So I got it. Okay. So, so what is the average of these?
How many are there? Five? Yeah. Five 6.4 6.4 6.4 that's the average. Okay.
Now we know the average move and you guys know by now that we multiply it by 16
102.4.
So,
so on the option chain you would see an implied vol for this five day expiry option
of 102.4. Okay. Because that's the average of all the days. Okay.
Now let's look at an option that is 20 days. Okay.
Or imagine we're looking at this one out here, guys, super far out. Okay.
It's called 200 days, 200 days.
Now this option is still going to see this 10% move.
It's still going to see the next day,
10% move and the next 5% and the next 5% and the next 2%.
It's still going to see that, but now it's going to have, so what's that? 1, 2,
3, 4, 5. It's going to have 195 days of 2%. Or 196,
1, 2, 3, 4, right? The fifth. So 196,
196 times two plus five plus five plus 10 plus 10 divided by 200. Yep. 2.11,
2.11% times 16 times 16 is 33.76 equals 33.76.
So if we looked on the option chains, right. And you know,
we looked at the five day expiry, we would see 102.4%.
And if we went all the way down the chain and looked at the 200 day expiration,
we would see 33.76 even though both see that event that's happening right now.
Right. They both see that event. Okay. So this is so important for example,
when we're trying to figure out, um,
non-event volatility and forward volatility, right?
When we're trying to calculate, calculate,
let's say the implied move number for a stock before the earnings event. Right.
That's so crucial. Um, so this is,
this is why guys we see the term structure move down like this. Okay.
Because this right here is the volatility is going to mean revert to the average
of 2%. There's so many days of 2% that that 10% move becomes less significant.
Exactly. Right. In the long, like imagine this, right? Like, um,
you want to pull up the S and P 500 and, and show like how, uh,
the big drops don't even show on the long, long, long, long term. Oh yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Um, yeah, actually I got, uh, yeah, I got a good idea here.
So look at this guys. Okay. If I go, if I go here and I go, can I go one year?
Okay. And we look at the 20 day. So actually we go,
let me go a little longer here. Cause we have COVID in it. Yeah.
Okay. So the blue, the purple line guys. It came in second, Neil.
What'd he say? He said,
I bet you didn't even win the national math competition in China. It's a,
it's a big, short record. Got it. Got it. Okay guys. So here is, um,
the 20 day realized volatility 20 day. Now let's look at the range of this.
It goes up to 60%. I guess all the way up here, let's say 200,
100% and as low as nine or 10%. So that's the range, 200% or 100% to 10%. Okay.
Now let's look at a 252 day realized volatility.
Let's do that. You put 2,500.
I'll look at it. It doesn't go above 40%.
So imagine you saw a 200 day implied move, implied volatility of 100%, right?
It'd be an easy sell, but that, that is why guys,
the volatilities mean reverting, right? In the long run volatility,
we're still on whiteboard. Are you joking guys?
Have we been on whiteboard this whole time? What? Oh dude. Okay. There we go.
Lame. Okay. We're looking down here guys. Purple line.
This is a 252 day volatility, right?
You can see that it doesn't go higher than 45%. Okay.
When we look at the 20 day realized volatility, it goes all the way up to 105%.
Okay. And this is on the S and P here. So you can see that in the long run,
right? Realized volatility, mean revert, and it's, it doesn't go wild, right?
It stays pretty tight, but in the short run it can be all over the place.
And that's why we see that mean reversion in the S and P. Okay.
You can actually see the mean reversion on this even. Yeah. Right.
You can see the volatility mean reverting.
Can we go back to the longer dated one? Stephen's asking.
So Co-op, this is not, this is not. So Co-op is saying,
and the Co-op is actually a really good point here.
Okay. Co-op has a really good point here. He says,
is this why tasty trade strategy works selling high IV? This is actually,
that's something actually really there's a big misconception there Co-op it's because
realized volatility is usually higher than implied volatility when it's,
when it's really, really high. Okay. It there's two things you're trading,
right?
There's the implied vol you're trading and the realized vol you're trading.
It's for a different topic. It's for a different, a different lecture,
but implied vol being high.
Sometimes realized vol can be even higher than that and you get screwed and it,
so it actually doesn't work.
Dylan's asking how can it be up to 100% in 20 days, but only 45% over 252 days.
It's because of that dilution, right? Imagine we were at a hundred percent,
right? Think about, think about this at 100% implied volatility.
The market is implying that the S and P is going to move at 6.25% per day for the
duration of the contract.
Imagine if the S and P moved at 6.25% per day for a year that doesn't exist,
right? So that's why the market's never implying that. Right. But if we did,
you know, 40 divided by 16,
2.5% given the fact that it's going to move like crazy right now for at least the
next 20 days, isn't it realistic that this might happen over the, over a year,
right? Going back down to a reasonable number,
still taking into account the fact, right,
this is not discounting the fact that we're having crazy volatility right now.
It's saying, is it, you know,
what is that volatility going to look like over a longer period of time? Right.
It's like, um, you know,
something bad happens in your life and right now it's really, really rough,
but you're going to mean revert to a, probably a particular level of happiness,
right? You know,
you wouldn't expect that to be the level of unhappiness you have for the next 40
years, you know, or if something great happens and you get a nice dopamine hit,
you know, maybe your, your, your one day top, uh, you know,
expiration option would be extremely high IV, but long run,
you probably mean revert in some way. Okay.
So we're going to show you guys how it actually changes. What actually,
what actually happens. We're actually gonna go through the,
through the numbers.
Okay. So volatility moves in square root time.
And you're actually going to see that if you guys do it,
if you look at the Vega for each expiration,
it actually moves in square root time. Okay.
There's actually a fascinating thing when I first found out about it.
So let's say guys, the 12 month, we're going to, we're going to look at,
pretend that we're looking at monthlies the 12 month.
So the one year option move because volatility is also calculated annualized.
So let's say that's all good. Keep going. Yeah. Okay. Let's say,
I'm just gonna jump on here. Okay. So let's say, so here's the month. Okay.
So we have 12 months. We have actually let's do one month, two months. Okay.
We're gonna go all the way down to 12 and let's say the 12 month contract moves.
The implied volatility moves 2%. Okay.
This option right here is going to move to divided by square root one divided by
12 first month of 12 equals.
Okay. If this moves to, the front month is going to move 6.9%.
We can bring that all the way down.
Oops.
So this one would be two divided by square root two over 12. Oh yeah.
I'm thinking in our, okay. Let's see if I can copy that now.
You can, you can, you can do like a, actually a good idea of bringing all down.
They just change the one number. So you keep talking. I'll do this. Yeah. Okay.
So this is how volatility actually moves and it's actually to a science, right?
And there's actually a lot of guys out there who fade these moves where it doesn't
move in square root time. Okay. So if you're seeing the S and P 500,
for example, it doesn't move square root time.
You actually have these guys that fade that move. Now,
sometimes though there can be kinks, right? Like imagine, for example,
there's an event right here. Well, now it's going to kink like, like, uh,
I can't, I can't really kink my, uh, my forearm, you know,
it's going to kink up a bit, right. Just in this spot.
And it doesn't make sense for this to move up. Okay.
So only this back half would get elevated.
And so we're going to graph this out here. Okay. So this,
where's the chart insert right here.
Okay. So there you go. We get a 2% shift in the back,
and this is how the whole term structure is actually going to move just like that.
And I'm sure you guys are asking me how, why in heaven's name,
does it move square root time? Who's got the answer?
Who's got the answer? Why does volatility move square root time?
I'm going to be super excited when Steve says this,
who's got it. Who's got the, who's got the sauce.
I don't think any of the boys got it here. Come on guys. You got the sauce.
Let's do it. Okay. Neil, my man, right?
Volatility equals daily move times square root time,
right? Volatility moves in a square root fashion.
Okay. So that is why we see this, right? And that's what Neil is saying.
There's 252 trading days in a year.
So we have that that's volatility.
And remember the reason it's one year is everything's quoted annually.
If it was quoted in two years, it would be 504. Wouldn't be 252. I mean,
I guess FSU isn't a, isn't really that bad after all.
They're keeping you at least a little bit sharp. Okay.
So now that we have that guys, what time we got here? 830. Okay.
Now that we have this and it's all recorded, so you have to go back, you know,
and, and, and, and re-listen to it. That's totally fine. Also guys,
if you want to ask some questions along the way, do so right now. And we'll,
as I continue, we will, Sean and I will get back to them.
Where to here? Yeah. I was going to show the terminal. Okay. Do it up. Yeah.
So let's say,
I guess we start with a discussion about what can we do with this information?
Yeah. Yeah. Right. Okay. Okay. I'll show an event here.
How it can be priced into an event. So yeah,
actually that's the best way to explain it. Okay guys. So let's,
let's take a look here. Okay. Let's say we have, okay,
let's say this was 10. Okay. Sorry guys.
We're going to get some numbers to work with here. So,
so it makes a lot more sense.
Okay.
So what does this look like guys? Let me, let me delete this here.
Right.
So we've populated a new implied volatility forecast for each of the months where
the back month is implying 20%. So when do,
when do we see this guys who wants to say it? When do we, when do we see this?
We see the market fear. Yes. Earnings a hundred percent, right?
We see when there's an event, this could be an election, right?
We see this could be COVID could be COVID right. When,
when something's happening right now or if something's about to happen, right.
The market is future looking.
So it's either happening right this second or it's about to happen.
So earnings event, any, any election you know,
any type of severe volatility like COVID you know, the, the,
the 2008 crash you know, any event,
any event that's happening right now or that's about to happen.
Right. So how do we calculate what is implied here? Okay.
How do we calculate what this big move is going to be?
Well, to do this,
we need to figure out what the event is going to be or what's going to happen after
the event. Okay. What's going to happen after the event. So let me,
let me start drawing on here. Okay.
So let's say the event is happening tomorrow. So this is the one month option.
Okay. This is the two month option.
The event is tomorrow. Well, after let's say the event goes away afterwards.
Okay. Let, let, let's, let's pretend we're looking at election fall. Okay.
Right now we're looking at election ball after the election is done,
vols vols over. Okay. So in order to be able to, you know, calculate this,
we need to find out what is the volatility after the event after when the event
is gone. So let me ask you guys this question. Okay. Where is there no event?
Where is there no event?
Event is everywhere. Yes. Okay. Steven event is everywhere.
So that's good that you said that, but now this is a little bit deep thinking.
Okay. And I'm also, you know, I know, I know this is gold guys. Um,
but where is there actually no event. Okay.
And there is somewhere where there's no event.
Let's see who can get this. Okay. Before the event. Yes. Somewhere in the past.
Yes. Yes. But we're looking here. We're looking here.
I know this is guys a little bit, um, higher level thinking, right.
And we're all going to get there. So please don't be discouraged.
But what do you guys think?
Let's give them a second here. See if they can really think about this one.
Buyout way out in the future. Okay. No, one's got it. It's between events.
Sorry. Between expirations. Is there an event between here?
Right. If the event is here, all of these see it,
but is there an event between these days? Is there an event between these days?
There's not, there's no event there.
Okay. And that is how we figure out non event volatility. Okay.
We say we count, and then this is called forward volatility. Okay.
We calculate what is the volatility between these expirations.
And once we figure that out, we have now figured out non event volatility.
Okay. Now I'm sure you guys are saying like Jordan, what the hell?
I'm not a math geek. No problem. No problem.
This is where predicting alpha comes in handy. Okay. So we're going to,
we're going to do an example here.
I hope you guys are excited about this because like this stuff really gets me really
gets my rocks off, really gets Sean's rocks off too. Right. This is where,
and this is stuff that can make you money. Yeah, exactly. Okay. Right.
So how can we make money?
So we're going to go and we're going to talk about that right now.
Open in browser. Yeah. Good. Yeah.
All right, guys, let me share my screen.
This is why Jordan is single. Jordan has more models than all of us guys.
Guys. So this is where predicting alpha comes in. Okay.
So we got something called event vol calculator. I know you guys, I know,
right. I know you guys are excited. I'm excited too. Sean is fucking Sean.
You know, when I showed Sean, Sean would calculate event vol like this.
I was like, Oh my God, he creamed himself. All right. So we're going to,
let's take a look here guys. Okay.
So let's say we're going to go back to our example here. We have 69% for now.
I would love that number. 69% for the first month option.
Oh, here it is. Okay. So I vol front month expiration. Okay. 69%. Okay.
In the back month, right over here. Right.
So what we're looking at here guys is we are trying to calculate what is in being
implied in the options market. Okay.
About this event that's coming up tomorrow or on November 3rd. And to do this,
we have to figure out the implied volatility between expirations.
So let's go ahead and head over to the terminal.
So we got 69% for the first month, 49% for the second month. So here we go.
49% and days to expiration we're going to say is 30 days. Okay. So go 1120.
And we will go December 20 or December 18th. Okay.
And now we're going to calculate. So in this case,
the forward volatility would be only 6.4%,
which is absurd because I
moved it too much in the back.
Sorry guys. Something's off with that. Maybe it's in the back end here still,
but anyways,
yeah. Unless it's, well, you know why.
Okay. There we go. Okay. Cause for, I was putting in the second month as the,
as the first month. So let's say we were looking at something like this. Okay.
So here we have the forward volatility as 48%. Okay.
So that's actually going to be the volatility once the expiration comes down.
Right. Once the event's gone, the volatility in the front month. Okay.
So this is going to drop from 69 to 49 or 48. Okay.
So once we have that, once we know that, okay,
well the front is going to drop from 69 to 48 and that's the non-event volatility.
Right. So the back is probably a drop from 48 to maybe let's say 35. Right.
And we can calculate that. If we look at the next two expirations. Okay.
Then we can plug that in here. So we can say the non-event vol is 48. Okay.
But the expiration vol is 69.
Okay. And the expiration we're looking at is 1023, which is today.
Okay. So out would come. The implied move is only 2%.
Okay. So this is how options work through time.
I'm almost certain I have a bug in here somewhere. All right, dude.
Give me one second. Can you,
can you explain this last part again one more time quickly? Yeah. One second.
Oh, you know what? One second, guys.
Don't change this because it's for the previous example.
I just posted it to our stories. Okay. Okay. Okay. Sorry guys.
Give me one second. Okay. Go. So the implied move for this expiration, right.
For this event that we're looking at is 2% and all of the options across the board
are going to see that 2% move. Just some of them,
the longer dated ones are going to be diluted. Okay.
So that is the implied move and for volatility calculation. Now,
okay, here we go guys. I don't know what happened there. Not too sure.
So you have 69, 48. Okay. We have front month,
which is one month out and back month, which is two months out.
We calculate it and the forward volatility is 25%. Okay.
This makes a lot more sense guys. No bugs. We're good.
Here's the front month, which is 69%. Here's the back month. Which is 48%.
We calculate for volatility. That's 25%. That's where the non-event vol is.
So we have 25%. It's going to be a big implied move number.
We have 69% for the total volatility. And then we have 1120. We calculate it.
Boom. So now the implied move is actually 14% and the event volatility is 341.
Okay.
So that is, that is your, our first lesson on event vol,
non-event volatility for volatility and calendar spreads. Right.
And we can trade. Oh, I guess we didn't get,
we didn't really touch on calendar spreads.
Calendar spreads can take advantage of that, right?
Calendar spreads can take advantage of the mispriced,
the mispriced expirations. Okay. Let's say for example,
you think that in one month, okay, here's a perfect example with JD. Okay.
Neil's JD. You think that the back month, once earnings is confirmed,
this back month implied vol is going to increase. Okay.
From let's say 48 to 60. Okay.
Well, you have to basically price out. Well, how's my asset going to change?
How's my calendar spread going to change? Right. And lucky for you guys,
we got, you know, we built out, it's crazy, man.
Every time there's always a new bug. Yeah.
As soon as you like go in and share it with someone, it bugs out.
Man.
But anyways, guys, so that is our that's our first introduction to part one.
How volatility moves through time. Okay. Let's stop the recording here.