Oh, man. Okay. Recording. Thanks, Eric. Dude. Brilliant.
Sean already killed me. Okay. Wow. We got some cool answers here. Okay.
So in percentage returns. So blessing is saying 8%. Okay. So daily,
daily blessing. Marcos is saying 0.4%. So Marcos.
Okay. So 0.4%. Okay. So okay. Steve's saying 0.007%. Koaw is saying 0.02%.
Okay. Okay. Ains is saying 0.3%. 0.03%. Let's see if someone...
Trent's saying 0.006%. Okay. Who had the lowest? Here it is. Trent.
There it is. Trent's saying 0.003%. Let's take a look, guys.
Let's take a look. 0.0002%. So what does this mean? What does this mean?
It means every single day. So while you're holding equity,
let's say I go buy the S&P 500 today. Every single day,
I am making this much money. Okay. For 0.0002%. So if I have, let's say,
$100,000 invested. Okay. I have $100,000 invested.
Then every single day, I'm making about $286.
Was that $100,000 or was that a million? That was a million.
If I have a million dollars invested, okay, every single day,
I make on average $286.
Now,
here's a really tough one, guys.
What do you think the most frequent return is going to be?
Like what is the median return? What is... So if we hold equity here, okay,
we're holding equity every single day. On average, we're going to make $286.
Some days, we're going to make $1,000. Some days, we're going to lose $8,000,
okay, if we have a million dollars of equity.
What do you think the most frequent return is going to be?
What do you guys think? Higher or lower than $286 a day?
What do you guys think here?
Sorry, guys. I got to move the chat over here. I can't see you guys. Hi. Hi.
Hi. Who's saying lower? Blessing. Blessing. It's higher.
It's going to be higher.
Blessing is always spot on with these. She must have had a busy day today.
Okay. So if we take the median, right, we take the median of the RETs,
of the RETs, okay, it's going to be 0.0006.
So almost three times more than the mean. Now, why is that the case? Why...
So if we took the median, okay, so we multiply that by a million, okay,
so 50%... So the median tells us the 50% mark, right? So 50% of the days,
we're going to be more than $634. And 50% of the days,
we're going to be less than $634. Okay. Now, why would that be the case?
Thank you. Thanks, Steven. Okay. It's because there's a big left tail,
meaning that stonks can go down fast, right? So because of that,
because the stocks go down fast, right,
you're going to get paid a risk premium, right? Because stocks can go down 50%,
you are going to get paid a risk premium. Otherwise,
why in God's name would you hold the stock, right?
Why would you buy stock if when you lose your job, equities go down as well?
You lose your portfolio, right? Think about this. When you lose your job,
the market's usually going down.
So why in God's name would I basically buy something where I'm going to lose my
job? And when I lose my job, I'm also going to lose my money and my portfolio.
It doesn't make sense. So, you know,
you're going to get paid an equity risk premium.
And if we do this, guys, check this out, okay? If we go, you know,
if we sum up the average,
if we cumulatively sum up those returns, right? Those returns that we just had,
we plot them.
Yeah, Tico, you see, I think Sean needs a new computer, man.
I think Sean needs the new computer, Tico.
Oh, you know what, Tico? I think this is the answer.
And the reason why I'm talking to Tico there is just because we had a little call.
So there you go, right? When we add up those returns,
we find that we get the equity price or the S&P 500.
So everyone understands equity risk premium because we're going to jump over to
variance risk premium.
Yeah, exactly. Right, Marcos?
So you add up all those little small days at the end of the year,
and you're going to get, right? Check this out. 0.00, what was it? 2.8, Marcos?
2.8 to the power of, or sorry,
okay? This is going to be very cool for you guys.
To the power of 252 trading days in the year, check this out, 0.0738, right?
There's that equity risk premium right there, right?
This is what you're going to get paid on at the end of the day.
If let's say your risk premium, let's say you made 0.002, okay?
Let's see how rich you would be at the end of the year. Steve B,
you ready for this one? Here we go. You double your money, right?
So just making a 20th of a percent every day would give you a huge return at the
end of the year, okay? So obviously, if we can find risk premiums, right?
That give us a little bit more money, but we're going to make quite a bit.
We're going to make quite a bit of money.
So we're going back to what Blessing was saying there.
It means you make a lot of money.
So let us get symbols, okay? We're going to do something very cool here.
Okay, guys, we're going to get what our buddy Justin was talking about.
We're going to get symbols. We're going to get the VIX. Okay,
now can someone tell me what the VIX is in brief? Okay,
the VIX is actually a very complex product,
but if someone could just give me a super quick idea of what the hell the VIX is
while I get everything else set up here.
What I'm just doing right now, guys, is I'm just calculating the volatility,
the realized volatility for the S&P 500.
Just bear with me, guys, for one quick second here. I promise you,
this is going to be very exciting. It's going to be very exciting.
So let, you know, oops. Let's take a look here. So what do we got here? So,
well, okay. So we got, maybe we talk, okay. Yeah, thanks. Cool. Okay,
so Marco's saying it's the volatility index. Great.
Renato's saying it's the vol of the S&P, okay.
Measures without any options of the S&P. Someone's been doing some studying.
Good work, Justin. Blessing, I haven't looked at vol Q and VXN.
Maybe I have looked at VXN actually, Blessing.
I don't think I've looked at vol Q. That's the volatility of the Qs, right?
Maybe not.
And co-op, send me a link to the singer Yang Zeng. Okay,
so what the volatility index is, is it's basically the implied volatility,
okay, of selling, or no, not selling, my apologies.
It's the implied volatility of the options on the S&P 500, the 30-day options,
about the 90 moneyness. And moneyness means if the stock's trading at 100,
it's the 90 strike, okay. So it's just below the at the money options,
the implied volatility. And so what it really is, is the market's,
it's the market's prediction of what the volatility in the future is going to be,
okay.
The market's prediction of what the volatility in the future is going to be.
That's what the VIX index is for the 30-day options, okay.
So for the 30-day options. Now, what I just did here was,
what I just did here, guys, was I calculated. So here's the VIX.
So let me give you an example, okay. The VIX closed at 10%, okay.
The VIX closed at 10%,
meaning that the market thought that there was going to be 10% volatility going
forward. And what, you know, at that time, at that time being,
the market was moving about 7%.
Now, we want to look at the variance risk premium, okay.
So given this data that I just showed you guys, what do you,
can someone explain to me what the variance risk premium is?
Just given this data that I'm just showing you right here,
what do you guys think it's going to be?
So this SPY vol, this is the volatility, okay. This is the realized volatility,
what's actually happened. And this is the implied volatility, okay. So what's,
like, what do you think what we're going to do here? Perfect. Thank you.
Thank you, Eric. It's going to be the difference. Okay. Okay, Mr. Smittypants,
saying delta, delta between. Okay. So, but what we need to do, though,
is we need to, well, we need to lag the volatility.
We need to lag the volatility, right? Because think about it like this, guys.
What we're looking at right now,
what we're looking at is this.
So this is time.
And we have the volatility that's looked like this,
and we have the implied volatility that maybe looked like this, right?
But what this VIX right here, okay, let's say this is the VIX. And sorry, guys,
you know, I'm really bad at sometimes, when I get a little technical,
I kind of, I kind of get bad at explaining, but this is the VIX,
and the VIX is saying, well,
what is the volatility going to be in the next 30 days? Okay.
What is the volatility going to be in the future?
And so we can't compare it to the realized volatility here to get the equity risk
premium or the variance risk premium. What we need to do is we need to say,
okay, what's actually happened, right? And we need to compare this with this.
We need to compare what the market implied versus what actually happened.
So what we're going to do is, is we're going to shift this back.
We're going to shift this back. So that's what I'm going to do right now. Okay.
A little bit of data science there for everyone, right?
Everyone in this group loves data science.
Okay. So we're going to call this one DF. We're going to call it actual,
actual vol equals two.
And okay, we're going to blank it back one month. Cool.
So now let's take a look, guys. We got the data. Everything's looking good.
So let's take a look super quick and we're going to plot it.
So you see that guys, look at this. We took this number.
That's 21 days in the future. Okay. 0.007. And we moved it all the way up here.
So we can say, okay, well, on 2007, January 3rd, the VIX was saying,
the market's going to have 12% volatility in the future. And so we said, okay,
well, what actually happened in the future? And let's bring it back to today.
Okay. And now we're comparing apples to apples. All right.
So everyone's good with that. Tell me if everyone's good with that.
I need to know.
What do you guys think? Are we getting smarter or am I just getting crazy?
Am I going a little crazy over here? What is going on?
Eric, that's funny, man. If you saw me full speed,
I don't know if you're being a little sarcastic there.
If you saw me full speed, dude.
Okay. Marcos saying yes, but market conditions change every year. You bet.
You bet. So I'm going to plot this Marcos and we're going to take a look.
We're going to take a look because Marcos, you are 100% right.
Can't come up with a decision looking at the past.
Blessing saying, so VRP is VIX minus RV.
Blessing took the words right out of my mouth.
Took the words right out of my mouth.
Can't come up with a decision looking at the past. Absolutely.
Let us create the spread. Here we go, guys. DF, VRP.
We're creating the variance risk premium equals the VIX divided by actual vol.
Okay.
So before we actually do that, I'm going to plot the two so we can take a look.
Let me just make sure we're good here. Sorry, guys. Bear with me. Bear with me.
Excellent. Here we go, guys. Ready?
So what do we notice? Come on. Who's the data scientist here?
What do we notice, guys?
What do we notice?
Who is the data scientist in the group?
So Eric, I'm definitely going to plot the difference in a second,
but as a good data scientist, we need to visualize the data.
We need to really take a look at it, right?
We'll take a look at how these things are looking. Just, you know,
just quick notices, and then we're going to plot the data.
We're going to plot the real data. Mean reverting?
Koa is saying mean reverting.
Koa, really? It definitely is mean reverting. Is that the...
What else do you notice there?
VIX is lower more times than high.
Oh, thanks, Stephen. I was going to say, where's Stephen's post here?
So the VIX, which is the black line, usually overstates realized volatility.
It usually overstates realized volatility. Now, what does this mean?
Before we plot the spread between them, what does this mean? Well,
let's take a look. Let's go to an option calculator,
and this is in the terminal.
So what does this mean, guys? Well,
imagine we're looking at an option on a stock, Tesla, that's trading at $800,
and we are looking at the $800 straddle, and the days to expiration are 20,
or 30. Sorry, we're looking at the one-month options,
and the implied volatility is 30. The implied volatility is 30. Well,
the option today, or the straddle today,
is going to be worth $27.40 for the call and $27.40 for the put.
So we're at $55.
So the straddle is going to be worth $55. But if the stonk realizes 20 vol,
right, if it realizes 20 vol, well, that option today is only worth $36.
So on average, if this is continuous, right, on average,
we're going to sell these options for $55 and basically realize only $36 worth.
So we're going to make money on average. So let's go back to our graph here.
So we realize that the VIX on average outpaces realized volatility, okay?
It outpaces realized volatility. So on average,
those options are going to be expensive, right?
And let's actually plot what Eric was saying, okay?
What do we call it again, Eric? VRP.
Not a great graph, but you could see here, right? Here's the line.
Here's when realized vol and implied vol are the same. It's at this one line.
And you can see, right, in March 2020,
realized vol outpaced implied vol like crazy, okay?
So we lost a lot of money here. But there are some times where, you know,
if we go back to the last graph, right,
there are some times where the stock doesn't move at all, yet it was implying,
you know, 15% and it only realized 5.
So those are times you're going to make a lot of money selling volatility.
But then there's are going to be times, right? If we look over here,
for example, the market implied about 18% and it actually realized 85, right?
So, you know, selling vol here would be a big loser. But let's go see what the,
you know, what the mean is here.
And this data is going to be a little bit biased.
I can't go into the nitty gritty about that.
So what this is saying is that on average, okay, on average,
volatility is going to be 32%,
implied volatility is going to be 32% higher than realized vol, right?
So the implied vol might be, let's say 10, but the stock realizes 8.
So that's what the variance risk premium is. It's the premium, right?
We're getting this extra premium for selling volatility.
And so just like the equity risk premium, you know,
I could be here all day trying to back out, you know, the returns for this.
We are going to make some money.
Now the good news is the variance risk premium is a bit higher than the equity risk
premium. Okay. It's a bit higher, it's about 2% higher.
The bad part is it can be a lot trickier to take advantage of. Okay. Right.
We're going to have some Delta hedging involved, you know,
a little bit more transaction costs could be a little trickier.
So what you could do is, right, and I really like this one is selling puts,
right? Selling puts, what do they take advantage of? Well,
selling puts take advantage of, well, who's got it? I'm going to ask you guys,
what does puts take advantage of? What does, what, give me some of the,
give me some of the premiums for selling puts take advantage of and why?
Did you guys fall asleep? Oh, no, sorry. Oops. Sorry, guys. I didn't,
I was not scrolling down.
Trent saying some skew premium, some Delta and skew. Oh, great one, Marcos.
Great one, Marcos. Pulumi. Pulumi saying Delta skew and vol. Wow, Pulumi.
I thought, I thought you lost it, man. That's exactly right. Okay.
That's exactly right. The selling the put, right? Selling, what is it?
Let's think about the put. The put,
let's think about the structure of let's say a Delta 25 put. It is long Delta,
meaning equity risk premium.
Stonks go up. Stonks go up. So we get that long Delta.
The short put is short Vega,
meaning we get variance risk premium.
Okay. What about skew? Well, if you put it a little bit out of the money,
we get the skew premium.
So we can structure a trade that's going to take advantage of all three of these.
And, you know, that's why on average you see,
I don't know if you guys have ever seen the put index.
I'm going to find it for you guys right now, if you guys want to bear with me.
And Pulumi, I'm going to give you a call right after this, okay? SIBO put.
Okay. Oh, this is the skew index indices. Just bear with me here, guys.
We're going to figure this out.
SIBO benchmarks.
Look, they even have an iron butterfly one. Okay. Okay.
20 Delta buy right index. So this would be selling those covered calls,
those Delta covered calls, right? Let's see how this is done.
Oh, is this here, right? It's done okay. It's done okay. Oh, look,
they got the same graphs as the terminal.
Okay. Let's look for the put right index.
5% protection put. What do you guys think that one looks like?
Buying Delta 5% puts.
Buying Delta 5% puts. Put right index. Here we go.
Here it is, guys.
And you can see it's done very well, right?
I won't be able to compare it though. Compare. Here we go, guys. Here we go.
Okay. So let's see if we can figure this out, guys.
You know what? They don't make it easy.
They don't make it easy. But so right now we're getting a little bit of,
so it's going to look like under performance,
but it's going to be a higher sharp. So you can scale. Man, so bad.
Sorry, guys. You know what? Should I do it? What time is it? 840?
Should I download and plot?
Let's do that.
This guy needs a new computer. Someone get this guy a new computer.
Are you guys still with me or did everyone fall asleep?
Let me give a little like or something.
Give a thumbs up on tonight's live if you're still awake.
Sorry, guys. It looks like it's not happening.
SIBO needs to get their stuff together.
Long story short, there's been a lot of research, a lot of studying,
a lot of data that's gone into it.
The put indexes outperform the SPY on a better risk-adjusted return.
So you can get leverage.
You can get leverage by doing so.
Selling puts has a better risk-adjusted return. It's not much better.
Otherwise,
everyone just sells puts and then that variant risk premium disappears on average.
And of course, it's going to go through periods of drawdown. Hey, Lawrence,
great to see you, man. The only person that said here, everyone else is... Oh,
here we go. Never mind. Hey, Blessing. Okay, Blessing's saying, yeah,
Blessing's saying, I'm a little bit confused here. And you know what, Blessing,
that is totally okay.
I think Steven is also a bit confused here because I'm not hearing much from him.
So let's talk about it, Blessing. What is going through your head?
What's a bit challenging here? I am usually not the best at explaining stuff.
So,
all right. So I'm going through the comments now.
So if you sell one-year puts... Marcos, this is 30-day puts.
This is selling 30-day puts.
Do you have the risk of a naked put? Yes. So Blessing,
the risk of a naked put is the same as the risk of a stock on the downside,
right? If the stock goes down, it can go all the way to you know, down to zero,
just like with a put, right? You sell that put,
the stock can go all the way down to zero. And so that's why, right?
You're getting that equity risk premium embedded in that put.
If we look at what a put looks like versus the call, right?
So here's our short put, right? This is the payoff for our short put.
And if we look at the stock payoff, it looks like this,
right? So both of these have that risk to the downside.
And so you're getting compensated for bearing that risk.
Marco's saying you beat SPY in the long run.
You beat SPY in the long run marginally. You know, it's not a huge beat, right?
Because variance risk premium and the equity risk premium are correlated,
right? You got correlated risk premiums.
Okay. Yeah. Risk adjusted. Exactly, right?
So the other thing Steve's saying is, well, if you leverage up, right,
you're going to have some more risk, right? The stock continues to go down,
right? Well, you can be in trouble, right? You can have some big jump risk.
And then the broker calls you and says, you're being liquidated. Okay.
And there are certain things that have higher risk premiums,
like premium on the S&P 500 has a higher risk premium than selling puts on CCL.
So is there any questions about that?
And a lot of people have made millions and millions and millions of dollars selling
puts and making funds and selling puts. They get too greedy. They leverage up,
they blow up, but it's not their money.
But a lot of people have made millions and millions and millions and millions of
dollars selling puts.
The liquid love,
Sean looking at liquid love?
Is that what Sean's doing late at night?
Far left.
Oh yeah. Yeah, right. I don't know. I'm scared to open that.
I'm scared to open that.
So no, no. Cause you're listening to a liquid love on YouTube. So yeah, yeah,
yeah. It's good. It's good stuff. You guys hear that? It's good stuff. Okay.
So Steven saying on Bloomberg, I'm not sure we're talking about there, Steve,
but guys, that is basically the live.
I hope we all understand what the variance risk premium is now.
We went into pretty extensive detail about what it is.
And what it basically means is that on average, you're going to get paid.
On average, just like the equity risk premium,
every single day you get paid a small amount of money,
even if you don't see it that day.
So any questions? Otherwise I will be signing out.
I think it was good. What'd you guys think? Was it a good one?
They set up so good. Like just like, I just really want,
I like love talking in this, this thing. It's great. Right.
You look like you're in a spaceship. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Guys,
this liquid love playlist. It's really cool. And look, like I'll mute it.
Look at the background. It's a little skeptical.
It's all these like little coral reef things.
That looks a little skeptical. If you ask me, Sean, it looks a little,
what the hell is that?
It's the ocean. It's the ocean. I don't know. Eric,
what do you think about that, man? What do you think in there, Eric?
Yeah, I know. Blessing. Mine too. Mine too. Blessing. Yeah. It's a,
it's a good, if you like, like, you know, I don't know. It's funky music.
That's for sure. Okay. Let's see the good laughs here. Let's see all the lols.
Okay. So blessing. Nice. So blessing saying, how do you execute?
So you sell a 30 day and every 20 days,
buy it back and sell a new one or let it expire and sell a new one.
So you're just basically doing it. It's just like buying a stock, right?
If you want to get exposure to that equity risk premium,
you just buy the stock.
If you want to get exposure to the variance risk premium or this risk premium that
we talked about, the combination of a couple of risk premiums, sell the put,
sell the put and just roll it.
Just keep rolling and rolling and rolling and know that there are going to be some
big losses. That's why you get paid. And the beauty,
the beauty of this a blessing is that we can go back in time to when the victims
created in 1999.
And we will see that this variance risk premium has lasted for years, right?
Something has lasted for years, 30 years, 40 years. So we have confidence.
I think this thing is probably going to last in the future or continue to be in
the future, right? There's going to be losing periods though, right?
As Marcos was saying, if it never had losing periods,
there would be no risk premium. It has to lose, right?
You have to pay out sometimes.
There's going to be periods where it doesn't work, right? But in the long run,
you guys can talk to Steve about this,
like value momentum risk premiums and oh, Pulumi, Pulumi still alive?
Pulumi? There's going to be risk premiums, right?
That go through really bad periods and periods that are like value, right?
And periods are really good.
Eric, they are the Delta 50. They're the Delta 50.
I believe the Delta 40s or Delta... Steve B, if you don't mind,
can you post the paper from AQR in the group? Delta 30 puts,
those have the highest sharp ratio, Delta 30 puts.
Marcos is saying, so if you sell every time it spikes on average,
you increase your chances.
Okay, Marcos. So the answer is you increase the chance of it coming back down,
right? Because it's mean reverting, but that's adding,
you are now adding a filter. You're adding a statistical signal, right?
And so you're also missing a lot of the times where it doesn't spike.
Like look at this whole year in 2017, where you got no spikes,
you got maybe one or two spikes and you missed out on months and months of collecting
that risk premium. So there are strategies though. So like, for example,
a strategy is sell puts when the VIX term structure is in contango, okay?
Sell puts when the VIX term structure is in contango,
buy those puts back when it's not. So here, let me just show you super quick,
Marcos. But now we're building a strategy. So that's something different,
right? We're just talking about collecting a risk premium, okay? That's there.
It's always there. It's there for everybody. You sell those day in, day out,
okay? But you can get better, right? You can do better than a risk premium,
right? But now we're talking about building a strategy.
That's going to be for a totally different life,
but I'll just super quickly tell you. That's how a lot of funds work.
When this is looking like this, okay? When it's looking like this,
you sell the puts, okay? You sell the puts. When it goes backward, okay?
You buy back those puts, okay?
So when the front month is above the second month, you buy back those puts,
okay? And the reason for that is, is because, let me show you, Marcos.
What that does, Marcos, is this. It keeps you always in on this period,
but it gets you out, Marcos, right here, so that you don't have that huge loss.
But what's the downside to that? Well, Marcos, it also gets you out right here,
and it gets you out right here,
okay? So by doing that, it stops the blowouts, okay?
But you give up buying back at the worst possible time.
Then you can add a second filter that basically says, well, if we add this,
well, now we actually stayed in during this one,
and we stayed in during this one, and this one.
So now we just added some benefits.
But that's strategy development, Marcos. That is not for tonight's live.
But I love how you're thinking, dude.
Blessing, so not just on the VIX, you can sell it on the S&P 500,
but you can sell it on the VIX. It's another risk premium you can collect.
That's called the vol of vol, okay, right? The VIX is volatility,
and we're selling volatility on the volatility, right?
So that's going to be for another live as well. It's like inception. Exactly,
exactly. And then you can sell vol on vol on vol.
That's the inception risk premium. You don't even know if you're in anymore.
Exactly. You might be trading delta one at that point. Yes.
Okay, guys, that is the live tonight. That was a good live.
That was a fun live. And we will see you guys back next week.
So have a wonderful night, everyone. Hope you didn't miss me too much.
He's right there, guys. I'm here, guys.
And I'll be sending the liquid squidly love to everybody. Oh, it's just,
don't send it to anyone. I'm sending it to Trent. Okay, and blessing.
I'll send that to you as well. Okay, see you guys.
At least let me post up the shame.