So a lot of the times when we're looking at trades,
we encourage you to look at very liquid names, right?
It removes a lot of the nuance that's needed. It makes it easy to get started,
right?
But there's opportunity any liquid names and tonight's topic is gonna help you as
you look to trade these illiquid names, right?
Which is something especially for our more advanced members.
It's worth exploring, right? Illiquid names are worth exploring.
So tonight's topic is how to identify and understand the vol line that you enter
a trade at, okay?
So instead of looking at just the dollars that you entered a trade on,
understanding and thinking in terms of the volatility that you entered your trade
at.
Okay, let's do it. Let's make it happen.
And we're gonna power through this guys. Let me just quickly see who's on,
who we,
sorry, one second guys, let me just,
hey Sean. Yeah, what's up? If I want to, so I can see the chat here.
I can't see the participants. Okay, can you see it? Oh, here we go. Got it,
got it. Yeah, I don't know.
Okay, perfect, perfect. Jared, nice to see you out here.
I see everyone out here. Margin, great to see you guys.
I think you guys are gonna find this extremely useful. Steven B as well,
just cause I know you've been getting into some of the liquid names. Okay,
so we're gonna look at ARCX.
ARCX, Steve B brought this one to my attention. So we're gonna chat about it.
And this is actually one of the gold questions as well. Or the silver test,
sorry, I should say. Okay, everyone.
So everyone can see my screen?
Yeah, I assume so. Okay, so let's take a look at ARCX here guys.
Let's look at these puts, 21 strike puts November. Bid is 50 cents, ask is $5.
You come in here, you put an order.
Let's say you want to buy these options and you go, you know,
you hit the mid for 275 and you get filled for 275 instantly, let's say.
And you think, hey, that's, you know, I got filled at mid.
The issue here is mid is not fair value. Okay,
mid is not even the market's fair value. Mid is just,
it's just the number between the bid and the ask. Okay,
if the person on the ask is more aggressive,
the mid is gonna be a lot favorable to the buyer than to the seller. Okay,
so the mid is not fair value. It's not the market's fair value.
It's just a number. And so as a trader, when we look at something liquid, okay,
when we look at something liquid.
Do you want me to slow down there and maybe like make it really,
really clear why it wouldn't be fair value? Yeah. I can do that.
Sure, I was gonna draw it up right here. Yeah,
I'll do it cause I can probably do it quicker.
Okay, so imagine we're looking at a stock. We have the bid and the ask, right?
We have someone sitting here at $5 or let's say, you know,
someone sitting here at $1 and $10. The mid is gonna be like $5. Okay,
so this would be the bid, the ask and the mid. Okay,
and let's say there's one lot sitting here and one lot sitting here.
Now let's say all of a sudden, somebody comes in here and puts an ask at $7.
The mid's instantly gonna jump down here, right?
Somewhere like maybe three bucks, right? 3.5.
So if the mid can change so easily,
all that happened is somebody came in here and dropped an ask lower than what there
is. How the heck can we think of this as fair value for the asset, right?
It's very, very malleable. Changes very, very easily.
And it's not really a reflection of what this thing's actually worth.
Is Jordan anything to add there? Nope, that's it. Okay, great.
I'll make you host again. Nice, that was quick, nice and quick.
Okay, so you guys saw what Sean was saying there, right? Mid is nothing.
So let's take a look. When we have something liquid, let's say the NASDAQ,
the Q's, mid is gonna be great. You got really competitive markets,
really smart people on both sides of the market, okay?
Mid is gonna be fantastic. That's a liquid market. But an illiquid market,
mark X, okay? Mid is meaningless.
So we come in here and let's say we think vol's expensive, okay?
Our brokerage tells us it's 40 implied vol. This number,
we don't even know if it's legit. There's no spread.
We can't just look at this number, right?
If we're looking at interactive brokers, we can't just look at the number,
especially on something illiquid.
So we need to come in here and we need to price this thing. Well,
let's take a look, guys.
Let's say I wanna buy this asset. I wanna buy it at 40 vol.
What number does that actually need to be? So let's come over to terminal,
okay? We're gonna come right over here. And ARKX is trading at $21.05.
So right now, guys, we're on option calculator, okay?
We're gonna show you two calculators today to get you guys on the way, okay?
ARKX trading at 21.05. Strike, we're looking at the 21.
Let's just double check. We're trying to price this option right here.
Expiration, type in expiration. November 21.
All right, Jordan, maybe slow it down for a second.
What exactly are you trying to do here? I'm pricing the option.
So I'm pricing the option using the Black-Scholes formula,
using how everyone looks at volatility.
And the reason you're doing this is because you can't rely on the market to give
you the right price. You need to actually figure it out yourself.
And the reason is because, basically, there's not enough people trading it.
Correct. It's like, you know how with supply and demand,
they meet somewhere and that's like the equilibrium. It's like, well,
what if there's only one demand and one supply? It's like,
how can you count on that being any sort of representation of fair value?
You can't, so you gotta go calculate it. Correct. Lucky enough,
we have that built into the terminal here. Yeah. So we choose expiration,
November 19, and we put in the volatility that we wanna buy it at.
Let's say we wanna buy it at 42 vol, okay? Or sorry,
we wanna sell it at 42 vol. And, you know, interest rates are zero, dividend,
we'll say are zero, okay? And when we run that,
we get the price of this call option at $2.77, okay?
So if we wanna sell this at 42 vol, we need to sell it at $2.77. Now, you know,
as we go below that, let's say we end up selling this thing.
Let's say we didn't know how to price these options and we finally got filled at
$2, okay? Well, we have something else. We have the volatility calculator,
okay? And what this is gonna do is, you're gonna put in the call option,
put option, whatever it is, okay? The underlying price, so 21.05, strike 21,
okay? November, and the market price. We just sold this option for $2.
We sold at a 30 implied vol,
okay? We sold at 30 implied vol, but we wanted, 278 was it?
We wanted that 42 vol line,
okay? So when you're trading in the illiquid market,
you need to price your options, right? If you were doing, let's say a straddle,
well, you would price the call and you would price the put,
all right? But this is crucial. This is crucial.
For the guys who are trading in illiquid stuff,
just specifically on this live for sure, Margin, Steve B, Jared,
I know you're getting into that space.
You need to be able to price the option or you're gonna get screwed getting in that
mid. And for those of you that aren't necessarily looking at it,
here's an example of where you'd use it, right?
Let's say you're on the volatility analyzer page and you see that, you know,
as a stock is trading at, you know, you look at the vol cone,
it's trading at the maximum vol, you think it's expensive and that's 100 vol,
all right? And you look at like the third quantile and you say,
that's where I think it'll drop to. And that's 75 vol.
But then you go to the option chain itself and it's illiquid, right?
You're seeing all sorts of random numbers there, right? You may be like,
what would you maybe see there, Jordan, if it was a liquid?
You might see for like on the option chain. Yeah.
You might see like some weird ass implied vols. Right?
Let me see if I can find one here for you guys.
I think it's a little bit more liquid now,
but what's an illiquid volatile name?
An illiquid, try like AMC.
Here, you know what? Actually, I think I remember one.
The furthest side of the money is like trading at like 1,100 implied vol.
AMC? Yeah, if you scroll all the way up. All right, you can see them there.
So it's okay if it's, okay. Aha, here we go, perfect. Yeah. Okay,
so look at this, guys, right here. This put is trading at 1,400 implied vol,
but the ask is, or the call is trading for 529 vol. Arbitrage, right?
But there isn't. This is just,
you can see the spread is 45 cents here and the spread here is a penny. Okay,
so that's why, you know, you're gonna get these weird vols.
But I think for different brokerages, as Jared was mentioning, is different.
For thinkorswim, the implied vol is at the mid, which is unrealistic. Okay?
Right, so what you'd wanna be doing is, you know, like let's say, you know,
you look at that stock, it has 100 implied vol on the, you know,
on your vol cone. You're like, I wanna be selling 100 vol.
But then you go to the option chain for that option and the spread is so wide that
the mid is not that. Well,
what price do you need to get filled at to actually sell 100 vol? You know,
a lot of us, when we're new, we would think we can just go in and sell it.
Just try to get a good fill.
But that fill you get needs to actually be what you want. Right? You know,
and if you're getting filled less than that, you need to be aware of it. Right,
so maybe you price it out with 100 vol using the option calculator,
and you see that you need to be selling the combined straddle for $10. Right,
and the mid might be $6. You know, who knows? You get what I'm saying. Well,
you know now that if you go below $10,
you're not actually selling what you think you are and you need to adjust.
You know, if we had- You can use it. Exactly. We had a guy in our group,
plays a lot of roulette, you guys might know him. And he slapped the ask today,
from what I hear, on a name where, you know,
the implied vol was so different at different strikes.
So here's an example of GSX, okay?
Let's say I wanted to sell this vol and I slapped the ask or slapped the bid.
Well, I'm gonna be getting filled, or I'm sorry, I slapped the mid.
I'm gonna be getting filled at 96 vol, right? Where the mid here is 105 vol,
107 vol. So you really need to be able to price these out,
especially in these liquid names.
Yeah, Technoking, you got me. It was me, it was me.
It was Sean, it was Sean, exactly.
Yeah, so any questions about this, guys? Right, it's not a super long live.
You know, what I would like to see is, you know,
I would like to see people using this.
You'll get a lot better by pricing it out.
Roubet Junkie is asking how do I- Roubet Junkie, how do you make money from it?
Every dollar saved is a dollar earned.
So if you spend a dollar from not knowing this, well, you just, you know,
you could have saved a dollar. AKA, you made money.
AKA, another round of Roubet.
All right. Any more questions? I think it's a pretty straightforward one.
There might be a little bit of like a gap still for some people, which is okay.
Go practice. If you wanna show us, you know, post it in the group,
go try and do it. We can all take a look. And now's your chance to speak up,
guys. We can go through an example right now. Now's your chance.
Going once, twice.
How flexible are you about the IV you want to sell? Honestly,
it depends on how much edge is there, right?
That's the important thing of valuing. So Harry,
here's something in not vol terms that we can all understand.
We think Apple's worth a hundred dollars. How much would you pay for Apple?
Anything below a hundred, right? Or with some room for error, okay? So,
you know, maybe whatever that number is.
But the key point is you had to value it.
You had to say Apple was worth a hundred dollars.
And the same thing goes for vol trading. We said,
when I ran that regression for GSX, the fair value of GSX vol was 105 vol.
It was 105 vols for value. We hit 107 today, 108, and we got out, right?
Perfect.
Yeah, so Kyle's saying, you ever forget to put the div yield in?
The div yield is actually pretty important. Right, Marjan?
Let's take a look here just super quick. Price calculator, volatility,
let's say 30, interest rate in yield. Okay, I'm sorry.
In dividend yield is in yield. So let's say 3%. It might have to be 0.03.
Let me just see what I did here. Yeah, okay, it's 0.03. That's 300%.
Okay, so that actually drops the option by a dollar. Okay,
but then don't forget, there's gonna be like three or four,
two dividends in between this. So, you know,
sometimes you do forget it's not usually that important, right?
Cause the put's gonna go up as well. And I usually, I'm doing straddles.
I'm not doing an individual leg, but if you're doing an individual leg margin,
it's important to understand that, okay?
This is annually. Yes, Harry, annually dividend yield.
Okay, any more questions?
Yeah, I did it on last week before I did it on Wednesday,
Wednesday of last week or Thursday of last week.
You just gotta be lurking around late on a Friday night or something.
Jordan's got a couple of drinks in him. He likes to give away some alpha.
He just streams himself, you know, coding and everything.
You remember when you used to do that? Yeah, yeah. No, no,
but this was on the live. I did this on a live on Wednesday or Thursday.
And this is Black Shoals, correct? Yeah, it's Black Shoals, correct.
And Red, I wouldn't get too caught up in all those fancy formulas, man.
The formula doesn't give you the edge. What gives you the edge is your value.
A 30 implied vol might be a 35 implied vol using a Heston model,
but all your vols are gonna be skewed.
So the only thing it's actually good for, let's say having a better model,
maybe a model with a backbone, or you can go further and further down the road,
is your hedging. So the way you calculate your deltas, all your Greeks,
that's where it could be useful. But as a prop trader, as a positional trader,
don't get lost in the weeds there.
Focus your time on where you're really gonna make some alpha.
What about for spreads with more than two legs, like an iron condor?
You'd have to price them individually.
So we used to have it where you could price the whole thing,
but maybe for down the road, we're gonna do that.
I have my own thing where I have them all priced out,
but people just weren't using it. It's a little bit of a hassle to build out.
So, but if you guys end up needing it, we can always throw it up there.
I have the code for it.
Ned, good of you to join us. We're just wrapping up.
Ned, generous guy, Ned. I still can't get over it, man. What? No,
just a little inside joke between Ned and I.
Whatever.
Okay, guys. I think that's gonna be it for tonight's live.
If you have any questions, just drop them in the chat and take it easy.
We'll see you tomorrow.