Hey guys, so in this live,
we're going to be chatting about spot and eyeball correlation.
And what we mean by that is, if let's say we're looking at the S&P 500,
if the stock goes up 1%, what happens to eyeball? The stock goes down 1%,
what happens to eyeball?
So that's what we're going to be chatting about today.
So if implied ball goes up, then what's going to happen to spot?
And when we say spot, we mean the underlying. So when we say underlying,
we mean, let's say, for example, the spot price,
meaning the current price of let's say the S&P 500.
So we call it the spot eyeball correlation,
and I'm just going to show it to you on the terminal.
So let's look at the ticker SPY,
and we're going to go to volatility. And we can see right here,
this is the picture we're looking at. Everyone see this?
And so what this tells us is, if the S&P goes up 2%,
the implied volatility usually comes down. When the S&P goes down 2%,
we'll say implied volatility usually goes up about 15.6%.
So that is what spot eyeball correlation is.
Now the reason we need to talk about this is because it helps us structure our trades.
Okay. So we can use GME as an example. I think it's perfect. But does anyone,
before we continue, is everyone from understanding of spot eyeball correlation?
Because if we can't understand this, this is the fundamental building block.
We're getting there, Koaw.
Okay. Koaw is saying, please repeat. On the X axis,
we have change in share price, right? So this is no change in share price.
This is plus 2% change in share price on this side, right? Plus 2 here,
minus 2 here. And then on this side, we have change in IV.
So this down here would be like minus 20%, right? Up here would be plus 30%,
right? And what we're saying is, well, okay, let's say we have, you know,
a 2% day in the S&P. We should see volatility come down about 10%, right?
Not 10 points, 10%. So if implied vol is trading at 20,
it should come down to 18. And for different assets,
this correlation could look different. Yeah. Actually,
it's not always the same. That's actually a really good idea.
Let's take a look at Tesla just because we got Tico on the line here. And Tico,
I was just chatting to a pharmacist today.
I'd love to have a little call with you this week sometime. Okay.
So look at Tesla, right? When Tesla goes up, implied volatility goes up.
When Tesla goes down, implied volatility comes down. Okay.
And we're seeing this with a lot of names. Okay. We're seeing this with LIT,
right? Let's take a look at LIT. Okay. So look what's happening here, guys.
I'm just going to do the implied volatility. Look at this.
As we see the stock rally, okay, we're also seeing implied volatility rally.
And when we see the stock coming down,
we also see implied volatility coming down.
Let's do a six month so you guys can really see it. Okay. Do you guys see that?
You see that correlation there? It's like identical. Right.
But what we see here is it's a lot.
So it's definitely a lot flatter than the S&P,
but it's still negatively correlated. But right now, currently,
we're seeing some correlation. Okay. Now, usually for an ETF,
we should see negative correlation. Stock goes down, implied vol goes up.
Right. If the ETF goes down, implied vol goes up.
But currently in the last three months, right, not even last two months,
we've seen if implied volatility goes up, the stock is usually up as well.
So does everyone understand implied vol versus spot correlation?
So is it an inverse correlation? So is it inverse to let's say the S&P? Yes.
Right. Not right now, not in the past. So usually, blessing.
So this is looking over two years of data. Okay.
If we look at two years of data, we see a negative correlation,
meaning that usually for lit, if it goes up, vols drop, if it goes down,
vols increase. Right. We see that. We saw that over here. Right.
During the crisis. Right. Vols went up and the stock went down.
But right now it's acting a little different. Okay. Now for Tesla,
we see a stronger relationship that when S&P, when Tesla goes up,
implied vol goes up. Okay. Which we're seeing a stronger relationship there.
Okay. But for the S&P, it's completely the opposite.
Okay. Completely the opposite. Does everyone understand that? Yes. Arnold.
So each dot represents a day. Okay. So on this day right here,
S&P was flat or it was down 0.89% and vols were up 26%. Okay. Now, obviously,
maybe not obviously, let me ask you this question. Okay.
What do you think during this time period, right?
If I were to tell you what day this was, okay,
what do you think the VIX was trading at? So we're looking at the S&P here.
What do you think the VIX was trading at? So that when the S&P went down 0.89%,
VIX went up 26%. What do you think it was trading at? Let's see who's got this.
Come on, Steven. When I say, let's see who's got this, I'm explicitly saying,
please don't answer Steven.
Nice. Okay. So Steven's got it, right? So Kou is saying mid vol.
So it's actually going to be really low vol, right?
If the S&P is down half a percent and the VIX is spiking 26%,
we're in an extremely low vol environment. Maybe VIX is 10, maybe VIX is nine.
Okay.
No, it's definitely not blessing. Another question for you. Okay.
Biotech, biotech company, meme stock, biotech or a meme stock.
What do you think the relationship would be?
Kind of funky. It is. It is. Positive. Awesome. Blessing. Awesome. Awesome.
Awesome. As exactly that stands in. Perfect. When the stock rallies,
we see an increase in vol. So let's see, let's see if that's the case.
Let's see. Thanks, Hannah. Thanks for, thanks for bringing that one in. Okay.
Let's see here. So I'll take a look at GME. Okay. And we've seen this with GME,
right? When the, when the, when the, when the stock,
when the spot price goes up, implied vol goes up. Now, not that much,
but we are seeing that. Okay. So how can this,
why and where should we use this? Okay. Well,
let's think about it before we even,
I really want you guys to think about this stuff. Okay.
Let's say we see a positive correlation between implied vol and spot price.
Okay. And we are bearish on vols. We're bearish on vols.
How might we structure a straddle? Where would we place it?
Let's say the stock's trading at 50. Okay. We're bearish on vols. Okay.
But we also have this like implicit risk of direction, right?
It's like when you buy the S&P 500, you're actually short volatility, right?
That's why they say buying S&P or buying equity is a short vol trade.
So Jared's saying 40. So stock's trading at 50 and we're bearish on vols,
it has a positive correlation with spot price. Jared's saying 40.
Does anyone agree or disagree with Jared? What do you guys think?
What do you guys think?
So stock's trading at 50. Okay. And we want to sell a straddle. Okay.
So here's our P&L graph. Okay.
Here's 50. This is where the stock's trading at. Okay.
And let's say this is 30 and this is 20 and this is 70.
Where do we want to place our straddle and why?
So Blessing's saying, would you do a put spread then? Not necessarily.
Not necessarily. We want to get short a lot of vol,
so we wouldn't really want to do a put spread here.
I think it's going to be two directional. Stanton's saying an at the money.
Okay.
So Jared's saying straddle over here. Okay.
Stanton's saying straddle over here.
Okay. Steve, thanks for not saying your opinion. I really appreciate it.
I know you're sweating. Ronnie's saying place it above the strike.
Ronnie's saying place it above the strike. Okay.
So no one at PA can agree with anyone.
Okay. Since Koa, okay. So since Koa and Ronnie said above the strike,
we're going to go with that one as PA's decision.
And that would be the correct answer. Okay. That would be the correct answer.
Now, why would that be the correct answer? Okay. Well, we are bearish on vols,
right? We think vols are going to go down. Now, if volatility goes down, right,
what is likely going to happen to the spot price? Well,
it's likely going to go down as well, right? We said that they're correlated.
Let's say we're looking at GME, right? If GME starts to fall,
implied vol is going to get crushed. If GME continues to rise,
implied vol is going to continue to get larger and larger.
So we want to be positioned above spot price, okay?
And slightly leaning long deltas, okay? Because think about it like this.
If the stock goes down, we are going to earn on vega, right?
We're going to earn on short volatility. If the stock goes up, well,
if we are positioned below the strike, well,
we're going to lose on delta and we're going to lose on vega, right?
So being positioned above spot price is where we want to be. Now, also,
the other thing is stocks that are usually correlated with spot price,
or sorry, implied vols are usually correlated with spot price,
tend to have extreme high volatility, okay?
So we're going to use GME as our example here. Okay,
we're going to go into thinkorswim and we're going to take a look.
So just so you guys can see with lit, let's get rid of that.
I don't know how that got on the screen. I don't know, man.
So you guys can see with lit,
as the stock rallies and it gets more and more and more, boom, boom, right?
Implied vol is increasing with it. And now as the stock has been coming down,
so has the implied vols, okay? So let's take a look at GME.
I heard it's up after hours. Let me just quickly take a look here.
I like that big red candle.
Okay, so let's take a look here. GME trading at 43, okay?
Trading at 43 right now. This is where, this is the at the money strike.
The first thing we're going to realize is that the Delta 50 is actually way above
spot price. Okay. Now let's go and do and sell this straddle right here. Okay.
So we're selling a straddle way above spot price.
Let's take a look. Okay.
So before the close, it's up after hours.
So thinkorswim is going to be a little bit off, but before the close,
it was trading right around here. Okay.
Now let's see what's going to happen here. We're going to stress our position.
So if the stock were to go up, so we're going to, we're going to move this,
let's say up 10%. Okay.
And we're also going to have another scenario where the stock is down 10%.
Sorry guys. It's because after hours data, thinkorswim is down like 20%. Yeah.
Because like thinkorswim is using this right now. So no,
even that should be over here. I don't know. It's all messed up. Okay.
Whatever. We're going to use this as spot price.
So we're using the close data as spot price right now.
Thinkorswim has the close at $46, even though that's after hours data. Okay.
So let's, let's say we drop vols. So actually, sorry. Okay. So scenario one,
okay. The stock moves up to $49. If it does move up to $49, right,
we are going to see implied vols, let's say rally another 10%. Okay.
And so we are going to be losing money on vega and on delta, right?
But thankfully we get, let's say we get a little theta, right?
We're going to be okay.
Now on the flip side, if spot drops, we are going to earn on vega.
And so it's okay to be positioned slightly.
It's okay to be positioned slightly long delta because even if it does drop,
right, we're still going to earn.
All right. And just to show you guys another example here, let us do this.
Where do the strike is,
let's say 46, or we have a lot of short delta. Okay.
It's all messed up. There we go. There you go. If the stock were to rally,
right, 10%,
we'd be losing quite a bit on delta and our drop in vega or our increase in vega
would really damage us.
So that's why we want to have positioned above spot with slightly bullish view.
We're taking like twice the loss that we would be, right. Or more,
three times almost, it was like a thousand last time, right?
So we need to remember that when we do take on these trades,
we sometimes have an implicit directional view. We might say, well,
we're bearish on vols,
but we might only be bearish on by being bearish on vols.
We are implicitly saying, we think the stock is going to go down. Right.
If we're looking at, that's the key right there to really know, right.
That Ivy spot correlation tells you more about your view when you,
when you put on your trade, right.
If there's an extremely strong correlation where, you know,
implied volatility goes up when this stock goes down or, you know,
implied volatility go for this example,
implied volatility goes up when the stock goes up. Well, when you're short vol,
you know,
you clearly don't want the stock to go up because what happens when the stock goes
up, vols go up, right.
So it shows you about your relationship with Delta when you're taking that view
on implied volatility.
Hmm. So in this case, if GME were to trade down to let's say $30 a share,
implied vol would be likely, let's say back to 140, right. Or lower. Yeah,
it could go even lower. So we always need to keep that in mind when we're,
when we're trading volatility, right.
We sometimes have an implicit directional view, right? If we are long equity,
right, imagine you were long in the S&P 500. You were also saying,
I don't think there's going to be a lot of volatility, right?
Because if there is a lot of volatility, the S&P usually goes down. Okay.
And so to answer Ko's question that he always asks,
how can we make money from this? Well,
it's not necessarily how do you make money from this?
It's how do you understand the trade you have on, right? At the end of the day,
sometimes we're going to have really bad ideas.
Sometimes we're going to have really good ideas,
but if we can't manage these positions,
if we don't understand the risk we have on or what we expect,
we think is going to happen and we can't make money.
If what we were able to do here was put on a trade that better expresses our view,
right? We knew that, you know, we could take off, you know,
we would be in a better spot structuring it this way because of that correlation,
it added another piece to the puzzle of our analysis.
If you're bearish on lit, right? If you think lit is going to trade down to 60,
right? You know, you sure you could take a short Delta bet,
but you could also sell vol, right?
And those are going to express a very similar view.
So blessing saying, you know,
is this what Wechsler from Maple Leaf Capital means when he says most option traders
are vol traders by default? So every option trader is a vol trader.
They are taking a direction on vol, right?
Think about it like this with a stock, you can say,
I'm going to buy Coca-Cola and hold until I'm profitable, right?
I'm going to buy Coke and I'm going to be a Warren Buffett and hold until I'm profitable.
But with an option trader, you are saying,
I'm going to buy this and something's got to happen by this date.
And so you are explicitly trading volatility, right?
You are adding that volatility component. Yeah. You have this,
how much component, right? Volatility is the size of these moves,
the how much is the volatility part, right? And then a lot of traders,
they don't know that they're trading volatility.
But what Michael Wechsler is saying is that you are a volatility trader,
even if you don't know it.
Exactly. Right. It's like, you know,
it's like some people know they're playing the game and people don't know they're
playing the game, but everybody's playing the game.
So Stan saying,
what if the IV and spot correlation changes after we put on the trade,
you know, so it goes from being correlated to uncorrelated. In that instance,
do we quit the trade because our premise is no longer valid?
So it's not your primary premise, right? It's not like the, you know,
that's not your main, your main trade is not the correlation there.
Do you have any trades that you do where that is the core? That is the premise?
Well, not, not necessarily. Like I always have a view on vol itself,
but we can say, for example, if I think let is going to trade down, right.
And it's going to trade, let's say, trade down slowly. I can just short vol.
Right. Of course I can short Delta, but maybe,
maybe I'm taking on too much risk, right? Yeah. I'm doing that. So in this,
we're basically saying like,
we're minimizing the impact of us being wrong on that by taking advantage of this
correlation. Right. But, but then if the correlations, let's say like,
you know, tomorrow lit goes down 2% and vols go up a point. Yeah.
We're not going to be freaking out. No, we wouldn't be freaking out.
Because that's not really like our, that is not our trade.
It's just a piece of the puzzle that we took into consideration when structuring
it. But the strategy or the idea doesn't fall apart in that situation.
But if let's say traded down 5% tomorrow and vols picked up,
now we're probably in a tricky spot here.
We'd probably exit the position because on a rally vols might increase and on a
future down move vols might increase.
We might actually flip this position and maybe, you know,
pick up some long vol. Hey Swati, good to see you.
Swati has a question here for us.
Isn't IV and spot correlation related to gamma?
Like negative gamma is buying dips,
selling reps and positive gamma is the opposite.
So IV and spot will be correlated, you know, on the basis of gamma. Okay.
So Swati, so a negative gamma,
so short gamma is you're actually selling the dips and you are buying the reps,
right? Because if you think about it,
so let me just put it up here to show you.
So let's say we put on a position here where we are short gamma.
Okay. So here we're short gamma.
We can see that right here through our risk profile,
we're short negative 28 gamma. Now when the stock rallies, okay,
when the stock rallies, we need to buy shares, right?
In order to hedge our position, right? Otherwise we're just going to keep,
we're just going to keep losing money, keep losing money. So we need to buy,
we need to buy shares. And if it, if it drops, right, if the stock drops, well,
we need to start selling shares.
Otherwise we're just going to keep losing money, right? If we buy these dips,
then we're getting extra Delta and we don't want that.
So when we were short gamma, we are selling the dips and buying the,
buying the reps and a long gamma is vice versa is, is, is on the flip side,
right? And we can see that right in the stock rallies,
we want to get short and when the stock pushes, we want to when the stock dips,
we want to, we want to get long.
So and then the second,
the follow-up part was to that was so Ivy and spot will be correlated conditioned
on gamma.
So Ivy and spot will be correlated, conditioned on gamma. You know what Swati?
I honestly, I'm not too sure what you are saying here,
to be honest, I'm not 100% sure about the question.
Yeah. I, I'm not 100% sure what you're saying here.
Maybe if you want to maybe ask it in a different way or,
or maybe clarify it a little bit, then I'd love to,
I'd love to ask for the lesson. Do we have anything else you want to add here?
Not really. Just be aware of it, right?
Be aware of the the implied correlation and spot correlation, right?
Be aware that if you're buying stock, you are basically short the VIX, right?
So just always be aware of that during the position and what you think will happen
to the stock.
If you're super bullish on the stock and it's correlated with vols, you know,
maybe it's not a good, maybe it doesn't really make sense to short volatility.
Okay. So just be aware of that. It's very cool.
So do we have any more questions for now? If not,
that will be the conclusion of the live.
So Swati says, I was trying to say, uh, it's maybe positive E,
positive EV gamma will be IV and spot correlated or no, uh,
it's maybe it'll be, uh,
uh, Swati, are you big on Twitter? I feel like I saw someone post,
so is this plus Vega gamma? I saw someone post VE one time as,
as Vega on Twitter. Okay. So I was trying to say, uh, is my, uh,
I was trying to say, it may be plus Vega, positive Vega,
positive gamma will be IV and spot correlated. Maybe I'm getting it wrong.
You know what Swati? Let's, um, send me,
send me a message after this or chat in the group. Yeah.
Let's talk about it in the trainers chat. Yeah.
I'm a little confused on the question you're asking here. Uh,
so sensing is implied volatility of an individual stock correlated to the VXX somehow
every stock, uh, has different IV in respect to their sector, right?
So every stock is going to have a different implied volatility,
not based on their sector, but based on a lot of things, right?
Their fundament, uh, their, their fundamental value, right? If a stock,
it only has cash on their balance on their, on their book,
it doesn't make sense for it to have a lot of volatility, right?
If you are a startup growth company,
it will make sense for you to have a lot of, a lot of volatility.
Then there's other things like, uh, if, if this, if stock X,
let's say Facebook is super correlated to, uh, the NASDAQ, well,
if it gets out of line with the NASDAQ,
arbitrage are going to come in and try to collapse that spread.
So there's a lot of factors that are going to play into, uh, the,
what is the fair value of this implied volatility, uh, of this asset. Um,
and I feel like we've done, we've made like hundreds of hundreds of videos, uh,
about that stuff, maybe like one, one piece at a time.
So if you just keep chugging away there, you'll definitely, uh,
you'll definitely pick up on all that. Stan,
as you work your way through that archive of 200 hours of content, it'll, uh,
it'll be there for you. And then, but Stan,
make sure you go through the bronze first, it's important. And then, so one,
one last thing, uh,
Stan saying is implied volatility of individual stock correlated to the VIX somehow.
So usually they're going to be negatively correlated and that's for the VIX is,
is the vol on the S&P. Okay. VIX is the vol on the S&P 500.
And usually stocks are correlated with the S&P 500, right?
Facebook is definitely correlated with the S&P 500. So,
and S&P 500 is negatively correlated with the VIX. So if S&P drops, uh,
vols go up. So usually you're going to see if the stock goes down,
the vols increase, look at Twitter, look at Baba.
Sometimes you're going to have these mean stocks,
these other stocks that when the stock rallies, implied vol picks up.
Even with those, like you, you wouldn't be, uh,
so I think an important thing to talk about is, you know,
let's say we're looking at Tesla, right? In a market crash,
Tesla vols would probably still go up, right? For these massive moves, right?
Let's say the stock drops 30%. Yes. Vols are still going to go up.
So you wouldn't, you wouldn't be using Tesla as a hedge, right? Right.
So super important thing, I guess,
last thing we should talk about on that is we are talking about the more or less
the non-event volatility of it, right? The regular volatility of it.
But if you have a huge catalyst that drops the market, you know, or, uh,
you know, a huge earnings blunder that caused the stock to drop 20%,
you should still, you know, it's,
it's highly likely you will see vols go through the roof still, right?
Super important point, right? You would not be, um, you know, would it be, uh,
you know,
buying vol on a Tesla or selling vol on Tesla as a hedge for a market crash?
Yeah. You would never do that. Yeah. Um, and you know,
Sean just gave me a good idea here to draw it out here. Uh, there's, it's,
it's, it's, it's path dependency. Okay. So you have this, let's say meme stock.
Okay. It's trading like this.
Now, wherever the implied, wherever the realized vol is going to increase,
okay, is where we're going to see, uh, the spot correlation, right?
So let's say this is the S and P 500. If the S and P 500 moves down,
we should see it move down with more volatility, right? Stocks go up like a,
uh, escalator down like an elevator. Now if we,
if this was Tesla and let's say this is Tesla at 800, okay.
If Tesla were to trade at 900 in let's say a month, where would volatility be?
If Tesla were to trade at 700 in a month, where would volatility be?
And what we should see, right, especially with these, these, uh, meme, these,
uh, you know, uh, wild stocks like, uh, GME is that if it were to trade to 900,
it would go there with pace.
The volatility along this path would be extremely high. Okay.
So options are path dependent and maybe we'll do a live on that down the road.
We did a lot. We talked about that in our, uh, one about,
we didn't talk about it like thoroughly, but in the one about, uh,
the event ball messing with the price of the option. Oh yeah. No,
we were like a whole bunch of slow ball days, one high ball day,
the option sees all of it. We, we, we drew out the decision tree. Right, right.
We started. Yeah. Yeah. I think we can go a little deeper. For sure. Um,
so if it goes to 900, the vol is going to be extremely high,
but if it goes to 700, maybe the vol is very low to 700,
but if it trades to 600, okay, vols get high.
So you need to think about that path dependency, right?
And that's basically what the implied vol spot correlation is.
The market saying, cause the market is what's implied, right?
It's the market's view. If the stock goes up, implied vols and go up,
the stock goes down a little bit. The implied vol will drop,
but if the stock goes down quite a bit,
implied vols are going to increase again.
And that's what Sean was saying about the Tesla.
And we just hadn't mentioned that. So super important. Yeah.
Yeah. Mark, exactly. Right. So Mark saying, uh, you know, you would want to,
you know, during a, to hedge a market crash, you'd want to be long VIX,
not long equities, unless it was an inverse ETF or something similar. Yeah,
exactly. Mark. The, the, the main thing that I, are you using this? Yep. Yeah.
No, no, no. Right. Yeah. Mark. The, uh,
the main thing I was just pointing out there was just because you see Tesla has,
uh, you know, when, when Tesla goes up, implied vols go up, you know,
you wouldn't be, uh, you know, selling vol on Tesla as a hedge for the market.
Even though, you know, when Tesla goes down,
we see vol come down because that's not taking into account,
like a massive move down or a massive move down would still drive the vol up on
Tesla, even though it has that positive correlation.
And so blessing saying, so the more uncertainty there is,
the higher the chance of non-correlation.
It's not really about the uncertainty blessing. It's just basically about, um,
where the stock is going to see the volatility.
Is it going to see the volatility to the upside?
Is it going to see the volatility to the downside?
Whereas where's the volatility coming from? Right. So for example,
if we look at Tesla, we see 6% moves up,
3% moves down on the S and P we see 1% moves up, 4% moves down. Right.
So where, where is the volatility likely to be?
And that's going to cause that implied, uh,
realized correlation or implied spot correlation. Yeah. Mark,
I was basically just saying that, you know, an, uh, an equity like, um,
Tesla has a positive correlation between implied volatility and a price.
So when the price goes up, we see the implied vol go up for Tesla.
When the price comes down, we see the implied vol come down.
Now for the whole live, we talked about that, uh, just as, as a statement.
And I was just clarifying that with this,
this is not saying that you could be using Tesla vol as a hedge against a market
crash because if test,
okay, sorry. Yeah. Just to clear that, that if the market goes down,
they're all going down together. Okay. And the vols will go up for all of them.
Okay. Yeah. Sorry. It wasn't clear there. Yeah. One last thing there. Yeah.
So Swati's asking,
is it always better to buy deep in the money leaps instead of equity because it's
protected? So the answer is, is, um, there's never any, there's never a better,
right? That's the, that's the one thing. There's never a better, um,
every tool uses is used for a certain situation. Buying an in the money leap,
you're still going to pay some type of extrinsic value, right?
Some type of premium. And so for that reason,
if implied volatilities are too expensive,
you're going to be paying too much for that, even though it's a little bit,
right? That being said, if let's say the stock were to come down like crazy,
sure. The implied volatility will pick up, right.
And offset some of your losses, but your Delta is one for those options, right?
Assuming it's really, really far in the end of money, let's say it's like 0.9,
right? So you're going to have such a big loss on Delta. You're offset from,
um, you know, you're offset from a little bit of a Vega hedge.
It's not really going to, um, it's not really going to cut it. So there's debt.
I wouldn't say it's definitely better. Also,
there's bigger transaction costs out there, right? Um, I would say if you,
if you want to be long to start or long Delta, nothing wrong with buying stock.
All right. Okay. So here we go. So that's it. Awesome. Great questions.
I really appreciated the really good questions tonight, everyone, um,
makes the lives a lot more fun. And, uh, I think for everyone watching,
there's so much more value when we have these, uh, questions come in.
So let's keep it up. Thanks guys. And, uh, tomorrow poker night, Mark, Mark,
you better be there, man. No excuses, buddy. Eric. You too.
What's Mark saying? Stan. You got to be there too, man. Oh, Hannah.
Don't forget to be there. Okay. We know you're going to be there.
What do you mean? Stan, you've got, you literally have 23 hours to learn. Okay.
Guys, go figure it out. Mark. No response. Yeah. I know. Right. Mark.
What's going on? If you go into the archive,
there's actually a few videos on poker strategy there. He's still Mark.
We need to see you out there tomorrow, buddy. Come on, Mark. There he is.
How old is Mark? If we, Sean and I are going to make a post,
if we get more than 15 likes on it, you got to come out. You have to come.
How about that? Even if it's for an hour.
Yeah. So if you want to learn a little bit about poker,
go online and learn the basics.
And then you can learn a little bit about poker strategy.
If you go into the live archive, we have two or three videos on poker strategy.
Yeah. We're going to be playing on PokerStars.
We have a homeroom that we play in and then Sean and I give out $25 to the winners.
Except we never lose. Except, yeah, Mark, we don't lose.
Hutch is probably fuming right now. Or Hannah, sorry, not Hutch.
Hutch is not here today.
So yeah, we definitely, we need some competition out there. Okay, everyone.
We will see you tomorrow for poker night and to chat during the day.
We're going to be doing a whole bunch of market analysis tomorrow,
so we'll see you in the chat. Yep. See you guys. Andres,
I see you sneaking in late, man. Hey, buddy.
All right. See ya. Bye.