Go ahead.
OK, guys, so in this lab, we're going to be talking about synthetics.
We're going to be talking about different types of strategies.
It's going to be a very interesting live and a deep thinking live,
in my opinion.
It's it's actually probably one of the fundamental lives.
Let's say if you were to get onto a trading desk,
this would be one of the lives that that they would chat with you about or one of
the lectures they would give you.
So I think it's a really good one for you guys to be involved in.
OK, so let's get started. We can pull this up and share my screen.
Sean, do you want to make me host there?
So we're going to use Tesla for this example here.
All right. So there was two strategies. OK,
I'm going to give four strategies here, four bullish strategies.
And I want us to rank them from the best to the worst.
If you actually do know the answer,
please don't please don't write it just so everyone can really start to think about
it. So that's what we're going to be doing. OK,
so four bullish strategies as a group.
We're going to rank them from best to worst and the reason why. OK,
and like again, like I said, I didn't see Steve B on the live.
But for anyone else who actually knows the answers,
please don't please don't give it away. OK, so here we are.
We are bullish on Tesla. OK, and I've seen a couple of these strategies,
so I just want to get your guys opinion on it and we'll rank them.
So one of the famous ones that I've seen is the wheel. OK, the wheels,
a bullish strategy. And you guys can correct me if I'm wrong.
But the idea is you buy the shares, you sell a call. OK,
and if the stock goes up,
you're going to your shares are going to get called away and you're going to sell
a put. OK, and then you're just going to keep doing that over and over again.
So if the stock comes down, you're going to buy that.
You're going to get called on shares, you buy the shares,
and then you sell a covered call.
So you're rotating between selling a covered call and selling a short put. OK,
everyone knows the wheel, right? Let's open up the chat here.
It's going to be a little bit of more interactive, interactive live.
So let's really chat about this.
Now, they're just roasting us for having ads all over our browsers.
Or everyone understands the wheel, though.
OK, Trent, saying the wheel was my main thing. Yeah, it makes sense, right?
You buy the shares, you sell a call. If the call gets called away,
you're going to sell the puts. And if the stock goes down,
you're going to buy the shares, sell a call.
Or if the stock continues to go up, you collect the premium, right?
Everyone knows this, the wheel.
So that's the first strategy.
The second strategy I saw is hanging around somewhere is you sell an in the money
put.
OK, the share goes up. You're going to sell an out of the money put.
And if the share comes down, you're going to buy that,
buy that put back and sell them in the money put. OK, so let me just,
I'm actually going to draw these out. So we're all,
everyone's on the same page here. OK, so first off, we had the wheel.
And the wheel is, you sell a call, sell a covered call. OK, Jordan,
don't do it this way. Use the text, just you can write it out. Got it, got it,
got it, got it. Yeah, good point, good point. OK, so wheel. OK,
sell a covered call.
OK, you can do it as a list. Yeah, you can do it as a list,
like you can have key points. Right, so if you just hit enter,
it'll just drop it down. You have a text box. Got it, got it. Perfect. OK,
so sell a covered call. And once you sell a covered call,
two things can happen. So scenario one, our shares, our shares get called away,
in which case we will sell put. Scenario two,
the shares go down and we collect the covered call.
OK, that's strategy one. Wheel,
I just want to make sure everyone's OK with this. Can everyone just say,
I understand the wheel or Jordan, I don't understand the wheel.
OK, perfect engagement, guys. Thanks, guys. OK. OK, strategy two.
I think I saw this on Reddit somewhere.
You start off by selling an in the money put.
And it kind of sound a little weird to me, to be honest,
when I saw this selling it in the money put to start. Then if the shares go up,
OK, scenario one, you keep the premium.
OK, if the shares go down,
then you you sell it out of the money put.
So shares go up, you get to collect the premium, shares go down,
you sell out of the money put.
OK, what do you guys what do you guys think about these two strategies so far?
What do you guys think about them?
Steve, I actually said I think you weren't here for it,
but if you actually know the answer,
we're going to be ranking a couple strategies. And if you know the answer,
please don't please don't say the answer. OK.
So strategy two, let me just make sure that everyone's clear with it.
You sell an in the money put stock goes down.
You sell an out of the money put the stock continues to go back up.
You sell it out of the money put. OK,
what do you guys think? Thanks to you. Appreciate it. Yeah, I Jordan,
I think there's a little confusion about strategy to here. OK. OK,
let's I'll break it down. For example. OK. OK, so in this case, we buy.
So in this case, strategy number two, we would sell an in the money put.
Let's say we sell a 700 dollar strike put now Tesla for Tesla.
So what do we want to happen there, guys? Just so we can go step by step.
We sell it in the money put.
What do we want to happen? We want it to go up. Thanks, Brian. Go up.
If it does go up, OK, if it does go up,
we're going to sell an out of the money put.
If it goes up, we're going to sell an out of the money put.
Maybe we're going to sell. Let's say if it goes like, let's say it goes to 700.
We're going to sell a 680 put.
OK. If it goes down. OK, let's say it goes down. Let's say it goes down to 600.
Well, we're going to buy back that put that we sold in the money at expiration,
and we're going to sell another in the money put. OK, so let's say it goes.
Let's say it goes down to 600. We're going to sell a 650 put.
OK, so it's a little fishy, right? But what do you guys think about that?
What's your what's your opinion on that so far?
Did I explain it there good, Sean? Ryan saying it seems like a bad idea.
Eric saying not a fan. Like a bad idea, not a.
Yeah. OK. Yeah. But what do you guys think about the wheel?
Did the wheel make sense to you guys or no?
Yeah. Writing in the money put sounds indefensible, right?
It just it's not making sense. Well, what do you guys think about the wheel?
Do you guys like the wheel? Do you not like the wheel?
Yeah. So Red made a couple of comments as well. What do you say?
It seems he said it seems risky to write a put right after the underlying increase
enough for the shares to get called away. Right.
So the thing here, guys, and this actually dawned on me.
So you guys know I'm not a big fan of the wheel, right? And Eric,
I saw your comment there. I ignored it for for a specific reason.
You guys know that I'm not a huge fan of the wheel, but a lot of people are.
However, a lot of people would hate strategy number two,
but they are the exact same thing.
Strategy number one and strategy number two are identical. Zero difference.
So we're going to go and we're going to we are going to we're going to we're going
to chat about it. So let's go with Tesla.
We're going to price this out so you guys can see exactly. OK.
And this is going to be our introduction into synthetics.
So let's say we're going to do the wheel on Tesla. All right.
So we're going to buy a covered call.
OK, so let's take a look.
So here it is. And you're still sharing your wife. Oh,
you're sharing your whiteboard, Jordan. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
OK, so they are the exact same exact same trade. So here's our covered call.
And what is a covered call? It's an in the money put. They're the same thing.
OK, so let's say, for example, we do a covered call with strike 700.
So Tesla's trading at 680 and we'll do the 700 covered call.
This is exactly the same as selling the 700 in the money put.
Exactly the same trade. No difference.
There was a difference arbitrage. So we're selling it in the money put.
If the stock goes down, what do we do with the covered call? What we see,
we sell a new call, aka we sell a new in the money put. OK,
we still own the shares and we're just bringing down our strike.
So the wheel is, in fact, selling an in the money put. If the stock goes up,
you're going to sell an out of the money put. If the stock goes down,
you're going to sell another in the money put. OK, same thing.
And this is a synthetic covered call equals short put. Right.
What's the difference between a call and a put? Who remembers?
What's the difference between a call and a put?
Shares. Right. The difference. Good job, Trent.
The difference between a call and a put is shares. Right.
We can create this put with a call and shares. OK,
it's the only difference now. Which is basically the covered. Exactly.
And I see Red was saying it's easier to get trapped because of IV.
They're the exact same thing. The risk profile is identical. So check this out.
Implied vol, let's let's look at our Vega profile.
So you want to show the price slices on it? Yeah.
So let's look at our covered call here. OK.
Our Vega exposure on this is one thousand negative one thousand.
Our Vega exposure on the short put is negative one thousand.
So a ten point drop in implied volatility is going to be the same effect on the
call and the put. If there was a difference,
let's say there was a difference aside from dividends and interest rates.
If there was a difference, you could arbitrage. OK.
And this is synthetics one on one.
So we're going to do a whole bunch of synthetics today.
And I think you guys will find this very insightful.
So Danny's asking a question here. Are you saying if they are the same,
why the hell do people sell calls? Puts generally have more skew, right?
So they're the same thing. It's it's people. So I remember I saw on Facebook.
So this is like a this is why when you go to a trade firm,
this will be like the first thing, right? The synthetics trade one on one.
A lot of people say I like buying the dividend.
I like buying dividend stocks and selling covered calls on them or doing the wheels
on them. We've all heard it. Well,
and then I remember I had I had a talk with some guy on Facebook. I said, well,
why don't you sell the put? You're going to get more you get better financing.
And he said to me, I want the dividend. OK, now,
why doesn't that why does that not make sense? Or why could that not be?
Why would I be able to sell a covered call and capture the dividend,
but sell a put same strike and not capture that dividend?
What would you do in that case?
Right. The dividend is in the options price. It's baked into that option price.
OK, you can actually do dividend arbitrages with options.
That dividend is going to be baked into the option price.
Who's got a big high dividend paying stock that's having a dividend coming soon?
IBM, let's do IBM. I don't know if they're coming soon, but let's take a look,
guys.
Let's take a look at a three year option. OK, or sorry, a six month option.
So we're going to do we know we are going to come back to covered calls in a second.
We're going to do another one. We're going to do another synthetic.
We're going to do create synthetic shares.
So I'm going to sell a call. Sorry, I'm going to sell a put and buy a call.
Same strike.
OK, there it is. Here is our our shares exactly the same. Now,
some of you guys might say, well, look at this.
If the stock let's let's let's take a look at this, guys.
I know this might be a little bit tricky and I'll slow down if you guys need to,
but this is very important, right? This is this option is one on one.
Look at this, guys.
We can put this trade on where our break even is 131 and the stock's trading at
133. Why would I why would I buy shares when I could buy this?
Who's got the answer? OK, why is that my break even on this trade?
131 when the stock's trading at 133.
I basically get a free two dollars to put this on.
That's the dividend being priced into these options.
Right now. Question for you guys. Deep thinking question.
What would you do if IBM had no dividend and you saw this?
What would you do?
IBM had no dividend and you saw this.
Thank you, Harry. Our short the shares,
short the shares. Look at this, guys. Risk free profit coming in.
So I buy 10 of those combos and I sell a thousand shares.
I just walked in two thousand three hundred and thirty dollars risk free. OK,
the answer is there's a dividend by me showing those shares.
I have to pay that dividend.
And this is where a little bit of an arbitrage should come in,
because sometimes these options aren't pricing in the dividend arbitrage.
Or sometimes, for example,
a company grows its dividend over time and there's a risk, right?
A risk of the company not having the dividend or not growing the dividend.
And so that's not going to be priced into the option arbitrage.
So let's go back to our covered call.
And guys, make sure you slow me down. We really need to understand this.
So important. Oh, shoot. Oh, that's why.
So short put covered call. No difference. It makes people feel better that,
hey, I'm going to collect this premium if the stock goes down. Right.
I can sell a call. The stock goes down. I'm going to collect my premium.
I'll tell you a funny story, guys.
When I was first starting trading out and I found out about the covered calls,
I thought it was awesome. Right. I get to buy the shares, sell a call.
Worst case scenario, my shares get called away. And I called the guy at RBC.
And I was young. I was maybe 18 years old. I said, hey, listen,
I'm learning all these covered calls. What's my risk here? You know,
I just seem so good to be true. What's like what's going on?
And the guy said to me, he said something like, yeah, there is no risk.
If the stock goes down, you collect the shares. The stock goes up.
You risk your things get taken away. No, he did say to me,
the worst case scenario for you is if the stock blows through the roof and your
shares get called away.
People people will look at a covered call and say, this is great.
But they will look at a naked short put. And they will say, holy cow,
unlimited loss. Right, Sean, you've seen it so many times.
Yeah, well, they'll argue to the ends of the earth,
but it's the exact same risk profile, like in terms of your exposures you have,
they're identical.
And if you stop and like really think about how the covered call sort of works.
It's like if the thing rips to the downside, you're going to lose. Right.
We can all see it. You know, you're like,
let's say you're holding a stock that's worth $100. And then you collect,
you sell a $5 call. It's like, well,
if the stock goes below $95 all the way down, you're losing money.
You can almost visualize it looks identical.
And if you think about that in your head,
it almost looks it look it's a short put. It looks like it, you know?
Yeah, exactly.
And I always find it funny when people say they're different because if they were
different, you would just arm them all day. Right. You make a fortune.
So that is that's what a synthetic is. OK,
so it's the creating something with something else.
So we're going to do a whole bunch today, guys. And before I even show them,
let's chat about them. Let's see who can get them. Besides Trent and Steve B,
because I know you guys will get them all.
A call spread. OK, a call spread. I'm going to price it out here.
And we're going to think of there's a few ways we can do it. OK.
I'm going to price this one out here. And I see this all the time, guys.
I see this all the time. It drives me up the walls.
So I apologize in advance if I get a little emotional during this live. OK,
I've had it. I've had it out with too many people. All right. So here we go.
Six fifty seven hundred call spread.
Let's see who can replicate this the most times. OK. Yeah, exactly, Parker.
How can we replicate this? How can we replicate this?
This is actually on the gold exam.
This is one of the questions on the gold exam. Coasting put spread. Love it.
What else? What are other ways we can we can create this? I love it. Love it.
Put spread.
We're going to we're going to we're going to price them all out here.
How else can we replicate this? Who's got it?
Fifty shares and covered call. No, no.
Because you're still going to have all that downside risk.
But you're getting there. You're getting there. Sell shares and buy calls.
So if we sell shares and buy a call, what does that replicate?
Mark was saying sell, share, buy calls. What does that replicate? Who's got it?
OK, here we got the answer for this one. We're going to get there in a second.
Really good one. Beautiful, Chris. Sell shares, buy call equals call option.
Sorry, put option. Right. Let's just do that super quick.
Buy shares or sorry, sell shares.
So shares.
There it is. Let's buy a call.
Voila. We have a put option. OK,
what's the difference between a call and a put?
Shares. Synthetics. OK, so Harry, Harry hit it on the head here.
How can we replicate this? Well, let's look at it, guys. What is this?
What is that right there? That's a call option.
What's this right here?
That's a put option. OK, so how do we replicate this? We buy shares,
sell a call, buy a put. OK, let's do it. Right. So market makers, right.
How market makers will do it is you'll come in with an order.
Let's say you buy a vertical spread and the market maker will see that vertical
spread and he's going to try to replicate it somehow some other way.
And he's going to try to replicate it cheaper, create cheaper,
sell to you for more.
Let's take a look here by the shares.
OK, there we go. We're going to sell a call.
All right. There we go. And we're going to buy a put.
And there we go, guys. Look at that.
Our vertical spread.
And Koa had the other one. He said, brilliant. You sell the put spread. OK,
I've seen this so many times where people say, hey,
I'm going to sell a put spread because I collect a credit. OK,
I'm going to sell a put spread because I get to collect the credit.
And I say to them, well, would you buy the debit spread?
It's the same thing. So I got the strikes a little messed up there,
but same thing. And I asked them, I said, hey, well, why not?
Why not buy the why not buy the debit spread? And they say,
I like collecting the credit. Right. I saw this on GME. OK,
there was a guy on Twitter. Not going to mention any names. Pretty popular.
And he said, Jimmy, his name is Darren, by the way.
He said, listen, he said, listen, Jimmy, borrow rate is insane.
So to collect that borrow rate,
I'm going to sell a put in the money put spread because I'm bullish on Delta and
they want to collect that borrow rate. And someone asked him, like, hey,
why don't you just buy the call spread? And he said,
I want to collect the borrow rate, is what he said.
That borrow rate is going to be baked into that call option just because it's a
debit outlay. Right. The trade is identical.
And that debit outlay makes people queasy. It gets them a little excited.
They don't they don't like paying that debit. However, it is identical.
Always remember that, guys. What's the difference between a call and a put?
Shares.
Right. So of course,
saying I like I like the put spread because I can get assigned the shares.
And I think, you know,
selling selling an out of the money put is going to be better than buying a covered
call in the money. Right. So and that's, I guess,
for some microstructure reasons. It's not a huge difference.
It might cost you five cents because the market maker is not quoting it in the money
option.
But, you know, or if you don't like the hassle of, let's say,
moving the positions around and you just wanted to get exercise, you know,
that's another reason why Coalmite is saying here.
I like those out of the money put options because if I get assigned,
I get the shares. I don't have to worry about doing anything else.
But they are the same thing. No difference.
Yeah. You know, is that margin seeing SPX is a margin. Are you SPX 4000?
Who's SPX 4000?
Chig's. OK.
I'm not I'm not going to I'm not going to hate on these people on Twitter.
I'm not going to do that on a live Chig's.
If you want to you want to message me in private, we can have a little talk.
So are you guys understanding what a synthetic is?
Any questions about the synthetics with respect to everything?
So, Marcos, so it's it's not. So you use them actually in a lot of places,
right?
And I'm going to break them all down for you, Marcos.
But there was something I wanted to say about that.
One that I'd like to chat about is one that would be good to chat about is for short
shares, you know, if you're doing like the deltas. OK,
so that's what we're going to say quickly before I get to their show.
Harry is saying, so they're the same respect to Delta.
They're the same in respect to everything identical. If they're not identical,
arbitrage,
excluding dividends and interest rate and borrow cost arbitrage. OK.
That has a question here saying it seems like with covered calls and callers,
you can take profits on dips and let them run much more flexibility.
So so they're identical, right?
The one thing that you might get from the covered call, let's say,
is the liquidity of the shares. So, you know,
you sell the call and then the stock dips and you sell another call and you're only
trading that call. And if you're going to trade the shares,
they're more liquid. But if you're doing this on, let's say,
NASDAQ or S&P or like any liquid names, there's going to be zero difference.
And if there wasn't arbitrage. OK, if there wasn't a difference,
you could arbit. So liquidity aside, they are the same.
And for for liquid names, they're going to be the same.
So, yeah, something like ARK or Buzz,
you can get extra liquidity by buying the shares and then selling, let's say,
an out of the money call instead of selling it in the money put.
So that's a good point, right? OK, so let's get back to Marcos here.
So where would you use them? OK, so a few places, Marcos.
Let's say you want to short shares. You want to short Hertz,
but you can't short Hertz.
You can't short Jimmy because your brokerage won't give them to you. Well,
you can come into the option market and create those short shares. Right.
I'm going to I'm going to buy a put and I'm going to sell a call. Same strike.
OK, so now I don't need to worry about there being no short shares available.
I can just create it. I can just create it myself.
Now, usually, Marcos,
what you're going to find is the borrower rates are extremely high on stocks that
have are hard to borrow.
And so usually this you're going to be paying a debit for these trades.
But it's exactly the same. Sometimes you can are the borrower rate, right?
If the borrower rate in the shares is, let's say,
X and the borrower rate implied in the in the option is why we can make the arbitrage.
Just like if the dividend is going to be a dollar,
but the implied dividend from the options is five dollars arbitrage.
Let's see how many times I can say arbitrage. Tonight's five, guys.
All right. So that is the that's one way you would use them.
Another way you would use the Marcos is let's say you want to take an earnings trade,
but the trade's too big, right? You're doing an Amazon or Tesla earnings trade.
It's too big. You can't even do a one lot.
You can't even do the one lot, Marcos. It's too it's too big, let's say.
Let's say I remember when I was doing Amazon one time. It's too big.
I couldn't do it. So I said, OK, this is too much for me.
I'm going to do a half lot. Well, how do you do a half lot?
You're going to buy a call.
Analyze that trade. And you're going to short 50 shares.
So now we have a position on that's a straddle,
but it's half because it's a half lot. It's half the position of a one lot.
So that's another place you would use them.
You would also use them if they're a market maker would use them if they're he's
trying to replicate something. So you come in, for example, Marcos,
with a vertical spread. The market maker says, OK, well,
I can actually create that exact same spread through shares and calls and puts for
10 cents less. So I'm going to create it.
I'm going to sell you this for 10 cents more.
So that's where market maker would use it, right?
They're using it all the time, creating synthetics all the time.
Trying to get a few pennies here, a few pennies there,
thousands of times a day. OK, so that's where he's going to do it.
Let me think where else you would use it.
A lot of people use it for covered calls.
Let me think where else people would use these.
OK, here's a good one. We use it all the time, guys.
We use this one all the time for liquidity reasons. Who knows which one it is?
Who knows which one it is? This is a really thinking one.
Who is saying reversal? No.
What's the synthetic you guys use at PA all the time? Synthetic option callers?
Nope.
What is it? OK, it is a iron condor or we call it an iron condor,
even though it's an iron fly. Right. That's a synthetic. So here I go.
I'm going to create this iron condor.
So 665, 665.
And then I want someone else to tell me how I can create this another way.
So here is the standard PA IC iron condor.
But what this is a synthetic what it's a synthetic butterfly. Exactly.
I can recreate this exact same structure by buying a butterfly.
Now, the reason why I like to do the IC is because we're not in the money.
So sometimes liquidity can be terrible and the market maker might want an extra
few, few more cents for you going in the money. Same trade.
Yeah, exactly. There's like you can create two vertical spreads.
You can create just so many ways.
But this is a iron condor that we talk about.
PA iron fly is the same as a butterfly.
OK. So that's one way.
Another way that we use the Marcos is to get a little bit extra liquidity on the
out of the money options instead of going in the money.
Yeah. So usually Marcos in the money options are slightly less illiquid. OK,
that being said, you should honestly be getting the same price, you know,
but sometimes you can get, you know, you can get a couple of cents.
The market maker wants an extra five cents in the money there.
The other issue is, especially when we're creating PA,
is having beginners trade in the money legs is probably not a great idea,
right? You know,
you don't need to get a little fishy when a little strange when it comes into expiration.
So, you know, that's another reason why we stayed away with those.
But they're really the same thing, Marcos. There's no real big difference.
There's no efficiency in terms of buying power.
OK, so that is the live on synthetics.
What's the difference between call and put? Shares.
And the difference between a covered call and an in the money short put?
Nothing. Nothing.
And the difference between the wheel and selling it in the money put and out of
the money put and in the money put is nothing. So, you know,
always be aware of that, guys. Whenever you see someone say,
I like some covered calls and you say, well,
what do you think about selling short put for margin efficiency?
And they say because of the dividends or because of max risk,
you can write them off right away.
Is there a way to synthetically replicate a caller?
Yes. So the caller is the vertical spread, right? Buy the shares,
sell the call, buy the put.
Same thing as a vertical spread or call spread or a short put spread.
And then same things. Harry had a question here. He's saying,
can you walk me through why you're only shorting 50 shares to replicate the straddle?
Is it because the delta of an at the money call? Yes.
But you're going to delta neutral. You're going to do neutral.
Just like you're just like a straddle itself.
And Marco's saying, so is there a Marco's? Yeah, go ahead. Yeah. OK, OK.
Is there is there an argument?
He asked it earlier as well,
because a lot of companies were suspending their dividend this year. Yeah. So,
Marco, what do you.
Yeah. So there could be. Right. You have Sean. No,
it's funny when you're talking to Mike. I don't know if it's on my end,
but you cut off. You break up like you'll be like,
I'll hear like five words and then three words gone and then five words come back
in later. Yeah. Or do you guys do that as well? Yeah, that's only me.
Oh, it's me, maybe. And OK. Interesting. You always end. No, no.
They're saying they break off. Sounds like, ha, ha, ha, ha.
OK. I mean, Ryan. OK, Marcos.
So it's all about what's implied in the options market and versus what happens.
So here's an example.
Imagine you you remember when when General Electric was given like a four percent
dividend and they cut all their dividends. I don't know if you remember that.
Well, the two year options were implying dividends for two years.
OK, because G is so stable.
Who would not think that they're going to cut their who think they cut their dividends?
They've been paying them for 50 years. So what you could imagine you knew that,
Marcos, imagine you knew that G was going to cut their dividend. Well,
you could buy General Electric and short that synthetic.
And then once General Electric cuts its dividend,
you're going to make all that money in that dividend.
In that from that from those options,
from those implied dividends being taken away from the options. OK, no,
it would be instant. Right. If if G says, hey, I'm cutting my dividends. Well,
there's no more dividends. So they're gone. It's instant.
It's instant right away. Now, that being said,
sometimes we're not instant inefficiency arbitrage, right?
You'd want to price the synthetic pre you know,
pre announcement of cutting dividends and then post announcement and see what happened.
Is it still implying a dividend? If it is, make it happen, right?
How would you structure it, Tico? You would just sell,
sell it in the money call. Sorry. So same strike call and a put and buy a put.
Right. You just create the synthetic shares.
So here you're saying realistically, why would there be an ARB in that case?
You're not going to find out about the dividend before the price is in. No.
And yes, yes.
The market is almost always almost always is usually very efficient. So,
of course, you're going to be pricing it. But there's a dividend risk premium.
Right.
Imagine how could a five year option imply five years of dividend from IBM?
Isn't there a risk that IBM stopped paying dividends? Of course.
So for that reason, the dividends are not fully going to be priced in, right?
Because of that, because of the risk that, you know,
IBM doesn't give their dividends or doesn't increase their dividends.
So that's just a risk premium. It's not an inefficiency.
What do you guys think? If that's no more questions,
we'll we will leave it there.
Looks like that's it.
OK.
Marcos, great seeing you out here. We've got one more.
Marcos is down in Mexico still, I wonder. OK, where's Red? Oh, for sure he is.
He'll come back. I guess we'll already come back. Red's saying, he's saying,
can't the top of that put credit spread get called away from being in the money?
For sure. But if it does get called away, how amazing would that be? Right.
It's another thing I see a lot of the time. People say, like,
I'm worried about assignment. I'm worried about assignment.
If you short a call or short a short put and it gets assigned.
All that extrinsic value is yours straight to straight to the bank. Right.
So if I ever got called away on on anything short with extrinsic value in it,
I mean, it's a it's a great day. It's a great day. Red,
if you want to look a little more into that,
you can check out the live archive. We have a video on it.
Just look up early assignment. Like just control go to the archive.
Control F early assignment should come up.
Yeah, right. Great questions, man. Keep them coming.
I'd love to see you on the live man. Good stuff. You know,
you're keeping the keeping the lives fun to come out, too. So keep it up, man.
OK, we'll see you guys on the next one.