Okay guys, welcome to a Wednesday Night Live.
We're going to be chatting about valuing volatility and subsequently valuing options.
One thing that I realized the other day was part of our core business in terms of
as a trader is value, right?
Can we find something that's cheap and can we find something that's expensive,
right? And you know, sell expensive things and buy cheap things.
And if we do that over and over again,
we're going to come out ahead in the long run. Similar to, let's say,
buying a value stock, right? Everyone knows, oh, you know,
I got to buy a cheap price to earnings stock or cheap price to book. And,
you know,
eventually that's going to come back to fair value and I'm going to profit.
But when it comes to the option space,
it gets maybe a little bit more tricky to understand, well,
what's expensive and what's cheap? Yeah, what's expensive and what's cheap.
But we are applying the same types of concepts.
Where can I find options that are cheap in terms of volatility, right?
We always have to remember that options are volatility products.
And so if we can find cheap volatility and buy that and sell a volatility that we
think is expensive, we can make money. But here is the important but.
How do we know what is cheap and what is expensive?
And how can we put a price target on that, right? Let's say, for example,
we are looking at Coca-Cola, okay? And we say, well, given, you know,
price to earnings of Coca-Cola or price to earnings of Pepsi or price to book value
or however many assets it has divided by liabilities,
whatever technique we're using, we can actually come up with a fair value,
right? We see like, let's say, Goldman Sachs comes out and says,
price target of Tesla, 15,000. Or what's that guy's name on Twitter, Sean?
Pateek. Pateek, right? Partel. Yeah, yeah. Actually,
I got a call yesterday from Kelly Patel. Interesting. Interesting.
I didn't answer that one. But so we actually see this in equity space, right?
Price target of this. But in the vol space, we don't usually hear people say,
I think implied volatility should be worth 40%.
Or I think it should be worth 70%. And so in this lab,
we're going to be talking about that valuation.
I wish Margin was on here. He did a very in-depth breakdown the other day.
Okay.
So I'm going to share my screen and we're actually going to use Diska as our stock
of choice. But does anyone have any questions about that so far?
Is anyone confused about what we're trying to do here before we jump into it?
A couple from some of the new members. What are you guys thinking?
What's going through your heads? Yeah. Let's hear some questions.
Okay. I guess no questions. All the new members are top-notch.
They're already pro vol traders. All right. Rachel's just commenting.
We want to find out the value and base volatility based on that. Yes.
We want to find the fair value of volatility, right? Let's say for example,
Rachel, you're looking at a stock. You might say, Hey, fair value is $50,
but it's trading at $30 today. So I'm going to buy it. Right.
And on the flip side, a short seller might say, Hey, I think this is worth $20.
It's trading at 50. So I'm going to sell it. But in the option space,
because the volatility concept is so hidden,
it's so far far off the beaten path, really,
especially in the retail community. You don't hear people say, Hey,
implied volatility is at 90. It should be worth 50.
What we hear in let's say like tasty trade is, Oh, there's high IV rank.
Let's sell it. But we didn't really come up with a value.
What should this volatility be trading at? And if we can,
if we can get better at pricing volatility, we can make money. And that's,
that's the important part.
All right, let's do it. Okay. Cool. Cool.
By the way, guys,
I just found the Avicii album 10 and it's just been on replay. Love it. Okay.
Let's see here.
Okay, cool. So everyone can see my screen.
We are going to do a valuation for Disco.
Now, if you guys want to see a really in-depth valuation, I did one on Tesla.
Sean, we have that in the recordings, right? Yes.
So I did a really in-depth valuation on Tesla.
If you guys want to go check that out. And finally, it's starting to come down.
So we saw Tesla going below 67 ball today.
And we're actually going to touch on that towards the end and same with Disco actually,
I think it's going to be good if we touch on this. All right. So let's go,
let's head over to Disco. So first thing is first, how did we find Disco?
Right? Well, we found it by searching for high implied volatility.
That means implied volatility rank, implied volatility versus our forecast.
Okay. That is what we searched for. And we found Disco here.
And some of the guys got in on March 19, March 17. Funny enough, Margin Kyle.
So you guys might know him in the group as Margin.
He actually sent me a message on March 16 saying, Jordan,
you got to sell the shit out of Disco ball. And actually, one second, guys,
I'm going to stop sharing my screen.
So I'm going to share Margin's work without his permission.
Don't tell him he's on the call.
Just give me one quick second here, guys.
This is what happens when you share good work. Gets leaked to the whole group.
Exactly.
But it's after the trade, so. Yes.
Okay. Here we go.
Okay. So I get a message from Kyle, March 16. Okay. The peak of Disco.
I don't know how sometimes our group members call these trades,
but I honestly think they just get lucky sometimes. So he says to me, hey,
Jordan, I think you're missing a big banger. The trade is Disco.
And what Margin did was, so he searched,
Margin is searching for high implied volatility stocks.
We're trying to find stocks that are in price to earnings terms are expensive or
cheap. We are basically saying, let's scan,
let us create a scan to find undervalued stocks. Now we can't buy all of them,
but we're going to create a scan to find undervalued stocks.
And that is what we do with IV rank, IV versus forecast, and a few others,
retail sentiment, et cetera.
So we create a basket of stocks that might be expensive.
And there's tons of lives about how we actually scan for that.
And we're actually just going to go into the evaluation of this stuff.
So he says, hey, you might be missing out on a banger here.
And the way that Margin prices, he did two ways.
The first way is in absolute terms.
So we will come back to Margin in a second.
So there's two ways we want to try to value something.
One is in absolute terms, and the other is in relative terms.
And this is going to be universal. This is not just for volatility.
This is for real estate. This is for equities, for valuations in general.
There are two key ways, in absolute terms and in relative terms.
So does anyone want to give me a quick example of what you think it means by absolute
terms and in relative terms? What do you guys think?
What's going through your heads?
And maybe actually,
if you could give a real life example outside of volatility trading,
absolute terms and in relative value terms. An example outside of trading,
it could be anything. What do you guys think?
Where's Steve? Is Steve on this chat, Sean? Yeah, he's in here.
He's sleeping though, isn't he?
Chris is trying to buy a house in the San Francisco Bay Area. Yeah.
Tell me more, Chris. What do you mean by that?
If we want to price it in absolute terms and in relative terms?
Koaw is like real estate in Montreal is expensive in absolute terms.
Eric's saying price per square foot comparison is relative.
Everyone's giving a real estate example. That's funny.
So Koaw is like real estate in Montreal is expensive in absolute terms,
but cheap relative to Toronto. Okay.
So let's actually go a little bit more with that, Koaw.
So when you say it's expensive in absolute terms,
why is it expensive in absolute terms? Actually,
Trent had a kind of cool one here. He said,
absolute could be saying that Jamal Murray is good at basketball,
relative is saying that he's bad compared to Steph Curry. Okay. I like that.
So usually when we're looking in absolute terms,
we're seeing how this asset relates to itself. Okay. So if we're looking at,
let's say at a certain house in Montreal,
we're looking at this house in Montreal and we graph the price of it over the last,
let's say the last five years.
And we see that it goes up and it goes down and it goes up and it goes down.
And right now it's up here. Well, in absolute terms,
if we're looking at it in a vacuum,
we are saying that this is pretty expensive right now, right?
Maybe we've also compared it to,
we take the price of the house and we divide it by,
let's say the rent of that same house. And we graph it over time, right?
We're looking at it in absolute terms. So for example, price to earnings,
right?
We're taking the earnings and the price of the same asset and looking at it through
time. Okay. And we could do price to book. We could do the price itself.
We could do all these different metrics within the same asset. Okay.
And that's going to be an absolute terms in the vacuum.
And we're just looking at the single asset.
Okay. So for example, if we come into relative value here,
am I still sharing my screen, Sean? Yes.
And let's say we're looking at,
you're kidding. Jordan was sober last night,
but relatively sober compared to Sean.
Perfect. That's actually a perfect way to say it, right?
I was at all times whiskey intake last night, personally, but relative to Sean,
my whiskey intake is very low. You can say something like that. Okay.
So let's take a look here.
Let's take a look at the implied volatility 90 of Tesla versus so actually,
you know, let's, let's just plot the implied volatility by itself.
So we can see like, for example, up here,
Tesla implied volatility is expensive, right? It's pretty expensive.
But one thing about this is like,
this is a kind of like looking at the price chart, you know,
it's not too exciting. So we could do is like, let's say,
create something like price to earnings,
but instead we are going to do IV 90 divided by RV 20,
similar to price to earnings. Okay. We're going to run the ratio.
And now we create another graph, all in absolute terms. And we could say, okay,
well, this implied volatility is expensive right now,
relative to it's realized volatility in absolute terms. Okay.
So that is the first way to do it. And, you know, that's how, you know,
you could take this anywhere. Is this expensive in absolute terms?
Now that's only one piece of the puzzle. Okay. We can't just say,
we can't just look in absolute terms, right? Things change,
things outside are changing and we need to, you know,
we need to be aware of that.
So let's say, for example,
we'll be good. So I don't do any real estate,
but I'm trying to just like make an example here.
You go and look at a real estate,
you go and look at real estate and there's this house that is looking pretty expensive
in absolute terms. Okay. In terms of the rent that you're,
let's say we create some time series. Yeah. You got it. Let's do it.
Let's talk about real estate, right? Imagine you're looking at a neighborhood,
right? And you notice that the average house there is priced at $300,000,
but there's one house that's priced at $350,000, you know,
that house looks expensive, right? It's like, wow,
around all these other houses, you know, it's you know, looks expensive, right?
But then you notice that that one house,
that house is maybe walking distance from a school,
walking distance from the subway.
There's a grocery store around the corner and a park across the road.
And then you look at other houses in the area that have those same characteristics
and they're all priced at 400,000. Now,
all of a sudden that house is looking cheap, right?
Relative to assets with similar characteristics to it.
Or you notice that that house went up through 50 grand. You're like, wow,
it's gone up a lot,
but you see it's actually still cheap relative to similar ones.
I like that one.
So that's, that's, you know,
it's a way to think about in terms of relative or it's looking expensive,
but a Walmart just got built or a school just got built.
And so now it's totally different. Things have changed.
So that's what we need to do. We need to price it relatively as well. Okay.
We don't want to just look at Coca-Cola by itself.
We want to look at Coca-Cola relative to Pepsi.
So that's what we're going to do here. We'll do Coke and Pepsi.
And what we'll do is we'll take the price of Coke and the price of Pepsi.
I will say, well, we will look at the IV 90s and we'll run the ratio, right?
We'll see what's going on here. And you can see basically like up here,
if we take, you know, Coca-Cola volatility and divide it by Pepsi ball,
this is when it got pretty expensive, right?
And you can see it stays within this range. It's pretty, you know,
it's pretty stationary. It's staying within this range. And this can, you know,
if we saw, let's say Coke all the way up here,
you know, this was going to be extremely expensive.
So this is what happened with Diska. Okay. So this is what Margin sent me.
So he did Fox A and Diska and he graphed these out and look what he noticed.
He said, okay, you know, these are, you know, pretty much in line,
but all of a sudden we're out to lunch. All right.
This thing is getting priced extremely high. I said, okay, well,
let's take a look here. If Fox A, what's that?
Yeah. Foxa was a, um, oh, so, okay. We're going to get to that in a second,
but basically it was a correlated stock. And I'll show you how we found that,
but there's a correlated stock, similar characteristics also in, uh,
in the same space as Disney discovery, whatever it is.
And you can also do Netflix, I guess, Disney, all those,
all those names to see what's going on there.
Um, so he says, it's pretty expensive. And basically you can see from this,
right? You could say, well, okay, on the high end,
Diska is usually 1.2 times the IV of Fox A. Okay. You can see that right here.
1.2 times is on the high end. So if we know that Fox A is trading at 48 vol,
then Disney or discovery should be trading at 48 times 1.2. Uh,
who's got the quick maths that's 60 vol 58 vol. Okay.
But instead it's trading at 83. Now, you know, this is sometimes, uh,
we can be on the wrong side of these, right? So we need to dig deep.
We need to really understand what's going on here. So what else does he do?
Well, you know, from our chat here, right? So here it is, guys,
here's Fox A and discovery. He does the ratio IV nineties.
That's what he's looking at. Okay. That's one way to look at it.
But here's what he also does.
He sends me this graph and this is in the terminal.
And what this graph is telling us is, are these two assets actually correlated?
Okay. He's trying to like,
you have to make sure that these two assets are correlated.
Otherwise you can't really compare, right?
You can't compare Shopify and Coca-Cola. So let's head back to the terminal.
So we're gonna come to correlation and do Disco and Fox A and here,
we're going to remove the outliers. So let's hit this.
So here are the price graphs. Look at that. Look at them.
Almost the same thing. Okay. Here's the rolling correlation.
So if we take 60 day samples, cut them up and we take that correlation. Well,
we're going to see that most of the time,
these assets are between 70 and 80% correlated.
70 to 80% of these assets are correlated over the last year.
And you can also see this, okay? That, you know, these are the returns.
So when Fox A is up 6%, you can see that Disco is up 1.1 times 6%. Okay.
1.1 times 6%. So it'll be up about 6.7%.
And this is what, this is how we're trying to value the volatility, right?
This beta is basically telling us that the volatility of Fox A times 1.14 is going
to equal Disco volatility.
Okay. So that's what Margin is doing.
He's making sure these assets are the same and he's trying to value it.
So now let's head back over to a relative value. He also did XLC,
which is an ETF that holds these, these like subscription companies,
like Discovery, Netflix, Disney, et cetera.
And you can see it was just like through the roof. Okay.
Implied volatility was just through the roof.
And there's so many more ways we can value this, guys. We can do more assets,
right? We can even do IV divided by RV. So check this one out, guys.
I really like this one. This is one of my little secrets.
I wouldn't say it's a secret, but I really like this one. So you take,
you take the implied volatility 90 divided by the realized volatility 20. Okay.
And that's going to give you a spread.
And then you do it for a similar company. This is,
this is in William Sinclair's book, by the way, guys.
So I guess it's not really one of my secrets.
Okay. And oh,
wow. Oh, guys, I have this one messed up.
Oh, shoot. Let's see if this works.
Sorry, guys. I got to change. I got to fix this. But anyways,
you take the ratio of these and the ratio of these,
and you'll be able to graph it, right? So if we did this, we ratioed, and guys,
stop me along the way. If we're confused, right? This is important stuff,
right? This is important stuff. We're trying to, we're trying to,
we're trying to make some money here. So this is important that we can,
we're trading volatility, right? We need to be able to value it.
Okay. So you can see here, Fox A was only 0.93,
was the ratio when Disco was 1.3.
We've got some questions coming in. Let's just take a look.
Why 90 days compared to RV20? First off, Rachel, thanks for asking questions.
You know, it's super important. It's super important.
So thanks for jumping in here. We're,
we're looking at the IV90 because that's what we wanted to trade.
We wanted a little bit more exposure to Vega,
meaning the implied volatility than we did to Theta.
So we went out a little bit more in time, let's say 90 days, 100 days.
And so that's why we're comparing the IV90 to the RV20.
Also implied volatility, it cares about what's happening now, right?
And the reason it's caring about what's happening now is because volatility clusters.
So we're not going to look at, let's say the RV60 or the RV90,
because that's going to have, you know,
what happened 90 days ago doesn't really care.
We don't really care about it today.
And so that's why we're looking at a shorter realized vol time period.
But we're looking at a longer IV period.
Chris is saying, how did you find Fox A?
I think Margin, so I didn't find Fox A, Margin did.
And I think he just went and did a Google search on what are similar assets,
what are similar companies. Reach out to Margin,
ask him what secrets he's got up his sleeve there.
Okay, so now we can actually price this implied volatility, right? We can say,
okay, well, it should be about 1.2 times Fox A and about 1.3 times XLC.
And we obviously, you know, value it in absolute terms as well. And we say,
okay, well, if things were to quiet down a bit, where are we going to go to?
Right? And we know volatilities mean reverting. So we plot the IV90 and we say,
okay, well, recently before this big spike, it was trading at around 56, 57.
So once this vol is, let's say, gone, this news is gone,
we should see this come back down to 57.
So now we're getting a sense of, okay, if we're right,
where are we going to be able to,
where are we going to get out of our position? And you can see here.
So even though the guys got out at 66, right, 66 vol or 65 vol,
it's continuing to melt off another two points today. And if our, let's say,
fair value was 55 or 57, well, we might want to keep holding this until we get,
you know, to the level we're looking for. One thing to keep in mind though,
is that there is an earnings event coming up in this cycle.
So we're probably not going to get that 57 mark,
which is why I think the guys cashed out yesterday.
Now, obviously there's more advanced techniques we can use to value volatility,
but I think this is a great start.
If you want to see a little more advanced tutorial, I did one on Tesla.
And that is finally starting to come down. I can't believe it.
Can't believe it. Right.
We saw implied volatility get all the way up to the high numbers here.
And it's finally, look at that guys. Just finally, absolutely melting off.
And, you know,
I'm still holding the position simply because I have it valued at 58 vol.
I have the two-year value at 58 vol. So I'm holding for another 10 vegas.
Right. It took so close saying it took a month, but the P&L is coming in huge.
Right. We're talking about an option that went from 850, $850, sorry, $85,000.
$850 is the contract, is the contract spec, but $85,000 for one lot. Right.
Coming down to $800.
So, you know, it might take a month,
but now we're making 10% P&L on our straddle. Right. And, you know,
sometimes you got to wait. Right.
Sometimes you got to be all good things come to people who are patient.
By the way, Sean. Oh, Sean, we haven't finished Ronan yet.
After this. Yeah.
So that is basically valuing volatility in a nutshell,
in a super high-level overview.
Questions, comments, concerns. What's going on? So, Jordan, you know,
should you, should someone be doing this for every trade they take?
100%. 100%. The last thing I'm going to say about this is,
the last thing I'm going to say about this is the spot IVOL correlation.
So check this out guys. Okay. Here is DISCA. Okay. What do we notice here?
Okay. What do we notice here?
What are you guys seeing?
Implied volatility, 90 and the spot price.
Rachel's saying they look correlated. Perfect, Rachel. Wow. Blessing.
Rachel's following it, following in your footsteps here.
She's, she's going to be a rockstar very soon.
So what do we see here? Well,
the implied volatility and the stock price are correlated. Okay.
So we might also have a directional view here and say, okay, well,
if I honestly think DISCA is overpriced, let's say that's what I'm thinking.
And if DISCA were to trade down to $60 a share,
what would implied volatility be at? Right. If it were to trade down to 60,
what would implied volatility be at? And if let's say we're to go to a hundred,
what would implied volatility be at? And that's, you know,
that's going to be for a more advanced topic,
but that's another way that we can value this volatility. Okay.
We're trying our very best.
The person that can value the volatility the best is going to make a ton of money.
So the more things we can do to try to get a sense of what fair value is for this,
then we're going to make some money. It's honestly like real estate.
It's kind of funny. Like people, a lot of people spend so much time, you know,
trying to price a house. Is this thing fair value? Is it not fair value?
But when it comes to trading, we don't really want to put any numbers to it.
We don't want to really value this thing. And I think it's so important that,
you know, that we do.
So, you know, it's, it seems like it's pretty clear that it's important to,
to value it.
Do you want to maybe show let's draw a conclusion here on DISCA for example,
right? And obviously we're looking at today's data,
so it's not going to be as pricey as it was when we originally took the trade,
but maybe let's draw our conclusion here on DISCA and then use the option calculator
to,
or the vol calculator to price out what the options should be worth and what our
expected value is. And, you know,
like how we can turn this into what we expect to happen for the trade.
Okay. So Jared, really good point.
Jared saying the catalyst for that repricing was the stock coming down, right?
Check this out. This goes down 10 and a half percent.
That's a crazy amount of vol,
but that catalyst to reprice the vol to what we think might be fair value or should
be fair value was the stock dropping, right?
Or was some news coming out saying, whatever it is. And that, that,
and that gave the reprice, but it's just like when we're buying an equity,
right? Let's say we're buying an equity and, you know, we think it's worth $80.
It's trading for 20. Well, what's that catalyst going to be?
That's going to shoot it up. Maybe the catalyst is the company says,
we are actually going to be paying all our debt or we just got a huge line of credit
or whatever it is, or sometimes it's even a company coming in and saying,
I'm going to buy this company for fair value,
but we usually need some type of catalyst, some spark.
That's going to bring this thing back down to our fair value price calculator.
So here we go. Let's say we're looking at this guy.
This guy was trading at 80 bucks and Sean,
let's say did the 90 combo. And it was for July. You're on June there.
Okay. And volatility was, what was it Sean? 85.
So here is what that combo was trading at $32.
So if you're going to sell the 90 straddle for, uh,
on Disco for the July contracts, now Sean did a strangle, but in this example,
we're going to do a, uh, a straddle. Okay. You can see our Delta is 50. Okay.
So we're selling the Delta 50 straddle on Disco.
Now let's say we think that fair value of this option is 65 vol.
That's how much, you know,
hopefully the market is going to realize that now the beauty of the,
of an option of the option market is fair value has to be recognized. Why,
why does fair value have to be recognized as an option market,
but it doesn't have to be realized in a stock.
Why is that?
Justin saying vol mean reverts. What do you guys think?
Because of realized vols time components. Thank you, Eric. Thank you.
And Steven, thank you. An option expires. So if, you know,
let's say we think fair value is 65. If it realizes 65,
we're going to get paid out with a stock.
It could stay under fair value forever. So that's,
that's the most beautiful thing of the options market that I love is that if there
is a fair value, the options will realize it.
The downside to that is sometimes you end up carrying this option for three months.
Sure. You're going to make money, but it took a long time to pay out.
Okay. And all you're going to be doing if it's,
if it's not paying out is every single day,
you're going to be making that data that carry,
it's going to be carrying very well.
Yeah.
Yeah. Jerry, we, we've definitely bagged held a few times here. No doubt.
No doubt.
If you have these ones, you're not a real trader. Exactly. Yeah, no doubt.
But the thing like, you know,
at least if you bag hold an option that's under fair value or, you know,
below fair value, that's right.
It's above fair value and you're realizing under it that you're going to make,
you're going to make good return.
And here is exactly how much you're going to make actually.
So let's go back to the example, implied volatility, 85%.
Option should be trading at $34. We think it's worth 65,
which means we think the option is worth $26.
Can someone break this down for me? Can someone break this down for me?
I'll show you one more time. It's currently trading at $33, $34 trading at 34,
the option. And we think it should be worth 26.
Can someone break down for me? What is going on here?
Eight chicken strips. Tell me more, Steve.
What's going to happen here?
Let's say we're right.
Stevie.
Lauren's saying predicting a different vol. Yes.
So what's basically going to happen is two things could happen here.
Imagine we're right. And this thing is actually worth 65 vol.
Well, we're going to end up, two things are going to happen.
The first thing and the thing that we don't want to really happen is we're going
to hold this option for three months and we are going to realize $8.
We are going to make $800 per contract.
The thing is, we don't really want to wait three months. But you know what?
800 bucks is $800.
The second thing that could happen that we want to happen is the market is going
to realize that we're right. Some catalyst comes out,
some type of repricing happens. And the market says, this is the fair value.
And the options will drop from $34 to $26.
In which case we would have earned $8.
And let's say a week or two weeks or three weeks. And that is what our goal is.
Our goal is for the market to eventually say, you know,
the guys are predicting alpha are right.
The guys and girls are predicting alpha are right.
And that this thing should be trading at 26 or 65 vol.
Okay. That's the best case scenario. Obviously,
the worst case scenario is we're wrong.
This thing's worth 110 vol and it blows through the roof.
But our expected value on this trade is $8.
Our expected value is $8. If we realize that $8 quicker,
higher return on capital. Better for us.
But the beauty is we will eventually realize that $8.
So, Cole, he doesn't have a view on Delta. Correct.
Sean, you want to add anything there?
So Ram's asking, how do we come to the assumption that it's 65 vol?
So Ram, it was all the valuation we did earlier. So in this case, right,
we were looking at, we saw here. Okay. Well, look, before this big expansion,
right? Vol was trading at around 56, right? We have an earnings event now.
So it's probably going to be a little bit higher, right? Maybe 60.
So that's one way, right? We're taking a look at the vol cone. Okay. Well,
third quantile is 53. That's pretty pricey, right? So right off the bat,
we're thinking it could definitely pop in around this area, right?
Between the mean and the third quantile. Because vol is mean reverting.
The second thing is in relative terms, right? When we priced it against box A,
we priced it against XLC. Okay.
And like I was saying, there's more sophisticated techniques. We can say, okay,
well, you know, we can do some quick modeling to say,
maybe we'll do a whole live on this on spot versus eyeball.
But basically if spot were to drop to a certain price,
what would implied volatility be? Okay.
So that's how we're coming to the conclusion.
We're trying to price this volatility, right? Like an actual hard number.
You guys have seen me in the group multiple times say, you know,
especially when we were doing the lit, the arc, the Tesla, you know,
almost never do we say volatility is high in this story, right?
That's usually a tip of the tasty trader way. Hey, vol is high,
right? That's not what we do here. Volatility is high. If we are right,
volatility is going to go to 50. If we are wrong,
we're going to stress the position to vol moving up 10 points and we're out of the
position. Okay. That's the big difference.
We're actually trying to value something. What is this thing worth, right?
Imagine Warren Buffett just said, Hey, the stock is cheap. And that's it. Well,
when would he get out? You know,
maybe he's cutting his losers too quick because his fair value is still a lot higher.
So what Warren Buffett does is he looks at the balance sheet and says, Hey,
this company is worth $80. It's trading at 40. Well, I can get 40 bucks here.
I think that's a big,
actually mistake that a lot of technicians do is they say, Hey, this is,
this is breaking out, right? It's like saying, Hey, this is a Lamborghini. Hey,
this is a, you know, this is this, but instead we want to say, Hey,
this is a Lamborghini. It's worth a hundred. It's worth, you know,
200,000 and someone's willing to give it to me for 50,000. Well,
now there's a trade to be made here.
Any more questions about that? You know, if not, just to wrap it up,
we're always playing a game of buy cheap things, sell expensive things,
and we can't forget that. Right. Um,
and just because something is high doesn't mean it's expensive.
Just because something's low doesn't mean it's cheap.
So these are the methods we use to try and find what we think it should be worth.
You can only say something's cheap or expensive when you can price what you think
it's really worth, right?
So these are just a couple of techniques you can use to do it. And, uh,
you know, we put ourselves in a better spot to win.
If we can take advantage of them, right? Like in the, in the retail space,
especially nobody has tools like this. And, uh, you know, by,
by learning to use them, we're setting ourselves up pretty nice to,
to make better decisions and keep practicing guys,
keep practicing pricing stuff, right?
I don't expect any of you to be born volatility traders, born option traders,
uh, keep pricing, keep practicing,
keep getting feedback and do it over and over and over again until you actually
get good. Right. And for example, uh,
someone was asking how margin found this ticker, uh, without asking,
I can probably safely assume by just doing a whole bunch of searching,
trying different, you know, looking, using different filters in the,
on the scanner, building out different lists, looking at it saying, oh,
this looks kind of funny. And then doing some more research, you know, and, uh,
it probably wasn't the first ticker he looked at.
It probably wasn't the last ticker he looked at. Right.
There's probably a lot of them in between. Well, a funny story though, Sean,
is that Disco and block were the top two on our, on our scan, right?
You just the top two on Ivy rank. Yeah.
Top two on Ivy rank and Ivy over forecast. Um,
those were the top two on our list. So, you know, that's,
that's probably obviously how margin found it, but just because it's up there,
it doesn't mean it's a good sell or a goodbye, right?
You got to actually try to price this thing.
So let's, uh, I think this is one that's worth like assigning some homework.
You know, like we should, we should set a little challenge here.
Let's think of something, Jordan.
I want to, I want to see some people's analysis. Yeah.
Maybe we can do a valuation and then best valuation gets, uh, so we'll,
we'll give out a company. Best valuation gets something. Yeah.
Or maybe we could do like a, like a pitch night, a pitch night. Yeah. Oh,
that's, that's so much fun. Oh, that's a great. Oh, that's a great idea.
What do you guys think about that? Chris,
you guys like that for the pitch night? Oh, thanks, man. Is Chris going first?
What? Chris wants to go first. He's saying, I think Chris wants to go first.
Um, yeah. Like where, you know, go out, you try and value a company and, uh,
you know, we could do a zoom, have like zoom for sure. Pitch their stock. Yeah.
Yeah. I like it.
I was going to come on and pitch why everyone should buy Tesla. No, nothing.
Just spitting straight fat.
You'll just show his PNL. Exactly.
Yeah. Let me know that idea. We'll, uh, we can, we can do something like that.
I think it could be fun. Game night tomorrow guys.
And then tomorrow game night. Yeah. Don't miss that. It'll be a,
it'll be a good, good time. Um, so actually one quick one before you guys run,
because it was a big PNL, a GME. So, uh, super quickly, uh,
GME came up on the scanner is extremely expensive. And then we valued the ball.
We said, okay, tomorrow, what is ball going to look like?
And then is that cheaper expensive relative to, you know, past moves,
historical moves, given what we know about the stock, given, you know,
did some ball rate analysis. Um, it looked extremely, extremely expensive. And,
you know, we basically said tomorrow it's going to be worth 300 ball, which,
which, which, uh, you know, fortunately it happened and a huge PNL day. Right.
So that's just another example of,
I was trying to value the volatility and not just saying it's high, it's high.
We have to stop.
Okay. Everyone, I guess that will be it for tonight's live.
Thanks for coming out.