Yeah. Okay, guys. So this week,
we're going to be talking about relative value, right?
It's such an important topic. And you know,
the new terminal is going to have all the relative value stuff.
We're actually going to be showing you the new terminal as we talk about relative
value. And you know, as we guys go forward, and as you guys, you know,
start growing your account,
relative value is almost certainly going to be in your book.
So I think someone wants to say something funny. I see you laughing. Yeah,
I just keep lowering Pranav's hand.
Yeah, so, you know, this is a really important topic. And not only for this,
guys, it's going to make you start thinking differently, right?
When you're thinking relative, you know, you can start to find new ideas. Like,
so for example, if you're doing earnings trades,
you're selling ball around earnings. Well,
what is Citigroup earnings relative to the rest of the bank sector? Right?
So these are type of things that thinking of relative value terms is very important.
And in fact, sometimes it's actually the most important.
And we're going to talk about that as we go through. All right,
let's do we have anything when you close here? Yeah,
let's just make this a big screen here for the guys. We got to set this up.
Okay.
All right. All right, guys. Here we go. Check this out.
I think this is Young Jojo. Young Jojo. Yeah, we'll go 1.5.
So it's only gonna be two minutes. Okay, guys. So here we go. What's up, guys?
Welcome back to the channel. And today I did my first trade,
my first earnings trade on MSM. And before we get to any earnings trade,
I thought I'd talk about why you should trade and the only time you should ever
trade. So there's a big misconception that, you know,
traders make tons of money and, you know,
you should quit your job and just trade full time for a living.
But the thing is, it's actually very difficult to trade, right?
Because you're competing against so many other people.
And so the only way you should ever trade, the only way you should ever think,
you know what,
ever click that mouse to say buy or sell is if you know something that the market
does not know. So for this example, I'm going to be using FIFA 06, right?
So I've had this game for 13 years. I played with all my friends,
love this game. Fantastic. Now, if I decide to put this up on eBay, right,
I could put up a value where it actually doesn't where it doesn't actually match
the actual real value. Right. So, for example,
let's say all let's say there's another FIFA 06 on eBay and it's going for twenty
five dollars. Now,
I know this one would be worth twenty five dollars as well if it was in the same
condition. But what if there's a little scratch? Right.
Then I could put it up for maybe twenty four dollars.
Get the buy knowing it's only worth fifteen dollars or five dollars.
And that's because I have an advantage of an edge there.
But if everybody was looking at this game, right,
like let's say I had a thousand analysts looking at this game.
They're going to someone to catch on this. And once they catch on it,
they're going to tell everyone else and it's going to affect the price of the value
of this FIFA 06 game. But when no one knows about it,
that's me having an advantage. So there's two ways we could trade this.
We could trade this. Absolutely. Right.
So whatever this whatever I think this will go for it,
whatever else someone is willing to pay for it.
And that's called absolute value. Right.
And then we also can trade it relatively. So for example,
this is going for ten dollars. Well,
then what is winning 11 going for or winning? Yeah. Winning 11 06.
So same year. Very similar. It's like Coca-Cola, Pepsi.
And if I know that winning 11 is worth twenty bucks,
why am I going to sell this for ten bucks? Right. It's worth way more.
And so that is relative value. And that's the better way to trade.
So the first thing we should learn about trading is only trade when you have an
edge. And how do you know you have an edge? Right.
Like that's that's that's the million dollar question.
How do you know that you have a statistical edge or how do you know that you should
put on a trade?
And the answer is, if you don't know, you don't have an edge. It's that simple.
I know that this game has a scratch on it.
I have an edge or I know that the Coca-Cola CEO is going to release this tomorrow.
You guys don't know it, but I know it. And therefore I should make the trade.
Right. Are you guys following me now? So thanks again, guys, for watching.
I'll see you guys in the next videos. I'm trying to get better at these.
So let me know in the comments down below.
What do you guys think where I can improve? And yeah.
See you guys in the next video. Cheers. It's on slow speed.
So let's see what the people in the comments had to say. There we go.
No comments. No comments. No comments. OK. So let's get into the vault up here.
OK. So actually, let's let's stop sharing the screen for a second.
We're going to chat about it. Guys,
make sure you're typing to all panelists and attendees.
Got a ton of people talking here, but you're not seeing what you're saying.
Yeah.
Yeah. I made I made all those all those videos private, guys.
Way back and way back when.
OK. So let's talk. Let's talk about relative value.
So what what is relative value right in the first place?
Relative value is basically when you're looking at one asset through the lens of
looking at all the assets that are similar to it. OK.
So super example of super simple example of relative value.
What is Bitcoin trading at relative to all the other coins relative to Ethereum
or Litecoin or any of those? Right. And that is the relative value lens.
We're not just saying, OK, here is Coca-Cola.
It has this much earnings is trading at this price. It's trading at, you know,
the growth rate is X, Y, Z. Instead, we're saying, well,
Coca-Cola is growing at 5 percent and Pepsi is going at two and a half percent.
Right. Maybe we can make a trade here. And that is relative value. OK.
So I want to ask you guys a question here, OK?
And this is how we can think about it.
You really like Pepsi. You think Pepsi is a great. Actually,
let's let's talk about Goldman Sachs. You really like Goldman Sachs.
They're growing at extremely fast rate. And but right now,
the market is saying, like, this company's dogshit. This company is, you know,
it's probably not a good company and like it's trading at such a low value. OK.
Extremely low value relative to what you think. What trade would you make?
What kind of trades can we start making here?
We can even give the example of the Apple trade that we're talking about,
the buying Apple stock. I think Apple's going up. Yeah.
We're giving an example. Short of the market. Oh, yeah. Right. Right.
So perhaps perhaps saying buy one, sell the other. I don't know.
I don't know what you're selling. I know what you're buying here. Right.
And then what Sean said as well was with the Apple trade. Right.
Like imagine you had a view that Apple was going to go up. Right.
But your view was actually like Apple is, you know,
going to the reason you bought Apple and not the S&P is you think Apple is going
to do better, obviously. Right.
You think Apple is going to grow 20 percent a year.
So why would you settle for an average of eight? Well, when you buy Apple,
you want to really isolate that outperformance of Apple. Right. You don't.
Remember, if you buy Apple, you have two views immediately.
You have a view that Apple is going to increase,
but you also have a view that the market is at least not going to fall out from
the bottom. Remember, the market goes down. Apple's going to go down with it.
So you have a view on both off the bat.
But what you could do is you could buy Apple and short the S&P.
And when you would make money is if Apple outperforms the S&P. Right.
The S&P goes up 10 percent. Apple goes up 20 percent.
You would capture that difference, which is really what your view is. Right.
So you're trading Apple relative to the market.
So once we have that view, right. And why would we do that?
Why you why would we just not go and buy Coca-Cola, right,
or go and buy Apple and not worry about everything else? Well,
by by taking the other side of the trade. Right.
So you have two legs in a relative value position. You usually have two legs.
That's not always the case, though. OK. You usually have two legs.
So why not just go and if Apple is cheap, why not just go and buy Apple? Well,
by selling the other leg, it reduces our risk. Right. Instead of, let's say,
if we're buying Pepsi and the whole industry goes down, well,
Pepsi's going to get smoked as well. Right.
And even though we were long the equity, we could still lose money. Right.
Even though our vision was correct. But we can reduce that exposure by selling,
let's say, Coca-Cola. And therefore, if the market goes down,
then as long as the spread between Pepsi and Coca-Cola collapse, we make money.
You want me to draw that out? Yeah.
And we're going to show you guys this in the new terminal as well.
Once we just get chatting a little bit about it.
And once we bring the ball into the picture. Yeah.
So here is we're going to call this pep. OK. And we're going to draw a Coke.
OK. So here's Coke.
OK. Now, what we notice, though.
So right now we can see like the two assets are correlated.
They're moving together. Right. They're moving together. And we can say, OK,
well, this is the spread is normal. Maybe if we looked,
if we let's say we subtracted the two stocks,
it would look something like this. Right. It would look something like this.
Where there's a small deviation, right, in the spread.
And every time it goes up here, for example, right, we could make a trade.
And when it goes down here,
we could also make a trade now because we're betting on it coming back together.
Right. Now, imagine we see all of a sudden and this happened on AMD and Intel,
actually, we did take a trade on it. All of us.
I think I think Hutch is actually alive and he was or we did it on IWM and the Q's.
Yeah. That wasn't false. Yeah. So imagine we see this. Right. Well, a couple.
We have to be careful when we see something like this happen. Right.
Because in this spread now, it would look like this. Right.
So we would have to really see what's going on. You know, right off the bat,
we would be like, OK, let's go and buy Coca-Cola. Right. Here's Coke.
This is pep. Right off the bat, we'd all say,
let's go and buy Coca-Cola and shorts and Pepsi. Now,
this is this is a naive way of thinking of it, because this breakdown here,
right. Technical term,
but this breakdown here just goes and shows you that there might have been a structural
change, right. Something might have structurally changed in Coca-Cola,
where the spread now going forward will look something like this instead.
Right. And this right here, guys, is the hardest part about relative value. OK,
this part right here, because it's easy to find these. OK,
but it's hard because sometimes it breaks down or a break to the upside. And,
you know, after some it usually happens after some big news,
the false breakout. Right. What do we do in that situation? Right.
And that's the that's the hardest part about relative value.
So any questions about that guy so far?
We're going to keep on we're going to keep on chugging along.
Classic Paris trading example.
Yeah. That's what it is.
So that's that would be a classic Paris trading example.
And so even if you look at like here, let me actually.
So if we even look at I'm just going to pull up Coke and Pepsi here, guys,
on the screen so you guys can take a look.
I'm not sharing this, though, right? Oh, wait. Yeah. Yeah. Good catch.
Guys, you know what I noticed? There's no more. There's no. I mean,
I used to block her and now there's no more Estonian women popping up here anymore.
It's the best part of the lives. I know, man.
So let's let me get this on a line chart, guys,
just so we can better see this and get rid of these these moving averages.
So let's take a look.
So here is the spread between Coca-Cola and Pepsi for a three year look back.
OK, so you can see here, right, guys, it's quite easily, you know,
it's quite easily stays in this range. Right.
And we actually drop this down a bit. But when we're actually trading this,
right, look what happened here. Here is an example of a structural shift.
Right. We would get in right here.
This is where we would get into this position. And it continued to move down.
Right. It's the new there's a new mean in town. Right.
So before the old mean was right here. Right.
We could say it oscillates around this mean right here. Right.
But now it looks like this mean has changed.
There's a new structural there's there's going to be a new mean right to structural
shift. And this looks like and this might be the mean going forward. Now,
this right here, this data alone is not very good,
but it's just to show you guys an example. Okay. In reality,
and we actually have this in the terminal called, you know,
I'm not going to talk about it today,
but it's called the vector error correction model.
We try to make more sense of this data. OK,
so we try to account for these structural shifts and try to get an idea of where
should this thing be trading at or where should this spread be trading at?
OK,
we actually put this on a longer time frame so you guys can get a nicer picture
here.
Look at this. Right. This spreads all over the place. OK,
so in part of quantitative finance here,
it's actually trying to take this and make more sense of it. OK,
so that is trading the stock price in relative value terms.
But as you guys know, we're vol traders.
And so we got we can do this exact same thing in vol.
OK, so let us pull up the new terminal and take a look. Well, actually,
maybe let's chat about it first.
Stopping. Yeah. OK, so let's before we even look at the data,
let's let's quickly chat about involving relative value terms.
So there's two ways we can trade this, you know, because we're trading vol,
there's more dimensionality.
It's a little more complex than just buying and selling stock. Right.
Which only make money up or down. Right.
There's no there's no curvature or convexity to the options. So to the stock.
So let's talk a little bit about the options trading vol through a relative value
trading. So let's say, you know,
we have two exact stocks or let's say two exact ETFs,
S&P 500 ETF and you pro or let's even go simpler and say S&P 500 versus another
S&P 500 ETF. OK, so we got two ETFs, S&P SPY and then IVV, I think,
is the other S&P ETF. Yeah. Yeah. IVV and SPY. Now,
we should see that these don't ever diverge. Right.
The volatility of these things should be exactly the same.
If if SPY goes up 5 percent, IVV should go 5 percent.
If SPY goes down 5 percent, IVV should go down 5 percent.
The vols should stay consistent across time. Now, that is the realized vols.
OK, so we have two dimensions here.
We're going to have the realized volatility. OK,
and we have the implied volatility spread,
the realized vol spread and the implied vol spread.
And we're going to come back to this in a second.
So when we're talking about the realized vol spread, right,
it's how much does one stock move relative to the other stock?
So IVV versus SPY should have their there should be no divergence.
You should always be the same. Otherwise, it's arbitrage. Right.
It's an arbitrage, the same asset. If they're not,
if they're moving more than 1 percent, let's say SPY is moving 1 percent and,
you know, IVV is moving 2 percent. Well, we can obviously make a trade there.
And that's called the realized volatility spread. OK,
what does one asset realize versus another asset?
Then there's the implied vol spread,
which is what is one asset implying versus the other asset? OK. Example,
SPY is trading at 30 implied vol, IVV is trading at 35 implied vol.
One ETF is saying the realized volatility is going to be 30 percent,
while the other ETF is saying it's going to be 35 percent.
So we can make a trade there because the realized vol spread should be zero,
even though the implied vol spread is five points.
OK, you guys, are you guys with me?
It's making sense. Making sense. OK, good, good. Now,
the last the last thing we can trade this is we don't need to think about it in
terms of realizing implied vol. We can just look at it in terms of implied vol,
where we say, OK, well, this asset's implying 50 percent, but it usually,
sorry, let's say that these two assets, right,
the implied vol spread between them is usually 5 percent,
but now it's 10 percent. So we can come in and make a trade. OK,
so let's go and take a look at the term. The new term,
my favorite part of every live now.
We're going to find it.
Is that it? That's the one. All right, guys,
here it is. Oh, baby.
Boom. OK,
so we're going to head over to the relative value tab here we have now.
So let's think about it in terms like this, guys. Right. We got two stocks,
SPY and I think it's IVV. We'll find out. We're going to find out.
And we're going to look at the implied volatility in the 30 days between these two
over one year. And we're looking at it as a ratio. Yeah.
So you guys can see here, right? The base.
So this is the one meaning that the one in one has been on this one right now.
I'm not right now,
but I can definitely I'm going to be adding that to the thing. Oh,
so you can see the blue is the SPY and the green is I is IVV. Right.
And you can see it basically never diverges. Right. It's exactly the same.
Otherwise, it's a pure arbitrage.
Right. So the question would be, for example, imagine we saw a situation, guys,
where SPY vol was all the way up here and IVV vol was all the way down here.
Yeah. Like let's say the graph looks something like this.
The blue line actually connected like this. Right. Green line's still up there.
Now, you know, a rookie trader would say, well,
I'm going to go and sell SPY volatility because it's so high. Right. So high.
But what if that's the more efficient leg? Right.
What if SPY is actually more efficient than IVV? Right. So we don't want to go.
Why not? Why don't we come in and buy IVV? Right.
And so that's the whole concept here,
where when we see something diverge like this,
we can actually pack on more size. Right. Think about it like this, guys.
If you sold S&P up here and your reasoning was if you sold S&P up here, OK,
and your reasoning was implied volatility is too high right now,
it's probably going to come down in the future. Well,
how much size could you really put on? Right. Probably not a lot,
because if you're wrong, you get blown out of the water.
Now, a professional would come in and say, well, I can sell this and buy this.
And I can put on as much size as I possibly can.
I can borrow to put on this trade. Right.
And that is that that is the beauty of relative value is we can find these relationships
in the market. Right. That are that are gone haywire and we can make a trade.
Right. So you guys can see here, for example, right. You know,
during the first spike on the corona crash, eyeballs diverged a little bit.
Right. It might have been too hard to take advantage of.
So if we turn this to absolute terms.
So right now it's a ratio, meaning one divided by the other.
And now absolute means one minus the other.
Right. So if you guys look here, we only got one point. Right.
It only diverged by one percent. That's not enough. We have transaction costs.
We have slippage. We have bid ask spread.
That's probably not enough to take advantage of. Right.
Even even this two point spread here might have been really tough.
We might have given up a vol or two just to get into the position and out of the
position. So this exact position, we wouldn't be able to find any trade here.
But this is expected. Right. This is arbitrage.
This is arbitrage that would be existed.
Yeah. So, Marcos, this is a really, this is a really good. Marcos is saying,
well, can we look at the can we look at the leveraged ETNs? Right.
And this is actually something I'm doing a little bit of work on right now,
Marcos. But you actually see they're very, very close together.
I think this is 3x leverage, though, right, Marcos?
Are you saying it's the inverse? Yes. 3x inverse leverage.
So we should. So you can see, Marcos, right,
there are there are periods where this gets out of line,
where this gets out of whack. Right. Because we should see here,
I'm going to do it SPXS instead of SPY,
just so you guys can see this more clearly.
So we would think that SPY,
SPXS should be trading at three times more vol than SPXS. Sorry.
SPXS should be trading at three times more vol than SPY. Right. Right.
So this white line right here. But what do we notice? Well,
we notice that it's actually a bit higher. It's actually 3.5% is the average.
Right. So this is pretty consistent. So there must be something going on here.
Right. And so that would be our job to figure out, well,
why is this trading at 3.5 times vol?
This is actually something that I'm working on right now, Marcos,
because I think there are inefficiencies in the 3x leveraged vol products.
So, you know, this is an example of where we can use relative value. Right.
We can see, OK, well, every time it touches the four mark. Right.
This is usually at the extreme level. So every time it gets close to there,
we want to start putting on a trade.
We want to start selling vol and SPXS and buying vol and the S&P.
OK, Steven, it's actually it's a little bit more than that.
It's not just the compounding effect.
And it's not actually the inefficiency is not really at the money.
It's actually in the tails. But that's for us for another day.
So the other thing we can look at, guys, is the realized volatility spread.
Now, unfortunately, I don't have that in the terminal today,
but that's going to be in there very, very soon.
So we would be able to see what is the realized spread. Right.
And if we graph the realized spread,
you guys would see that it actually is above three,
meaning that the implied vol spread is actually doing a good job of predicting the
realized vol spread.
OK,
pretty cool.
Anything else you want to show them here?
Correlation? Yeah, I guess we can take a look at this. Right. So here,
for example, guys, we can, you know, we want to take a look at SPY, right?
And SPXS.
Or let's look at something more interesting, like two fang stocks or something.
OK, OK, OK. So that Apple and Amazon. Gotcha. Or something like that. Gotcha.
Gotcha. Apple and Apple and Microsoft. OK, so we're gonna take a look at this.
Apple, Apple, Microsoft. OK,
so here we can see, guys, the rolling correlation between. So the thing is,
we have before we're going to make a trade on two assets,
we want to make sure that there's a relationship there.
But if there's no relationship, we can't perish trade Apple and some penny.
STNG. Yeah, STNG or INL, right?
We can't do that because we might get fucked on both legs. Right.
So for that reason, we need to make sure that some relationship exists.
And so we could what we could look at is one metric is the 90 day correlation between
the two stocks.
So you can see right now they are about was a number 70 percent. Right.
Apple and Microsoft right now are 70 percent correlated.
And there's a reason for this. Both of them make up the majority of the Nasdaq,
make up the majority of a bunch of ETFs.
And if investors are going out and buying these ETFs, right,
then the ETF has to go buy Apple,
Microsoft and investors go and sell these ETFs.
They have to go sell Microsoft and Apple.
So it makes sense that this correlation, this this relationship should exist.
And so we can make a perish trade on here if we saw some opportunity,
both in the vol space or in the Delta one space.
Another very, very useful metric is, well, when Apple moves,
how much does Microsoft move? How much does Microsoft move? Right.
So we can get a beta. OK, so in this case, for example, what we got left here,
0.62. So Microsoft has a beta of 0.62 to Apple.
OK, what else here? So we can look at the implied vols graph,
let's say for Apple, Microsoft. You can actually, by the way, guys,
you can plot four stocks. Yeah. Yeah.
Because the reason why we have four is because we're going to we're going to have
it. So you can plot Apple, Microsoft, implied vols and realized vols. Right.
So then you can see both spreads.
So let's take a look here. So when, let's say,
Apple vol goes 1.5 and we might say that's too expensive. Right.
And once we have the realized vol graph here, guys,
you guys will be able to understand why. Want to throw the realized vol on it?
I don't. I have to pull it. I don't. Yeah. I mean, I hear. OK. Let me see.
We can do it super quick here, guys. No, no. No. OK.
So that's that's that's basically the introduction on relative value,
relative value. OK, I'm going to end the recording here. Let's hop into a Q&A.
Any questions you guys have? Let's tackle them now.