A couple of new faces here, you know, it's always nice, it's always nice,
you know, seeing new faces, right? It means community is growing, it means,
you know, it's getting more and more exciting for the group, right?
People are really starting to collab, and we're noticing it in the live,
in the chats now. So very exciting to see. Jared, actually, quick comment,
if you want to leave it down there, did you exit the BYND position?
And let us know how that went.
So guys, yesterday, in yesterday's live, we talked about relative value,
we talked about it means to do a relative value trade, to do a pairs trade,
and why we do relative value, right? It was just a general talk about it.
But in today's live, we're going to talk about,
we're going to actually go in actual examples that people and professional traders
have used to try and make money. Okay,
and now there's so many examples of relative value.
But just from recent memory, I decided to choose a few, you know,
for explanation purposes and for, you know, to get general discussion going.
So let me, so let me share my screen.
Okay, guys. So remember, relative value, oh, look at that, the guys,
the guys are, the guys are all, three notifications. We're almost there. Okay.
So guys, remember,
the whole point of relative value is to be able to trade one asset versus another
asset, right? A lot of the time, we can't get enough leverage, right,
by just trading one asset. If we think something is expensive, right?
So let's say we think S&P volatility is expensive. Well,
we can't get a lot of leverage by selling vol, right? Or if we think, you know,
S&P is cheap, we still can't get a lot of leverage, you know,
buying vol because at the same time, if we're wrong, we could lose a lot.
So what relative value does, or pairs trading,
is it tries to minimize that risk so we can get better exposure, right?
And it also allows us to take a view on relationships rather than just in absolute
terms. Okay.
So this is a recent example that I found online that I thought we would chat about.
So for those of you that don't know,
Chris is a portfolio manager over at Ambrose Group. He just recently started,
recently started there after leaving BMO.
So I'm just going to go through the tweets so you guys can really get a sense of
what's going on here. Okay. So historically,
XLU and XLPI vols don't trade too far off from each other.
But I'm surprised XLU is only trading three vols higher based on the allocation
breakdown. The quality of the holdings between the two are night and day. Okay.
So, so let's, let's break this down here.
So he's saying the utilities ETF and the XLP,
which is the consumer discretionary or the consumer staples ETF. Okay.
So utilities and consumer staples ETF are only trading three implied vols apart.
Okay. So what does that mean? Well,
it means that both options of XLP and XLU roughly estimate the same volatility in
the future, the same realized volatility.
So XLP options think that the volatility of XLP is going to be very similar to the
volatility of XLU. And what Chris is saying is, well, I opened up these ETFs.
Okay. I opened up to see what is actually inside of them.
And what he found was, okay. In XLP, you have stocks like Procter and Gamble,
Walmart, Pepsi, Coca-Cola, right. Philip Morris, Colgate,
you have all these like big, well-established companies, right. The, you know,
probably not going to have a lot of volatility. Okay. And then on the XLU side,
you have these utilities, which, you know, I guess Chris is saying they don't,
they don't really have they're, they're not really that, you know, that stable.
So he's saying, well, given that, you know,
XLU is a lot more unstable than XLP, why should the vols be the same?
So what he's doing is, well, maybe he's going to say,
let me go and buy some vol on XLU and sell some vol on XLP. Okay.
And as long as XLU vol is more expensive or realizes more than XLP,
we're going to make money on this trade. So the way he would structure this,
let me share my screen. You're sharing your screen. Oh, sorry.
Let me share a new screen. Whiteboard? Yeah. You can just do this. Oh,
there it is. I didn't see it there.
So what he's saying is, well, let me go and sell a straddle. Okay. On XLP.
And let me go and buy a straddle on XLU.
Okay. And what he's saying here is, as long as XLU does something like this,
and XLP only does something like this, we're going to make money.
And the reason this is the case is again, guys,
he's saying that XLU has worse holdings than XLP.
Meaning that the volatility on XLU realized should be higher than the volatility
on XLP realized, even though they're trading at similar implied volatilities.
Right. Now,
we're not going to go into the details on why this may or may not be a good trade,
but what we're going to do is just continue down the thread because I think we have
some good banter going on.
Okay. So I think there was a, before we jump into my comment,
I think there was a really good post.
Okay. So actually it wasn't a really good post by this guy, but anyways,
I came in, I said a couple of things. So we're going to,
this is all relative value. Okay. So, so I'm just saying, you know,
a couple of things here.
It's much better to compare the ratio when doing index versus index for relative
value trades. Okay. So if index one moves 10%, we would expect index two,
if correlated to move by some ratio of that, right? Some beta. So here,
what I did was I plotted the historical implied volatilities.
I don't know why I didn't put the dates here,
but I plotted the historical implied volatilities where I took the two largest holdings.
Okay.
And what we see here, right,
is that the implied vols are actually really correlated.
They're really correlated and sorry, they're not really correlated, but they,
they move together and they're not usually far off, right?
They're usually in the same range, which is why, you know,
we're seeing if the two underlying components are the same implied vols,
then we should see that, you know,
the ETFs are going to have the same implied vols, right? That only makes sense.
So, but that's the implied vol. Let's take a look at the realized.
Okay. So with the realized vols, they also, they don't differ that much, right?
They're pretty similar. And in recent times, right, and this is where,
you know, maybe Chris could have made a trade here, right? In recent times,
they're starting to get wider. So it seems like NEE, right, in blue.
So this is what's actually happening.
The realized volatility is actually moving quite a bit relative to PG.
Now, what did I say here? So then I said,
I think the real question you're asking is why do the components of XLP and XLU
have similar eyeballs,
given that the components of XLP are much better quality than the components of
XLU, right? So what we're saying is it's not, we're not,
we shouldn't be really looking at the eyeballs here alone, right?
We need to be able to compare that with, let's say the realized vols.
What's actually happening? What has actually happened, right?
Is it likely that the quality of PG has changed so much in the last month relative
to NEE? I'm not too sure. But what we can do is we can say, well,
PG probably doesn't change that much. Let's see how much,
let's see how it's done, you know, the last year or last two years,
last five years relative to NEE, right?
Do you think a utility changes that frequently? Probably not, right?
It's unlikely for the spread to just randomly break down. Okay. We need,
there needs to be some other reason for it. So if Chris was more like, okay,
given NEE has all this fundamental stuff coming out, right, and XL, XL,
what was it? PG has all this like, this other, you know, it's super stable,
then maybe there's a trade there, right? But we need, we need to really,
when we go into these relative value trades,
we really need to understand what's going on, right?
What has the relationship been historically and what,
and if it were to break down, what would be the reason for it?
Okay. Okay. And this guy, Chris is basically asking the same thing. It's like,
how,
how are the components moving, right?
How are the components moving inside this, inside these ETFs? Okay.
So that was one example. Do you guys have any questions about that example?
Yeah. So yeah, yeah. That's Moonwater, Chris. He's really good.
So let me just see.
Yeah. Steven, we could have a hundred percent done that. The only issue is.
For the live, right? Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
Questions even asked is why don't we just look at the realized vols of the ETF?
Yeah. And that's a, that's a really good point. Steve.
The issue we would have is, is that the underlyings change in that ETF, right?
The underlyings are constantly changing. And his point was that the,
that the equities in this ETF, you know, are not,
are lower quality or lower quality.
Okay. And then quote, quote, I'm actually saying not the quality,
but the performance under stress. I'm not too sure what you're,
what you mean by that. Maybe if you want to elaborate, we can,
we can get to that. Okay. So another example of a relative value.
Okay. So we're right now, guys, right up here, I have the VIX central.com,
which is basically the VIX futures curve. Okay. So for example,
we have the November VIX future. We have the December, January, February,
March, April. Now a relative value trade we could take here, for example,
which people were taking a lot before the election. Okay.
Was selling one expiration and buying another expiration.
So throwing on a calendar spread. Okay. So we're going to go and look at, okay,
we're going to go back to the election here.
Okay. Let me take a screenshot of this cause it's going to move.
Click on it. Yeah. Okay. So here you guys can see, right? Okay. So here is the,
the front month election vol.
And now the stance that a lot of people were taking were, okay,
the December contracts are way too expensive relative to these contracts out here.
Okay. So what they were doing was they were selling December and buying,
let's say March and what they,
what they were hoping for was once the election came out and was done,
you would see,
you would see these contracts drop. Okay.
Now they couldn't go out and just go and sell these naked, right? You know,
you could, I mean, we did, right.
But they want to take a more risk averse approach. This could blow up.
And if you're held, you're, if you're holding naked, you're in trouble.
So what they would do is they would sell these and buy these so that if this were
to go up, this would also go up, would also likely go up.
So even though they're losing money here, it would make money here.
Okay. So you can do this, for example, with calendar spreads in inequities,
right?
Let's say you think Apple 30 day implied volatility is too high relative to Apple
90 day implied volatility. Well, you could sell those and buy the 90 day,
right? You're selling gamma here and you're hedging with Vega, right?
And that's a little bit of a tricky concept,
but what it basically means is if the stock moves like crazy,
then the implied vol in the back, remember,
cause you got all Vega in the back is going to blow up.
So you're selling the gamma, but you're hedging with the Vega, right?
Let's think about that.
If you have something that's expiring soon and you get a big move,
it's heavily impacted, right? Cause there's not much time left.
But if you're getting massive moves now,
what's the market going to potentially imply about the future? Well,
it might imply that, you know, especially if you, if you position it, you know,
you're not, you're not selling two years out.
You're selling a couple of months down the road, right?
It could imply that this, this volatility will continue into the future.
Okay. So Mark was saying,
why don't you look at other components instead of big ones? So Mark was,
that's a really good question.
The reason why we look at the bigger components is because they make up the majority
of the ETF. Think about it like this. Okay.
We have one ETF that has 99% Apple and 1% Microsoft.
This whatever happens in Microsoft is not really going to impact the ETF.
Instead we want to focus on the things that make up the majority of the portfolio,
right? But in Mark's defense, the highest component was 16%. Yeah.
And it was a whole bunch that were like four and 5%. Yep.
So it's a really good point.
Mark was also a time component where we didn't have five hours to analyze that.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly. Mark was, that's, that's in that case, that Mark was,
it's a really good point. You'd want to, let's say break up.
So this is called principal component analysis,
where we would basically take the ETF and find out, well,
what are the highest components that drive the volatility of this ETF, right?
And we would probably say, let's just take the top 75%.
Whatever makes up the top 75%, we're going to take those, right?
We don't want to, we don't, we can't worry about everything, right?
Imagine we were doing a trade where we were trading the component against the ETF.
Well, we don't, we don't have the infrastructure to trade,
let's say a hundred names,
but we might have the infrastructure to trade four or five names. Okay.
So Ray had a good question here. He said,
wouldn't you lose more on the front end than you make on the back end doing this
VIX trade? Yes. So if it were to come down, right, so Cody,
with this relative value trade,
this is a little bit different than let's say a calendar in the equity space,
because these are futures. These are not options.
So if the first month were to come down, right,
we would make money because we're selling that. And if it were to go,
if let's say this were to go up, we are hoping that this would come up as well.
Right. And we're hoping actually that this would come up even more than this.
Right. So if this, let's say we remove two points, this would move 2.5 points.
And if this were to come down, right, this would come down,
let's say five points, but this would only come down, let's say two points.
Right. So,
but of course we would lose money if this went up five points and this only went
up three points. Right. So, you know, with every single trade,
we have to take a view, right? We have to say, okay,
this is what we think is going to happen. And if it doesn't happen,
we should expect to lose money. Right. I don't know.
I don't know of a situation. Yeah. Right.
The market's not going to give you a risk-free trade. Right. Yeah. I mean,
I don't think I can think of a situation where I want Y to happen and then X happens
and I make money. Right. Because then it was a bad trade. Yeah.
It was a bad trade because I wasn't expressing myself properly. Right.
And I was like, okay, if Y happened, maybe I lose money.
So right.
Okay. Yeah. So Mark was saying like,
but imagine like the 30% small ones all move crazy and the 16% big one doesn't move
30% so all the small ones have high volatility, let's say,
and the big one doesn't. Yep. Or maybe it's implying the other way.
And then the small ones all just go crazy. That's a really good point, Marco.
So as long as like you, there are, um, if, if a stock makes up,
let's say 2% of the portfolio or 1% of the portfolio,
and there's other stocks that make up 16 or 20%,
these ones will have to move in a huge amount,
even just to really come up on the radar. Right. Think about, uh,
think about this, Marco's stock has 20% is a 20% of the index.
And you have another stock that let's say is 2% of the index. Well,
this stock has to move 10 times as much as this stock to have the same impact.
Right. And when do you ever see, um, you know,
let's say this top stock has 30% vol. This,
this little tiny stock has to have 300% vol, right. To have the same impact.
So, you know, you could definitely, um, you know, you, you can definitely find,
you know, maybe a company that's 5% that moves it, let's say 30% a day, or no,
that's too much. Let's say 5% a day. Right. And use that in your,
in your analysis. Um, and that's a really good point.
That is a very good point.
Speaking of the underlying, so we want to talk about how, uh, uh,
high volatility in the underlying can still reflect low volatility in the, uh,
in the basket. High volatility in the underlying? Like if they all move.
Oh yeah. Yeah. So guys,
imagine a situation where we're going to show you something really cool right now.
We've talked about it a little bit in the past,
but I think you guys will like this. What the fuck is going on? One second.
Can I close this? Yeah.
Okay. Okay. So we got, um, um, we got stock one, we got ETF one. Okay. Okay.
And this has two stocks, Apple and Microsoft. Right.
And this is more dispersion trading guys. We'll,
we'll just touch on this briefly, but we're going to get back into, uh,
it's just cause it's kind of like, um, related to what, uh,
Chris was kind of getting towards. Right. Right. Right.
This would be like if Chris took it to another level.
Right. And actually that is what, um, that is what, uh,
this Chris is saying is like, right. It's like, well, sure. They might have,
um, so that, that, that, that's what this Chris is saying. It's like, sure.
They might be bad names, right? They might be shit quality,
but if they're not correlated, you know,
then the volatility should be low of the basket. Right. And so,
and we're going to talk about that right now.
Do you want me to draw it? Yeah, sure. Probably do.
What the hell is that? A little firetruck. Okay. So we have, you know, uh,
ETF one and it has two components. Let's say it has Apple and it has Microsoft.
You want to explain it as I draw? Then we have ETF two. Okay.
So we have XLU and then we have XLP. Okay. So XLP has Apple, Microsoft.
Let's just say this has stock one and stock two.
And XLU has stock one and stock two.
Now imagine Apple and Microsoft are shit quality. Okay.
And the volatilities of Apple is 50% and the volatility of Microsoft is 50%.
They're shit. They're garbage companies.
And ETF two has volatility of stock one of 15%. Okay. Because it's, uh, it's,
it's a Walmart and stock two of 15% because it's a target. Okay.
Two really good companies. Now imagine an ETF one where Apple,
Microsoft have a negative correlation. Okay. Negative one correlated.
Okay. So if Apple goes up, Microsoft goes down. And an ETF two,
they have one correlation. Okay. Meaning if, if stock one goes up,
stock two goes up. Okay.
Imagine what happens tomorrow. Okay. So let's,
let's talk about what happens to these ETFs tomorrow. Apple moves up huge.
Okay. Apple moves up 5% tomorrow, but Microsoft has negative one correlation.
So it also moves down 5%. Okay. So Apple moves up 5%.
Microsoft moves down negative 5%. The ETF doesn't move. Yeah.
Assuming these are equally weighted, right? So this is a 50%, right?
This is 50% of the basket. This is 50% of the basket.
What happens to the price of the ETF?
Well, the ETF would be like this, right?
So the question is, what's the vol here?
What's the vol of Microsoft?
And what's the vol ETF one, right?
Now ETF two, right? They have one correlation.
So stock A moves up 2% and stock B moves up 2%. Well,
what's going to happen to the, to the index? Well, it's going to move up 2%.
Right. So I'm sure these components, these, you know, these components are,
are, are of worse quality,
but because the correlation is a lot lower than the volatility of the basket is
going to be a lot lower. Oh, the correlation is higher here. Yeah.
Sorry for A1. So do you guys, does that make sense to you guys?
So let's say, okay, so here's a cool one.
So let's just wrap up what we see here. If the underlyings are correlated,
the ETF vol and movement will also be correlated with the underlyings.
Make sense?
So question for you, what, if we find an ETF like ETF one,
what's the opportunity? What's the trade? Is there a trade here?
Let's see who can answer this and explain why.
So what's the trade?
Exactly. Jekka.
Okay. So the answer is you guys are on the right track here. Yeah.
The answer is Jekka hit it right on the head is we buy Apple vol,
we buy Microsoft vol and we sell ETF vol,
right? We sell that vol.
Does that make sense? So let's see.
Let's just explain how that happens a little bit more.
And Steve, it actually can't be nothing. I'll explain to you afterwards.
It can't be nothing. Okay. We're going to get rid of some of that stuff.
So you want to explain that? How it can't be nothing? No, no. Why this works?
Oh yeah. Because you're selling, you know, the,
the ETF let's say has implied vol of let's say 20%, whatever it is, 30%.
You will be able to that, that you're basically going to get a no vol on that,
right? On that ETF.
So you can buy the components and you're going to get vol there, right?
If you're buying vol in the components,
you're going to get when the stock moves, you're gonna make money,
but you won't make money on the if you buy, if you sell the ETF,
you're going to make money because it's not going to move.
And what like, so, so obviously there's the component of this where it's like,
what's the market saying? Right. Right.
So what we're seeing here with the market is the market saying low vol on this and
high vol on this,
but why is there money to be made selling this if the market saying it's going to
be low vol or is the market pricing it differently than what we're looking at here?
So if there, so remember when we're, when we're looking at the formula for it,
uh,
it's square root, uh, weight or weight,
weight of asset one squared times the vol of asset one squared, right?
Plus the weight of asset two squared times the volatility of asset two squared,
right? And then we have this thing, Steve,
where it's the plus the correlation to the power of two,
not square or a square. Yeah. My bad. Totally fucked up.
I haven't done math in a while. Okay. Hold on.
I thought you were using the wrong symbol there. I think,
I think you and Jack are chatting too much. I know.
If I can turn you into Jack, man. Okay.
Look at this. I haven't done English. I can't even spell.
I think you're talking to Jack too much too, man.
So, uh, Steve, because it's, we have two components going into this, right?
We have this and we have a correlation factor. So even if this is zero, Steve,
we still have this. Does that make sense? So it's never going to be zero,
right? But then again, you're never going to find a,
maybe you can construct a position that is, you know, perfectly neutral, um,
and then be able to create a strategy around it.
Okay. Um, so that was just a quick briefing on, uh, correlation trading,
which we, we kind of got a little excited there, went off, uh,
went off track a little, but let's get back to it. Well, not,
not a hundred percent. It's, it falls into a similar, uh,
like train of thought, you know? Yeah. And actually it explains the, uh, the,
the Chris thing really well. Oh, sorry. Here. Yeah.
Let's do a new share. Let's get back to one more example.
Um, let's see which one's a good one.
Okay. This one was a good one. I like this one. Cause you roasted them. Yeah.
But we're not going to go into that. We're not going to go into that. Okay.
So let's take a look here. So, um,
and the only reason why you guys were using Chris here is because in recent memory,
um, He looks at this stuff. Yeah.
You don't have a lot of people that trade relative value. It's, it's a,
it's a very small market. So, you know, uh, this from recent memory,
this is what I could find. So let's chat about this. Chris is saying here,
bank earnings in a few weeks.
I'm a little surprised the market is trading cough left wing 10 volts higher than
WFC default on those sub 400 credit score approvals, question mark.
So what's he talking about? Well, what are you saying here is you guys,
you guys know the skew graph by now, right?
Here's here is the percent of the stock, right? So a hundred percent moneyness,
right? So let's say the stock's trading at a hundred. This would be the,
at the money strike, this would be the one Oh five strike.
And this would be the one 10 strike one, one 15 strike. This would be the 95,
the 90, the 85, right? So it's percentage of the stock. Well,
what do we notice here? Right?
So cough is in purple and what was the other one? WFC is in blue. Okay.
So what he's saying is, well, look at this. Okay. Look at the tail here.
It's so much more pricey than the WFC tail. Okay. The market's saying, well,
there's a greater chance of a massive down move in capital one,
which is cough or there's more risk of it. Yeah. It could be bad if it happens,
right? If the stock does, we talk about skew it where, you know,
when the stock does move down, right? It's going to move down more.
That's what the skew is saying here. Right? And that, you know,
there is a possibility.
The probability of a huge down move is larger here than there is here.
And his question is, well, why is this the case? Right? This,
this he's curious to know, right?
Banks come bank earnings coming up soon and he's trying to construct some type of
trade, some type of relative value trade here.
And so what he might do is he might say, okay, well, this is a little pricey,
right? This, this far left tail is a little pricey relative to Wells Fargo,
right? Maybe he has some analysis where in the same business model,
relative same size, et cetera, et cetera.
So he's going to come in here and start selling capital one ball deep out of the
money puts and buying Wells Fargo deep out of the money puts to hedge. Okay.
So that, that is an example of trading the tails, right?
Not at the money anymore,
but now we're taking advantage of the wide range of the,
of the vols in the tails, right? There's not really a big range here, right?
And the market saying, well, look what's happening out here or even up here,
right? So that is, that is an example of using relative value, relative value,
right?
You're looking at two similar assets that are being priced differently in the market.
You're asking why?
And then you're constructing a trade to take a view on this difference coming back
together. Yeah. Steve, it was funny. What do you,
what do you forgot to realize was that, so, okay, it was funny. I did.
Oh, I guess let, let, yeah, let's get that to clear. Oh yeah. Yeah.
What he forgot to realize was that cough had earnings vol,
had the event vol a lot sooner than a Wells Fargo, right?
Which is why we were seeing the bid up in the skew. But here's my reply to it.
Oh,
my bad, dude. That's okay. I thought we were moving to close it. My eyes,
my eyes. How do I go? How do I look at my tweets?
Profile maybe? Oh, there we go.
Okay, here, let's go. It's in replies. Oh yeah.
I was like, you guys should grab a coffee and talk it out. I know we should.
Right. Okay. Let's chat about this.
So,
so Chris saying, go look back at my tweets. Right. Okay.
We're not going to talk about what he's saying, but he's basically saying,
look, I was doing a relative value trade. I was buying up, you know,
the tails in, in a lot of these underlines, right? Because they were cheap.
Right.
But right before this, he came out and said,
I'm going to be buying vol on JP Morgan, right? Before the earnings event.
He didn't talk about any other vols, but he said,
I'm going to be buying vol on JP Morgan. Right. And it made sense. Why? Right.
Right. Let's go back to that. Before I show you guys mine,
let's go back to that. That's going to be too far gone, dude. Hold on.
We got it. We got it.
It's right here. Oh, you know what? Yeah. Okay. Okay. If you scroll up.
I don't think it's on this tweet. It's not. Oh, you know what? It's right here,
actually.
No, it's not. Oh, well. Oh, well.
Okay. Okay. So what I found was cough vol or JPM vol was extremely cheap,
right? So we can kind of understand why he was long JPM vol, right?
Why was he buying JPM vol?
And I'm sure a lot of you remember him coming out and saying, I was long vol.
I'm buying the tails on JPM, right? Before the earnings event.
And we could see exactly why this was the case.
Because before he made the tweet,
JPM vol on the tails was the lowest relative to all the other banks, right?
JPM is in white.
The out of the money puts were the lowest relative to every other bank he was looking
at. So it made sense for him to come in here and buy JPM vol, right?
Now does that, just because it's the cheapest, does that make it a good trade?
Right? And the answer is no, right?
There's a lot of more stuff has to go into it.
Maybe it's trading like that for a reason. And in this case, it actually was,
right? JPM barely moved. Every other bank moved, but JPM stayed flat, right?
And then eventually it spiked up, you know, just last week,
but this is way before then. Yeah. This is like a month ago.
So just because we see these like these spreads,
we have to really understand why these spread exist and that's where a lot of money
can be made because relative value trades,
they do exist and they exist quite frequently. Okay.
But understanding why it exists is the most important part because otherwise you're
gonna get burned.
And I've seen so many situations where it looks like it's a good trade,
but when you really dig down into it, you can get crushed.
Okay. So really take that in mind.
And guys also remember the reason why you can get crushed with these trades is because
you can pack on size, right? You have to pack on size.
You're only making a few points, right?
Because usually we're trading a relationship. So if this goes down,
this usually goes down together, but what we're hoping for,
we're just trying to get this,
right? So in order to make money here, we need to get more size on.
And so if you're wrong, right, and this is what they call,
they say getting fucked on both legs because it's gonna go like this, right?
So it didn't go like this or like this or like this,
but it went like this and now you're really screwed, right?
And that's the worst position to be in. And it happens. It happens, guys.
It's happened to me before. It happens.
Okay. So that's the live. If you guys have any questions,
we'll chat about it and then Sean and I are gonna grab some pizza. Yeah.