I'm going to shape my beard, hopefully, uh, you got to go to offman, man.
Next, if this, if this, uh, come on, if work pays off, then I'll, uh, okay.
So, um, guys, so in this video, we're going to be talking about, uh,
managing relative value positions. I know, you know,
I've told you guys a lot of my book is relative value that is though,
because I'm a little bit bigger size. Um,
and we're going to talk a little bit about that today as well,
but a lot of you guys have been asking me like Jordan, you know,
how do I manage these positions? Like, you know,
so today we're going to be talking about that.
How do you actually manage these relative value positions? And, uh,
first and foremost, guys, these positions get extremely messy, right?
The really complicated trades. Um, I don't know if you guys saw my tweet, but,
uh, relative value understanding relative value is a little tricky, right?
It's a little bit of a hard concept,
but the real difficulty in managing relative value positions and trading relative
value is actually managing the book. Okay. That's,
that's actually the hardest part, um, in relative value trading and you know,
a lot of the times, if your account's smaller,
you really just want to trade one side of the market. Um,
and do I explain what you mean by that? So imagine guys,
we are looking at two ETFs. Okay. So we're trading one ETF versus another ETF.
And, um, you know,
we're selling vol on let's say S and P and we're buying vol on NASDAQ. Well,
a lot of the times it's going to take a shit ton of margin to sell the straddle.
Right. And then when you do, when you buy the wings, let's say,
let's say you want to do an iron condor to make it more efficient versus long straddle.
You're kind of giving away a lot of edge there by buying the wings, right?
Like your hedge is already the NASDAQ strategy and you're overhead,
you're overhead, you're adding too much. And so, um,
we usually do straddle for straddle, strangle for strangle, um, you know,
or an out performance option,
which is just basically buying a call for this stock and then selling a call for
this stock or selling an index for that stock. Um, and so, um,
a lot of the time guys, you just want to be on one side of that trade.
So what I mean by one side, we have two legs. Okay.
When a relative value share, we have two legs, but you can actually say, okay,
well, and this is called an error correcting leg. Okay. So which is,
which is going to correct, right? There's an error, right? There's an error.
So stocks, stocks go like this. Okay. And now they're like this. Well,
there's an error, right?
And then for those of you that took any level one stats or level two stats,
right? It's a, it's a residue, right? So we've got an error here.
And so instead of trading on both sides, we might say, okay, well,
this is going to be the error correcting leg, meaning this is going to snap up,
right? It's not this going to snap down or they're going to go like this,
but this is going to error correct to this. And so that is most,
that is the way, um, a lot of you guys should be doing it, uh,
especially with smaller account size. Um,
and just by taking the error correcting leg, um,
it's usually a lot more beneficial. So for this live,
let's talk about straight up relative value, not, uh, not one leg.
And what we should do is we'll start with, um, putting on the position.
So position at inception and then position management moving forward.
Cause that's when it starts to get messy,
but I think it's also important to cover actually putting on the position.
Yeah. Okay. So let's jump into it.
So share my screen and we're going to pull up, uh, we actually,
for this whole live guys, we were going to do a, uh,
uh, what do you call it? A whiteboard. Uh, it's like a fake example,
a hypothetical hypothetical example. Okay. So let's say we're looking at SPY.
Okay. And if anyone's saying like, let me see the chat.
Oh, wait, sorry. Can you tell us, sorry guys,
can you tell us how to determine which leg we should error? Correct.
Let's do it at the end. Yep. So we're going to get there. Okay.
Let's keep going. Okay. So we have, we have two legs here. Okay.
We'll one leg is SPY.
Okay. Ah, so it is my computer that that's, that's tough. What do you mean? No,
I just, okay. And what's the other one? And that's accused.
So here we got a SPY and the cues. And so we're saying, okay,
well this relationship is out of whack. Okay. The implied vols are,
have gone bananas. Okay.
And we think eventually that the implied vols are going to come together so we can
come here and put on a relative value trade. And let's say, for example,
SMP is trading at 30%. Okay.
And NASDAQ is trading at let's, let's also say 30%. Okay.
These are the eyeballs implied volatility.
But when we actually look at the NASDAQ and the SMP,
we see that NASDAQ has a beta of 1.5 to the SMP 500. What that means is, okay.
Is that if let's say this is negative 5%. Okay. And this is 5%. Okay.
And here we have SPY and these are the returns. Okay. And over here,
we have the NASDAQ and shouldn't call it the cues. Okay.
And we have negative 7.5 up here, down here.
Okay. And we have plus 7.5.
Well, what this beta is telling us is that if SMP is up 5%, well,
then the NASDAQ should be up 7.5%. And if the SMP is down 5%, well,
the NASDAQ should be down negative 7.5%. Okay.
And all the other returns lie along this line somewhere. Okay.
Somewhere around here. Now,
obviously we're not going to see a perfect line like this.
We're never going to see a perfect line like this. Unless it's,
unless it's the same stock, unless it's SPY versus SPY or SPY versus IVV.
There should be some type of beta and the returns will fall along this line somewhere.
Okay.
And depending on how strong the relationship between the two pairs will depend on
how tight it is around this, this, this line. Okay. So we have a beta of 1.5.
So far so good, everyone.
So we have a beta of 1.5. So what that means is given SMP vol,
NASDAQ should be trading at 45. Okay. How did we get that? Well, we took SMP.
So imagine this, what the market's saying here is the market's implied.
So with a relative value, I'm going to step one step back here, guys,
with a relative value, guys, trade, guys, we're saying one is fair value.
And then what is this asset relative to this being fair value? Okay.
That's all we're doing. So we could say it two ways.
SMP 500 is trading at 30 eyeball,
meaning NASDAQ eyeball should be trading at 45%. That's 30 times 1.5. Okay.
And why is it like that? Well, because if SMP is up 5%,
NASDAQ is up 1.5% on average, right? That's the beta. So SMP 30,
we should see NASDAQ 45, but we're seeing NASDAQ at 30.
So another way we could say this is given NASDAQ is 30. Well,
SMP should be trading at 22.5, right? Because 30 divided by one point. Yeah,
close enough. Oh, wait, wait a minute. 2020. Yeah, yeah. It's 20. Yeah.
Should be trading at 20, but it's trading at 30. Okay. So together, relatively,
if NASDAQ is fair, SMP is underpriced. If SMP is underpriced, if SMP is fair,
sorry, guys, sorry, sorry. If NASDAQ is fair,
SMP is overpriced because it's trading at 30 eyeball,
but it should be trading at 20 given NASDAQ. On the flip side, given SMP at 30,
NASDAQ should be trading at 45, but it's trading at 30.
If we determine that SMP is what's actually fair value.
Like if SMP is more correctly priced. Right. So if we think SMP is fair,
NASDAQ is cheap. If we NASDAQ is fair, SMP is expensive. Okay. So we say, okay,
well, there's a trade to be made here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to sell ball on SMP. Okay.
And we're going to go ahead and buy ball on the NAS. Right.
Let me think here. Cause remember, right.
If we come back to this graph for one second,
what we're actually seeing right now, right.
If green is what we're actually seeing, we're actually seeing this.
We should be seeing the red, but we're seeing the green.
Or at least that's implied, right?
The green line is what's implied right now versus the red line.
But what the market should be implying is this, these should be down there.
Given the fact that the beta to the SMP is 1.5 for the cues.
So it's almost like you're trading the implied beta versus the realized beta.
Okay.
So here we have, so here we have the two, the two, the two ETFs. Now,
in this case, we need to structure this. Okay. We need to structure this.
The best way to structure this. Okay. It's theta neutral.
Now there is times where we don't do that. And as time where's the other,
how the night goes, if we have enough time, we're going to,
we're going to get into it.
But why do we make an assumption to go theta neutral off the bat? Right.
And the reason why we do that is because it's stock versus stock or ETF versus ETF,
right? It's the same, same type of asset. So when you say theta neutral,
what do you mean by that? So there's data exposure, obviously, but like, why?
And like, what are the actual implications of that? Yes.
So this is a little bit hard to understand. Okay.
It's a little bit tough to understand,
but you're actually monetizing your gamma. Okay.
I know it's a little tough to think about, and we're going to,
we're going to break that down right now. Actually. Good, good call there.
So before we even jump into this, guys think about it like this. Okay.
There is two there's theta neutral and there's Vega neutral. Okay.
Theta neutral and Vega neutral. Now I'm actually going to, you know,
these are really like, you know, big term,
but we're actually going to simplify it. Okay.
Theta neutral means premium neutral. Okay.
Premium neutral Vega neutral means notional neutral. Okay.
So what does this mean? We're just going to, you know,
really start at the core,
start at the fundamental premium neutral means if I'm selling,
it means the extrinsic value is the same across. Okay.
Basically I'm going to sell $10,000 of extrinsic value here and buy $10,000 of extrinsic
value here. And if nothing happens,
I'm going to lose 10,000 and I'm going to gain 10,000. Right.
So I'm going to be flat so far. So good. Premium neutral, theta neutral, right?
Remember theta is their sensitivity is the decay to time.
So if these are both decaying at the same time, well,
they must have had the same to start with.
They must have the same extrinsic value to start with. Right.
Does that make sense?
I'm just trying to think if there's anything I can add there to clarify it.
Chris. Oh my gosh, Jekka. Chris never said that. Okay.
Chris still wouldn't understand. I'm pretty sure you took it from Chris. No,
I took it from one of my mentors.
Chris. We're on the same page here. Yeah.
So yeah, like I'm just trying to think about.
So what you're basically saying is when you have two of the same, like,
let's say on your sell side, you sell $10,000 of premium.
If you want it to be theta neutral off inception,
you would buy $10,000 worth of premium on the other asset. Yes. Extrinsic.
Extrinsic. Not intrinsic. Extrinsic. Okay. So the same extrinsic premium. Yes.
Okay.
And then what you're saying is the reason that's theta neutral is let's say the
eyeballs don't change or anything and they,
but they move relative to each other. Now you'll break even correct.
If the only thing that changes is time, if you've, if,
if the premiums don't change, right. Right. One will decay to zero.
The other will stay at 10 K. Yeah. And you'll break even. Yes.
Hence data neutral. Correct. Got it. Now you can get a little tricky guys.
I hope you guys don't mind if we get a little into this. Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
So I know, I know Steve B's going to love this one. He's probably,
he's looking at his lips right now. He's got the bottle of Vaseline out. So,
okay. So I want to ask you guys a question. Okay. So we've got two stocks.
Okay. So we've got SMP at 30 eyeball. Okay. And we got SMP too. Okay.
Which is the same thing as SMP. Okay. It's S it's a, it's a,
it's a made up ETF. Okay.
It's a made up ETF but it's the exact same thing as SMP and it's trading at 25%
volatility. Okay. We're gonna have to start off really basic guys.
So you get the, you get the assumption. Yeah. They would have a beta of one.
They have a beta of one,
but what do you guys think the theta let's say the theta is for this $10 a day.
Okay. Well, what's the theta for this option?
What would be the theta for this one? Okay. So we've got SMP trading at 30%.
We got SMP to trading at 25%. Okay. What would the theta for this be?
Okay. Well, while they come in from grabbing a glass of water,
my mouth is fucking dry. Okay.
Okay. Jacko, you want to expand on that?
Say less than the 30, like less than SPY one. Yeah. It'd be less.
Steve gave a number to be honest with you.
I don't know if that's the exact number. Maybe it is 8.5. It'd be close.
So it's going to be less than 10. The, you know,
it's going to be less than 10 and maybe it's 8.5. We'll call it 8.5. Okay.
So now I want you guys to think of this in terms of like,
imagine this thing existed. Okay. Which, which it doesn't. Unfortunately,
this would be a great trade, right? It doesn't unfortunately exist like this.
If you ever see this, something's wrong. Okay. Something inherently is wrong.
You're missing a point. And I've seen this, I've seen this across many tickers,
ETFs, where it looks like it's an ARB or very close to an ARB.
But when you factor in a whole bunch of other things that, you know,
a lot of people miss out, it's not, okay. It's really not.
And those can really be devastating. And it's happened to me before, right?
It's, it's happened to me. So this is going to have, so let's, let's rewind.
We've got S&P trading at 30%. Okay. IVOL,
it's going to have $10 in theta a day. S&P2 trading at 25% IVOL,
it's going to have $8.50 a day. Okay.
Now both of these ETFs should have a beta of one, right?
The beta of these two ETFs is one.
Okay.
What are you doing, dude? Okay. Sorry, guys. Okay. Beta equals one. Dude.
Now, what does that mean? Now,
now this is what we're talking about monetizing our gamma. Okay.
So what it means is to get theta neutral, we have to buy more of this.
Okay. We have to buy more of this to get theta neutral. Now,
before we jump into theta neutral, and slow me down guys,
if I'm going too fast, and this is recorded,
so you guys can go over it afterwards. Let's talk about vega neutral. Okay.
So we now know what X trend, now we now understand theta neutral, right?
We understand theta neutral now, but let's talk about vega neutral.
Okay. Man, you know, we got to get, we have to get the writing pads.
Like this is fucking brutal. I know. Honestly, man.
I swear we were good at this last week, man.
If I knew where you were going with it, I would just,
I could do it quick and I could use like the text and stuff. Okay.
So vega neutral. Vega neutral is notional neutral.
So here we have S&P trading at 100. Okay.
And we have S&P 2 trading at 100 because they're the same,
they're the same thing. So vega neutral would be notional neutral.
And notional neutral,
meaning that the dollar amount is the same in terms of what the underlying is,
right? So, so we would sell in a vega neutral manner,
we would sell one of these and buy one of those.
And that would be vega neutral. Okay. Because it's same notional, same vega.
Okay. We're good. Okay. So if we have the same vega,
then what we're really exposed to here is the changes in implied vol. Okay.
The changes of implied vol, but with theta neutral,
we're actually going to monetize our gamma. So here let's,
let's take a look here, guys. Okay. I know, I know Steve,
you're gonna have a lot of questions about this. Are we going to go over them?
Okay. So, so far we're good. Vega neutral, theta neutral. We're all good.
Let me know if we're not good. There's obviously going to be some questions,
but like just as a general concept. So here you guys are going to see this,
right? Well, take a look at this. We gotta go back even a further step. Okay.
So this is such a complex topic. Okay. Let's just keep it simple.
Let's only look at theta neutral. Yeah. No,
but like it's trying to explain everything. So like with the theta neutral,
okay. Let me know if I'm getting too ahead here, guys. Yeah.
There's something called the rent ratio. Okay. The rent ratio.
And that is your theta.
Okay. That's your theta over your gamma. Okay.
And that's called the rent ratio. Now in this case,
let's explain what the rent ratio is quick. Yeah.
It's basically remember one man's data is another man's gamma, right?
You get paid data because you're giving someone exposure to large moves or you are
paying gamma or you're,
you are paying theta in order to get that exposure to large moves.
Let's say you're the one paying it.
You can think of it as you're paying rent for access to this, right?
Your theta is your rent for it. Well,
how much rent are you paying relative to the exposure you're getting?
That's your rent ratio, right? So in this case, okay, this right here, this,
this one right here, guys, the 30% eyeball is going to have a higher theta.
Okay. But the gamma is actually going to be the same. Okay.
Between this and this, the gamma is going to be the same. So this, this,
this asset.
So the reason why the gamma will be the same is even though they're implying different,
they're the same asset. If one moves 5%, the other moves 5%,
the actual moves for them is equal.
The only reason the thetas are going to be different is because they have different
implied volatilities right now, right?
Which means the market is implying that it's going to give you access to more,
but it's really the same, right? It's going to have more extrinsic value.
So it's got to lose more by the end of the expiration,
but the stocks are going to move the same. So here we have, let's say, um, our,
our, our theta gamma ratio for, for asset one for stuff, for SPY-1. Okay.
It's going to be, let's say 1.5. Fuck the numbers. Okay.
It's going to be higher than this one. Okay.
It's going to be higher than this one. So when we go theta neutral,
all of a sudden we are,
so here is asset one and here's theta gamma ratio for asset two. Okay.
These are going to be the same,
but the gamma is going to be much higher on asset two.
So now you are theta neutral, but you're exposed to long gamma, right?
You're monetizing that long gamma. That's what's really making the money here,
right? The money is being made when stock one goes from, let's say,
SPY-1 goes from 10, moves up 10% and this moves up 10%. You just,
you were long gamma on this, more gamma on this than you were this. Okay.
So we're going to, we're going to,
we're going to circle back down and we're going to start doing, going back to,
maybe we should actually stick with SPY-2 because it's simple. Yeah.
I think it's good. But Ned's just asking, so if the vols were both 30%,
they'd have a rent ratio of one. No, they would just have the same rent ratio,
right? The ratio of the ratio would be one.
So, okay. I'm going to, I'm going to delete this for now guys,
because we don't, we don't really need this. We need to,
we need to work with simple numbers for us to really get a sense of this because
doing it against the NASDAQ makes it a lot more complex.
Okay. So now what do we do? Well, we go into the market. Okay.
And we sell 10 straddles or strangles. Okay. We're going to say,
we're going to call it straddles for now. Okay. We sell 10 straddles.
Do you want to, do you want to type in this man? Yeah.
As long as it's something straightforward, I can follow what you're doing.
10 straddles. So what are we doing? We're going to sell 10 straddles. On what?
SPY2. SPY1. Okay. So we sell 10 straddles SPY1.
And now let's say we collect $10,000 in premium.
Okay. Well, now we're going to take that 10 grand.
We're going to go buy straddles on SPY2.
Here's the beauty though. The straddles on SPY1,
because they're trading at a higher implied vol, are trading at, let's say $10.
SPY1 straddles are trading for $10.
SPY2 straddles, because it's a cheaper implied vol, is only trading for $7.50.
So we now own 100 short straddles on SPY1. We own,
let's say 150 long straddles on SPY2.
The thetas are the same. Okay. Are you guys with me so far?
The thetas are the same. So every time the stock moves, we make money.
And that's why it's called monetizing power gamma.
Questions? Thoughts? I was hoping this was going to be a short live.
It's going to turn to a three hour live. It's going to be a nine o'clock.
Right. Net. So obviously if the spread collapses, right, let's say tomorrow,
the S&P, the vols collapse. And now the thetas are the same. Right.
And so we wouldn't want to stay in the position, we'd exit the position,
our money has been made. Okay.
You know, so either this vol can increase, or this vol can decrease.
But once the vols collapse, there's no more edge, we're out of the position.
And then Ned saying, do we scalp theta to hold the position?
So we never really scalp the theta, it's we scalp the gamma.
And so that's another thing, right? scalping gammas, delta hedging, okay,
is actually a tool that's used to reduce your directional exposure. Okay?
If you think, for example, Ned, that the stock is just going to chop, chop,
chop, chop, chop like this. Well,
then you want to be scalping as much as possible.
But if you think it's going to trend, well, you don't want to scalp at all,
you want to let that thing ride out. Okay, also scalping is also expensive.
Okay, cool, we can maybe do that towards the end.
If you add the element of them being different assets,
it just makes it more complicated.
Because what we're trying to do by saying spy one and spy two is it is that they
move the same, right?
It's not like they have different underlying assets as a part of the ETFs.
They're the same ETFs. They're just implying different things in the market.
Can we take advantage of it? And how would we go about doing it?
Was that a question? Yeah, I just answered. Okay. Steve had a good point.
Why don't we do these Vega neutral?
And see, to be honest, I think you're coming from a different perspective.
Okay, and I won't share on the live, but if you want to send me a message,
we can talk about it.
But there's a reason why you wouldn't do Vega neutral here.
And there is a reason why we would do Vega neutral here as well. Okay,
let's say for example,
you think that the implied vols of asset of spy one are going to increase,
or sorry, spy two is going to decrease. Okay,
so we have right now we're like this, sorry, we're like this, spy one, spy two.
And if we do Vega neutral, okay, and this increases, well,
we would have been better off if we did data neutral and this increased,
because we have more of these. But if we think this is the expensive leg, okay,
let's say we think this is the expensive leg. Then when this decreases, right,
we're going to make more money if we have more size here.
So that's one reason why we would do Vega neutral. And this is like, oh, man,
yeah, we're gonna get too deep. Yeah, yeah, we gotta slow down. Yeah. Steve,
send me a message. Yeah, we'll get back.
I think I know where you're coming from as well. And what you're trying to do.
So just send me a message and we can chat about. Okay,
so just because we got a little off track. Let's recap what we've done so far.
And then let's continue on this example. We have two assets,
spy one and spy two, call them whatever you want. The whole point is,
they are the same thing. Okay, they move exactly the same.
They're the same company, let's say, for a co-op,
we'll say it's Tesla one and Tesla two, okay. Or we can bug them and be like,
it's Tesla and NIO.
The only thing that's different about them is when we look at the market,
we see that asset spy one has an implied volatility of 30,
when spy two has an implied volatility of 25. But they're the same thing,
they should have the same implied vols.
So how can we structure a trade here to take advantage of it? Well,
we start off by saying,
do you want to explain that this part just because I'm not sure how you went from
here to here for the rent ratio? Oh, yeah. Okay. So we're,
what we're saying is,
the rent ratio in this asset is going to be more expensive than this asset.
So we're basically flattening them. Okay.
And that's your theta over your gamma, right?
So how much rent are you paying for exposure to gamma,
because you should be paying the same, right?
They're going to have the same likelihood of big moves,
and the big moves will be the same for them. So why are you raising this?
I was gonna move this up and then we can keep it going. Yeah,
just just while I'm explaining. So what we're gonna say is,
is there a way we can make the rent ratios equal for them. And then we have,
you can hopefully collect, basically what we're doing here is we're monetizing,
monetizing the long gamma, right? Because we have more of it now. It's like,
we just sold two properties, the exact same properties,
one we're collecting higher rent on than the other one,
we're collecting higher rent on the other. So this one was going for 10 bucks,
this one was going for 850, we said, so what we could do is we sell 10,
that 10 straddles on spy one, and we collect 10k for it,
then we take the 10k that we collected,
and we buy $10,000 worth of straddles on spy two.
So the reason we're theta neutral here is the premium,
we're equal amounts of premium in both short 10,000 here,
long 10,000 in premium here of extrinsic. Does that make sense?
Right? So now, we are short straddles on spy one,
and we are long more straddles on spy two, but they have the same theta,
meaning they decay at the same rate.
Right? So let's make sure that we're clear on why they decay at the same rate.
It's because one decays quicker than the other, right?
Spy one decays quicker than spy two. But we have more of spy two,
so that the actual dollar decay per day is the same for both of them relative to
the premium that we either bought or sold.
Okay, let's keep moving here because we should stay on track with this. Okay,
so Bala, we're gonna get back to that afterwards. Okay,
so we're gonna clear this up. Yeah. So we're gonna get rid of the top part.
Yeah. So now we have our position on. Okay, we got our position now,
everything's good. And now things start to move. Do you want me to keep typing?
Yeah. So now things start to move. Okay. Now, because we're long more gamma,
right? Think about this, guys. We're long more gamma,
we have more straddles in asset two on the same ETI.
When we start moving in one direction, we're gonna pick up more deltas.
So at inception, we're delta flat. Yeah. And delta neutral as well.
Now, in time step one, tomorrow, the stock moves 5%. Okay,
so now we're gonna be long delta, right? We have more straddles.
So we're gonna pick up long delta. And this is where things get messy, right?
This is where managing the book, it's extremely messy.
Because not only now are we long more delta, we're potentially long more theta.
Okay. So, you know, when I first started out, I say, okay, well,
let me just rebalance. Let me just close it out, rebalance.
And that's actually so pricey. It's super, super pricey,
especially when you start trading size, and you can go a little more liquid,
things get super pricey.
So what you need to do is you need to buy an option that offset or sell an option
that offsets this. And this can get very, very tricky. Okay,
because think about it like this.
You are long, let's say the 100 strike call, or straddle,
and you're short the 100 strike straddle on SPY2.
Okay, so we're short and long the 100 at inception, the stock's at 110. Okay,
if we buy a 100 strike call, let's say to offset our delta and our theta,
we might not be able to manage the position, we might not have enough theta,
let's say on that in the money call.
So we let's say now have to go buy a 110 call.
So now we have two straddles and a 110 call.
And then it moves again. Right? And now we go have to go buy something else.
And so we end up having this book, where we have all bits and pieces,
all chunks going on here to create this relative value position.
It doesn't actually end there. Because this is the only time guys,
this is the only time I will ever say third order Greeks matter. Okay,
this is the only time because you're let's say the 110 call that you just bought
is decaying at a different theta than your 100 strike straddle.
And your delta is now decaying at a different rate.
So managing these positions can get extremely, extremely complex.
And to be honest, we don't have the time to do this in a 20 minute session,
or 20 minutes from now,
we could do like down the road an entire weekend on relative value,
we could do a whole weekend, we could do that. Or when you guys at 100 members,
we'll do it, we'll do a weekend. Yeah. Long, in depth, relative value session.
Yeah, we're even when we get the new terminal,
and the guy started showing ideas, we can and we put on a position,
we can manage it with the group. That'd be kind of cool. That'd be a good one.
So as you guys can see, like, it gets very complex.
And I'm just trying to think how we should go about talking about this.
We do like a theoretical example.
It's tricky. I think I can do this quick. Quick. Okay.
So we're long 10 100 straddles. Okay. And we're short or sorry, we're long 15.
We're long 15 100 strike straddles. If the guys fall asleep,
like during these like rants, we go on sometimes.
Let me know if you guys are sleeping. We sure don't think they can sleep.
No one responds in there. Okay. We short 10 100 strike straddles. Okay.
And spot is trading at 100. This is our initial position. Now,
tomorrow spot moves to 105. We're going more, we'll go 110. Okay. Well,
we just made a shit ton. Right?
We just made a shit ton because our long 15 straddles are making way more than our
short 10 straddles. Okay. Now, the thing is, though, the spread is still there.
Okay, we can't be moving these positions like crazy. The spread is still there.
So what we do is we look at our new position. Maybe we are long 200 deltas.
And we are now short. Well, yeah, we'll say we're now short 50 deltas. Sorry,
50 thetas. Sorry, sorry.
So what do we do? Well, in this position,
we have to go out and basically sell 200 deltas. And whoops.
In short, and get long 50 thetas.
So what we might do is we might sell a call option.
So why do we need to do this? So okay, right. So yeah,
we put the position on where exactly the exposures we want. Stock moves,
we make money in some places a little somewhere else. Well,
we now have these other exposures. Yeah,
we want to keep the position on because it was a it was a big move in the stock
that generated our income, but there's still a spread,
we still actually have the same view.
So we need to go out and we need to return to our original view.
But why can't we take this? Yeah,
why can't we have the 200 delta exposure and the 50 thetas? Well,
it's just like any other trade, right? And like any other trade,
where do you want this 200 deltas and long, long or short?
Along these 500 thetas? Do we want that? Right? And if the answer is no,
we don't want that. Well, we have to offset it, right?
Because if the stock goes back down tomorrow, but we just lost our gains,
and we weren't able to monetize in our gamma.
So what we will do is we'll go and buy, let's say a put option,
which offsets our short data, our long theta,
and also gives us our short delta.
But this put option is not going to be the 100 put anymore. Okay,
it's going to be maybe something like the 110 put, right?
And the reason that is, is because if you go way out of the money, guys,
your delta is low, but your theta is still high, right?
The delta theta ratio starts to increase as you go out of the money, right?
So we have to find the right strike,
it's going to be able to offset and offset this the cheapest way possible.
Okay, and that is what that's what you that's what you end up doing.
And let's say you have this position on for 30 days, right? And you're hedging,
let's say every two days, every three days, well, this can get costly,
this can get you end up with a book,
that's a whole bunch of different strikes all over the place. Right?
And this is a simple example. This is an unrealistic example,
where we have two things that are the same,
trading at the vastly different vols,
and no other reason to justify those vastly different vols. In reality,
we're doing S&P versus NASDAQ. Well,
now we have to consider our beta in our deltas, right,
and our beta in our thetas. So if let's say we pick up long 100 thetas in S&P,
well, we have to make sure that we only have 66 deltas in the cubes. Otherwise,
we're leaning.
Okay, so that's why I don't recommend anybody in this group to do this,
at least at first. You think for a taste of relative value,
they could maybe do in the delta one space? Ah, it's so different.
It's so yeah, yeah, yeah. So different with the with the other Greeks. I mean,
you guys can do like, like if here's trading for Yeah, to see what it's like,
right? That's what I'm kind of talking. Oh, yeah. But managing the position,
it's gonna get tricky, I guess, way trickier in in the option space.
Like simple things, they could they could do an out performance thing. Like,
you know, Tico was joking around, I think, but he's like,
my dreams finally come true. I can be long Tesla short S&P. Right? Right.
And then things guys, you can do one side, you can just do one side,
you don't have to do both sides. Right? This is it's not first off,
it's not margin efficient.
It's the first thing it's not it's more when you have more size, and you do,
let's say, increase your sharp ratio,
that you should not be doing that in your in your scenarios.
You want to trade the one leg. Okay, now,
they'll drive up there'll be another reason for, you know,
finding out which market is the most likely to be efficient. Okay,
is it is it the S&P? Or is it the NASDAQ? Right?
If you're trading to the liquidity, one, one liquid ETF, and one liquid ETF?
Well, all this is pretty easy, right? Yeah. Okay.
Right. So maybe we can give them the example of when we were trading,
what was it? IWM and Q's?
Is that IWM? IWM and Q's? For what?
When we were at we had a relative value trade on? I think this was during?
Yeah, we did. We did it multiple times. Yeah, we did multiple times.
You guys don't want to go check out our 100k challenge we did multiple times.
And we paid out huge is one of the reasons why we stayed afloat during that during
that week.
So a couple things, we're going to answer a couple questions now.
I hope that didn't discourage any of you. This is just like,
so this is high five. Maybe what we'll do is, you know,
there's only a couple questions. So we'll see five minutes at the end for it.
We'll go straight right to nine this time.
Maybe let's talk for a second about like,
just where these guys can start with it. Right?
There's a lot of interest in the group about it. Yeah,
that this is actually a gold topic. This is not a silver topic. But you know,
we wanted to chat about it. So you know, there's, there's, you know,
even before like, all of last week's lives were about relative value.
So let's talk about trading one leg and managing that and what you should look for
in that. Yeah.
So at the end of the day, guys, if we're doing it, one leg, we're just saying,
okay, implied vol should be here, given, given this information,
given that S&P is usually the liquid leg,
and it's usually the it's usually the most margin efficient leg.
And that is the that is the estimated forecast, right? At the end of the day,
guys, we want to we're trying to we're trying to say this is cheap.
Because our forecast is different. Right? Our forecast is different.
So if we have something that's super liquid and super smart and super sophisticated
saying, this is what eyeball should be.
And we have another something else saying no, it shouldn't. Right? Well,
obviously, and we can say, Okay, well, this might be the less efficient way.
So maybe we'll say is to start off,
maybe we'll say is this find? Yeah, so charger as well.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah, we're almost out.
So we'll say this find pairs of ETFs where one is liquid is extremely liquid.
And the other is not right. So one pair that we looked at,
I think it was I WM versus qqq. Right? SPY versus, you know,
put in another one here. Right? So go find pairs,
where you have like a super efficient asset,
and something a little less efficient. And then look at how they move together,
right? Look at what they're implying. Go look at what they're made up of,
right? So they might be carrying, you know, 80% of the same assets,
meaning they should move very, very similarly. So Jordan,
I'm just recommending here, the guys go, and they find pairs of ETFs,
that where one is extremely liquid, and the other sort of follows it,
but it's less liquid. Yeah. And actually, guys,
that's actually where a lot of the edges made is like,
understanding the makeup of these ETFs. So you got one ETF,
where it should be made up of, you know, recently,
this ETF recently got very similar,
picked up a lot of very similar equities to this, right? And now,
but the balls haven't changed yet. Right?
It's those things is where you really find it's not going to be like S&P IVV.
Right? You're not going to see that it's too obvious, right?
It'll be too small to be worth it. Right?
Again, they want to find things that are not obvious, really not obvious.
Right? And those are the positions you want to find yourself in. Okay?
It's too obvious, it's not going to be there, unfortunately.
Okay, so what we'll do now, so that's where you can start, go find these pairs,
go take a look at them. And bring them to the group,
we'll start chatting about them. I think that's the best place to start,
go do some research, bring it to the group,
ask questions about what you're seeing. And we'll go from there.
So we have a couple questions that we'll go through.
And then we're going to wrap it up. Because, once again,
as all these lives end, I'm getting hungry.
So let's see, where was Bala's question?
Oh, wait, Bala left. So Oh, he's out. Oh, no, there he is.
I was looking for Bala not Siddharth. So at the top of the list. Okay,
let me see.
I'm not seeing it. Bala, do you mind retyping?
Is it possible for the IV spread to reduce but still not make money on the trade?
Where can we go wrong? No. So okay, yeah.
So you could go wrong where let's say, well, if the implied vol reduces, right,
if it goes back to normal, then you would make money, right?
Nothing would happen there.
But there would be the case where the stock just like,
where one stock moves like crazy, and the other stock doesn't. Like remember,
in our example, they're the exact same, but in real life, they're not.
And I've seen some.
One second.
Yeah, I've seen some times where it's like,
you think these ETFs are correlated,
and then and then they end up not being or, for example, a current so okay,
so here's a good one, too, is like a currency, right? So you might have like,
let's say two similar things trading on different exchanges.
And then you would have the currency vol, right? People will be like, Oh,
you know, this is this doctrine for this. And this is the same thing,
just different exchange. You know, I could sell vol here and buy vol here.
But what they're forgetting is the currency, the currency vol that's embedded,
right? Or the correlation to the currency that's embedded.
So these are the types of things that you know,
you really got to make sure what you're doing,
you really got to understand the product, right?
And they're not going to be like, right out there.
They're not going to you're not gonna be like, Oh, this is the you know,
this is right there. It's actually not going to be the case. Okay,
you they're going to be really subtle things that you pick up on and you guys are
gonna get better with this that you can they can grab.
Did that answer it? Did I answer it? Yeah, I think so. All right, here,
let's go through one more question. So Jack has question right down there.
There's a couple on the way here.
Okay. And if we miss your question, guys, rewrite it, and I will,
we'll get back to it. So, so they're saying,
let's say two illiquid ETFs bank ETF and nifty index.
Ideal to stick with nifty to be at fair value, most likely, right, most likely,
but then at the same time, because it's the big index,
that might be a little bit overpriced. Right?
So you really got to you really got to look into these things.
Okay, that's it, which I said, would we be managing this the same way?
If with another underlying,
like if we do a relative value trade with between a 30 DTE option and a 90 DTD option?
Like a calendar? Yeah, on the same stock. Okay, so we did a calendar spread,
what we managed the same. It really depends. So in our work example,
I don't know if you fell asleep already, but we actually did that data neutral,
right? We actually went flat gamma. But you can do them vega neutral as well,
which would be a regular calendar spread.
Marcos, how do you close out positions,
you close out when the implied vol spread collapses,
or you can find a better opportunity somewhere else.
This is a gold topic. No wonder he wore a gold shirt. Exactly. Come on, guys.
Not saying is the beta consistent throughout the trade?
The answer is not always right.
You could have these ETFs moving like crazy or the stocks moving like crazy together.
Let's say beta of two, and then eventually they just stop.
And then last question,
have you ever done a trade where SPY was mispriced compared to another ETF,
where SPY was actually the weak leg? Yeah,
the SPY is usually a little bit overpriced, right?
SPY is actually usually a little bit overpriced.
So usually I don't want to do that data neutral,
I'm usually leaning a little more vega neutral.
Just because I know that that S&P leg is usually the overpriced leg.
Marcos is asking,
could the correlation change over like a really short period of time?
100%. 100%, right? You just don't want to find yourself in those situations.
You want to be pretty confident that this relationship is going to last.
And it should be there for a fundamental reason.
You guys should never take a trade just because it's been correlated, right?
It's got to be a fundamental reason why these are correlated.
Steve's saying, imagine the USO trade. Steve,
want to elaborate a little bit there? They should never last?
Yeah, exactly, right? The relationship only lasts if they're half Asian,
exactly.
Yeah, exactly, right? So I'm 100% sure, I didn't go back to it,
but I'm sure you could. XLE versus USO, or even guys. So here's a good one too,
right?
Here's a really subtle one that maybe not a lot of people would have picked up on.
And actually would have been like almost an arbitrage. You get an ETF,
let's say, going from 3x to 2x, you already have a 2x leveraged ETF, right?
And as soon as this, let's say oil 3x, oil 2x.
Did they announce this is going from 3x to 2x? And these aren't matching,
right? And these are subtle differences that need to be adjusted quickly,
right? And sometimes you might get an hour, two hours,
a day before they fully collapse.
And we talked about something like that before, actually. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah.
All right. That is going to do it for tonight's live.
Good seeing everyone here. Siddharth,
it was a pleasure having you on the live with us today, man.
So for those of you that don't know, Siddharth lives in India.
He's an absolute rock star in the academy. He's basically taking PA principles,
doing a bunch of coding on his own,
building models for the Indian market and absolutely crushing it.
So it's always good when he comes out of the dark, the Indian wizard.
Happy Diwali, my friend. Okay. Take it easy, everyone. See you guys.