Some of you guys are really gonna enjoy this one. All right so You know,
we always talk about like you should find out if there's evidence, right?
You should find out like does this strategy work over time, right?
Especially for the technical guys here.
So There are really two things With that we can look at trading right one way is
is this asset mispriced? so for example, if if I'm selling you this phone,
okay for 500 bucks in Imperfect condition right in the box and you go online and
they're all selling for $1,500.
Well,
this is probably mispriced right and the way you figure out if this is mispriced
is You look at the specs, right you say, okay.
Let me see the condition Let me see if this is actually real you do your research
right who the seller is etc Then you find out this phone is actually mispriced.
That's what happens a lot of times in Option trading right, you know,
you look at you find the option here and you say well it's implying a volatility
of 50% and You know given hits historical returns or historical Last hundred days,
let's say or not last hundred days.
Let's say two years It's only moved this much and all the other sectors are moving
this much.
So this is probably overpriced or underpriced That's a lot what we do we find mispricings,
but then there's another side Okay, there's this data science field.
So that is just like knowing your asset pricing your asset then there's this data
science field where it's like Well,
can I find something that predicts the future?
Can I kind of predict the future? Right given this information, right?
Let's think about we're the weatherman Given this information.
Can I predict what tomorrow's weather is gonna be?
Okay given People coming into Amazon Can I predict what they're gonna buy right
and that is a whole field in itself and it's another way to look at trading Sorry,
I said my screens a little dirty here.
I'm sure So do you guys understand that do you have any questions about that there's
really two methods to look at trading Okay,
like two two ways to approach the market.
You guys have any questions about that?
So we have the mispricing and then we have the forecasting two different approaches
Is that basically sums up all? Professional trading these days.
Yeah all of it And most of the time in options, we are finding a mispricing,
right? This assets price at this but it should be priced over here.
We saw we know in the in the In the USO example,
you know Sean I always go back to it Given the contango.
It shouldn't be it shouldn't be priced like this And to a lesser degree that's what
we're doing with VIX Right, it's obviously it's not as extreme. Otherwise,
we'd be piling in a lot heavier,
but it's the same concept same concept So do you guys have any questions about that?
It seems pretty quiet right now Because I'll go over it again.
Looks like we're good.
I've never put these guys to sleep in first eight minutes crazy Okay,
I see contangle contangle on individual securities same way right same way all it
means is The the market's implying more volatility in the future,
right and If it's too much, well you can you want to sell that right? Okay,
so we understand that now when we come when it comes to forecasting some of the
times we can actually use technical indicators,
but we have to do a Quantitative driven approach an evidence-based approach.
So I highly recommend All of you go and read the book evidence-based technical analysis
Because what the author does and he's a he's one of my favorite traders of all time.
Okay, his name is David Aronson What the author does is he says,
okay this this method of technical analysis where you're just you're just You know,
you're you're just using your mind and and you're just thinking about it and rationing
about it is garbage And what he does is he says, okay. Well,
let's take an evidence-based approach Okay,
so that's what we're gonna be talking about right now and building your own strategy
right obviously or not Maybe obviously but it's gonna require some work Everything
good in life requires some work.
So Here's actually one of the articles from David Aronson. Okay,
where he actually goes about talks about how to build a strategy Okay,
and what we see here is on the left axis He has the stock return in a day.
Sorry on the y-axis On the y-axis,
he has the stock return the next day on the x-axis. He has the RSI level Okay,
so this is a theoretical example,
but what can we what can we see from this graph? What is this graph telling us?
Someone want to tell me what this graph tells us?
Cool. Let me let me check my phone. Actually.
I do not recall I Do not recall that chat I mean I'll have to take a look at it
before the live ends and Koa, we made a trade on VXX today.
If you look in the PA trade journal in the discord You'll get a full breakdown of
what we did.
So Koa is right. There's an inverse versus RSI So, what does that mean Koa?
Can you just go one step further? What does that mean that there's an inverse?
I was pretty quiet. The answer is actually on the screen. Oh, is it?
Yeah, so Okay,
perfect cause so what it was saying is the higher the RSI Then if you know if the
RSI is high today tomorrow's return is gonna likely be low And if the RSI is low,
then tomorrow's return is likely to be high, right?
That is You know a mean reversion strategy, right?
You basically want to Buy when the stock's low sell when the stock's high and that's
what he's doing here. He's graphing that relationship It's evidence-based.
It's empirical. Okay,
so what I did Was I did an RSI strategy on so if that's a load,
sorry guys Okay, I didn't RSI strategy on IBM Okay,
and what I did was if our side goes above 70 Sell IBM and if it goes below 30 by
IBM and this is over 10 years I plugged it into the computer and the computer did
Thousands of trades and now we can see our P&L curve. How have we done?
Right,
the blue line here guys is the number of shares that I currently own The green line
is my P&L.
The red line is my drawdown and then this orange line is the RSI It's our side three
day and you can see like the strategy doesn't do good.
But this is taking an evidenced evidence-based approach Okay,
so I'm just gonna pull it up here super quick Sorry guys,
give me one quick second Okay
Here we go, perfect So here we actually have the data, right? We say okay.
Well, what are what are we trading? Well in this case,
we're trading the close Okay,
and every time the RSI goes below 30 we get a signal to buy right if it goes above
70 We're gonna get a signal to sell and we're just gonna go over and over and over
in the compute Oops,
and the computers gonna do this over Over and over and over again,
there's no hindsight bias.
There's not there's just what would have happened over a given period of time now
We can see this we can see now. Let's let's step back for a second. Okay,
and let's take a look at this strategy Okay,
just just take a look at this painting for a second Now imagine your boss said hey,
I want you to go out and trade this koa I want you to go and trade the strategy
and you had a couple winning trades Well,
would you let's say you had ten trades in a row? Okay,
you saw this and your boss said you know what?
It's actually a good negative correlation to one of our other strategies I want
you to trade this and You got ten trades in a row that were correct.
You were like, let's say going on this hot streak right here Okay,
nice big hot streak. How would you guys feel?
I want you to please comment down below How would you feel as a trader good?
You feel good What else what else how else would you feel how else would you feel
like put yourself in this position? Okay,
you just you just you just did the back test and your boss said go to go do it Marco
said confident Graham said on my 11th. I'm betting the whole company Okay,
we feel confident guys Why would we feel confident here?
I'm very curious to know why would we feel confident here?
Why would you feel good? You got ten trades in a row. Why would you feel good?
We're winning correct That is correct, but we gotta go deeper right?
We've seen what what the strategy has done,
right? Okay So the answer is we wouldn't feel anything. We wouldn't feel good.
We wouldn't feel bad The reason we wouldn't feel good is because we know that in
the long run.
We're still gonna break even we're just on a hot streak So we shouldn't feel good
because we know in the future. It's gonna come back down, right?
We know it's not gonna continue and we don't feel bad because we know this strategy
breaks even Right. We we know what's going on.
Our emotions have been taken out of the equation. We know what to expect Right.
We said look at this We go let's say we go on a 20-day hot streak.
Okay guys from 2011 to 2000 and almost 12 Okay,
we went on this like Tear we're almost every trade was a winner But we can see this
and we could say oh, you know what?
We are just probably somewhere on this graph right now But in the long run if I
keep doing this,
I'm not gonna really make any money I'm not gonna make any money.
So I'm not nervous. I'm not excited.
I know what to expect now What if this graph went up straight into the right?
okay straight into the right and You started trading this and You did ten trades
in a row that were profitable. How do you guys feel now?
How do you guys feel now?
Tell me how you feel So this we bet we back test it and this thing goes straight
up and you start trading it and it's up ten times in A row. How do you feel?
Well,
you feel good this time this time you actually feel good because you know that this
is gonna actually play out in the long Run you're actually going to make money Right
if this was down into the right and you went on ten times in a row you just be like,
ah, whatever I'm gonna lose. Anyways, I'm just catching a little run here,
right?
But it's because we know what to expect that we don't we're not emotional anymore
We're not excited about if this happens today.
It's what is supposed to happen Right when you get in your car and it starts going
forward You're not excited.
You're not sad This is what's supposed to happen if you get in your car you press
the gas and it go starts going backward You're gonna be like what the fuck?
Right,
or if you can't if you can't shoot three pointers and all of a sudden you shoot
through two three pointers in a row You're not gonna think I'm gonna be going to
the NBA, right?
You're gonna be like I got lucky and this is how we need to think about trading
and building strategies, right?
We need to be able to see what has actually happened,
you know and with option trading It's difficult because you don't it's hard to get
your hands on historical data Each situation is usually unique because there's expirations
Right, you can still do back testing for a lot of different strategies,
but usually they're very unique so like here's a way to think about it like This
might not be the best example.
I'm sitting here trying to think of an example to help Clarify what we mean by when
we say like there's no emotion attached to it We're not saying people like traders
don't feel happiness or feel sadness they're not robots they're people oh yeah,
this guy in the Zuck maybe are a robots by aliens,
but imagine this like imagine you ran a Landscaping company you mow lawns you mow
lawns for a living you own a company that does it and you make $200,000 a year doing
it but all your money is made between spring and Fall and when winter starts to
roll around you make zero you make zero dollars so for two-thirds of the year or
let's say for half the year you make $200,000 and then for the other half of the
year you make zero dollars and you know this you know This is gonna happen every
single year moving forward and today is June 1st,
and you're making money You've made a hundred thousand dollars in the last three
months and you're gonna make and you're like this is gonna want forever You for
six months you make you've made two hundred thousand dollars now,
you're not sitting there like yeah This is gonna go on forever because you know
That first little bit of snow falls No money's coming.
You're aware of that before it happens.
You've anticipated that you've calculated for that you spend accordingly So when
it does happen, you're not sitting there going. Where'd my cash flow go?
And when you're making money, you're not like yeah Yeah,
you're like this is my business.
My business is seasonal So you're not excited when you you know,
and then all winter you're you make no money and then You know spring rolls around
again, and somebody asks you to come up, you know,
mow the lawn for the first time You're not like oh my god.
I've broken the dry streak. You see what I'm saying?
You're aware of these things going into your business So you're not emotionally
attached to the fact that it's seasonal You might you might run multiple strategies,
right?
So you might run a summer strategy where you mow lawns and then a winter strategy
where you shovel driveways Exactly Marcos.
That's exactly we're thinking the same way, right? So and that's the thing.
Maybe you run multiple strategies, right?
So this strategy maybe runs counter even though it doesn't make money It runs counter
to the main strategy that the firm runs because it reduces their drawdowns Makes
their P&L more smooth reduces the volatility of the portfolio Right.
So does that make sense? Does that make sense why?
There's no when we say there's no emotion attached.
It's not that we don't enjoy money it's not that we don't enjoy making money is
that if you're aware that you make money now and you don't make money down the Road
and that it balances out to you making XYZ amount per year You're not sitting there
Freaking out when you're making or losing money you're only gonna start getting
a little nervous or excited or at least you know,
maybe neither but just Critical thinking about it when something outside of the
realm of what you're expecting happens,
you know Maybe it's December 30th and somebody's asking you to mow their lawn and
they pay in advance and you're like wait What why is everyone paid me to mow lawns
in winter has something changed? Yeah, you know what?
I mean global warming is like You know what? I mean?
That's a really good way to put it man, man Yeah,
so I was sitting there silent for about trying to think of something.
So take a look here All right, guys. Take a look.
This is a mean reverting strategy and you know what?
Imagined you are right here.
Take that in Imagine you just started trading the strategy.
You haven't back tested it properly with a computer and you're right here You're
on this huge upswing Huge upswing.
Could you imagine your P&L going forward? Could you imagine?
What would be happening?
You start making a lot of money You might buy some things you shouldn't be buying
Like a computer And then You are in a long-term losing game.
You're in a very long-term losing game, but in the short term, right?
You could be you could be on any one of these tears Any one of these rips and if
you don't fully understand your strategy,
you don't fully understand what's going on here You are gonna be really really tough
spot Okay,
this is what happens to all the traders all the all the traders they go on these
swings right here They have no clue what's been happening before Okay,
so how do we how do we fix this how do we fix this? well,
the the and maybe not how we fix this because you know it it's gonna require some
You know some other other tangible skills if you're doing the forecasting.
So remember we said there's two types There's a mispricing and then there's a forecasting.
So forecasting you'll usually see in People who are doing directional trades right
because we're trying to predict tomorrow's to the future price of the Stocks movement
Right,
you'll see this in high-frequency trading to a high-frequency trader will do although
they will do these back tests all day long They'll try to find these variables which
we saw here, right?
They're gonna try to find a variable here that correlates With the assets return
and that's what they're gonna do all day long, right?
They're gonna work on their execution skills But at the end of the day,
they're trying to find something that's gonna help predict the future Now what we
actually see in financial markets,
okay the actual and this is what's gonna blow your mind Okay,
you guys are gonna book you guys you guys you guys are gonna be like buckle up buckle
up Actually, it's not gonna blow their mind too much. But okay.
I hope it gets you guys really thinking Okay of what we actually see in the world
so if I asked you guys What does your strategy look like? Okay,
if you let's say this was yours your signal this y-axis was your signal Sorry,
the x-axis was your signal.
So maybe it's your one three two step trading to finding breakouts okay,
and These were your signals right here and over here was the stock returns Okay.
So for example when your signal said buy let me draw. Can I draw on here Sean?
Okay,
so when your signal said buy so here's where it says buy and Here's where it says
sell which graph do you think would be the graph?
That would best describe your strategy Which graph do you think it would be and
why and let's say you had no emotions.
You were a robot Let's say you were a perfect robot who always executed always did
perfect risk management Which which which which one would you be on the graph?
Uh-huh.
Oh, you're hilarious man. Okay. Okay. Um Okay, maybe you guys can oh wait.
Oh see. Oh, oh, sorry. I thought okay. Sorry Cole.
I was looking at the wrong one I was looking at the wrong one call. Let's see.
Okay, that's it.
Yeah I was thought you were talking about F Cola aka if it was by you'd lose money
sell you this one. Okay, so Willis Marcos you guys are saying a Okay,
so Can you guys explain a little more why would it be a Why would it be a maybe
I should be a little more clear here. So so here is the stock returns.
So Here would be let's say like 10% and here would be negative 10% So when a you
guys are saying when your stock says buy when you're when your signal says buy you
lose 10% And when your signal says sell you're gonna You would lose 10% right because
the stock goes up Okay, so you guys are saying D Carson saying D.
So the reality is guys the reality is Okay,
the reality is your signal is actually gonna look like C This is actually what a
good strategy looks like is C I don't know you guys are saying like what the hell
this C means C looks like nothing C looks like absolutely nothing There is a correlation
of point zero eight, okay,
so what that means is this This our signal here briefly explains Has a very very
very very tiny bit of forecasting ability Very very small right exactly Marco.
It looks 5050, right? It looks 5050,
but it's not it's not it's super super super small and this is Actually a massive
edge in trading Okay,
a lot of traders are gonna shoot for something like this or something like this
or like even like this Right,
they're gonna try to get good signals like these or good signals like the ones All
the other ones right these are great. This is a great signal.
This is a perfect signal same with this one One to one one to one you signal says
this it does this This looks like there's no correlation. It's just noise.
Okay And in fact, it looks just like noise. Exactly.
It looks just like noise and the relationship just Very small,
I guess I did a little too small Right,
it doesn't even look like that's that's deep But this is actually what you guys
are gonna see in the market this right here.
This is your 90% hit rate your 90 93% hit rate your 85% hit rate your 70% hit rate
this over here This is your 52 53 percent hit rate and there's no way a human mind
a human human eyes can actually see this Right you you if you're really trained
at it,
you can see it But that's why it's so hard to actually think to actually know you
have an edge Right because you might win.
Let's say 55 out of 100 times and think you have an you know and think you have
an edge But an actual fact it's might just be 45 55 in the other in the opposite
direction or maybe even 50 50 So this is actually the reality of trading you guys
have any questions about this That you're that you're you're there's so much noise
There's so much noise in the markets and you're all you need is a super small signal
The signal has to be extremely the predictive power has to be extremely extremely
Small in order to make fortunes And I know that sounds crazy guys because everyone's
talking about a 60% hit rate a 70% hit rate an 80% hit rate it's actually the reality
a casino casino built a billion-dollar Empire off of 1% edge off a 2% edge off a
52% hit rate. Okay,
so keep that in mind By hit rate we mean like being correct Carson So
like if you were flipping a coin and you called heads you would have a fit if you
called heads 100% of the time You'd probably you'd have a 50% hit rate in the long
run And yeah Carson, why would you want a or B?
So just like in this graph right here Carson Let me just exit here.
So Carson just like in this graph over here And Carson, I know you're you know,
you're big into code.
You might want to check out the Quantstrat github This is where I pull the code
just to do the run run the back test there. It's done in R though Okay,
we're so remember remember in this right here,
oh do you know how to delete all the stuff here Sean This is a quick a quick like
a race all Annotate clear. Oh, okay. Perfect. Nice hide this. Yeah,
so just like in this graph, right? This is our signal.
This is our Our variable and in this case is the RSI Right,
so RSI tells you when something is cheap relative to the mean and expensive relative
to the mean So if you saw this Right,
even though it's negative you would say well every time RSI is below 30 buy shares
because it correlates with a 1% return the next day and Every time it's above let's
say 70 You'd want to sell shares because it goes below zero the return tomorrow
is below zero But what we see here is that this variable this trading signal whatever
it is You know, this is your one two, three step to trading, right?
This is your Buy when this and sell when this right whatever it is,
whatever your strategy is This is it and all this is telling us is well when it's
up here Things go down when it's below here things go up and it can explain the
returns tomorrow, right? This indicator explains the returns tomorrow.
Do you guys see how do you guys do you guys see that and this is This is what?
Professional trading in quantitative trading in the directional space.
This is what the best guys are doing Okay,
I just wanted you guys to get a feel for that to see what evidence-based trading
looks like Right, we're moving. We have computers now.
We're trying to move away from You know discretionary trading go do you want to
expand on what you're saying there and Just to touch on it quickly so Marcos has
asked a couple times during this just like or mentioned like it'd be kind of cool
to be able to do it for like multiple ideas or like What if instead of using the
the weekly you use the three-day or like, you know, like you use the 90-day?
Yeah,
right So I think so the thing about so the reason why people do this all day every
day Marcos is because there are unlimited combinations There are so many combinations
so many different things you can look at in so many different ways That you need
to do it all the time,
right if you're always looking for strategies you're doing this all the time We
actually tried to build out a backtesting model for the terminal but the thing is
that there's so many combinations that it's not feasible to To build to build it
out Hey Ram, you want to know one that?
Works out that we tested earnings Earnings does a great great job.
So does So does long overnight? Yeah long overnight,
that's what that's gonna be in the new terminal that's gonna be the new one back
So we have a couple of predictor variables where that explains the overnight return
right, and this is This is what's gonna be embedded in the terminal.
Eventually.
This is just a couple because like obviously we can't give you everything away There's
a couple good great strats for you guys to get involved and start doing it And I
know it's tough right? I know it's I know not everyone codes.
I everyone can do this There's actually backtesting softwares that can help you
with this Right,
but the point is you need evidence That's the whole point is that you need the evidence
You need to know does this actually work?
So so Ram I didn't know you actually followed us when we were running the overnight
Yeah,
so we were doing it live on the IG We stopped it after after 16 days because the
market literally fell out from beneath us and it's a long it's a long Long equity
trade so we were like this is this is not and that's actually when we started the
options Academy, right?
That's when we made that change But take this in Ram Matt Maddy Matt Robinson in
our group.
He's been running the overnight the whole time So he's been on a huge tear huge
tear you can reach out to him to ask him about that if you want.
So Ram so our overnight strategy Okay,
so our overnight strategy does really well in the long run really really really
really well and But one thing about it is that it's tied it has correlation to the
market So imagine Ram imagine this was all the way up into the right this graph
right here What happened was we were we went we were on a run we were on like we
were during this period right here, right?
We were going up up up up up and then market got hit Or we started losing money
and Sean I realized hey, listen, you know what?
We can't have our business tied to the market, right?
We can't just be these guys that pump out one strategy and then You know,
so the originally we were actually teaching guys how to do this kind of stuff and
giving them the tools And to trade these these strategies, right?
We had we had a short strategy for example That was short Boeing before the crash
and actually held through the crash and you'll you'll did it you'll held through
right Neil did really well there We also you you know, this might you know,
I swear to God you guys can reach out to to Damien Instagram he's actually in the
discord. He's in the discord.
He we had a we had a value strat That's a value momentum shot that said by Kodak
in May and like, you know,
you're supposed to know it was in April Yeah And it was these are like, well,
you know Strategies are supposed to hold for quite a long period of time.
So we have these strategies built in But we don't we don't want to be a signal service
and we don't want people to be tied to our strategies Right.
So that's why we decide to move over to the the option space and teach right and
actually like educate on how to build Your own tools how to build your own systems,
etc Yeah,
so Kodak wasn't in the terminal because it was too small back in the day in micro
cap Yeah,
we don't we don't have that in there because you shouldn't be trading options on
those Yeah, and actually I don't think they had options until Release.
Yeah Till I went to the moon. Yeah, and then back down to earth really quick.
So cool has a couple good questions here Up a bit. Okay. So Koa said like hey,
you know what? I actually only so he uses a back testing machine a fantastic.
Oh, I'm very happy to hear this man.
So he actually uses a Back testing machine trade machine trade machine and he said
like I like to look for high probability strategies The problem is if you just so,
you know We all think in terms of expected value and this yeah,
and this can't be So one thing is if you test everything a couple things are gonna
hit Right, like you see so,
you know how I did on Apple and the P&L looked way different I bet you if I did
this exact same strategy on a stock. I don't know. Give me let's do. Okay,
let's do Okay,
once give me a stock here any stock quick quick quick quick Baba actually,
okay Baba trend so ramen this won't work on there.
I need something like here's a good one actually So this is natural gas So you guys
see how the computer is running super quick doing all this this would take years
for a human to do This is gonna take years for the computer to do. Yeah,
so We're still in 2014.
Yeah You know by testing this strategy on thousands of thousands of equities We're
gonna find one that it actually does well on and this is actually,
you know Let's see how this did okay it into to all Yeah,
it definitely into to all did terrible actually I'm like wait a minute But if this
if the stock just chopped up and down like this,
it would it would done really well The point is it's we can't be doing this with
like thousands of stocks and not understanding why we're doing it We need to have
the reason I'm back testing this strategy because of this and this and this Yeah,
so you remember this Patterns exist in randomness and in order,
okay They you will find patterns in the clouds You'll find patterns in human behavior.
You'll find patterns in data Some will make sense.
Some don't make sense a prime example.
You can go watch it Jim Simons talks about it The founder of Renaissance Technologies
probably one of the group Probably the greatest trader of all time big big fund
manager trader of all time 70% year-over-year averages with a 10-figure account
how the fuck he does it.
No one knows except for him and his team But the point is that he gave an interview
where he said we actually found a one-to-one perfect correlation for the S&P 500
returns we were looking at the S&P return and predictor variable was Corn cycles
in Italy something about something wild corn production in northern Italy and You
can sit there and go Wow one-to-one Phenomenal, but should you trade it?
Does it make sense that how much corn was grown in a region in Italy?
Predicts how the biggest market in the world returns.
Does it make sense? Like should we trade even though it's perfect?
We look back to back test is like you would make you'd be the richest person in
the world if you did this Does it make sense? And then, you know,
there's things like overfitting for example, right?
So there's lots of different Yeah, exactly.
Like should if mercury's in retrograde should should we be?
selling futures Right You know what I mean?
So with when you're creating a strategy guys,
especially in the directional space, okay,
especially in the directional space When you're creating a strategy you first have
to answer the question Why should this work? What are you looking for? Right?
example in the overnight returns we said What one of these signals is is the VIX
in contango. That's one of the signals that actually works okay,
and Our theory is well when implied volatility is high involved volatility is high
We are less likely to see high overnight returns Because stocks when stocks are
volatile, they're usually going down Okay,
if the markets expecting so VIX is the future looking forward looking So if the
markets expecting volatility in the future and we know the market's smart Then we
shouldn't be long overnight.
And so that was our theory then we tested it and guess what it worked That's how
you have to build these systems.
That's how you have to build these strategies Even if you're doing it discretionary,
even if you're saying I'm gonna buy when there's a new 52-week high I'm gonna buy
when there's when we're looking at an intraday breakout.
We have to ask the question. Why should this work?
Okay, and it can't be human behaviors.
I don't know if some of you guys were in live yesterday We can't say oh because
of human pattern human patterns. It's gonna work. Okay,
there's no intraday human patterns, right?
90% are algorithms 90% of the volume is algorithms. There's no emotions there.
So we need to ask yourself. Why would this work?
Once we do that we try to test it as best we can we either use a software or I mean
I really don't want to say this. Actually. I'm not gonna say it.
I was gonna say You do it manually. I'll just say you don't do it.
You don't do it like that That's how you build these strategies or you go on Fiverr
and say hey, buddy. Listen, can you back test a strategy for me?
He'll charge you 20 bucks. You back testing a strategy.
He lets you know how it worked We used to do that we used to do that we were 50
bucks now, we're a hundred bucks Oh, you want your strategy back testing? Okay,
but not for the group though for the group.
We give you guys 90 bucks Okay Right. So Ram.
Why don't why don't you break down a strategy you're thinking of and we'll talk
about it We're gonna talk about it right now on the live Ram right here.
Tell me about it What were you thinking up because I know there's other guys in
this group Yeah, I know those other guys in this group You know,
I know Marcos for example,
he's very he's he's he's active He's very active and he has a signal he has a strategy
He has a signal but what we need to do as a trader say well to get that confidence
A lot of people are looking for confidence here all the time We're looking for confidence
to get that confidence.
We need to know if it actually works Ram do you mind explaining your strategy a
little bit?
I don't this is it I've seen something like buying aftermarket spy and then selling
it at the open the next day. Is that the one?
Okay, perfect. Well Ram. It says you raised your hand.
Did you want to come in the life?
Okay, perfect. Let me Okay Sean's the the zoom technician.
Let me see if I can do this Ram Okay, I think I think we got it. Hey,
buddy Hey, hey, man. Hey, hey Jordan yet so for for the stocks, okay Yeah,
no worries For stocks when the 5 EMA crosses above the 10 and the 21 EMA Okay Shit,
what else is that? I had it written down. Yeah,
maybe that one For short term right when the 5 EMA crosses above the the 10 EMA
and the 21 EMA Okay,
so super easy to back test and I'll actually do that for the group.
I think Marcos wanted that as well I'm not gonna do it on the life here,
but I'll do it for the group. Cool So let's actually talk about this though.
Why do you think this should work? What? What made you think of this idea?
Yeah.
Well this one I got actually early on when I when I started trading I read this
guy's books very concise to the point books Steven Joseph Burns,
I think I follow him on Instagram, but I was like, you know, what? Why not?
let me let me give this a shot and Based on what he was doing and then I applied
it and I really didn't even tweak it I just used it and it worked for for for trading
trading wise,
right and it works pretty well And then sometimes I even expand it out like on a
weekly Weekly chart or like a monthly right if I'm trying to go long something kind
of kind of swinging something or if I want to Hold something as long as that holds
Like even if though if the five crosses above the ten and the twenty one then,
you know Let's say the twenty one crosses above the fifty days simple moving average
Well,
like the fifty crosses above you get a golden cross or some shit like that It'll
work like we're for like a swing trade and I seen it like Although I was making
money off of it. And so I got a cool. Are you still using it today? Yeah,
just for like for swinging stocks Like in and out kind of thing yeah,
the five when the five crosses above the The ten and the twenty one I'll use it
Gotcha,
and so if I like tested it on Apple like you would think it should have a positive
Expectancy perhaps. Yeah,
I'm interested in seeing because I like I don't know anything about coding like
I see you get voting It's like is this long and short or just long Short as well
short as well.
So when the five crosses below the ten and the twenty one and Then even through
the the the fifty,
you know sometimes I sometimes I get an early which kind of messes me up sometimes
but When when the five crosses below the ten and the twenty one like, you know,
it's on a downtrend maybe for the short term But I'm interested in seeing what that
actually yields Over the long term. Yeah, definitely.
I like that's I can definitely do that for sure Ram,
but my question is like why do you think this might actually work? Like,
you know how like for example, we sell options around earnings and we say well,
it's overpriced because of you know People don't really know how to price these
assets. They're they're buying options to take directional bets.
There's no real up.
There's no real Natural sellers right hedge funds are using it to buy protection.
So we usually think all should be overpriced In this case,
what do you think is causing that return?
I'm not too sure To be honest with you.
I'm not I'm not too sure maybe maybe it's just the price action the way that the
stock is moving like I don't know like I'm not I'm not too sure Um,
so like this, you know, it might be working for you right now,
but this is something that we can kind of like Get in trouble with right because
like Sean always says like, you know, you start you start to say like,
okay This actually works and then when it stops working,
you don't know why and you can't trading it and you keep trading it.
Mm-hmm We always want to find out why would this work?
Okay. Okay. Yeah, does that make sense? Yeah,
I understand and that's where you're really gonna find the edge because you're gonna
totally understand your strategy yeah,
and we got to remember right like and I'm like,
this is not an attack on you in any way.
Like it's just like to get you to think about it You know, yeah. Yeah, right.
Yeah, dude. This is awesome. You came on man. Love it.
Remember like You're your own portfolio manager Right.
So imagine imagine you weren't your own portfolio manager Imagine you were investing
in you and you went to talk to you and you said can you explain this to me?
Right and there you explain the strategy go cool and they're like,
but why should this work and you're like,
I don't really know But it does You know what? I mean?
Like you like why the fuck am I giving this guy my money, right?
See that we got to think about it like that,
right if we remove ourselves from the situation We go like would I give someone
my money who's running this strategy? No,
no Yourself your money right and like that's why we got we got to think critically
right like um and look if it's worked so far and like look there's you know,
it's It sounds like there's some thought that's gone into it All that needs to be
done now is we need that we need to look at this idea test it and we need to understand
Why this might work? Right,
right You know like for example the overnight strategy the overnight strategy basically
filters out assets that we should be buying at the closed selling at the open because
they have a like a liquidity risk premium Right.
So because it's the markets are closed The market could tank overnight and you can't
get out and you're holding the bag if it opens So there's a premium for holding
these assets overnight And what we see is that these premiums that you're getting
paid outweigh the losses of when some shit does go down That's why this makes money
because someone else is not willing to carry that risk.
We are willing to carry that risk We get paid a premium for carrying the risk that
someone else doesn't want what what happens just a question here What happens like,
you know When when Tesla stock is gonna split or Apple stock is gonna split at the
end of August for for Apple What happens to those options?
Let's say you were holding Longer data does they'll adjust they adjust like perfectly
they there's there's no arm there or anything like that.
They'll adjust immediately Does that strategy take a long time to to to test or
it just kind of look like the 5 10 20 thing? Yeah,
it would take me it would take me 20 minutes. Okay. Yeah,
if you want to write it down on paper so I can just Frequent it that'd be great.
Yeah And so also so right right off the back so I got tested so many strategies
In the past Ram what we see is like so that's a trend-following strategy Yeah,
if we do it on a stock like Apple Tesla Amazon those are right because they trend
for a long time. Yeah. Yeah Maybe not they trend for a long time.
They have been trending.
There's a difference Yeah That's what I was reading in the book as well Like,
you know Like the trend is your friend and this this one helps you with the trend
right or whenever it's down Like when you when you see a reverse from like a bullish
trend to a bearish trend you can use it the other way As well, so yeah, right.
That'll be really interesting to see the results,
but if we did it on a stock like IBM, right?
We probably wouldn't make any money Mm-hmm,
because IBM is mean reverting right once once we get the crossover. Yeah,
it's not gonna trend anymore It's gonna come back down right if we take a look at
the chart for IBM So, okay, so you see here for example,
let me pull it up here Okay, Ram, you see the RSI strategy here on Apple. Yep.
It does so bad Right does terrible right and the reason it does terrible is because
Apple has just been trending for the last 20 years But if we look at a stock like
IBM Where there was no trend. Mm-hmm.
All of a sudden this mean reverting strategy Does a little bit better than break
-even Right.
So what the core thing is what you would want to do in this situation is like what
is it that out? Why is it that Apple trends? Right,
what causes Apple to trend what causes Amazon to trend?
It's not the EMA 5 over the EMA 20 that causes Apple to trend.
It's something else about it And that's that's the real signal Right.
So you so you have like two different types of when you're building out these strategies
You have two different things you have a signal and a filter So a filter tells you
these are the stocks you should trade The signal tells you when to trade them.
Does that make sense?
Yes,
so just to just to clear just to make sure it's 100% clear Let's say your strategy
is you want to buy value stocks? Okay,
you want to be let's say the guy that picks the bottom and the stocks rally Well,
the filter would be like find stocks that have a low price to earnings the signal
would be Buy the stock when the RSI goes below 70. Oh, sorry goes below 30,
right? So you're having that filter plus the signal gives you the trade Cool.
Yep. I understand Ram if you could please send me that list man.
I honestly dude I appreciate you coming out here and chatting man.
Anytime you want to come on. Just let me know Of course. Yeah,
I'll send you a message. Yeah,
please do or even post in the group post in the group I'll get on that look like
right here. No, no, no, like posting like the the traders chat or something.
Gotcha Okay, Ram. We're gonna let you go if you pulled that Okay Hey,
can you repeat the last statement Jordan? Can you repeat the last statement?
Don't remember it. Oh cool. Was it the one where I said?
Put it in the traders chat Okay, so there's a filter and there's a signal Okay,
there's a filter and there's a signal the filter tells you what you should be looking
at, right? There's 7,000 stocks out there.
The filter tells you what I should be looking at the signal tells you when to make
that trade Okay, if there's a value stock that's super cheap,
but the signal says it's not there yet It still has a little bit more room to go
That's the signal so you find so here's a great example. Okay,
you figure out what's in common with all trending stocks Those are your groups of
stocks to look at The signal is well is the EMA 5 over the EMA 10 and is the EMA
10 over the EMA 21 If it's not you don't take that trade.
These are hypothetical by the way. Yeah,
I'm not telling someone to do that Right, right. No, no,
like you wouldn't for example if the EMA 5 and the EMA 10 are over the EMA 21 on
IBM You wouldn't take the trade.
Why because IBM doesn't trade doesn't trend But you might do it on BYND or you might
do it on Tesla, right? So it's filter signal.
Okay Awesome awesome so Marcos has one last thing here
I saw a post some time ago a woman trader backtested that strategy and beat the
actual spy by 10 to 20 percent if That's the case. That's great. But Here,
I'll repeat this if you don't know why this isn't working You will get screwed.
Yeah,
you can't put your money behind it You can't it's gonna it's gonna bite you in the
ass because that that is gonna bring that I don't have any confidence I don't have
any confidence about this trade right Another way to think about it.
I'm just gonna say there. No,
okay So there's a guy and actually I actually talked to him Online before many times.
His name is Rob Carver. Okay, so he used to work at a QR Sorry,
he used to work at man capital,
which is one of the biggest like biggest quant firms ever He did really well and
he did like I was it like I think 35% 40% on his capital and this we're talking
millions of dollars for Quite a long period of time. Okay,
it was fantastic Great great great trader the signal, right?
So let's say it's the we're gonna keep it super simple simple The SMA 200 that signal
has to pick up on trends. So what does that mean?
The way they do it is they'll create simulated data. Okay,
this is how this how real traders do it They'll create a simulated data So they're
gonna do random data,
but they're gonna put a trend factor in there They're gonna say,
you know random data but at a trend Very small trend at it and then they're gonna
create the strategy and see if it can pick up on it Can it pick up on the simulated
data? Can the 200 day moving average pick up on this trend?
How well does it pick up on this trend?
And if it picks up really well, that's gonna be their signal now.
All they need is the filter What should I put in this signal? Okay,
and that's how these like in-depth Delta one Delta one mean directional strategies
are actually built created and used in in the professional space Okay,
and you can read his book his book is called Systematic trading Rob Carver all about
trend following and how he uses the filters with the signals to build a strategy
Okay, guys, I think that is going to do it for today's live. Yeah.
I hope you guys are pumped Yeah,