All right, everyone. So in this lecture,
we're going to be talking about trade idea generation all the way to Implementation
and execution. Okay,
so really the whole process So this might be a little bit of a longer one.
We're gonna go through two examples and There's gonna be no well so for each structure
right that we were actually going to trade here There's gonna be an optimal trade
right,
but sometimes optimal is not best and we'll talk about that as we go through So
this isn't really intended to be a really You know really tough live,
but it's a really important live All right. So let's let's jump right into it.
Let me just open up my screen here So you'll want to start with how you found her.
Yeah. Okay. Okay,
so Just before I show my screen here one thing to keep in mind guys as traders.
We're always looking for information We're always looking to see what what are other
people doing? Okay, we're always trying to see. Okay. Well,
where is there some activity? Where is there somewhere?
There may be an inefficiency going on Right if we knew for example,
all Robin Hood traders were trading this one product that was let's say very illiquid
Well,
we would obviously know there's gonna be a lot of opportunity there But if we know
a lot of Robin Hood traders are gonna be trading in the S&P 500.
Well That's not really gonna move the needle, right?
So we really we as traders we have to stay attuned to the market, right?
Every time someone says something You think I wonder if there's an idea there or
I wonder if another people or other people are talking about it, right?
That is that is the life of a trader Okay,
always remember that and I'm sure say it one more time so we can really really understand
it as traders We have to be attuned to the market. Okay,
we have to always be thinking in terms of could there be a trade here?
So quick example,
one of the trades we're gonna be looking at today Was because I was listening to
Sean's live in the morning But I was listening to Sean's live and I saw another
trader talking about one of the trades so right off the bat I'm gonna look into
it and I was like, oh, you know, actually there is something here.
Which one was this?
Okay,
so That's how That's a lot of the idea generation is sometimes gonna come from that
so let's jump right into it and ask your questions along the way guys okay,
so When we're looking for vol opportunities Everyone is gonna be a little different.
Okay,
Sean and I we like leaning short vol just because it's usually gonna generate a
High-return long run.
Okay options are on average Overpriced right if if the stock market on average goes
up then on average I want to be long vol a long S&P 500, right?
I don't want to be on average short S&P 500 if in on average it goes up, right?
That being said doesn't mean I don't go short the market Doesn't mean Sean doesn't
take long vol trades Right.
It's just that's usually where I'm looking for first, right?
That's usually where the mispricing is gonna be first Okay,
so always keep that in mind.
So Right off the bat. I want to look for a short vol trade.
And so what I do is I come to the volatility insights and Over here.
So here's our cruiser global dashboard you come in but then we head over to volatility
insights And so roughly about we can use this screener right now in the equity in
the options market We have thousands of options and thousands of stocks So for that
reason we need something that can help us boil it down right narrow it down So let's
say a handful of ten stocks that we can look into and so First thing we're gonna
look at here And actually I already predefined the screener is I want to see the
implied vol versus the forecast Greater than 1.05.
I want to see implied vol greater than our forecast Right.
Our forecast looks at a lot of historical data.
It looks at implied volatility data.
It looks at how When stocks go up usually right Vol goes down and when stocks go
down fall goes up.
So it takes into that it takes that into account so We want to have our implied
volatility higher than our forecast right if we're short volatility So I want to
put this number above 1.05. Okay,
and this is just saying this is taking the implied volatility number right here
And dividing it by our forecast It's that simple. Okay.
The next thing I want to look for is I want I want there to be some vol But I don't
want to trade an asset that has an implied vol of 10 It's just it's just not gonna
move the needle. So I want to have at least implied volatility Over 35. Okay.
I want at least some type of implied volatility Right and just for perspective imagine
S&P vol was trading at 35 and let's say realized vol was trading at 20 Well,
this is a great opportunity, right? It doesn't need to be let's say 90 vol,
right? It's not always about that high IV rank. In fact,
it's actually never just about the high IV rank Okay,
or the high implied volatility level next I want I Want IV rank above 60? Okay,
I want implied volatility to be relatively high if I think you know volatility is
a mean reverting asset All right volatility if we look at it,
right if we look at volatility right here if you look at this green line It goes
up and it comes down It goes up and it comes down you can do this on any stock and
you always see that it goes up comes down It's mean reverting.
So for that reason if it's high,
I want to be I want to be in it when it's high Right now that being said there's
opportunities to get in when it's very low Okay,
it's not always the best but I you Generally like to have some type of implied volatility
knowing that it can come down So we got IV rank above 60 and what IV rank above
60 just means is that if we look at the data over the last two years Okay,
we want to see that. It's above 60% of the time Okay,
if we look at all the data this point will be above 60% of the time.
Okay?
Yes,
I'll show the Volcom And just like So this this blue line here this light blue line,
for example is the 75th percentile meaning it's 75% of the time. Okay,
so if it's above this not this blue line, right?
So if we show right now where it's currently All right.
So what stock we're looking at we're looking at arc. Okay,
right this baby blue line This is where it is 75% of time and right in on this green
line.
It's above that It's probably above 80% of time so it's gonna be in the let's say
80 percentile right the 80 IV rank So let's keep it going here.
So once we have that then we have narrowed it down from 875 stocks to 48 entries
Okay,
the last thing that I want to do is I want to make sure that there's some type of
liquidity Right. There's some type of volume happening here.
And now we are at 16 stocks Right. We've narrowed it down From 873 now,
we're down to 16 And the last thing we could do you don't have to do this is you
can increase the price of the asset Right,
maybe we want to see things that are only above 25 Right.
I think that takes out silver. That's what we'll do 20 only above 20, right?
So here we go. Now.
We're down to only 11 stocks But we've just narrowed it down so much to meet our
criteria Now not all of these 11 stocks are gonna be great stocks So they're gonna
be fundamental reasons why something is like that, but in general,
this is gonna be a good start So then what the last thing I like to do is filter
for IV vs forecast So now we're looking at this stocks with the highest IV versus
the forecast and so Okay Make sure that we're really clear on this.
What we're basically doing is we have this giant. It's like this Right.
We're basically doing is this this is all the assets we could look at We apply our
first filter and now we're only looking at like these ones Right.
None of these ones made it right if these if every like all these circles would
be different stocks None of them made the cut then what we do is we apply another
filter and maybe you know These ones are the only ones that make it Right,
and then we apply another filter and maybe this is our last filter and now we have
just these ones that we're looking at We basically set a bunch of criteria for ourself,
it's actually four circles jacket Thank you,
but you get my point guys we're trying to do here and say there's all these things
out there and we apply more and more and more filters and we end up taking excluding
a bunch from our search leaving this was a small list to look at that meet a Predefined
criteria for us and then we go deeper on them Right.
Those are the ones that we are worth our time to learn more about And it doesn't
mean that those other ones there's no opportunities but at the end of the day you
are a human being you cannot look at 10,000 stocks with 10,000 options.
You need to be able to find something that's gonna work a strategy that you know
You've really thought about and that you can bring to the market.
There's something that actually makes sense so if you guys can if you guys actually
So if someone wants to comment if we could sum up this screener in one word what
I just did here right the screener We've just applied all the filters.
We just applied when one word How would you guys sum it up or in two words or like
a sentence? How would you guys sum it up?
Yes, blessing. So last filter was the IV rank right here,
which we put above 60 Danny said edge. Okay,
it's not actually edge It's not that's not non edge Short vol guys.
Let's think about what is the screener saying? Okay,
Jack is almost everything juice, right?
We are just saying apply this filter Why why would we want to apply this filter
filtering towards our view? Okay Getting there.
We're almost there right what we're really saying here right when we think about
what is happening here Okay, remember the market is efficient most of the time.
Okay,
it's efficient most of the time So and maybe this will help you guys out understand
a little bit more. What do we notice between realized vol and implied vol?
What do we notice about it? Okay, what do we notice when we look at this?
Okay That's the blessing things overpriced not necessarily Okay,
what do we notice about this graph right here? Right implied volatility,
which is what the market's expecting and realized volatility what actually happens?
Okay Okay, some of you guys are going off the deep end now. Okay.
The answer is they move together They move together.
The market's pretty smart volatility clusters volatility is not that hard to predict,
right?
So when we have You know as the realized vol goes up the implied vol goes up as
the realized vol goes down the implied vol goes down So what we just filtered for
if we really think about it,
okay We just filtered for implied volatilities high so uncertainty Okay,
implied vol is a lot higher than our forecast and we want to forecast has historical
vol priced in right?
and so what this is telling us we just made a filter for The market expects something
big to happen That's literally what we just scanned for there is some uncertainty
in the market.
We just built this scanner Okay If we look at all the filters and what we just filtered
for The market is tell all these stocks the market is telling us something is about
to happen Okay,
quick example quick example to show me PSTH Pershing square holdings.
I think it's good about it's gonna buy out a company.
It's like Something big is happening with the stock and the market is saying something
big is gonna happen or something not big hasn't happened It's about to happen,
right?
So now we have this filter where we can come in and say is this overpriced or is
this underpriced?
Right if we if we find out that Pershing square is all retail buyers Well,
we can almost not almost certainly but we can be a very confident in saying There's
probably some Extra unwanted unneeded fault unnecessary vault Pinterest GSX,
right?
These are a lot of these are hype stocks And but the people are telling us something
big is gonna happen right the market's telling us something big is gonna happen
and now we can filter for that and Right.
A lot of the money is made around uncertainty and we're just we just searched for
uncertainty Okay. So anyways, we're gonna take a look at silver.
We're gonna take a look look at silver It's right at the top of our list here And
I'm just gonna you know,
do one quick all the way through so you guys can see arc is also here as well Okay
And there's just some other names for you guys arc G is there as well Okay,
so that's the first thing. Okay.
I hope some of you guys are taking notes along the way I know I know my man margins
taking notes along the way here So silver top of our list,
let's let's go through this one step at a time Stock price trading at 25 average
option volume 333,000 IV vs forecast we can see if we divide 47 by 32 We're gonna
get 140 point four four.
So implied vol is 44 percent higher than our forecast Okay implied vol is 30 90s
for sorry implied vol is 47 47 across realized vol is 25 Our forecast is 32 and
the reason why our direction forecast is 32 is because it incorporates some of this
implied vol in there right because remember it's always good to have implied volatility
into your model because There could be some insider information priced into that
implied vol right which you wouldn't get from historical data Okay,
so it's always good to use implied vol as well.
So busting out a question She's like since RV and IV move together when there's
separation. Is there some sort of implied uncertainty? Yes Right.
What what the market is telling us there is that realized vol is gonna pick up big
time Realize vol is gonna be a big time and it's our job to come in there and say
is it or is it not right?
It's exactly what happened to us in lit All right We said implied vol is gonna come
down when the market was saying realize vol is gonna go up and market was right
And that's gonna happen So IV rank 72 Okay And then skew call put ratio,
you know,
I'm not gonna go through all this but that is that is silver What's looking like
so let's start diving in. So now we have this idea, right?
We have these 11 stocks So now we got to go to work.
Well, what do we notice first off right off the bat, right?
Implied vol and realized vol huge separation.
We're gonna get into this a little more but there's a huge separation So market
obviously is saying realized vol has got to go up, right?
Remember these are these are gonna move together So here's Nick.
Here's another example,
right if we look over here something very similar happened,
but guess what the market was wrong and Implied vol came down rather than realized
vol going up, right? but here's another example where The market was saying,
you know implied vol is gonna be 22 and then realized vol went up to like 41 Okay,
so Sometimes the market's right.
Sometimes you're right or sometimes markets wrong.
So right now we're in a situation where there can be a trade Right.
We just search for uncertainty the market saying the realized vol is gonna go up
but it might not and if it doesn't go up we make a lot of money and Especially knowing
that implied vol is usually overpriced.
It could be that implied vol comes down. Okay?
So let's take a look here guys Okay,
we can see green line right at the 75 mark and You know,
we think this could drop down to let's say it's a medium right 28 29 percent.
Okay, so that is So far so far. We're good.
We're gonna keep it going here We're gonna keep it keep it exciting.
Keep it fun.
Move on to the next stage So we know we can see right now that there is implied
vol is definitely high.
Okay implied volatility is definitely high We can see the through the volcone and
we can see through the implied volatility realized volatility chart And we can also
see that the price is rising to new highs, right?
We're just trying to get ideas Maybe this might be the case Maybe you know We're
always trying to think I was trying to think of new ways that this could possibly
be and we're never ever Gonna get tied to a belief Okay,
sometimes we believe this one thing and we say and we just try to prove that prove
it, right? Okay, that's not how the traders are.
We take a new information we adjust. Okay, so here we go Implied vol pricey.
That's so far. What what our conclusion is if you look at this,
right share price goes up vol goes up So it makes sense that we're seeing an increase
in implied vol when the stocks making new highs Exactly. Okay,
so now Sean always says how do we know what this thing is worth?
How do we know what the hell this thing is worth?
Well right off the bat we think given our forecast right here.
This should be be worth 32% Okay, this should be worth 32% now.
I want to ask you guys a tough question What else can we do to see if this is worth
32%? What else how else can we go and price this thing?
Okay, how else can we go and price this thing?
Okay, I'm gonna give you guys a hint. I'm give you guys a hint here Okay,
we see Sean right strong strong Strong Indian man half Indian man,
right you see that now now how are we gonna know and Someone comes to you and says
hey are all are all Indians strong.
I are all Indian men strong What would you do? Right,
how would you tell if Sean is actually strong or not compared to you know,
everyone else out there?
Maybe maybe everyone else it is way stronger and Sean is actually weak Kyle's saying
ask me Right ask Sean sure Stephen's got it there,
but Stephen's got we're gonna find more info We're gonna go find yeah,
we should go to India and see how everyone else is So what can we do here?
well we need to find other assets that are similar to SLV and now we can really
start pricing this thing in Absolute terms we think SLV is overpriced, right?
We got Divi and Ram here. Yeah, that's three for three There you go,
there you go,
right there you go so implied volatility right now is pricey Relative to our forecast.
Okay, so that's an absolute terms, right?
You see you look at Sean you look at me Sean looking pretty strong Okay,
so good pretty strong, but we need to see more.
We need to see other people who are similar to Sean Right,
maybe maybe Sean's not that strong in his asset class Right,
and so we gotta start getting some work done here.
So what we do is We go and look at what other stocks are they're gonna be so we
have this thing built into the terminals called our watch list okay,
and so What I did was I went on Google I looked up. Okay. Well,
what are similar assets to silver? Okay, and you know,
there weren't really good info,
but right off the bat from what I've known as a trader gold is pretty good Okay,
gold is pretty good. Maybe lithium. It's pretty similar, right?
So what I did was I added Silver, okay. I added gold. I added lithium. Okay.
I added S&P 500. I added real estate I saw some one article.
I'd said real estate's correlated We have to see we're just finding out we have
to find out we don't know right via real estate and We'll go with that. Okay.
So then what else I did I did IV vs forecast IV 60-day I'm trying to get some some
tabs here RV 10 RV 20-day and then I run that okay And what we get here is a correlation
matrix You got to take off this What we get is a correlation matrix and right off
the bat we can see gold and silver are 77% correlated Okay,
it's actually if we look across silver,
we've got 32% with lithium obviously one with silver 27% with S&P and 32% with VNQ
with real estate.
So really only looking at gold here Yeah Gold is a good one to really to really
compare that with right?
So we're looking for correlation like for our example here We're basically trying
to get a better forecast of what realized vol might look like What level of correlation
would be like adequate to at least consider for 75? 75% and above. Okay,
Marcus thing. How about silver miners? So we're Marcos,
you know the ETF for that one 100% because Marcos for example gold in GDX.
So GDX is the gold miners 100% Marcos,
do you have it off the top of your head real quick?
Okay, I'm just gonna throw a gold miners for now I'll look it up.
I don't know if there was one,
but let's see what we got here Marcos with gold miners gold miners 55% correlation
with silver.
I'm sure if the silver miners would be a lot a lot thing But you see you see how
you're thinking of that idea. I say L There we go, okay,
let's see here there it is Marcos boom huge Corley GDX Is it?
Oh slv 68 that's not bad. It's not bad. Okay, so we can still use it.
It's not great But it's not bad. Okay,
but we're thinking right PAS I think that's an actual. Yeah. Yeah,
I think that's an actual stock, but we'll go with it.
Anyways PAS right here So it's not the greatest not the greatest.
So for now we got gold is the highest we're gonna use gold.
Okay Marcos So you can see right here guys We're gonna filter for IV versus our
forecast right and what we basically see is that silver?
Okay is the highest versus the forecast Okay,
it's the highest versus the forecast meaning that if we know that let's say a similar
asset, right?
It should have a similar IV versus forecast but this one has a much higher one right
much higher than gold not much higher but higher than gold I'm much higher than
every other asset, even though you know, they're not perfectly correlated.
Okay? Now this is where the real analysis kicks in. Okay.
So now remember we're still trying to price this thing So we found an asset that's
similar. Okay, it's kind of similar It's very similar.
So we need to go head over to the relative value and we need to start digging deeper
So here I populated silver and I populated gold. Okay,
and I removed the outliers in the data sets When we run it, okay well,
we see that the prices are pretty correlated right you guys can see that right they
move together and here is the rolling correlation if we look at 60-day chunks and
we see that it goes from anywhere between 86 percent and 55 percent. Okay,
so gold and silver are between over the last two years 55 percent correlated and
86 percent correlated Steve's asking why are we removing outliers if there's no
earnings or anything like that? Yeah You know,
it's a really good question Steve It's just because I really like to look at you
know The group the core right what's really happening in the middle in the middle
of the body and not really focusing on the tails too much But you know,
you can definitely play around with that Steve if you want to remove them go for
it Totally up to you.
So next we can see we have this number here. It's called the beta okay,
and this tells us basically if Gold went up 1% How much would silver move if gold
went down 1% how much would silver move and so silver moves? 1.299 times gold.
Okay.
So here's an example if gold went up 2% Silver would go up two times 1.299 and that
would be this blue line right here.
So gold would be up a silver would be up about 2.75% Okay,
we're a little less two point two point six percent Okay,
that's how much silver should be up on average.
And so we have a beta of 1.3 Okay,
if if gold is down 1% then silver is down one point three percent Okay,
so that and you can see the return so each dot is a return a silver day return for
each of them. Exactly Okay, so now we're getting a sense here. Okay.
Well Now we can really start pricing this thing Really really start pricing this
so we know that gold silver should move about 1.3 times gold.
So we come over to So if we go back to our implied vol tab here Okay,
sorry go back to our watch list.
Well if 60-day implied volatility Okay for gold is 19 and a half.
Well silver should be 1.3 times that which is about 26 It's about 26 is trading
at 47 and a half. Okay, that's That's extremely big. Okay,
that's extremely big but we got to keep digging we're not done we're not done yet
Okay, we got to keep digging here.
So we head over to head over to relative value Now we're over here at relative value.
Let me just take all this down. You don't want to ruin the surprise yet Okay,
head over to relative value and we need to see well what's expensive is the 30 days
expensive is the 60 days expensive is The 90 days expensive what what what's expensive
here?
And so what I usually like to do is I put the IV 30-day versus the IV 90-day I'll
take the ratio. I'll take the ratio of that and it looks about even right?
We're Basically at the mean here.
There may be a little bit cheap But we're basically, you know,
we're really at the mean here.
So let's let's try to maybe IV 30 or IV 90 IV 60 You know more us.
Yeah more or less the same thing, right? So now it's a question of okay well,
what do I want exposure to realize vol or implied vol and You know in this case,
I'm just gonna go with the IV 60-day Blend of both. Yeah, it's a blend of both,
you know, you can do the 45s I think you know,
I think that's a pretty good pretty good Place to be at so we're gonna go with the
IV 60 days So what we're gonna do is we're gonna compare IV 60-day versus its realized
volatility Okay, it's the first thing we're gonna do. So look at this guys.
We're at all-time highs We're at all-time highs of implied vol versus the realized
volatility Okay Pretty expensive, but let's go and plot gold against that.
So in absolute terms This looks pretty expensive The absolute terms is actually
extremely expensive. Let's go and plot Gold IV 60-day versus RV 20-day.
Okay, and you guys are gonna notice something pretty cool.
Okay We notice it's actually maybe not that expensive Take a look. Okay,
take a look here.
The blue is silver Okay implied vol over realized vol and the green line is gold
implied vol over realized vol and what we see is Okay They're pretty much matched
right now. Well, they pretty much match up in general right now.
It's a bit pricey Okay, silver is a bit pricey,
but it might not be as pricey as we thought it was in the first round Okay,
so it's still pricey. Don't don't get me wrong. We're still up here, right?
We're still at the top of the range here Still pricey,
but it might not be a no-brainer if we saw let's say gold down here at 1.45 and
this was at 1.85. Well,
maybe this looks like a little bit of a no-brainer But you know,
it might be expensive for a reason.
So Danny saying they're still moving together. Yep. So, you know,
this is basically We're pricing the implied vol of gold Versus realized vol which
is the green line here Okay,
so this is the implied vol versus the realized vol for gold and then this is the
implied vol Realized vol for silver and they should move together Right.
Here's an example There's gonna be a big there's gonna be a big inflation period.
Let's say okay or someone's about to win the election and one one of the members
you know is if they get in they get If they get in charge,
they're going to you know,
increase inflation like crazy They're gonna print money like crazy and then so,
you know And on the other side the other party is gonna do the opposite.
So you got a lot of uncertainty and let's say in metals And so you're gonna see
that uncertainty in gold and you're gonna see that uncertainty in silver,
right?
So these vols should move together and they're implied to realize vols should move
together as well Right, but when they diverge You might say okay. Well,
this one's a little pricey Right.
This one's getting a little pricey relative to the rest of the assets that are similar
to it, right? So So Eric's asking, you know,
it's more so we're saying is it more inclined for RV to come up versus IV coming
down? So it doesn't necessarily right,
we're just saying it's like It's not like we're seeing low IV everywhere and like
this one's caught a bid for some reason and it's like wow These things move relative
to one another and this one never caught a bid but this one caught a bid What we're
saying is they all caught a bid. Maybe there's something happening.
You know what I mean? Right, and so, you know for that reason something,
you know, it might be overpriced.
It might not be underpriced It's our job as a trader to figure this one out.
Mm-hmm Right,
it's not as clear-cut as it initially appeared when we just had this one plotted
right? We look here or the blue one Oh, yeah, so I have the gold there.
Yeah when we have SLV plotted like this looks like a no-brainer, right?
Let's draw a nice little line here Yeah,
look at this Right looks like a no-brainer But then we look at it relative to gold
and we're like, oh wait Maybe maybe there's a reason right?
Maybe it's not just a no-brainer because golds also golds implied to realize it's
also pricey So something is gonna happen.
It looks like in the metal space Right some some some there's gonna be some event
coming up which could be tomorrow's event But there's gonna be something coming
up that's gonna cause realize vault to increase But then if we look at it,
let's go back to something quick if we look at the term structure for it,
though It's pretty flat. It's just flat across the top strange. Good point,
right? So so now here's another level of our analysis.
Maybe there's no event Because When you see an event, right?
If we go to let's say and you and you right and you has earnings coming up in two
days We look at the term structure Look at this the implied vols way up here and
then it drops it lets us know there's an event here or let's look at one that has
an event like a little bit further out like BA has one in like a month.
Nothing really pricing. We'll try Tesla and that's it.
If you look at Tesla I think there's come up to but right check this out.
We can see that the implied volatility Increases up to 60 days and we have this
event here,
right somewhere in here We have like they're implying a lot of volatility,
but when we go back to SLV We can't seem to isolate any single event.
Like there's no time day that there or you know Timeframe where they're saying there's
an event.
They're just saying vol is gonna be high and you guys can see like We look at realized
all here implied vault across the board is very pricey relative to how much this
thing actually moves So let's get the check. Okay,
so Marco's saying can you check out copper? Marco's ETF real quick for that.
Yeah,
you can send the ticker So here we are relative value now We also just quickly I
was just thinking about we're going through this For the guys that are coming into
the morning lives if you want us to do more stuff like this We can do breakdowns
like this on the morning lives.
I would just need some of your help I just get the tickers quick.
So I'm not spending the whole time trying to find something to compare it to Okay
So even if we if we price implied volatility 60 for silver and implied volatility
60 for gold We do a division of that right to see what is implied vol relative to
gold pricey The answer is not really a little bit. Yeah, sure. It's pricey.
Sure. It's in the pricey range, but it's not like what wild Yeah, right.
So we're digging deeper into this thing and So far conclusion is silver is expensive
fall is expensive. No doubt about it, right? Especially in absolute terms,
but how expensive it doesn't look like it's a crazy expensive.
It just looks overpriced Okay,
so we can't go in with huge size and that's incorporating into our Into our the
amount we're gonna trade here. Okay.
So Marcos is saying we got a couple right here.
Thank you Marcos and Ram as well Let's go back to the Into this super quick guys.
We might not have all of them, but we'll give it a shot here.
Okay, no JJ Cop X. Are you sure? That's the one?
No,
we don't have the Marcos tell me now just like copper this they're too cheap Don't
have those you are a let's see No, okay soon soon soon soon.
Yeah guys ticker soon. Don't worry. Yeah. Yeah Okay.
So now we know that this thing is a little bit pricey And we come to the conclusion.
Okay, then we got to see. Okay. Well what's happening here, right?
you know when you go on the news and We can go do something like silver seeking
Alpha, okay,
and right off the bat we got a article here December 9th and Here we can read this
article from this guy. Okay, and he's gonna be you know, a pretty good article,
right? We can read this we can get a lot of insight what's going on here.
What's going to do this guy's head, right?
You know sure using technical technical analysis,
but he's trading silver like a lot of these guys at seeking Alpha They actually
trade their product. Okay Here we go. Best silver mining stock.
Let's read this thing.
Let's really get inside of the hedge Who's buying this stuff?
I'm gonna sell it wonder who's buying this.
So we start reading the stuff and You know,
we can even go on stock twits and see what the hell's going on here and Like look
at this guys. We don't even see crazy. Hype. We're not even seeing crazy.
Hype on this stock, right?
So right off the bat originally super bullish super bullish,
but the message volumes not through the roof.
It's like average So right off the bat we went from like this is a no-brainer trade.
We're digging deeper. We're digging deeper And now it's just a mediocre trade,
right? But at the end of the day,
we usually have to have a position on We usually should at least maybe I shouldn't
say that. So I have some capital deployed.
We should have some capital deployed And it's not like this is a bad trade,
right?
So if it happens to be the best trade you maybe slap some on right and you guys
always remember There's not always a good trade right the market for the most part
is efficient. You have to always remember that There's not always a trade.
Mm-hmm Open up thinkorswim and now so we let's say we decide okay silver is pricey
Right, I think all those can come to the conclusion.
That is a little pricey This is we want to trade it.
I can't go on stock puts on the lives. Really? My computer explodes Okay,
if Lynn had paid off I was gonna buy a new computer And guys for homework do this
on arc do the same analysis.
We'll upload live right after this mark I hope you're on live will upload it right
after Do the same analysis as homework on arc and I want you guys to come to your
own conclusion Also share it in the group.
Yeah share in the group and make sure Make sure you look at the amount the sentiment
analysis. Okay,
make sure you look at what is happening What are people saying about this seeking
alpha stock puts read the news really try to understand who the hell is my customer?
Right. That's probably what 99% of traders don't do and you know,
they just think it's breaking out.
I'm gonna buy Right choose your customer here really think about it.
All right. So here we go February 26 46 days out. I like it. We're gonna go.
Let's say We want to be short Vega. Okay. So in this case scenario,
I'm probably gonna because silver isn't gonna have buyout potential It's not gonna
have bankruptcy potential.
I I would prefer to go naked on this And just have a really good stop-loss here.
So in this case, let's say I'm doing the Delta 40 strangle.
Okay These are like my Delta 40 strangles. Here we go 24 50 27 Okay,
so here we are.
Okay,
here's the trade now We look at my risk if I just showed Sean my risk and said we're
short 70 Vega long 36 Theta short 176 gamma and long basically zero Delta 20 Deltas
or short 20 Deltas Sean would say I Would say why I got so much gamma It's a short
fall Right.
We're definitely short convexity here and we short volatility not good one Grady
And so now the next step would be okay, well if we're right Okay,
if we're right in this scenario, what should happen? Okay. Well,
we can use kind of the gold reference to see Okay. Well, where should this go?
Right?
So let's um So you
have to get a sense of okay, well,
where should this be priced at right and We can use a couple things here.
One thing we can use is the volatility Volcom where's implied ball gonna go after
the event after those things all over right and we could see well the 60-day It's
probably gonna come below the 75, right? It's probably gonna come,
you know in somewhere between 27 and 42 Okay,
that's our first that's our first area of looking at right between somewhere between
27 and 42 and we can look at gold Right and look at the relationship between gold
and silver right Or sorry realize volume implied ball, right?
So we can look at gold right and look at the relationship between Okay, well,
you know, it's probably gonna meet in the middle somewhere, right?
So 47 plus 25 is 75 let's call it 65 divided by 2. Oh, sorry. Yes. Yeah. Yeah,
let's call it 35 and a half Okay, 735 and a half.
So there's if these were to meet in the middle, right?
We're gonna get somewhere 35 35 looks like it's inside our range here No,
this is probably a good place to start right if we're right ball is probably gonna
come down from 47 to 35 Okay, so Let's head back over to think or swim.
And of course guys you can do more analysis here You know getting more stocks in
your analysis to try to price this thing.
You'll get a better sense of okay What's gonna happen here, right?
Example for our lit I was we were pretty certain that vol is gonna drop down to
40 or sorry 35, right?
So The more data you get the more the more work you put into it the better analysis
you can do So here we are.
So if we're right vol should drop to 35 to 12 points Do 10 points more like you'd
be 37. Okay 10 points. So here we go. Okay, so this is where You know,
this is where we should this is what our profit should look like if we're right
now Every good trader doesn't just think about if one of their right they always
think about when they're wrong Okay, so if we look back here Okay,
if we're wrong, I we could probably see because you know,
we could probably could potentially see you know Back to these levels here.
Let's say 65, but we also want to say well, when are we wrong?
when are we gonna get out of the position and in in this case scenario,
I would get out when implied vol and realized vol connect right or Collapse that
implied versus realized collapses. And so, you know,
we only have 10 minutes here We're not gonna go too deep into it.
But let's say we get out at around 50% implied volatility. Okay,
that's more wrong.
That's when we're out of the position And we're going to move on just like what
happened with lit right?
We sold it at 45 all it's not really a 48 vol and We're wrong you're wrong we got
out so let's price down here plus 3% 5% and
Let's say we stress it to a 10% move on either side So now we can see relatively,
you know an idea We certainly can start getting an idea of where our risk is right
how much we're gonna lose if we're wrong So in this position,
we're probably gonna lose about 800 bucks All right. So now we say okay. Well,
here we go. We have a structure.
We understand our risks we know what we're gonna be wrong,
we know when we're gonna be right and Now let's throw it.
Let's slap it on Right,
and let's see what happens and let's re-evaluate every single day or every single
minute when new information comes in It's asking so, how do we get out?
We would actually just straight-up close the position Yes,
right We're not really a big fan of you know Trying to band-aid positions trying
to save positions trying to get back some of the money We make the best trades we
can When we're right, we're right when we're wrong,
we're wrong and we just own it and find the next trade I would even say we're actually
anti band-aiding Yeah bandaging bandaging. We're anti bandaging. Okay,
if you're wrong You get out of the position Okay,
and that's gonna make you guys much much better traders. Okay,
you know And we would close the whole position As a rule of thumb you'd close the
whole position. Yes, not just one leg.
We wouldn't close a losing leg We're gonna roll one of the legs out We're wrong,
right and that's a tough thing that we have to take it on as traders and you know
a lot of time people say we'll get into this position and then you know roll one
leg to Roll the defending leg or the attacking leg, whatever it is.
You're just trying to keep this position alive.
That's not going good for you Are you trying to get back now in hope in hope mode
I don't want to be in that mode and sometimes it does pay off, right?
Yeah sometimes it doesn't but your capital is being tied up to something that usually
usually and I know you guys can some of you can really Really feel with this one
is that you put on a trade it goes against you You bandage it up and then as soon
as it becomes break-even you get out of the position, right?
That's not that's not that's not what trading is We have an idea we take advantage
of the idea we place a trade and if we're wrong, that's okay, right?
The market's smart and that's really okay guys But in the long run we have to become
we have to come out winners And all that means is we're gonna be writing more often,
right?
Especially if we're short of all we're gonna be right more often right and our winners
our losers are not gonna cripple us We're not gonna bandage bandage bandage,
you know, next thing, you know,
the room's still open We get crushed we get a scrape we throw some Throw some ointment
on it. We get back out there.
You pour a bit of our whiskey on it And we we keep going we get back out there.
Okay,
so I hope Hope you guys found that walkthrough insightful 50 minutes on one trade
not bad. It's on one trade. I want you guys to do this analysis on art Yeah,
everyone give it a shot. Thanks, Jekka.
Let's talk about it in the traders chat I'm gonna I'm hoping to see the answers
rolling in or the analysis rolling in by 10 p.m So,
let's see what we can do here and Jordan. I'll be around to chat about them,
too I'll be doing lots of code though. Yeah, Jordan actually won't be there.
I'll be there though. Okay.