All right, guys, so in this live,
we're going to be talking about how to value vol in this type of environment.
And when I say this type of environment,
I'm talking about a not as high vol environment as what we were just in. Okay,
so for example, VIX at 16 seems low, but if you look at the VIX over the last,
let's say, five years, it's extremely high.
It's just because in the last one year, we've had VIX 25.
And so it's like we're coming off the freeway. And all of a sudden,
we feel like we're going extremely fast, or no,
we feel like we're going really slow,
even though we're actually going extremely fast. Okay,
so that's what it kind of feels like. And this live,
I just wanted to basically talk about how do we price vol? How do we say,
you know, is volatility still expensive? Is it still cheap?
And we can go from there. It's funny, Jordan, remember,
so my birthday was a couple weeks ago, and I rented out like a, like a Mustang,
just to rip around. And I got it up to pretty good speeds,
having a great time with it. And then exactly said, like, you know,
I was back in like the neighborhood and I was going slow,
or it felt like I was going slow, but I was going like 60 or 70.
You know what I mean? And I literally felt like I was crawling,
but I'm still driving at a speed where like, if I crashed, I might die.
You know what I mean? But it felt like I was crawling,
like the car wasn't neutral. Right.
And that's sort of what you're alluding to is how the vol environment currently
feels, where there is still implied vol, there's still realized vol,
but it's not, it's not, we're not in a, in pandemic territory anymore. Exactly.
I saw someone on Twitter say like, VIX seems like value right now,
but in actual fact, it's like a GME, you know, went from $4 to $350.
And now that it's at $200 or $150, it seems like value,
but in the grand scheme of things, it's still not. So I think that's, you know,
a lot of people, they thought the VIX floor was at 20 and we just saw it just,
you know, capitulate and implode and go down to 15.
So why don't we chat about it? And, you know, even some of the PA guys here,
members are going to be getting tripped up because things like the volcon,
right? Everything on the volcon right now is under the median,
but that's because of the look back window that that median is taking into consideration
is what is it? Is it 18 months, Jordan? Yes. 18, right? Right.
So it's a 18 month look back. And of those 18 months, 15 of them are, you know,
chaos, right?
So this live will help you navigate the current landscape a lot better.
That's the goal. So make sure you ask questions along the way.
I'll be monitoring the chat, Jordan. Yep. Let's get into it. Okay.
Let me just pull this here. One second. All right.
Let me share my screen.
And guys ask questions along the way. All right. Very important. Yeah.
I'll keep my eye on the chat here, Jordan. Don't worry.
Right. Everyone can see my screen.
So right now I'm just looking at the S&P and what we notice, right?
Let me just take off the max here is the vols are at the lows, right?
And we're not just seeing this with the S&P.
So when we're looking at the volatility cone, let me just,
I'm going to take out a couple here. I'm going to take out the median.
Actually I'll take out the first quantile and the third quantile there.
So what we're seeing here is that vols are at the lows, right?
16 months ago or 14 months ago, COVID started or, you know,
vols started picking up. And so we're almost at just, you know,
just before the COVID lows. And a lot of people are saying, Hey, this is value.
This is looking like value. And we're seeing this across the board, right?
Every single equity, we saw Pfizer back down to pre COVID lows, right?
In terms of vol. And it's,
it seems like it's getting harder and harder to find short vol opportunities.
Yet we're seeing the VIX go from 20 to 15, right?
And this should go much lower, right?
VIX should all the way back down to remember those days when it was nine,
right? Not saying it's going there anytime soon,
but it could be making its way back down there.
And so even though we're looking at 15 VIX, it actually may not be real value.
And so a good way to compare if something is over or under priced,
we need something to compare it to. And as you guys know, we don't, we don't,
I don't think we've ever talked about macro vol. Do we talk about that, Sean?
Three circles, man. That's it. Yeah. Right.
It's we don't talk about what the S&P is doing tomorrow.
And the reason we don't do that is because it's too competitive, right? It's,
it's too many players are trying to play this game.
And I'm not too sure why I would want to participate in this, right?
Which is way too, it's way too sophisticated. There's so many parts happening.
There's so many good players happening, you know, trading in that space.
I don't know why I would want to want to be in there. So breaking the alpha,
you're rarely going to hear me saying, hey,
I'm selling as an offset of something, but it's never going to be my alpha leg.
I'm never going to be taking a view just strictly on S&P vol. Rarely,
very rare. But what the S&P does do is it serves as a benchmark.
S&P vol is extremely, extremely efficient. It's the most liquid market.
It's got the biggest players. It's got the most eyes. Okay.
It is going to be priced the most efficiently.
And so the way that we use it is a benchmark, right? Where is this?
Where is volatility right now? What, what is fair value?
And then we go out and we say, okay, well, this is fair value. What's this at?
Is this cheap or expensive given we know this?
And so that's what we're going to be talking about today is using the S&P,
NASDAQ vol can be used the same as a benchmark, as the fair value, right?
And then you trade the inefficiencies that are happening around it.
So how do we do that? How do we do that? Well, we know that basically,
Ivy rank is low for everything right now. So we can't just go, you know,
if we're using that as our signal,
we're always going to be long vol over the next year, right?
And that could be devastating. So we need another way to figure this out.
So I'm going to go over to relative value tab here and for the relative value tab.
Okay. There we go. For relative value tab,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to plot S&P vol, my apologies.
I realized that there's some few tiny bugs on this,
but I think we're going to be good here.
Okay.
So we're going to plot the S&P and what I'm plotting is the implied volatility 30
day over divided by the realized volatility 30 day.
And that the divide by is coming from the ratio here.
And so what we can see is that right now,
implied volatility is 1.3 times the realized vol. Okay.
We can see the realized vol right here, right?
Realized vols at 10 and implied vol right now is 1.3 times the realized vol.
So this is going to be our benchmark. Okay.
We know that implied vol and realized vol are correlated. Okay. We know that.
So instead of what we need to do is say, okay, well,
this asset is trading at 1.3 times the realized vol. Now,
anything that's trading above that should be expensive.
Anything trading below that should be cheap. So to do that,
I'm going to plot Apple.
For some reason, you have to run this twice.
I don't know what the deal is here, but so what do we know?
So let's focus on this graph right here. Okay. We have two graphs.
I'm going to go step-by-step very slow.
So we'd make sure we all understand this. We have two graphs here.
One graph in green is Apple's implied vol 30 divided by Apple's realized vol 30.
In blue is the S&P vol 30 divided by the realized vol 30.
And what we see here, okay, is that they move together, right?
They usually don't get too far out of line.
And so this is what we can use to compare the rest of the assets, right?
Implied vol right now,
it should be about 1.3 to 1.4 times the realized volatility. All right.
And when we see something that's way out of line,
that could be a good indication if something's cheap or expensive.
So I'm going to do, I'm going to do,
so does anyone have any questions about that before I continue?
I'm not seeing any. Okay. You guys, sure. We're using, we're saying, okay,
what is the implied vol of this asset over realized vol?
Because that's how we have to compare it, right? Sure. Implied vol is cheap,
but realized vol is even less. So we can, we need, we, you know,
we can't say S&P VIX should be, let's say 20 or 30, right?
We can't say that because it's only realizing 10, right? That's, that's,
you know, everyone would be a seller at 20 VIX.
Everyone would be a seller at 25 VIX, right? And so it's going to come down.
We need to compare it to what's happening right now, which is the realized vol.
And so that, like that is our benchmark. Okay. 1.3,
that's the efficient benchmark. Implied vol should be 1.3 times realized vol.
Okay.
So I was talking to Margin. I don't know if he's on the call.
No margin. Okay. Talking to Margin about SMBR. And we were just looking,
you know, he was looking for earnings trade today and he said, look,
implied vols, there's no way implied volatility is going to go down to 49.
This is the lows he said, right? 49 is the lows.
There's no way the day after the event, it's going down to 49.
So maybe it's going to go to 55, right? But let's take a look at S&P.
Okay. The S&P, unfortunately, like these are the lows here, 16.
The S&P has dropped below that, right? It's now 14. It was 13, right?
So it can go lower and it will go lower. And the way we need to, you know,
figure out, well, how much, how much lower is it going to go? Right.
We need that comparison.
We need to take a guess, right? Well,
what does implied vol going to go to after the event?
And does anyone have an idea of how we would compare this? Does anyone,
does anyone have an idea on how we would figure out where this is going to go given
what we just noticed?
Does anyone want to take a guess? Last earnings. Last earnings. Okay.
So you think it's going to go down to 57 currently trading at 68.
You think it's going to go down to 57. What do you guys think?
Where's implied vol going to go after the event?
You're saying, can't you just run the same ratio of IB to RV? Thank you.
Who said that one? Adam. Adam. Thank you. So let's take a look at RV. Okay.
Okay. We're going to go over to the, uh, to relative value.
Um,
and I gotta, I gotta figure out why I have to run this twice to get it.
It's very strange.
Hmm. You know what guys? Eric's saying change your top left ticker. Ah,
that's why. That's it. Thank you.
There we go. Thank you.
Uh, so we should see a 1.3 times after the event. And now, um,
so something else to keep in mind here, guys is for SNBR. Um,
I don't know why I have these on here.
Okay. Uh, for SNBR, uh,
I know realized right now for the last 30 days of 64 in the last 10 days,
it's only been 30. Okay. In the last 10 days, there was some, uh,
some ball to that happened here recently. Um, and that's, that's going to be,
you know,
a little bit of a nuance and single names because you could have like one day of
a big event. Right. And that changes the whole vault, the realized volatility.
So you gotta be very mindful of that. Um, for these, uh,
for these single names, which is different than in the index. So if we had to,
if we knew, let's say realized volatility was at 30. Okay.
We would say that implied vault should be 30 times 1.3 or 40. Right.
And that's what, you know, that's what I would be guessing. Um,
I think actually realized vol is like 35, uh,
the last 10 days I was looking up on, uh, uh, on my, on my data feed. Um,
so in this case, right, we see realized vols at 64. Uh, we would say, okay,
64 times 1.3 should be the implied vault. However,
realized vault last 10 days has been very, very low.
We could actually see that in the volatility analyzer here. Uh,
here's the realized vol, right. It's been, it's basically nothing. Oh, here,
right.
Realized vol realized vol is at 41. Okay.
Realized vol the last 10 days is at 41. And so 41 times 1.3,
it's going to give us something like 50 vol. Okay. 53 vol.
And so that's what we think, uh,
the implied volatility is going to come to after the event, but, you know,
looking at, looking at the, um, you know, if we don't look at it like that,
right. Well, implied vol doesn't seem so high.
It doesn't seem too high right now. Right.
And how are we going to sell an earnings event when implied vol is not even in the
third quantile. And the reason for that is because, um, we're coming off,
you know, extreme volatility. Do you guys have any questions about that?
We just turn on the light here. One second, guys. I guess it's getting dark,
starting to look shadow of vol again. Exactly.
So Ram just wants you to confirm, uh, how you got 1.3. I used the S&P vol.
And the actual fact is,
so when you guys get more skilled and you get better and better at this,
you do this over and over.
Um, 1.3 is going to be high.
1.3 is going to be high because does anyone know why that 1.3 is going to be high?
So 1.3 is what S&P is. S&P implied vol to realize vol.
Why is 1.3 going to be high?
Eric's saying because the market overstates vol. Exactly. Right.
The S&P it's well-known and well-documented that index vol, uh, is, is,
has a lot higher risk premia than single name vol. A lot higher risk premia.
So you're, it's going to overstate slightly more than, um,
a single name equity.
So we might have 1.25 and we're going to look at similar ones.
We're gonna look at similar companies, right? Um, we're going to, you know,
try to find, we're going to do as much research.
And we did a relative value on the other day where we did DISCA.
We talked about, uh, you know, relative value, um, and, and valuing assets.
You're going to have to spend some time and value the vol.
Okay. And the way we use it is S&P is benchmark. Get S&P, try to get,
get a basket of stocks that is similar to the one you're looking at,
see what they're doing. And then, you know, rank them, right?
You can rank them in the scanner here, right? IV versus forecast, right?
Or whatever you're looking for. Red's asking is realized volatility, uh,
being used interchangeably with historical volatility here? Yeah, same thing.
Just what happened in the past. And then Crawford's asking,
would the stocks beta be a consideration? Yes. I think that's very good. Right.
So who said that one Crawford, man, our new members really, uh, stepping it up.
Yeah, really stepping it up. No pressure, no pressure. Uh, old members,
no pressure, all members. You guys suck.
Uh, just kidding guys. Just kidding. Um, yes, Crawford. So you could use,
you know, uh, you can use the correlation here to, to figure that out. Right.
But the issue is sometimes, um,
uh,
sometimes the stock is not going to have a high beta to the S&P because it's not
correlated. Right. And if it's, if it's not correlated, um, then it's,
you know, if the beta is not really going to matter here, we're going to put,
uh, we're going to put S&P on the Y on the X axis instead.
Right. So it's like, because there's no real correlation between, uh,
the sleep stock and S the S&P it's not really going to, uh,
the beta is not really going to matter here.
Okay. So I gotta fix something here, but anyways, um,
if the stock is going to be correlated, let's say Microsoft Apple, then yes,
you'd want to use a beta, right. To also get that, you know,
how correlated is this thing? Uh,
and then you would multiply the beta times the vol. So the vol,
let's say the beta was two and S&P vol was 30, then fair value would be 60.
And you can see here, like the rolling correlation between the two, you know,
it's, uh, it's 17%. Like it's nothing, you know,
it's definitely not high correlation.
So you can't, you wouldn't, you wouldn't use the S&P beta here.
The other questions. Nope. That's it for now. We'll keep it moving. Okay. So,
well, I mean, that that's, that's really it, right? Like I, right guys,
we're coming in, we're,
we're in a new environment now and we can't be just looking at IV rank, right.
We need to be able to find another way to value this.
So let's, uh, let's talk about this then Jordan. Uh,
is this the same methodology you would apply when looking at like a, uh, uh,
a play on realized volatility versus implied volatility and on a current implied
vol versus future implied vol level, would you use the same thing?
So short dated options, long dated options. Yeah. Yeah. You can,
in the relative value tab, you can do, um,
because it's still correlated at the 90 day, uh, on, on 90 tenors.
So instead of IV30, you would maybe do IV90 day, right? You're just,
you're trying to value this thing as much as possible. Um,
but one thing that you shouldn't be doing, and I honestly would say it's a,
it would be a naive way to think about it is because is if, because VIX is low,
that means it should go back up, right? That's almost never the case. Um,
the best time to sell vol is when vol is low, right? That's,
that's the same people. You say best time to sell vol is when it's high,
best time to sell vol in terms of implied versus realized.
So shorter dated options,
let's say 30 day options and less is going to be when the VIX is low and the vol
is low. And it can just keep bleeding out.
Exactly. Right. And like, if you think about it conceptually,
it kind of makes sense why that's the case. Um, you know, when, when,
when things are stable, you know, it's, uh, you know, easier to price things.
Uh, you know, it's risk premiums more clear when things are wild, you know,
it's pretty easy to miss the mark.
So the easiest way to think about it is the market has that, uh,
an embedded risk premium that it's easier to collect when in low realized vol environments
than in high realized vol environments,
because the things is so hard to price because it's moving so much.
And people are also more likely to buy vol when things are low,
when vol is low. True. Right. Which is going to get,
which is always going to give that embedded risk premium.
Why? Uh, so, um, let's see, uh, Adam's asking,
could you compare the IVE ratio of a specific stock during a previous period to
the ratio of spy at that time? IVR.
I'm assuming IVR of a stock previously to a stock. No. Yeah. A hundred percent.
Right. Uh, well, let's look at Apple.
You don't have the ratio clicks for a spy, but,
or you don't have spy on at all. I thought you, okay.
You don't need to do anything. Yeah. I didn't. I didn't. Sorry. Okay.
I got a song. Someone's a little buggy here. I got to fix it. But anyways,
you can take a look here, right? Like Apple and spy have all,
you can see that the market is actually using this factor, right?
If the market wasn't using this factor, these things wouldn't be correlated.
So you can see like market makers and other traders use this as one metric.
Right. And that's why you see them in the RV, the IVR V they move together. Um,
um, I guess does that answer your question? Uh, Adam,
I think you just said like, you wanted me to plot it, right?
You meant for something like SNBR, if it isn't that correlated to spy,
can you do that? Yes. Yes.
You can still do that because you were looking at the, uh,
at the risk premium that the pricing in relative to what's actually happening right
now. So our corn is asking, uh,
why do this versus the non-event term structure, non-event vol term structure.
So I guess for, uh, for your SN DL trade or whichever company you're in,
right.
So in this case, um, we were, we were chatting about it. Let's go to SMBR.
You basically also think non-event vol is expensive,
right? So yeah, exactly. Right. So, um, let me just get rid of this.
Okay. So when we look at this, a quarter mile, we see, okay, well front month,
first off there's, there wasn't a lot of data points with SMBR. It was,
it was a monthly contract. Um, and so what we can see here is like, okay,
well sure. Implied vault, you know,
30 days is going to be 68 and non-event falls going to be 60,
but look at the realized vol, right.
It was high, just like the whole market. If I plotted the S and P 500,
30 day vol is high across the board, but over the last 20 days or last 10,
15 days, we've seen vol completely drop off across the, across all assets.
Vol has shrunk. And what do we know about volatility? It clusters, right?
That's probably one of the,
that's probably the strongest factor is that it clusters before being reversion.
Um, and so when, when we're seeing, when we're seeing vol at this low level,
you know, at these levels here, uh, and we're seeing non-event vol at 60,
it's going to be hard for it to stay up here, right?
One of two things are going to happen, right? Like, well, like,
what do we notice about this relative value graph, right? What, like, what,
what do we notice about this thing? When we divide IV by RV, it mean reverts,
right? And that's a pretty common factor. It's a pretty strong factor.
So if we're all the way up here, right. On IV versus, let's say 60, um, uh,
on IV versus RV, right.
If we're all the way up here and it's actually a lot higher right now that we're
looking at the 30 day. If this was the, uh, if this was like,
let's say a 10 day, right. This would be extremely, extremely high. And so,
you know, one of two things are going to happen.
Implied vol is going to increase or, uh, sorry,
implied vol is going to decrease or realize vol is going to increase.
So we need to make that decision. And, um, in my opinion, uh,
usually implied vol is the one that eventually matches with realized vol.
It's usually a lot less stable.
Cool. Um, let's see. How about if the asset is not in the SMP?
What if it's in something like IWN? Do you use that instead? Yeah,
you can do that instead. As long as the, what you're using is efficient, right?
You're trying to, you're trying to benchmark it to something.
You're trying to say, Hey, look, this is, this is fair value, right?
This is what I think fair value is given this.
And so the thing you're using is not efficient. You know, it's,
it's going to be tough, right? I remember when we were,
we were doing the oil trade. Uh,
I can't remember how long ago this was maybe like 18 months ago or two years ago.
And there was a big, uh,
a whole bunch of oil companies where vols were just through the roof and I had to
compare it to something that was liquid.
And I said, okay, well, given USO vol, what should the, what should the,
you know, similar assets be worth? And then, you know,
you try to find relative value trades or just one leg and trade that.
We have a comment from, uh, our buddy, Mike, I hear he says,
when markets are calm, you collect your VRP. When markets are volatile,
you pay out. It's like insurance.
Yeah. It's, uh, you know,
there's a few guys have done lots of studies on this and it's, uh,
there's a lot of people who've done a lot of studies on this, um,
selling vol during low vol environments pays out the most.
Then when you sell high vol environments,
but the thing is we were rarely selling S and P vol, you know, the,
some of the smartest guys, I know trade S and P vol.
I don't know why I'd want to participate there. I just use them as a benchmark.
I say, okay, you guys do your job. You guys are good at your job.
You price this as efficiently as possible. And I'll,
I'm going to use this as my benchmark, or if I need liquidity, I will,
I'll use this because it's very liquid,
but I wouldn't try to outprice them for sure. Yeah. You know, I hope, uh,
I hope you guys have some good ideas, uh, uh, flow flowing,
flowing through your minds right now. Cause you know, there's a,
I feel like this, this is a really good library and opened up a lot of, uh,
a lot of potential. Nice. And we'll see, we'll see guys, SMBR,
or we're going to see what vol goes to tomorrow.
Remember it's hard for someone to sell vaults to keep vol at 60 when it's only realizing
40. Right. It's very hard. Eventually, uh, eventually it's going to go back.
So any other questions there? Or we'll, we'll, we'll wrap it up.
I think you put everyone to sleep. Yeah, I normally, I normally do that.
I got started doing a strip tease or something mid, mid, uh, mid-session. Uh,
yeah, that'll, that'll definitely wake people up.
I'll definitely make people up.
Right. But read the, uh, the risk,
the risk characteristics are exactly the same, right? You're short vol,
you're short gamma, you're long theta, whether it's a strangle,
whether it's a straddle, the risk profile is not going to be that different.
Right. How could it be?
Okay. I'm going to stop the recording there, Jordan.