Okay, guys, so in this live,
we are going to be going over calendar spreads in depth. How to use them,
why they work, but not just why they work. Also,
we're going to talk about time, how volatility moves through time, right?
This is a gold topic. It's a very advanced topic, but it's crucial.
For a lot of you, it's the final piece to the puzzle. Okay. Now,
before we get started,
the reason why we're doing a gold topic tonight is we actually have our first two
gold members tonight. And they are, so it's Jeka, oh my gosh, LOL, it's Jay,
and Ned, otherwise known as Bingo.
I want to give a huge congratulations to them. They did fantastic on the test.
The work ethic that we've seen from these guys in the last two weeks,
in the last month, it's just been through the roof. For those of you,
if you go look at any point during the trader chat,
you'll see Ned and Jeka just grinding away.
They're doing some really advanced stuff in R.
They're really trying to dig down the material.
I went over their trade journals. They've done some very in-depth trades,
all the way from risk reversals to relative value,
all the way to the opposite side of the chain,
doing straight up iron condor shortfall. The amount of effort,
if you guys saw their trade journal, it just blew me away.
I'm just so happy for these guys. They crushed. They grinded.
They grinded so hard. And I also want to say,
this is actually really exciting as well, so Ned is very new with us, but Jeka,
his P&L, real money has been, it's just, it's speechless. I'm just so,
so excited for these guys to see what's going to happen with them in just a year.
They've learned so much already in a month, two months,
and I just can't wait to see what happens going a year forward. Wow. Yeah.
So reach out to them, guys. They're very knowledgeable. They're young bucks,
22? Yeah. 22. They're young bucks. 21, man. Yeah. So reach out to them,
and they're definitely on their way to making it in this game. Okay.
So with that said, guys,
we're going to jump right into the live and get going on calendar spreads and how
these work.
So the way we're going to start this live off first is I want to ask you guys a
question. What do we use calendars for? If I had to ask you guys,
what would you use a calendar for?
What risk exposures are we expressing or do we have on when we have a calendar spread?
What do you guys think?
So you put on a calendar spread, and the calendar spread,
for those of you that don't know,
we're selling an expiration and buying a different expiration. Okay? Okay.
So Ned's saying we're long vega, and Anne and Alan are saying time. Okay?
Okay. So. Okay. We're saying decreasing in the future. Okay.
So what we're first going to do here is we're going to take a look at the position.
Okay? What is it? How is it constructed? How is it constructed?
What our risks are at inception. Okay? So let me just open up thinkorswim here.
I'm going to share the screen.
Okay. So when we're doing a calendar spread, right,
we're going to be trading two different expirations, right? We're,
it's called a calendar because it's through time.
So the usual calendar spread would, let's say, sell a front month option.
So if we're looking at, let's say Apple, okay,
we would sell a front month option and buy a back month. So in this case,
let's go and sell the Jans, the one 22 fifties,
and we're going to buy the April one 22 fifties.
And are we just trading a single option there? Are we trading like a,
something different within each expiration? How has it done? Yeah.
So it's just going to be a single option. Okay. So in this case,
you guys can see right here,
we are selling the Jan buying the April's and we're going to go to one 22 50.
Okay. So this spread is going for $5 and 50 cents, but that's aggressive.
I must have had some short ball on, on Apple. Okay.
So here's our calendar spread guys.
And you know, if anyone here has experience with tasty trade, right?
We are told that it's used when we think volatility will increase, right?
It's a, it's a long Vega position, right? We can see right here. Okay.
If we look at the middle row here,
we can see how our Vega position is changing. So this middle row right here,
okay. We can see that our Vega is 135. So we would think right off the bat,
well, we're a long volatility. We want volatility to expand and a naive,
a rookie trader would come in and say, okay, well, if I,
let's say increased volatility, 10 points, I'm going to make a lot of money,
right? Because we're long that Vega. But in actual fact,
the different expirations do not move the same way. Okay.
Do they do not move the same way?
And we're going to actually go do an exercise here.
And so I put together an Excel sheet for you guys to go over this with me.
I think you guys will find this extremely, extremely exciting and intuitive.
But before we do that,
does everyone understand what a calendar spread looks like?
Yeah, exactly. Steve, Steve's having a good joke.
It's like a rookie tasty trader would sell vol and then buy a whole bunch of calendars
to hedge. What, you know,
I've seen done before because I think they're long Vega. Okay.
So we all get it. Now let's head over then to, let's head over to,
here we go guys, here we go. So I want to,
what I did here was I got all of Apple's implied volatilities. Okay.
So we've got a couple of columns here, guys. On the first column,
we have the month. So the month until expiration. So for example,
this is a one month option. This is the two month option,
and this is the 12 month option. Okay.
And these are the implied volatilities at the beginning.
So let me just head back over to Apple. So you can see the one month option,
okay. Has implied volatility.
When I was looking at these earlier, it was 45, but the one month options,
let's say have implied volatility of 45. Okay.
And we're going to say the back month options have an implied volatility of 30.
So if we graph this, okay,
we graph this, this is what the term structure looks like.
All right. So again, the PA terminal,
if we head over to Apple and we
look at the term structure.
Okay.
So this obviously is a little different than what we have here,
but you see how we have different expirations and different implied volatilities.
So that's what I have graphed right here. Okay. Here's the first month option.
Okay. So expiring in, let's say 30 days, and then we have the 12 month option.
Okay. And this would look maybe like,
let's say there's an earnings event coming up where the near dated options are more
expensive than the further dated options. Okay. And we could see that,
for example, we can see something similar on Tesla,
right? So here we go. Okay.
You see how the near dated options are expensive and the far dated options are a
little cheaper in terms of implied vol.
So this is what we have. Now the way these options move, though,
is a lot different than a lot of people might think. They might think, okay,
if implied vol comes down 10%, right,
this whole thing is going to move down 10%. Okay.
But this is what actually happens.
Volatility, okay, is going to move in a square root fashion. Okay.
It's called root time. Okay. Now, what does this mean? Let's say we change,
okay. So let's say we'd go from, let's say the front month options increase by,
let's say, 20 points. Okay. Big news comes out.
Something's going to happen like now. Yep. Right. Vol shoots up. Yeah.
That's another good way. Let's say market crashes and this is the S&P. Okay.
Big spike down. News comes out. Coronavirus. So vol spikes the front 20 points.
Well, this is actually how the rest of the term structure is going to move.
So for example, the second month is only going to increase 14%.
The third month is only going to increase 11%. Okay.
So let's graph these out so you guys can see here.
And so funny. Always works.
Always works when you're doing it on this side here. Ned, where are you at,
Ned? He said trying to do two series. Yeah.
Strange. It was literally just working. Said do what you did again.
So go insert.
Oh, here we go.
So here we go. Right. So we're going to, let's see. Okay. If we drop this,
let's say,
so right now they're the same and let's say implied volatility spikes 10%.
Okay. Well, this is what's going to happen.
The front is going to move up 10 points,
but the back is only going to move up 2.8 points. Okay.
That being said on the flip side, if we go down, let's say negative 20 points,
okay. This is what's going to happen.
This is how the term structure is going to move. Now a lot of people might say,
no. So before we keep going on here, continuing guys, we have a second sheet.
Do you guys understand what's happening here? Okay.
Remember volatility is equal to,
okay. Remember this guys, volatility equals standard deviation. Okay.
Square root time. Okay. Where time is, let's say one month over 12 months,
right? This is for the first month. Okay.
Or let's say second month over third month or a second month. Right.
So it'd be two over 12. So you see how it's volatility, right?
Standard deviation moving through time. Right.
And that is why if we look at the formula for this, okay.
If we look at the formula,
okay.
We have annualized vol divided by square root month to expiration divided by 12.
Okay. Because the volatility is moving through root time fashion. Okay.
Now this is only the, the only, this is not even the most interesting part.
We're going to get to the most interesting part,
but let's just make sure we're all on the same page here.
Can you explain why the curve changes shape? Yes. Okay. Steve,
really good point. So Steve's saying, well,
why is it that when ball drops this, like let's drop it even more,
let's drop it 30 points.
Why is it that this gets smoked, right? But then this stuff only drops,
you know, it doesn't like flip, right. You know, it's like,
it doesn't go concave, but just the front really drops.
And that's because Steve, this is dropping by more than these are dropping,
right? This is these, this was above all of the ones behind it.
And now it's going to be below all the ones behind it. Right.
And that's why you're going to get that flip. Right. Think about like this.
You got two things here. It's up here. Imagine we didn't move this at all.
And this dropped. Right. Well, now it's going to look like this. Right.
So if we're going like this, Steve, right, this is what's actually happening.
We're starting up here. And as we come down, this is coming down faster.
So that's why we're getting that curves flip.
Yes. Okay. Eric. Great. So Eric,
that's going to be where it gets really interesting.
Oh, okay. So Steve's okay. So let's drop it. Maybe five points. Steve,
you're saying, or let's go eight points. So it actually looks meaningful.
So here it's still dropping. It's not dropping enough for it to get that flip.
Okay. It's still this, it's still above the second month. Okay.
And as we change, okay, as we go, let's say negative 30 or 32,
let's say negative 30. Right. There's that big flip.
Now, so some people might say, okay, well, if I have a calendar spread on,
right, imagine we're doing this calendar spread.
Let me make this a little bigger. Just not a cool point.
Yeah. Right. It's not, it's not linear. It's not a linear measure. Right.
Like take a look at the change here.
Right. It's not linear. Right. If I change this.
Right. It's not linear. And so for that reason,
we're not going to have linear moves in the underlying and we're going to have it.
It's going to be curvy.
Okay. Now people, some people might say, okay,
well if I have a calendar spread on, okay,
so this is the term structure when we initially put on the calendar spread.
So let's say we come in here and we sell this and actually, and we buy this.
Okay. Well, the naive approach would be if volatility increases,
we're going to make money. Right.
So let's go up 20 points and you can see we increased, okay,
we increased, but this actually increased more than this.
Okay. And then, well, some people might say, okay, well,
I'm going to put on a calendar spread where I think vol is going to decrease because
this is going to decrease more than this. Okay. So we show that here.
Let's drop this 10 points or negative 10 Vegas. Right. Some people might say,
well, you know,
I sold up here or should we drop it even more to make it really,
I sold vol up here.
And I bought vol back here and I got this massive move and I got this,
I only got this little move. So my short leg,
cause I'm short volatility here should have made a lot more money. Okay.
And this is where Vega comes in.
So let's move to the next spread.
This is where Vega comes in. So what I've done here, guys, is I have,
so we have the same thing from,
we have the same pieces of information from last time.
And also for guys that trade like the earnings calendar spreads like Kyle I hope
you're starting to see where like the back month, you know, how,
like what should change, what should not change. Okay.
And we'll talk a little bit about that towards the end.
So we have the same thing here. Okay. We have our same thing here,
but look over here, guys,
what we have here is something a little different on our first column.
We have the months to expiration just like this.
And over here we have the Vega for the options contract.
So I did the one month option Vega, the two month option Vega,
the three month option Vega, four months, five months, six months.
And what we notice obviously, let me just plot this.
What we notice is that as we go through time, Vega increases,
Vega increases, but what is very cool about this?
Who can tell me what is very cool about this, about this chart?
Nobody, everyone's asleep. Everyone fell asleep tonight. Typical, typical,
typical. What is really cool about that chart?
Inverse to vol term structure? Nope. Dimas saying almost linear. Nope. Nope.
I want you guys to think, really think about that.
How vol moved previously in the previous section. Okay.
And inverses, okay.
So nope. So the answer is guys, there we go, Eric. There we go.
It also moves in the root of time, right? So check this out guys.
Vega divided by square root one over 12 is equal to 3956. Second month,
which is second month divided by square root two over 12 is 3950.
So adjusted for square root time, they all have the same Vega.
They all have the same Vega. So what does that mean? Well,
let's go back over here, guys. I want you to watch our P&L column now. Okay.
So what I did for this P&L column was I said, okay, the change in Vega here,
I'm sorry, the change in implied vol times our Vega, right? If we have,
let's say 1,100 Vega and we multiply it and we're short 10 Vegas, or sorry,
if we have 1,100 Vegas and we lose 10 implied vol points, well,
we're going to be down 11 grand, right? Oh, sorry. 1,000 or 11 grand.
So watch what happens guys. We're going to go and increase.
So we're going to go from 45 to 55.
We're going to go from 45 implied vol to 55 implied vol.
And look at our P&L guys. They're the same. They're the exact same.
Okay. Just let that sink in for a second.
If we change implied vol, the term structure is going to move,
but the way it's going to move is that it's going to,
they're all going to make the same amount of money. Okay. So far we're so good.
Is that, if that's a little confusing, I can slow it down.
We can chat about it.
Okay.
And we know guys, so we can, we can make sure we're all on the same page.
Don't be, don't be afraid to speak up.
Okay. And I'll just,
what is the formula again for the root time adjusted vega? Here it is. Okay.
It's Apple vega divided by square root, the month divided by 12, right?
Square root time. Okay. Just like this is month is two divided by 12.
So what we have here is in a change in implied volatility,
I should change across the whole term structure. Now the beauty of trading,
okay. Is that sometimes these moves don't happen. Okay.
Sometimes these moves don't happen. Now, most of the time,
these moves are going to happen. Okay. Fall is going to move in root time.
And what I mean by that is let's say we're looking at an earnings event. Okay.
After the earnings event is gone, they should all drop.
Meaning that the implied move was the same throughout the term structure. Okay.
So imagine this guys right now,
we're at 45 vol and it's an earnings event tomorrow.
And so let's say after the earnings event,
volatility for the front month drops by 20 points.
Well,
every single month is going to lose the same amount of money because they all have
the same implied move baked in. Otherwise it's an arbitrage, right?
Otherwise you can buy a cheaper implied move and sell a more expensive implied move.
Now, what happens though, is that sometimes these moves don't always work out,
right?
Let's say company releases a terrible earnings implied move drops in the front.
It drops across the whole term structure,
but this also signifies more volatility into the future, right?
Or it signifies more volatility in the next earnings event.
There's like a change in the term structure. Exactly.
So we don't get that root time movement.
And that's where the calendar makes money.
It makes money when non-root movements happen.
It makes or lose money when non-root moves happen, okay?
And there's other ways to, so there's other ways you can set up the,
so let me ask you guys this question. If you actually want to be long vol,
a calendar spread, okay? How would you structure it?
It's a trick question. How would you structure it?
That's saying sell front buy back. That's just the regular calendar spread,
right? Let's say if implied volatility does increase, you want to make money.
Wait it. What does that mean, Steve? What does that mean? Wait it.
Exactly. Exactly, Dima. So a regular calendar is called root time vega neutral,
okay? It's called root time vega neutral because any move,
any root move that happens, it's going to be,
it's not going to make or lose money, okay? It's called root time vega neutral.
Now if you want the position to actually make money when implied vol increases,
you have to be gamma flat, okay?
And so we're going to structure one out right now.
So to do this, you actually have to do a straddle versus straddle.
So here we have our short straddle,
okay? And then we're going to go back,
let's say we're going back to the March one again.
We're going to buy the straddle, okay? So you're on sale. Oops, thanks.
Okay, so now this looks like a regular calendar spread, right?
This looks like our calendar spread we were just talking about.
But this is root time vega flat, root time vega neutral.
In order to make this actually make money if implied volatility increases,
we need to make this gamma neutral. So you guys are going to see this here.
Watch this, okay? So look at our gamma. We're obviously short gamma, right?
Concave function. Watch what happens now.
Okay, we're picking up a little bit of delta,
but basically we are now in this position.
You're gamma flat and you're actually long vega. So if for example,
so we're going to do this together, guys. This is month one,
this is month three, okay?
If implied volatility moves up 20 points for month one,
that's the January contract, okay? That's what's going to happen.
But what's going to happen to the back? Okay, let's go back to our,
let's go back to our Excel sheet. Okay, so we said plus 20 points.
So that means month three is going to move at about 11 and a half points.
So watch this. Okay guys, watch this. We make a ton of money.
We make a ton of money, right? Five grand.
Now watch what happens if I make this root time vega flat,
a regular calendar spread.
Look at that guys. No P and L, no P and L change.
And that has the parameter changes, right? If we go to more parameters here.
Yeah. Right. Those are still on it.
There's no P and L change in our calendar spread. And this is, you know,
this is the, this is the reality of how calendar spreads actually work.
And this is why it's a gold topic.
And the only reason why Sean and I wanted to do this today was because congratulations
to our two brand new gold members.
So, so Stephen's saying, well, if you're gamma flat and long Vega,
you are short data. Yes and no.
So it really depends on what level of vol you're buying at, right?
The higher level of vol you're buying at,
the more theta is going to be embedded in it. So let's take a look. Steve,
let's take a look at this structure. What was it? 20, right? So this,
this is short data. Yeah. You're short data here. Okay. So as time goes by,
you're going to lose a little bit of money,
but it's not always the case, right? Sometimes you can sell at a crazy vol,
buy at a cheaper vol, right?
Especially when you're doing a relative value play. Like let's say what,
what Ned and I are working on, where synthetically we're almost long theta,
long gamma, long Vega, right? If you can find these trades where it's,
you know,
and obviously it's not arbitrage because IWM and SPY can move differently at any
given moment, but if you can find these trades where, you know,
one vol is really cheap and one vol is really expensive,
you can structure your book to be in our case, right?
If you look at the case between Ned and I, we are flat theta.
We have zero theta, but we have long gamma and long Vega. Okay. It's a,
it's a win-win until things stop moving, right?
Or until we're wrong until let's say SPY doesn't move and IWM shoots through the
roof.
Exactly. Exactly. Steve. Or, or implied vol,
the implied vol spread forces is out of the position. Okay.
So we're not always saying when you sell a strangle straddle in the front versus
the back and IV collapses, your P&L is bigger in the,
in the back than in the front.
Why is that then? So this is not true. It's not true. We're not.
So if you are a root time Vega flat and implied vol drops,
your P&L is going to be the same throughout. Okay.
It's going to be the same throughout. So it would only be,
it would only be unless you're saying if you're doing them separate positions,
it would be the same thing, right? What we're betting on is non-root movements.
Okay. Non-root movements. That's what we're really betting on, right?
We're betting on, let's say for example,
if we're looking at an earnings calendar, earnings calendar trade,
we're looking at the back to the front to drop in the back to shoot up. Right.
Or the, just the front to drop. These are non-root movements.
So even if, so Renato, even if we have different positions,
one is not going to make more money than the other. Okay.
One is not going to make more money than the other.
The, so the area under the, it's actually, okay,
so the area under the curve is going to be different. Okay.
The area under the curve is going to be a little bit different. So with,
with the Vega, with the Vega trade, our P&L should be the same. Okay.
But what's going to happen is your width of your breakevens are going to be wider.
Okay. Whereas in the front,
your sensitivity to that time is going to be more important.
So imagine like this happens, Renato,
let's say you sell a 120 day straddle and you buy a or let's say we're on the same
side. So you sell a 10 day straddle and you sell a 200 day straddle.
Now tomorrow your theta P&L is going to be a lot more important to the front month
expiration. And let's say implied vol drops, root time, your,
your 200 day straddle is going to have more width. Okay.
It's going to have the break evens are going to be a lot wider, right?
But your,
your straddle in the front actually increased in height due to that time factor,
that time decay. Okay. And let me just, let me just, uh,
I know it's a little bit advanced guys, but. That's why it's gold topic.
That's why it's gold topic. Right.
And this is why it's so important when you guys are in silver to really get a grasp
of it because what's coming in gold is, uh, is it's big news bears. Okay.
So Renato, watch this.
You see that, see that height pop, right? Look at this height pop. Okay.
Now watch what happens Renato when we go way back.
So here is our long dated option. Okay. Here's,
here's our break even right now. Watch this height pop.
There's none.
There's none. Right. But watch what happens Renato when we drop fall,
look at the width, look at the width on that Renato.
Can't even get it on the page. Can't get it on the page. Right.
So we get this extremely wide, uh, break even, but we get no height, right?
So that, that's the, that's the difference. Okay.
The difference is with the theta,
tomorrow's P and L is going to be based on that theta. When in the back,
you're going to get that, that width when the Vega drops. Okay.
Does that make sense?
Sorry. Uh, sorry, Kyle. Thanks for, thanks for calling me out on their margin.
Okay. So, um, when we're looking at like, let's say an earnings trade, right,
an earnings calendar spread, and we get, uh, you know, sometimes we'll say,
okay, well if they release the announcements, um, the back should increase.
Well, that's not necessarily true.
What might actually happen instead is that the front is just going to decrease.
Okay.
And that's another reason why we see that pattern leading up into these earnings
events.
Okay.
Any questions, guys? That's going to be,
otherwise that's going to be the live it's eight 40. Yeah.
A little bit of a gold topic for the, for the new gold guys.
I'll have to give them their badge right after the, uh, yeah,
Renato send me a message, buddy.
Good stuff. Jekka. Marco's saying only use them on events. No.
So you want to use them, um,
Marco's wherever you think there's going to be a non-route time movement.
An example might be, um,
an example might be, uh,
let's say right now the term structure is looking like this term
structure is looking like this. Okay. Well,
we also need to think about the position, right? We're we're long theta here.
Okay. Short gamma.
And we're hedging that short gamma with some of this long Vega out here.
So you might think, for example, um,
Marco's that realize volatility is not going to move. Okay.
Realize volatility is going to be very low,
but implied vol is going to stay bid in the back, right?
This could be for many reasons. For example, once COVID started slowing down,
implied volatility in the back still wanted to stay bid because who knows what could
happen in the future.
But the near dated vol started dropping like crazy and not the implied,
but the realized. So what you could have done was say, okay,
well I'm going to sell some of this,
get that exposure to that short gamma long theta,
and I'm going to buy these back month options because this is going to lose a lot
of money, right? If the stock doesn't move,
this is going to lose a lot of money,
but this is still going to stay high in terms of implied vol. Okay.
So that's one way you can use them. And then let's say for an earnings event,
so sometimes I've been doing this recently,
you have an earnings event that looks like this.
Here's the front. Here's the back. Well, what I've noticed a little bit,
you know, is some stocks, this drops like crazy and this doesn't change.
This stays bid. So what I like to do is I try to figure out,
I try to price the back months here and I just go and sell the front, right?
Because what, what, what,
what this is telling us is that there's a big earnings move implied in here,
but there's no earnings move implied over here, right?
So obviously those are going to be fantastic trades.
So there's lots of different ways to use them.
That is just one example or two examples.
You're basically looking for an auto when you want to see implied moves across different
expirations change differently.
They're not root time movements and root time movements just being means normal
movement.
Okay.
Okay. Perfect. Everyone's passed out.
Everyone's going to get a good night's sleep tonight. Excellent.
Oh, Ariel. Thank you. You know, thanks for joining, man. We, we, we, we have,
we have a surprise guest, Ariel. He's just, he's dropping in,
taking a little peek into our, into our lives today. So nice to see you, buddy.
Okay. Well, if that's it, oh wait, last question here from Anne and Alan,
how long do you hold the position? Yep. So it really depends until you're,
it depends on until your, your view has come to fruition or when, you know,
before you enter the trade, right, we should always think of, okay,
when am I right? And what am I wrong? Right. And so if, if, if,
if the wrong thing happens, you have to exit the position. Right. And, but if,
if your, if your position does come to fruition,
then it's time to take off the trade. Right.
So let's say we're doing an earnings event and we don't think there's going to be
a root time movement in the vol surface. So once the earnings event is done,
right, if it's happened, or if it hasn't happened,
we're out of the position because we took this position.
We took this trade anticipating that after the earnings event is done,
this should happen. And if it didn't,
we were wrong and we have to admit that to ourselves and move on to the next trade.
Tico, send me a message, man. I won't have time to hop on a call,
but if you want to send me a message, if it's important,
then of course we'll jump on a call.
Okay. Everyone. Okay. That's the live for tonight. Once again, congrats, Jekka.
Congrats, Ned. Unreal stuff. Yeah. Really good stuff. Really, really.
Congratulations guys.
And tune in to see how Ned and I manage the relative value position.
So far it's pretty good. We're like 3% on capital.
And like not even talking about risk,
we're 3% on capital in like five days of trading on it. So, you know,
stay tuned for how the position evolves.
Ned is posting daily updates twice a day, I think morning and how it opens,
how it closes. Really good stuff. He's also messaging me with all the sweat.
He's dying. Every 10 minutes I get a new meme from him. That's so funny. Yeah.
The sweat. That's so good. Yeah. Okay. Okay, guys. Have a great night,
everyone.