All right. Okay, guys. So in this lab,
we're going to be talking a little bit about forward vols, where to use it,
and basically what structures we need to use to take advantage of it.
So we've done quite a few lives on what forward volatility is,
and you can check out the archive for that.
But just we'll give a quick summary of what forward volatility is.
And to do that, I'm going to share my screen. Let me make you host.
Okay. Go for it. All right.
All right. So what we're going to look at here, guys, is two volatilities.
Okay. We're going to look at, actually, we're going to go to block.
Okay. So we're going to look at this screen right here,
where all the implied volatilities are. Okay.
And what I graphed here is two volatilities.
One is the implied volatility of the 30-day,
and the other is the implied volatility of the 90-day.
So if we go to thinkorswim,
we have the implied volatility of, let's say, the 30-day, right?
And we have the implied volatility, in this case, of the 156,
156 days to expiration.
Now these are just the regular implied volatilities.
But what the forward volatility is, is the volatility between two expirations.
Jordan, maybe you should share your whiteboard here and draw it out. Yeah.
And also, guys, I want to keep this one a little bit exciting.
I feel like sometimes when we talk too much,
when I use the word volatility too much, people start to fall asleep.
So I want to keep it exciting. Okay. So you guys,
let's try to keep it pumped up here. So share your whiteboard.
And the reason that I actually, maybe not anyone else does,
but I think this is really exciting because you think you have it all figured out,
and then this whole new element comes into play. And you're like,
wait a minute. I'd never even thought of this before. You know what I mean,
Jordan? Yeah. And to keep it more motivating, this is rarely modeled.
So meaning there's going to be lots of alpha here, right?
I was telling a story the other day about how I picked up these calendars for five
cents, and they're worth a dollar within a couple of weeks, right?
So these things are, they're available, and it's because it's rarely modeled.
And in fact, Margin, one of the guys in our group, put on a trade today, WSM,
forward vol trade, and the number of returns he's made on that,
he's closing it out tomorrow, but it's gigantic. Okay. It's gigantic.
And I'm a little upset he's not on the live today,
but you guys can reach out to him, ask him about it. Hopefully he'll post it.
Yeah. It's a forward vol play, and it's going to earn quite a bit. Okay.
All right. Jordan, quickly here, let's talk about what,
like draw it out so that everyone understands what forward vol is,
and then let's hop right into how we trade it.
Because we have a few lines where we break down exactly how it works,
and we talk about time, we talk about forward vol,
we talked a little bit about calendars, but let's turn it into strategy. Yeah.
Love it. Love it. Love it. All right. So here we go. Here's zero days.
Here's the 30 day option. Here's the 90 day option.
This option right here might have, let's say a volatility of 50%. Okay.
And this option right here is going to have, let's say a volatility of 40%.
I don't know. Okay. Two arbitrary numbers.
Maybe draw out the like lines for them.
So like show like to the 50 and then to the 40 and then do the thing. Yeah.
So this option is going to see,
this 30 day option is going to see like the volatility like this. Okay.
This option right here is going to see 40 vol, not 50.
So it might see something a little bit smaller over on this side, but together,
okay, 50. And let's say this is 30, 30 vol together.
It's going to be 40 volatility. And this 30 right here is the forward vol.
Okay. It's the volatility between the expirations.
And you can't just see that looking at your brokerage or anything like that.
It's sort of behind the scenes, right?
You have to infer it from what you're seeing.
And of course we need to use a little bit of math for that,
but don't worry guys,
we have a little special tool that you guys can take advantage of.
This little thing called the terminal. The terminal. Oh, you spoiled it, man.
Why? Why did you spoil that? It was the closing remarks. Okay.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to go look at the terminal. Okay.
And we're going to talk about how we make money, all that stuff, guys,
but we really need to understand what this volatility is.
Okay. So we go to the terminal. Okay. So let's take a look here.
We see implied volatility 90 in red and in green, we see implied volatility 30.
Now when I look at implied volatility 90 here, I say, wow, that's pricey. Wow.
That's pricey. But it's not like it's at its highs.
It's not like unbelievably pricey,
but look what happens when I look at the forward vol 90 30, right? This is,
this is us finding our edges, right?
We're looking at the world through a different lens than everyone else.
Look at this. Here's the forward vol 30 90. You can see it's at extreme highs,
but it's never even been close to this high before. Right.
So these are the kind of, you know,
hidden trades that we can kind of find out there in the wild.
And we're going to do a whole bunch of examples here.
What does it mean that the forward volatility is high?
So what it means is that if we're looking here at the forward 30 90, okay.
What this tells us is, so this is saying 93 vol.
So what that's telling us is once 30 days goes, right? Once we,
once the 30 day options expire, what will those 90 day options be? Okay.
Once the 30 day options expires, what will those 90 day options implied vol be?
And this is saying that it's going to be 93. Now we might say, well,
I don't think that's the case. Once these 30 day options expire,
it's these options are actually going to be worth 75. And if that's the case,
well,
this is super expensive and you could sell this forward vol by selling a calendar
spread. So before we get there, Jordan, maybe like a way to think about it is,
um, imagine we're looking at, uh,
the forward vol between the 10 day and 20 day option. Okay. And we see that,
uh, you know, the, the forward vol between them is really high,
but we look at the T the difference between the two.
We look at everything happening around the stock and we see that there's nothing,
there's no real, like, there's no difference between these two. Like, uh,
there's no event in the back.
There's no event a week and a half or two weeks from now,
what is driving all this really high vol, right?
Unless we come to the conclusion that it's,
it's like people bidding up the two week, right?
It's all the volume on the monthly or whatever we come up with. And well,
now we can,
we can actually see what's being priced into that back month more than that front
month or front week. And we can actually make a trade out of it. Right?
So when it's high like that, what criteria,
before we jump into the trade Jordan,
if let's build a strategy out of trading high forward volatility, what, what,
what, what helps us convert it from it being just high to being expensive?
Yeah. Yeah. That's really a question. Um, and here would be the answer.
So imagine we're looking at this Volco. Okay.
And we're going to go over a couple of examples, guys,
where you guys are really going to paint the pitch really and paint the picture.
The forward vol here. Okay. Imagine forward vol was 150.
Well, you clearly want to be a seller of that, right?
So what you you're basically saying, right. In 30 days,
what is this vol going to be? And we can look at, let's say the Volco and say,
okay, well, if in 30 days, the 90 day options are going to be one 50. Well,
that's never going to be that. That was never seen before. Right.
I've never seen something that high before, or the market's never seen.
That's probably too expensive. Right.
An example with one that I was looking at was that, um,
the vol was actually 12. The forward vol was 12,
but implied vol has never seen below 35. Okay. So let's on the flip side. Okay.
On the flip side, what if forward vol was 25? Well, that's extremely low,
right? Considering where, where realized vol is right now.
So you're still thinking, well,
what would make this forward vol cheap versus expensive, right?
Just like implied volatility.
What would make this implied vol cheap versus expensive?
You're just trading a different volatility. Okay. Does that,
did that make sense? Let's do an example. Let's do an example here, guys.
We can also do more examples.
I can start doing them on some of the morning lives as well. Okay. Okay.
I like that. Um, let's do, okay. You know what? Well, let's look at,
take a look at the trade, um, that margin did today. Okay.
So we'll take a look at the trade margin did today. So, um, oh,
they are so bad after hours here. Let's do something like, uh,
who's got a stock. Who's got a stock.
They want us to take a look at their forward vols. Who's got it.
It's first come first serve ride. Oh, this better be liquid.
I'm going to lose it. Okay. Perfect.
Okay. Perfect.
So here we go. Oh, is this thing moving after hours?
Oh, it did. Okay. Can we get a stock that, uh, you know what here,
I'll do the analyze, think back feature that way.
Everything is going to work out. Good. I mean, you can't analyze the trade.
If you do that. All right. Just do Neo Rob. Sorry. Okay. Neo, Neo. Yeah,
I guess.
Um, okay. You know what, Rob? Hold on. Okay. Actually, Sean,
we're actually gonna, we're actually gonna do right here.
We're going to do right here. I think it's a good one to do, but, um,
and then we'll, we'll do Neo afterwards. We'll get,
we'll get two examples in here. So, uh, ride.
Let's take a look here. Rob implied vols, uh, was 185%. Okay. For March 19th,
they had earnings. So, you know, 185% vol there. Now let's look at,
let's say the April. Okay. April is 141. Okay. And that's,
and that is 31 days out. Okay. So let's do that. 1.85 for the first month.
Okay. Volatility. And what did we say the other one was?
140.
Okay. 140. 140, three and 31. Okay. Let's take a look.
Let's see what the output is. The output is 134 volatility.
So what that's telling us is once that expiration is gone. Okay.
Once this is gone. Once March 19th is gone.
This volatility here is going to be 134%.
So after the earnings is gone in three days,
what is this April 16 volatility going to be? And the market saying it's 134%.
Now let's go over here. To the terminal. Let's type in ride.
134%. Rob, what were like, what do you think about that?
What do you think about the 30 day options right here? Okay.
Going to 134 after the earnings event, is that cheaper expensive too?
Maybe it's nothing. What do you think about it?
What do you guys think? Cheaper expensive. 134.
Co-hosting cheap. Co-hosting cheap. Cool. That's all the way up here.
I looked for a little bit on the pricey side.
Jared. Yeah. What's yours? Pricey. Yeah. It's a little bit pricey, right? Well,
it's not like, uh, actually it does look a little pricey. Right.
And so we might think that that's expensive.
And we'd want to be a seller forward ball, but take a look at this guys. Okay.
Imagine that that April contract had an implied volatility of 100 instead of 1.4.
It had a volatility of 100. Well, now the forward vol would be 86.
Okay. The forward vol would be 86. Now, when we look at this,
is 86 cheaper expensive?
What do you guys think is 86 cheaper expensive? Cheap. It's super cheap.
It's super. It's in fact, it's never been below 95 before.
So we could lock that in. Right. We could lock in that 86 of all, uh,
by trading a calendar spread. Okay. We could do that by let's say selling this.
Okay. Selling the March and buying the April. And that's going to lock into 86.
And what we're actually going to find is tomorrow.
So the market's not going to price that 86 of all. Okay.
The market's not going to, well,
you're not going to wake up and see the back at 86. Instead.
What are you going to see happen? What do you guys think?
So today we're going to say month one. Is one 81.85. Month two is equal to one.
Is month. Tomorrow is month two going to equal to. 86 to 0.86.
What do you guys think?
Jared's saying no. No. How come Jared? Well, what's your opinion?
How come you don't think it's going to go to 86?
Blessing saying not yet. Okay. Blessing saying not yet.
So we got a little bit of a little bit of batting in the heads here.
What are you guys thinking? What's going through that head?
Words that each day and then fall off after the front month expires.
I feel like, I feel like red posted that one. Was that from red? No,
that was from Jared. Okay. Okay. Say it again.
It will move towards that each day and then fall off after the front month expires.
Okay. So.
What's what's actually going to happen here is after the earnings event,
this is going to drop off. Right.
So M one is going to drop off to maybe let's say a hundred ball. Right.
Earnings events gone.
But what we're actually going to see in month two is it's not going to change.
It's going to stay at 100. Because. Remember if month two went to 86.
Everybody would buy it.
It's been the it's it's 10 points lower than it's ever been.
So month two is never going to see 86. And that's the forward ball.
It's because this is so high. Right. The front is so high.
Relative to the back.
That it's making this illusion that the market thinks that after the event,
it's going to be 86. But it's not right. Imagine for example,
we'll do one more example here. Imagine this. Was two 20.
Or let's go even higher. Three 20. Would we ever see volatility of 10%?
Right. Would we ever see a volatility after that expires of 10%? Never.
We would never see it. And that is. It's just a forward ball.
It's the market saying, Hey, I think that given the,
given these two expirations. Board ball is going to be 86.
But we can look at that and say, there's no way. Right. And by,
by buying the back and selling the front. We can capture that spread. Right.
So we'll do Neo where we can actually analyze the trade.
And I think this is going to. Solidify it for everybody.
So let's take a look at Neo.
And we're going to do instead of. Instead of March 19. We're going to do.
April. And may. Yeah, we're going to do it. Let me see if it's.
Okay. You know what? We're sorry, buddy.
We're not going to do Neo because the vols aren't different enough.
If the vols are the same, right. If you have, let's say. 0.85. And 0.85. Right.
Well, the forward ball is going to be 0.85.
So we can tell you that's a little bit different. What's that buddy. Game stop.
That's a good one. Game stop.
Okay. That's perfect.
So let's take a look here. Let's do.
Okay. Let's do this.
Okay. We're going to do the forward vols between. April and July. Okay.
So three, three, seven. Let's do this.
Three. We'll say four.
And.
Two four. So three. Four two. Four.
And that's three days. And I believe. Sorry, 31 days. And.
Okay. So the forward volatility. Is 195%. So after in 30 days, guys. Okay.
In 30 days. What's the market is saying is. The volatility for July.
Is going to be 190%. Okay. In 30 days.
The volatility for this July contract is going to be a hundred. And. 90%.
If it's larger than 190%. And you're long. These you're going to make money.
And if it's less. And you're in your short fees, you're going to make money.
So let, let us take a look at this trade. So first off,
what do you guys think about that? 190 Vol.
190 Vol. Any opinions?
Steve says it seems fair. Steven, man. We have to live a little man. Come on.
Let's live a little. Is it under overpriced? What do you think?
Under or overpriced. Let's take a look. Jimmy. Okay.
This is a 200 line is right around here. Just above the third quantile.
Okay. Let's see what realize vol is. Realize vol is about.
About three 80 right now. Okay.
What do you guys think? 190 Vol cheaper, expensive.
Here is the historical 90 day implied volatility. Okay.
So one 90 is right around here.
Jared saying cheap. Okay. Perfect. I was hoping you'd say that Jared.
So. What do we think? Okay. So what Jared,
so what do you think fair value might be for this? In 30 days,
what do you think the fair value would be?
What's Jason. He said, go back to think or swim.
To think or swim. Yeah.
Pretend this was three 37 and this is two 40. Yeah.
He wants to go to the chain. He's looking at it.
He wants you to open April. April's open there, Jared, the monthlies.
Or maybe open the ninth for him.
What do you think Jay? One 90.
He said. Two 90. Hell yeah, man. All right. All right. So.
Jared saying in 30 days. Or basically. After this expires.
This option right here is going to go from two 15.
To two 90 or feel slowly creep up to that two 90 mark. And so.
To get that forward ball. Okay. It's a relative value play.
So one of two things can happen here. One. Okay.
This needs to go up.
Okay. So either it goes from. 2.4. Okay. To three. Then we get our two 90.
So the back needs to go up to 300 today.
Or this. This. Needs to drop.
Okay. From three 40 to let's say two 70 or two 20. Or 200, sorry.
Or even one 90.
Okay. So one of two things needs to happen. Either the front needs to drop.
In order to get, you know, what Jared is, is really. You know,
Thinking of or the back needs to get pushed up. Okay.
So one of those two things. Needs to happen. In order for,
for Jared to think that forward ball. Is going to be at two 90. Okay.
So let's head over to the terminal now or the.
The chain and let's put on this calendar spread. Now.
If in fact. Right. So two things we know can happen here.
Either the front needed to drop like 80%. Okay. A little bit wild, but.
We're living a little. Okay. In this case.
That is what that would give us a forward ball of two 90. Or.
So we would make a ton of money there. Or the back needs to explode. Okay.
I think we said 60%. Okay. So one of two of those things. Needs to happen.
And that is as long as one of those things happen. We're going to make money.
Right. It's we're creating that forward volatility. On the flip side. Okay.
If we're wrong. If in fact. Forward ball is one 10. Okay. Well,
this is going to have to maybe drop by 60 points.
Right. Or maybe the front increases drastically. Right. So let's say.
Let's say another 60 points.
So by training this calendar spread, we can take advantage of mispriced.
Forward volatility.
Okay.
Neil, what do you think? I did a good job explaining this.
Are you still with us?
I think we might've lost him at one point there. We did.
He's out to go get a bagel cinnamon raisin or a subway. I'm just thinking like,
cause he said, I think the right answer is choice. C. Is that what he said?
Yeah. Oh my gosh. You must be.
You must have a cinnamon raisin bagel in one hand in the subway.
And the other hand right now.
Yeah. I'll post it up for you, Chris. No problem.
Okay. So Jordan, do you want to maybe do a recap? Yeah. So.
I was using some code there, but in reality, you know, Sean,
I never want to leave you guys hanging. So instead what we're going to do.
Is we are going to. Oh, we have embedded it in the terminal for you guys.
So you head over to event IV calculator.
And here is your forward volatility calculator. Right here it is.
So let's say eyeball. First expiration is. What was it there? Three 40.
And eyeball second was. Two 40. I think it was. We'll just go with that.
And this was expiring in April. I have to fix these date things.
Okay. April. And this one was expiring in.
July. I think we said. Oh, it was August. Or was it? No, it was.
I think it was July.
Okay. Okay.
So we run the forward volatility and then we have our volatility of.
Of 200%. Okay. So now we can make that decision of. Is that cheap or expensive?
And. You know, sometimes you can find some unreal deal guys. Like sometimes,
for example, there's just so much. Pressure coming into the front month.
So it's buying pressure coming into the front month. That this becomes,
let's say. I don't know. Three 90. Right. Right. Well,
now we have a volatility. Affordable of one 72. And we can say, okay, well,
that's dirt cheap. Right. We want to pick that up.
Let's make it clear for everyone. Buying the front.
If that was the case where it was three 90 to 40.
Would you be buying the front selling the back or would you be doing the opposite?
If it was three 94. You'd want to be selling the front,
assuming you think that. The forward ball is cheap.
So you think forward ball is cheap. You're buying the back, selling the front.
If you think forward ball is expensive, you're selling the back,
buying the front.
Okay. Can we. And for forward vault. 30 90. Right. So that's not in this one,
but it's in the new one. That's being released extremely soon. And you can,
you can of course. Graph it as well here. If you guys want. Yeah.
Jared was saying we need to write this into the scanner. Yeah.
Sometimes there's some super like. Insane deals guys.
I've seen some insane deals during my time. Where it's like,
The implied ball is just actually happens around earnings events too.
Sometimes where the implied ball is just in the back.
When you look at the forward volatility. It's just so, so low.
And so when you get the adjustment tomorrow,
What we actually find is that the front moves down too much.
And the back stays up. So let's take a quick look at Tesla.
Cause I think there was a time to buy very cheap, cheap forward ball.
Or sorry, sell, sell expensive ball. So, so this is what the,
this is what everyone else sees. Everyone else sees the IV 90.
They see the IV 30. Okay. But they don't see the forward balls.
And this is where things can get interesting.
So actually it doesn't look like it was too out of line.
But they're actually okay. So down here, for example. Right. So down here.
Jan 15, 2020. So, you know, before everything started happening.
Forward vols got extremely low. Look at that. Basically the 90 day options.
The market was saying in 30 days, the 90 day options are going to be a 40 ball.
Can you imagine that sub 40? Okay. I know that. I know. Yeah. Go ahead.
The forward vault to the Vulcan for a reference of higher low. Yeah.
A hundred percent. Right. Or 100%. You know,
and obviously we're all using two years data here, but.
So we can't go back in time to see forever, but there are times guys,
especially in these like not super, super liquid names.
Where a whole bunch of vol, a whole bunch of pressure is going to come in.
Let's say some type of expiration.
Maybe it's the front and it's just going to drive up the price,
but the back is not going to change as much.
And so you can structure these calendar trades to, you know,
to get some real nice returns. Busting out a good question here.
She was asking if we could put this as one of the strategy filters.
Like we call it calendars. Yeah,
I guess we could run something like forward vault percentile.
Yeah, I guess, I guess we could do that blessing.
Just for you.
Yeah.
But I'm actually working on a project right now that is looking at the one-year
two-year forward balls. And that's you know, that's, I think there's so much,
I was talking about it.
I think there's so much money to be made in the longer dated forward balls.
Any other questions there? Any, any quick ones?
You guys want me to look at the forward balls and then we'll call,
we'll wrap it up.
Right.
Okay. So forward vols are dropping. They're at one 80, one 83 for the 30,
the 90. Okay. Let's take a look. Let's take a super quick look here.
Okay. Right. Which ones were you wanting? Which,
which four balls you want to trade? Okay. So you can see here. Okay. Wow. Good.
This is getting really pricey. Right. So check this out.
You're going to like this one. Who asked it? All right. Right.
Jared. Jared. Okay. Jared. You're gonna like this one. Okay.
So this is where four balls probably going to be super expensive.
So you can see here, Jared. That. This option for the April. Is one 65 ball.
And for the June. Is one 71. Okay. So before I actually go and price it.
I have a question for you guys. Is forward vol going to be higher.
Or lower than one 71. Let me just, let me just close everything else here.
Is forward vol going to be higher or lower than 71. One 71.
Guys are saying higher. Guys are saying higher. That's it. PA gang, gang, gang.
And why is that? Because this option. Is going to see 165 all. For 30 days.
But then it's probably going to see one 80 ball. For the next 60, one 85.
And the next 60. Which is driving up. That June volatility.
So let's go and price it out in the terminal.
Option calculator. First expo is what do we say? One 65. And second was one 80.
Or one 75. Yeah, it was a little lower. One 75. Four 16. And. It was.
It was June. No, July.
It was June.
All right. So there you go. Right. The forward volatility is going to be 180%.
For this option. And if we look at, if we look at the chain here.
Let's take a look.
If we look at the vol insights. Or even look at realizable.
Like one 80 is super bid. Right. One 80 is all the way up.
It's literally the highest for the 90 days. Right.
We're going to be at the third quantile. Sorry.
We're going to be the third quantile for the 90 days. When that expires. And.
You know, given that realizable. Well, realize ball has been moving Jared.
Right. It's been moving quite a bit. But let's say for example.
This was at like, you know, we're not going to find inefficiencies everywhere.
It's going to be. The one-offs. Not the one-offs, but you got to look for them.
If let's say realize volger. Never got above one 70. Never got above one 70.
While selling eyeball. I saw a forward vol at one 80.
That's like extremely pricey. Right. And we could,
we could kind of find that because. There was contango in the term structure.
Even though. Falls were so high. Right.
And that's where forward vol is really going to look pricey.
So there you go. That's a. That's forward vol.
That's how you take advantage of it. You just trade the calendar spreads.
After this, we'll chat about how we can throw it into the strategy thing.
I think it'd be good to have something for calendars. Yeah. Good return on.
Great return on capital. Great return on debits. They're great.
Very cool. And maybe we'll do a part two of this.
I have a few questions that I'm going to build out that I think just from what you've
done here that I think we can do a part two. That next week.
Cool. Okay. I'm going to stop the recording.