So guys tonight we have a pretty special live we have the man himself the pancake
man himself. Mr. Josh Hutch Josh It's a pleasure, man.
Thanks for thanks for doing this. I think the guys are gonna love it my god.
I'm excited I just hope I can bring a little bit of value So just to set the stage
here, but Josh has been with us for what 10 12 months now almost yeah,
I think April is my one year Wow Unreal and basically Josh is the the go-to earnings
guy at predicting alpha since day one. It's been the strategy that you know,
I think it comes from him loving a good gamble,
but it was the one that spoke to him the most and he's just gone hard at it ever
since and That's what we're really here to talk about what it takes to crush a strategy
because this last earning season man like unbelievable Yeah,
wait this this season was awesome.
This season was awesome for sure Oh the way that we're gonna do this is Jordan has
a bunch of questions lined up We're just gonna chat chat trading chat earnings chat
strategy chat getting better at trading lots of different things And then at the
end, we're gonna do a little Q&A.
So everyone in the chat if you guys have questions take note of them at the end,
we'll do a little Q&A and You can ask them the tough questions not the staged ones
I'm not you know I think these lives are really important because or these interviews
because hutch has nothing to sell you, right? You know,
you see my story you see Sean story and you know,
well at the end of day we are running predicting alpha so I think hearing from someone
who has nothing to sell and who is literally Just grinding it out,
right and and really what it takes to to build a profitable strategy what it takes
to be a profitable trader and And that's really what you know,
these interviews are for to inspire you to you know,
give you guys insight look that's not biased at all Okay So much thanks for coming
out man, we really appreciate you, you know,
you know spending time with us this evening I had a couple questions that you know,
I want to chat with you about get your opinion, you know,
and then of course You know really inspire the people on the team here.
Let's get into it Um, so hutch when did you first start trading or you know,
what like when did you really get into trading?
Yeah uh So I started trading probably four or five years ago. Um I i'm 29.
So I mean like a decent chunk of my life, right? I mean not you know,
four or five years doesn't seem like that long but being 29 pretty decent pretty
decent amount. So Yeah, and like, uh,
you know when you were first starting out what kind of what kind of strategies were
you running there?
So I so when I first started trading I went straight to options.
So I never like dabbled in like delta one or anything like that um I've always liked
leverage. I've been a real estate investor for a while.
And so leverage just makes sense to me. Um,
I Started out with credit spreads or shorting verticals is what you guys call it.
Um are mainly around uh Moving averages like crop like crossing Uh,
like pull across bear cross moving averages selling credit spreads at that um And
then after that started taking my hedge off going naked uh shorts right Uh here
and there and then right around the time that I joined,
uh predicting alpha I was doing a lot of delta 30 strangles.
So um I was shorting, uh,
I was shorting strangles and then I would go for like high Volatile high premium.
I would pack it on Um, you know to get in and out of the trade,
you know in a few in a few days um You know to try to just like scalp premium basically
and then You guys found me when I found myself assigned to a shit ton of short shares
on a stock that went vertical And I was in a bad place. Uh, so So, yeah,
that's that's kind of that was kind of the evolution to how I got into vol You know,
what's funny hutch is that that video is actually saved on uh Was saved on my computer
before it got erased. So, oh, no, did you lose it? That's gone. Yeah,
that's gone Oh, that's okay. Yeah, i'm not i'm not mad that it's gone, but Um,
and so like hutch what were your signals like what would like what would tell you
like hey,
you know This is a good thing to short ball or this is a good strangle to do like
what was your mindset at the time? Right. Yeah,
so for the strangles for the for the non-directional like premium scalping Uh,
I mean and I mean now looking back I realized that okay I'm collecting variance
risk premium like on these like highly volatile names people don't know whether
they're going up 10 or down 10 Um,
you know those delta 30 strangles were really wide, right? um, and so and so,
uh,
that's that's kind of what I was doing there my signals for The credit spreads around
moving averages was I was looking for a building rsi And a bull cross and so I usually
like to trade them from a uh from a from a bullish standpoint Um selling the credit
spread below, you know selling the selling the put uh spread below. Um, Uh,
you know below the moving average as as a cross that's that's simply what I was
doing I think it's a super actually popular strategy amongst the retail traders.
We have a few members here who were uh,
Who were you know doing credit spreads and uh,
you know directional credit spreads, you know,
nothing wrong with that If you find an edge,
but uh I'm sure you learned on the hard way as well, right? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
No, I mean because because for a gambler like myself, uh,
it's hard to Just bring in the human bias to things.
It's hard to stay disciplined scalping like that little of like premium, right?
It's like, you know 70 bucks here 50 bucks here, right?
And so it's just hard to stay disciplined on that stuff.
And so inevitably you're going to go to higher premium stuff And then you're going
to be short and strangles on overstock like I was right to get more premium but
when there's more premium there's more risk and You know,
that's what you're not always taking into account And then when you get into the
voma and you know how the wings like,
you know expand on you or whatever Which I didn't learn until like here recently
um that you know,
it gets it's a lot more complicated than you're than you're doing and that's pa's
Uh, that's that's pa's like calling card, right? It's like hey,
you're taking risks that you don't understand, right? It's not bad,
but you need to understand them, right? nice um, and and so much you're like,
uh, you know, You you I should always say like you are the earnings guy, right?
You are the earnings guy And I was curious to know like what draws you to earning
so much Yeah, and maybe you can actually uh,
if you can maybe explain a little bit Just like in a nutshell about your strategy
and we're going to go more into detail about it But maybe in a nutshell,
can you maybe explain to people why you like it and and what you're doing?
Yeah So me being the earnings guy is not self-proclaimed.
I'm going to say that You guys you guys tagged me as the earnings guy,
which I mean, I love earnings.
That's that's for sure um But I mean my question to that is like what what's not
to love about earnings as a trader, right? It's got the volatility.
It's got the in and out in the day Uh, it's got the rush.
It's got it's got frequency.
You always know what's going to happen There's a ton of plays.
There's a ton of momentum So I I I love all of that from from from that standpoint.
Um,
also One thing that I don't think we talk about enough is uh is when you're when
you're making positive expected value bets Which we can explain expected value here
in a little bit,
but for everybody that's tracking with me When you're making positive expected value
bets, it's all about frequency because Because of the law of big numbers,
even though you might be making a positive EV bet You need to make a lot of them
so that your edge plays out over time If you're making one or two isolated positive
EV bets, right? Like you can hit tails six times in a row Right,
but you need to make sure that you flip 500 times To make sure that you have a positive
edge over time and earning trading gives you frequency, right?
The market doesn't all the time give you a trade, right?
And so and so because the market can be stubborn sometimes in giving you trades
and giving you opportunities I like earnings because it has that you always know
that earnings come is coming around So you always know that you have frequency so
that your edge is going to play out over time. So um Yeah, I love it.
And I love the like peaks.
I like I make fun of like how oh earning season is done I'm gonna go into withdrawals
and all that stuff like I make jokes about that But it's really fun to like go really
really hard and then kind of like take a step back read more Research more and everything.
I think that's really awesome to be able to do that.
But my strategy um I I'm very reliant on the terminal Um for for my earning strategy,
so I mean the earnings tab is what got me into it is what's kept me through it um,
and my strategy got better when Jordan's data got better, so um, I mean Yeah,
i'm highly reliant on the on the uh on the terminal So in the earnings tab,
I like to see at least a two percent edge, uh implied move to average move Um,
I like to see seasonality Relatively low.
I'm not as strict about that as some of the other earnings boys Uh,
Daniel's chuckling right now margin's probably chuckling right now as well.
I'm not as strict about that I like to see the straddle not profitable the long
straddle not profitable Um,
I don't like to see a lot of big moves I like to see I like to see the you know
for the straddle a not profitable long straddle Means that the market is consistently
Systematically overpricing this event, right?
And so that's when I want to be a seller Um,
I like to and this is this is relatively new Jordan,
me and you talked about this at length this weekend,
but the term structure I want to see a very steep term structure um So that we can
get that collapse. I want to see low realized vol. Um Uh, so,
you know if the stock isn't moving like a ton, right? um and uh,
and I like to see a substantial edge in Event vol so I want to have high event vol
in relatively low non-event vol like,
you know In the 20 to 30 range i'll take something less than that,
but I like to see 20 to 30 range That's what gets me interested then going directly
to the brokerage.
I like to see relatively high volume I have some questions that some guys sent me
about how I take low volume trades uh,
which is kind of funny to me because that's something that I look at that I filter
things out by but um Yeah, real like pretty good volume So so in a nutshell,
you're basically uh selling uh volatility collecting that risk premium But then
you're also adding this extra filter to try to like wean out What are the best trades
and what are like maybe just okay trades would you would you say that's about accurate?
Yeah, no,
I mean that's good I mean and when you're talking about so if you look at the if
you look at the definition of the equation of Expected value it is is it is amount
that you're going to win Or or amount that you're going to lose times the probability
of that happening, right?
So in my mind probability of that happening means i'm building confidence with my
data, right? So that's why I have all of those checklists, right?
If I go through my checklist and I say hey,
this is this is why the market is overpricing this event It builds the probability
that i'm right right because no one knows if they're right or wrong But all you
can do is take a bet right? And so yes I love that.
I love that With uh with this last earning season, right?
It sounds like you're doing a lot of filtering How many trades do you think you
took in just this last earning season? Uh,
that's a good question um off the top of my head I I think I I think I pasted return
numbers here. I don't think I pasted frequency man. I'd say 50 or 60 Okay,
yeah,
so that's a lot of filtering then because there's you know hundreds of events,
uh, yeah a lot more than even the seasons before Yeah. Yeah.
So I mean when margin and I started trading, uh,
Trading earnings like we took everything we took everything that moved,
you know what I mean? Like I mean, we like I was posting hundreds,
you know what I mean? Just like just like scripts, right?
um a lot of my pickiness and my filtering,
uh came down to Me going naked instead of buying wings too.
So I got a lot more picky when that happened Um, which I think has been great.
Um, we've we are our win percentage has gone way up um and um Sorry,
I had a mosquito that was flying around my desk um, and uh, yeah,
our win percentage has gone way up and I think I think it's been great. Yeah.
I mean, yeah picky for sure I don't take very much long ball either you know,
I I took some heat from that from somebody in the chat after I posted my rules for
long ball and they were Like that's never gonna happen. I was like, well,
I mean I I have a positive win percentage and it's pop, you know,
and my strategy is positive, right? So yeah,
let you know a little bit less frequency, but it's not like i'm taking,
you know I'm, not taking trades, right?
I took like 60 trades in a couple months,
which is a lot How many trades do you think you were winning?
What was your win percentage do you think yeah around 80? Wow Yeah, well,
I mean dude this season was insane.
I don't think it's going to be that high I think it'll probably settle more around
like this 70 percent range,
but like yeah around 80 Um and so hodge like You know,
you've placed I think honestly,
I think you've placed officially more earnings trades than I have and you know a
lot of traders,
um They kind of get stuck like really understanding Uh getting better and like building
a business, right?
Because like I feel like the way you're talking about it right now is like you're
talking about your business, right? There's always going to be earnings.
You're always going to be employed um You know,
so and you're like constantly working on that business You know,
so you've let's say done 500 earnings trades.
Um and like from all that experience,
you know from where you were when you started out Trying to build this business
to where you are now What like what have you learned like what are some of the important
things you've learned along that journey of building that business Yeah um uh Probably
probably too much to like just straight up like pontificate here, right?
Like a lot. Um,
but like just high level um Knowing your edge backwards and forwards, right?
So That's one thing. Um You gotta know when things don't seem right,
right like but We got an earnings trader in the making yeah,
that's right uh so So you I mean But knowing when things don't seem right uh you
know in like cause for more like,
uh Experimentation and like digging into like fundamentals and everything that kind
of comes just with like trading a bunch of trades, right? You're kind of like,
okay. This just doesn't this doesn't feel right, right?
So that just comes with like, uh familiarity with the markets,
but knowing your edge backwards and forwards I think is really really important
because new things are going to come into the market new like Strategies and ways
of thinking about things and each season's different and stuff like that So knowing
things backwards and forwards and knowing why your edge is there knowing why you
have an advantage there um So that you can continue to isolate that right?
So we we dropped the wings here recently and when I say wing,
I mean I when I say we like I literally mean Me I talked to some guys about it,
right? So i'm talking to these guys and i'm like,
hey I think i'm gonna drop the wings. I think this is what i'm gonna do, right?
Neil thought I was off my rocker, right?
Neil was like hutch don't do this Don't don't drop the wings right and I was like,
here's the here's the thing. Here's my logic, right?
And that was all about isolating my advantage, right?
I felt like the wings were costing me too much I felt like they were reducing my
edge on on execution on fill execution And so it's about isolating my edge because
I know my edge like I know my advantage when it comes to that trade um,
and then finally probably uh if you see a A banger like if you like if you see like
a okay can't miss trade Never gonna be 100% Prop, you know,
i'm never gonna be 100% sure but like a pre-release, right?
We had a couple pre-releases this season,
which i'm sure we're gonna talk about on this uh like coals Which was my biggest
pnl ever on a trade uh That was a pre-release our our our conviction on that trade
was so high Like I poured through all the releases I worked my ass off on that trade.
My conviction was so high and I got my chips in the middle, right?
So if i'm up against jordan heads up in a poker match and I have the nuts and he's
coming out strong I'm doing absolutely everything I can to get all of the chips
in the middle, right? And so and so like i'm selling things.
I was doing this with coal. I'm selling things.
I'm shedding leverage I'm shedding my margin, right?
I'm getting it all in i'm figuring out what can go wrong and i'm hedging that right
i'm getting it all in. Um,
so being able to find The banger trade and and really really really press on it.
Um, so and that's that's recently learned um, so Yeah, so I guess uh,
I guess you're not a fan of those people i'd say, uh,
Talk about the two percent rule Man,
I I mean I follow a percent rule for max loss, right?
So but that's on my like normal earnings trade, right?
And I mean when when I and and i'll walk you through that cold straight,
you know, i'll i'll talk about it later Uh, you know,
I can walk through that cold straight I was taking probably 10% risk like the max
loss on that trade was probably 10% risk on my account which is large right is is
large for a For for a trader,
I think that's that's that's that's large but like yeah,
I mean it I But I was using all of my available margin to get to that 10% too because
I was selling it naked So I was you know, anyways, but yeah, I mean,
I don't hate the people that say two percent Especially when you're your size jordan
with your account, right?
Like two percent is still sizable and you're taking you can take pretty much any
trade that the market throws out there any structure It doesn't matter with two
percent of your account, right? so I don't I don't hate them, but I mean Yeah,
it's being able to push it, you know,
push it all in Follow for your for your earnings trading.
How did you pick that percent? Uh, oh the percent rule Yeah,
like the rule that you follow for your trading right?
Is it arbitrary or did you? Factor something in this decision. Yeah Uh, yeah,
I mean loosely based off of some of the things that I read and listened to you guys
about kelly Criterion, right? So that three to five percent max loss um,
you know being ideal like that's just kind of In general in general some respected
traders that I read uh that I listen to uh that talk about Long-term betting strategies
say that that three to five percent is is is pretty safe Um,
and I feel confident in my edge.
And so I typically go five about five percent But you're naked on these positions.
Yeah, how are you pricing that three to five percent? Yeah. Yeah,
so i'm stressing the position um,
so i'm taking what I do for my stress is I load up my proposed position into thinkorswim
And then I stress it to the biggest move that that uh,
Security has had on earnings ever so I go through it doesn't matter season either
okay,
so we're looking at one cue data right now like I'm looking like if if this thing
moved twenty percent four cue two years ago That's the one i'm taking right?
So if that thing took twenty percent i'm taking that twenty percent i'm stressing
this to twenty percent um I don't stress vols upwards Um,
because i'm already i'm already selling into beak. I mean steep,
uh backwardization and so I don't think Vol really increases after this event very
much That's a little uh,
that's a little nuance and a little complicated so I can circle back around to that
But i'm not stressing balls up, but I am stressing move, right?
So i'm stressing biggest move ever and then I take so I take one lot.
I literally do this This is what I do. I take the proposed trade.
I put it in I stress it to twenty percent Or whatever it is,
whatever that move is the biggest one for the security And then I take the loss
for that at that twenty percent move and I multiply that up to five percent of my
account That's my process Got it I like that new word beak.
It's a steep backwardation Yeah, that's uh,
that's what it is Uh hutch you actually you you touched on something there that
i'd actually like to chat about um, you said,
you know Neil said you were crazy right,
um How important do you think it is to have a team? Right and uh,
like a lot of traders think I gotta trade in the zone It's all about me,
you know me me me, but how important did you find it?
Like it is actually To have a team to be able to bounce ideas off someone Yeah,
dude so I don't want to give margin a big head here,
but like i've got i've got a man crush on our team like I think it's Probably the
probably the most important thing that has happened to me like on my trading career
Being able to have high level conversations With guys who are grinding it out And
being able to talk those things out. I'm an external processor too, right?
So like I I I back At I back into things As i'm talking like I do it all the time
And so being able to talk things out dude We were up until I mean my time almost
midnight last night talking about forward vols Right after that live like after
the live Which i'm sorry for everybody who wanted a technical live after last night.
This is not a technical live that one was but uh,
we were up to I was almost to midnight and i'm old, right? I'm,
almost 30 years old. I don't stay up until midnight, right?
And we were 29 29 So, I mean, yeah, so So I don't stay up until midnight.
We were talking about forward vols the whole time,
right and talking about Uh margins trade on uh on uh,
william sonoma He fucking crushed it, right? It was awesome,
and I didn't understand it And so we we talked about it and steve jumped in and
and being able to have high level conversations and really work out edges Is is
so huge and jordan doesn't answer his dms.
So I have to find somebody else Yeah margins margins a great resource there We'll
have to have them on one time Yeah um Okay.
So before we like really dive into uh Into the strategy and like,
uh you know what like what you're really doing, uh behind the scenes,
you know time commitment and um All that good stuff Um,
where do you think a lot of traders go wrong? Right?
Like we have we you know We have newer members in the group who are uh You know,
they want to get to a position where you are, right?
um And and what do you like?
What do you say to someone who is or maybe even maybe not someone else?
But if you were to talk to yourself You know when you were starting out like what
do you say to someone who's trying to grow a business?
We're trying to grow their business um so so Get data as fast as possible like good
data um and understand the data Um,
so that was I mean that transformed my trading just being able to have it and and
i'm an engineer I always i've known that data was important for a really long time.
But like but um, I dropped coding after grad school.
And so like I didn't really have a great way to process the data And a lot of the
like publicly available data on stuff like stock twits and you know I mean like
like like screeners like publicly, you know use screeners and everything.
They're just not they're not super reliable Um,
because they're not really processing the data from an operator's standpoint.
They're processing the data on an easy to understand standpoint um And so get good
reliable data um I'm,
probably preaching to the choir here for for people that are in pa but There's a
lot of new members Yeah, so so here's here's the thing.
Here's the thing these guys jordan and sean I remember so I remember right when
I got into pa And you guys started doing lives Back, then it was every night,
which I was like,
this isn't sustainable So i'm glad i'm glad that you guys went to three nights a
week. I think it's wise on your part Yeah,
I mean you're killing it like I was like dude when I when I started looking at the
data I was like, okay, this is this is pretty cool. Right?
And then the community is like, okay, you know,
we talk about trading That's cool, too Um,
and then and then and then you guys were like, hey,
we're gonna get on for an hour every night every day of the week And we're gonna
talk trading like you guys can ask questions.
We're gonna talk trading right when somebody is giving you that much time From a
business standpoint.
It's it's that much It's it's that much more time that you can see them fuck up
right like like from a from a business standpoint like Like if if I can make things
look shiny on the outside and they don't actually see that like i'm human Right,
and they see like my business from the outside and they're like, oh wow,
that's great, right? Uh, then then like it's easier to fool people, right?
But you guys are here Every single night going like hey, here's the thing.
I just took a huge drawdown, right?
That's how you know that they're a real trader, right?
So being in a community like this and people that are transparent and talk data
and talk um Talk trading talk the game right understand the game understand that
shit happens. Um, so Yeah, so that's so get good data get reliable data.
Honestly, I wish I would have never stopped coding Um, jordan's like yes,
I know But I was gonna say how much are we paying this guy? Sean?
He's really not boosting us up here, right?
Dude i'm sitting back. Yeah. No, so I mean Yeah, so anyways coding Um,
I I have a matlab background.
I wish I had transitioned that into r I mean that lab they say it's really easy
to transition into r but I didn't know jordan back then So he wasn't there to convince
me um, but uh, so that's that's what I would tell myself, uh,
And and where I see a lot of traders go wrong um I'm,
just going to use i'm going to use kind of an example um I mean,
i'm going to use an example and then i'll transition that into like a more like,
uh,
like broad like principle I see a lot of guys and I saw this last year when I first
started trading earnings, too Um,
I won't shout anybody out here but buying tight wings On earnings,
okay So like I I was telling guys about this when I was when I was trading a couple
seasons ago And I was really just starting to pick up into earnings Um,
and now i'm like after our talk Uh saturday I'm, like pounding.
I want to pound the table on this right? Buying tight wings reduces your edge.
Okay, so So I i'm seeing neil's messages pop up here. Uh, I Yes, neil.
No one listened to us.
So here I am with the stage and i'm gonna say listen to me So if you are if you're
looking at a trade that has eight percent implied move five percent average move
All the other stuff that I talked about steep backwardization good seasonality good
volume all the things that I was talking about, right? Uh,
no proclivity to move really big like all these things, right?
It's a great trade It's a it's a good trade you go to the chain and and you price
out the straddle you price out the wings and let's just say this is like a This
is like a mcdonald's. Okay, say this is a mcdonald's.
This is a big dollar stock It's like a $200 stock, right? And so you're like,
hey, I can't go naked on this. I'm gonna buy wings, right?
And so i'm buying the standard deviation on this thing is,
you know 18 20 bucks, right?
And so you start pricing out your five percent of your account blah blah blah You
go through your risk sizing all this stuff and you're like,
hey Like I can't I can't put on this trade because my my wings I have to take them
out here And that means my risk is too big on this trade. Okay?
What people were doing was tightening their wings in so that they could make the
trade based on their risk tolerance But what you did when you brought that in is
you reduced the move?
That you're covering You're that you're selling that ball around that move.
And so now you're selling a you're selling a six percent Move right or a five percent
move, right?
You're reducing that edge sometimes even a three or four percent move if you tighten
them enough, right?
And so and so that's the move that you're covering there where you're looking at
the data and saying Oh, well, i'm good out to an eight percent move,
but your structure doesn't reflect that right?
And so and so And so you got to look at your coverage If you're going out there
and buying vol you got to look at your coverage That's what that's what convinced
me to go start going naked, right?
Because sometimes I can get more like I can get that strangle and I can get more
than the implied move out there Um,
and so and so while you're struggling to get out of your wings Because the stock
moved six percent and you're only covering six percent and then you're wondering
why you broke even I i'm i'm covering eight percent and i've got my two percent
edge and i'm scalping that ball right there and i'm i'm loving life right Um,
so because the six percent is a pancake to me, right?
Six percent is a pancake to you, right?
So understanding and so here's my bigger principle, right?
Understand your edge Understand what your you know,
your structure there your structure has to reflect your advantage, right?
Does that make sense? I feel like I kind of rambled there. No, dude,
that's perfect Uh,
look at your structure and does that express the view that you that you think is
going to happen? Yeah, exactly.
I I know pernab was having some issues with that. Um, and what do you like,
uh hutch? So um What about the people that buy the wings? Is there anything?
When when they're going to buy wings, is there anything they should be wary of?
Let's say they're doing a two a three sd wing because or two and a half sd because
you know,
they can't short naked Um What do you say to people buying those wings? Yeah,
sure. So pay attention to skew That's a big thing that I was looking at right?
So if you're if you have a smiley skew So for any of the new people if you're looking
at the skew graph and you pull up the equity on the vol insights And the and the
skew goes make sure that i'm in the middle here and the skew goes like this,
right? It's smiley.
That means that at the money has a lower vol right and it skews outward So the farther
you go out on the wings the vol is more expensive Right.
And so when you're buying wings into skew,
you need to go farther out I would also consider when you're going three standard
deviations out That's going to take out a lot of the equities that you can trade,
right?
Because the volume is going to be at the money and you're going out very very far
So make sure you're looking at volume out there at the wings, right?
If there's only one contract that traded today on the wings It's not enough right
So I would look at the volume.
I would look at the skew and then I would consider from a from a uh Like a uh a
fill standpoint like a like a execution standpoint consider Selling the iron condor
buying those wings and then just and then just assuming that those wings are transaction
costs like Unless it blows out right unless it blows out and then your wing is super
valuable, right?
Then make sure you get a good fill on that but consider and look into um,
look into Selling the iron condor and then when it comes the next morning and your
edge is played out Then just buying back the straddle make sure you get a great
fill on that And then and then you know,
take your time getting out of the wings Maybe even let them go,
you know to back down to zero Um,
because you don't want to you don't want to pull it put in a whole order for the
iron condor Not get filled on a market maker perspective because your wings are
shitty, right?
And so if your wings are holding up your fill getting out of the trade Then you
might get fucked on the on the straddle, right?
So consider lagging out of it That's what they would say is lagging out of it leg
out of the straddle and then leg out of the wings Um, I would just consider it.
I'm not saying do it. I'm saying look at it Um,
you guys notice how the I just want to bring to attention hutch the way you're talking
about this, right? Like, you know every corner of your business.
Uh I think that's so important right like this is so different especially to a lot
of the new members here Uh, it's so different the way hutch is talking about.
Uh About this, right? It's like he knows every corner Of you know,
where like we're talking transaction costs.
We're talking execution We're talking, you know,
the vol space all that stuff like he knows every corner.
Uh Of this business model,
right and I I think that's so so important to understand as a trader um Yeah,
so, you know hutch the trade-off Yeah,
the trade-off there is you sometimes you wake up in a cold sweat thinking about
salesforce blowing out five standard deviations, right?
Every good business is worried about their competitor, right? Yeah,
that's right Um Okay,
so hutch you you mentioned there like for someone who is Uh,
who has a smaller account let's say right, you know,
they can't trade those they can't trade those ones, right? Yeah, you know,
so they bring the wings in so it can fit in their account size What's the deal there?
Yeah, right. I got a five thousand dollar account. I want to trade earnings.
What's the deal? Yeah Yeah, for sure Is pranav on this live?
um Dang it I hope he I hope he listens to the I hope he listens to the replay I
like pranav a lot. I think he's gonna be a great trader one day.
I I really do I I know he thinks that I hate him,
but I don't um so We will cut that we will we will cut that part out.
We'll let me So I I don't and I think this is a funny question for me too because
I don't think I have the biggest account Or anywhere close to it, right?
So i'm trading with like fifty thousand dollars, right?
So i'm i'm sure that there's guys in here with 100 150 200 thousand dollars,
right?
I I i'm pretty confident of that actually So so i'm i'm speaking from a practitioner
standpoint on this like i'm growing a smaller account too, right?
um So I think that the biggest thing so first of all, I would say, uh,
literally trade paper and then Trade paper work out your edge, right?
Start to understand it While you do that understand that paper trading the fills
are really really easy Okay,
so I was taking everything under the sun on a paper account and I like just like
blew it blew,
you know Like I I mean I was killing it right and it was because all my fills were
cream Like it was it was super easy, right?
And then I went to live and I had a had a tough time, right?
and I said there was a there was a learning transition there,
so I'll say that with a caveat but but trade paper first, right?
when you when you're in a small account to work out your edge and I say that I want
to start with that because um because I think That most everybody in this group
maybe with the exception of a few is like under 35 I would say like under 35 under
40. I don't think we have too many people older than that Maybe i'm wrong,
but I think I think that mostly it's a younger crowd.
So what you're Somebody said I'd be old We have steve b here isn't steve b like
50 something dude,
he sounds like it for sure You're talking about bonds today Uh, no,
I mean i'm not i'm not alienating i'm not alienating older older people but but
the reason why I say that a majority of the people being younger is because Is because
like i'm sure that they have other areas of their financial life that they want
to put money to right?
Buy a house buy a car Uh fund a retirement account uh buy some long-term indexes
in and and uh And pay down debts pay on student loans like you're talking about
like a multi-faceted so looking just looking at it from like a a personal financial
standpoint You're got you've got to look at your trading account and say hey,
how much do I want to put into this trading account? right and so um,
and so you got it,
so I would say like Understanding your edge is really important because like for
me right now from where for where i'm at with my edge and um and understanding How
well i'm doing and why i'm doing well and everything I'm,
like i'm like trying to find money under the couch cushions right to put into my
trading account So I think I think a difficulty for someone who's growing an account
Is convincing yourself that putting money into the account is going to be a worthwhile
investment Right.
So an investment up here that you're learning a new strategy of making money,
right? Um, and also like a financial, uh incident, right?
So so you got to convince yourself that it's a good idea to put money into this
account before you start Not contributing to your 401k to put money into your retirement
account, right? Like you have to convince yourself.
It's a good idea um Secondly,
I would say I mean I would I would lean back on I would lean back on um Daniel yeah
Yes,
I that was that's funny because that's an example of something that I did recently
and he's reaming me about it I stopped putting money into my 401k.
Um uh to put more into my trading account, um, so So yeah, I mean Is that good?
Is that I feel like I answered the question. Is that? Yeah Dude,
I think that's that's great. And uh, you know, you know,
you're doing well when you want to add money into your account, right?
You know a lot of times we have traders say like how much should I start with?
you know,
like i'm only gonna put in five thousand dollars and it's like It's kind of like,
you're going to the casino with five thousand dollars knowing you're gonna lose
it, right?
You know start off understanding your business like and then you know as you get
better and better You want to start allocating capital towards it, right?
Like any good any good business? Yeah No, I I'll piggyback off of that too.
Like figure out like it's not bad to start with five thousand dollars But or a small
amount whatever the relative small amount is, right?
it's not bad to start with a small amount but like Learn your learn your strategy
and understand if that's a lot or a little Right.
So like like you said like somebody trying to sell naked on earnings You can't do
that with under ten thousand dollar account.
You just can't do it It doesn't make sense, right?
You're gonna have to put your whole account on every single trade and so learn but
if you're gonna buy If you're gonna so Sean did a live on buying flies right out
of money flies with like a with like a $3,500 account, right?
So like those out of the money flies if you're buying for a hundred two hundred
whatever,
you know 50 bucks here flies here and that's the strategy that you really like and
you start to understand it Great that you can start with a smaller account on that.
So understand the structure that you're trading understand margin Understand the
business before you understand how much you're gonna put into it And then I would
just say like learn right learn what good trading is learn betting strategies learn
statistics Listen to these guys every single night and and then build,
you know Build your confidence so that you can build your account and have confidence
putting money onto it, right? I I put I put Dude,
I put everything on that cold straight and it was because everything I learned up
to that point was like screaming in my head like this is a huge opportunity,
right?
and we smashed it right and so But that was only because I learned up until that
point and I built confidence and I put and I put money into the account I was ready
for it, right? Yeah, it's funny.
Yeah My checking's account is zero My 401k has zero dollars in it Every single dollar
that I own Is in is in my trading account and I you know,
every time I try as much money in there as possible Yeah, so thanks.
Thanks for that color Yeah,
when we go to when we go to Tim Timmy's to get a coffee Jordan has to move money
out of his great Dude,
I mean listen to that though like the dude has so much confidence in his craft Right
like people people say all the time Like okay,
so so what so what does Warren Buffett do and this is like totally different,
right?
Warren Buffett is not nowhere close to what we do But like what does Warren Buffett
do when he can't find a good investment?
He buys shares in his own company Because he knows that he's confident in his portfolio
And Berkshire Hathaway is going to perform over the long run, right?
And so where if I come into some cash right from whatever is going on businesses
return on investment, whatever If I come into some cash,
what what's the first thing that comes on my trading account?
That's where my confidence is, right? Um, so yeah, so anyways, oh, yeah,
man um So hutch rolling off of that Yeah What I know you're a cowboy, right?
I know you're a cowboy but Besides that hutch What do you think makes you different
than all most of the traders out there, right?
Like you you know the rule 99 people lose money and I I don't think it's that bad
But when it comes to like actually trading an option,
it's probably extremely high like I'd say plus 90% of people in the long run Are
gonna lose money What do you think?
What makes you different than all these people out there?
so um I think that my edge personally And I've taken some time to think about this
like because I've thought about this before before you're even asking me um Because
there's a freaking ton of smart people in this group And I know that this group
is a very small fraction of the competition that's out there, right?
so like So like it can't just be data. A lot of people have data, right?
It can't just be like execution because i'm fucking using tos.
I don't have a bloomberg, right? You know what? I mean, you know, you know,
there's there's people out there that have a lot more tools than I do, right?
so um I think that my I think that and i'm not saying that this puts me above All
the traders out there.
I think that it gives me I think that it keeps me going keeps me in the game I think
I think my advantage here is the ability to get up off the dirt and keep trading
Um,
so you're in a you're in a drawdown and I shake it off and I make another trade
So I have i've been in conversations with guys Working out grinding out earning
strategies when we're talking about different pieces of the puzzle and we take a
We take one on the chin right And then and then the person i'm talking to or whoever
that we're i'm gaming this strategy out with They're like, oh dude.
I need to sit one out, right? Well,
here's the thing your back test that told you that this was a profitable strategy.
It didn't sit one out Right that back test didn't sit one out.
It took the next trade So you need to you need to make sure that your position sizing
is right So that when you take one on the chin that you're still in the game Okay,
so that's important, right?
You need to make sure that the money is still there, right?
And then also you need to make sure that you can get over your bias of loss aversion
and and get up off the dirt and and and and uh And and make and make the trade make
the next trade There's been so many times when I took one on the chin I saw somebody
sit out the next one and i'm like, hey, dude, there's a trade here.
Let's do it It's even better than the one yesterday.
Like we it was a positive expected value yesterday It's it's a positive expected
value today and i'm taking it and they're sitting out and I make back my loss Right,
like your your back test doesn't sit out it trades no matter what It doesn't have
loss aversion, right?
And so to make sure that your real life trading Matches your back test of what told
you was profitable. You have to keep going, right? I think it comes back.
I growing up.
I played baseball and so like that was I played other sports But like that was my
sport, uh, and I was a pitcher and my dad always told me next pitch, right?
You throw a bad one next pitch, right?
You can't the the last pitch is already gone. You gotta throw the next one,
right?
And so I think that just that was ingrained in me I think I know a lot of I know
a lot of Guys have sports backgrounds and girls too girls have sports backgrounds.
It gives them a competitive edge, right?
It gives them like a mindset that they can bring to trading and business and all
those things, right? um, so I would yeah,
I would just say I would say next pitch like just move on. Let's you know,
get the next one Very nice. Very nice. Uh,
i've got two last questions for you here, buddy Okay, so one is if you uh,
if you want Can you maybe disclose some of um?
uh your uh Pre-releases or what that what that means to you and also would you say
that is the biggest?
uh One of the biggest uh things that you found or you know,
maybe you can try a little bit more about strategy Pre-releases is proprietary No,
i'm kidding, uh, what'd you say sean Spoken like a good trader. Yeah,
that's right.
That's right You don't need to give any secret sauce where you can say,
uh that uh, your firm cannot uh The earnings boys, uh choose to not comment.
No, i'm kidding. I'm definitely gonna uh, Uh, yeah,
daniel daniel and marjorie and steve are gonna be mad at me. Uh,
but it's okay Uh pre-releases. So yeah, so that's dude.
That's a huge Huge edge you gotta have time right?
So jordan when you when you revealed it to us So I will say too.
I did not find pre-releases jordan told me about it, but I spent some time,
you know Refining it. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah making it better, right?
So we and we take yeah And now jordan expects us to give us give him the releases
since he came up with the strategy, right? uh, but yeah,
so pre-releases If anybody was paying attention this quarter, um, uh,
a lot of retail companies pre-released Uh,
that's because of covid obviously retail took it on the chin because of covid and
a lot of them were then they were reporting their 4q year-end Stuff right their
numbers for the whole year of 2020 Right.
So a lot of them pre-released So that they didn't get smashed, right?
So basically what I did is I went through the tickers and this takes a fuck ton
of time, right? So I went through the tickers Um,
and when we found out that retail was kind of the sector doing it then I was looking
at all the retail ones, right? Margin does this too, right?
We spend a lot of time doing this We look and see if there's any sort of press release
That would insinuate a pre-release so so, uh,
the the words that you're looking for are business update or Sometimes it's sales
update, but you have to be careful with sales updates.
Sometimes companies do sales updates all the time So if a company always does a
sales update, it's not an edge, right?
It's always there market's expecting it um the ones that you're really loving are
Preliminary results, right? If you see preliminary results,
like i'm reading that whole press release like i'm looking at it In detail i'm going
back. I also like to go back two to three years predominantly three Um,
and if the investor relations page allows me to so also I don't go on yahoo finance
Or google or anything like that i'm going to i'm literally googling I'm,
i'm googling cole's investor relations.
I'm going to the investor relations page.
I'm looking at their actual pre-release I'm bringing up the pdf that's posted online
on their website and i'm reading it. Okay um I look to see if they do this,
right if they do pre-releases ever A lot of these retail companies they did they've
never done one Then they did one right when covet happened then they did one for
the year-end results, right?
And so the theory behind pre-releases is they will typically do it a month to two
months before their earnings report Okay,
and so when that happens the market is going to price in what the numbers are Okay,
um,
and so you're going to be they're going to the market's going to price in uh,
what the numbers are I see neil's question.
I'll go ahead and go ahead and hit it what i'm looking for in these pre-releases
is Is that they hit a lot of the numbers?
that They are going to talk about if they give earnings per share if they give sales
And revenue if they get give net sales if they give depending on the company like
capex expenditures Whatever right if they give any sort of forecast, right?
And a lot of these so one thing that uh,
one thing that american eagle didn't realize so we did american eagle I think everybody
pretty much got out unscathed on that,
but it didn't end up being a very profitable trade And they pre-released was because
they didn't put their e-commerce sales In the pre-release and we're pretty sure
that the e-commerce sales because they grew was what blew it out, right?
So so i'm looking for a holistic Report of the numbers.
It doesn't have to be like,
oh if they didn't do earnings per share then i don't take it, right?
It's not that like minute But um, i'm looking for a i'm looking for uh,
like I I want them to give a full report, right?
If they just give sales It's not that much of an edge right like people probably
had a pretty good idea of sales anyways So then what the what happens the mechanics
of it is the market prices it in a month to two months before the event And then
and then we also want to see So this is a thing for anybody listening to me.
That's like a new new person here Then you're thinking okay,
okay like your mindset, okay,
if I see a pre-release i'm selling vol that's not true, right?
So if I see a pre-release and then I also want a build up in the implied move and
the event vol going up To it as well.
Sometimes the market will overlook these things because it's hard to find them,
right?
So the company will give it give give the market the numbers and the numbers are
relatively known And so the numbers are going to be reflected in the analyst reports
Okay,
so the data that's out there on the company is going to be is going to be there,
right? And then the market overlooks that fact, right and they're like,
okay Uh coles is going to report earnings What do we think it's going to be and
the analysts are like it's going to be this this and this because they already know
Right.
It was in the pre-release And so then the market builds up this event vol into the
into the security into the term structure We sell the shit out of it, right?
Because because the numbers are going to be exactly what the analysts are saying
or close to it, right? There's a risk there, right?
There's a risk that there was like a quarter Or whatever,
you know a month or whatever that they those numbers changed and it was different
or whatever But um, i'm not saying this these are without risk,
but the risk is muted Uh because of our confidence in the numbers that they're about
to report. Um, so, uh, so yeah Does that is that is that a good explanation,
okay Yeah, I think that's really good.
And I I I know we're we're running out of time here I just want to say something
super important that hutch. Um,
Mentioned there was kind of like a read between the lines kind of thing if you were
paying attention And it's probably the most important thing that is that is going
to come out of this. Uh,
uh this live in my opinion What hutch said about american eagle there,
so I really want if you guys could pay attention to this.
This is super important hutch took a bet on american eagle And it wasn't the greatest
trade right, you know, he made a little money Maybe he lost a little money,
but he didn't just go on to the next trade He sat there and said what went wrong?
And he looked into it and he realized that they didn't give the e-commerce number
and now he's going to take that idea And move it forward and all of a sudden his
business just got better Right,
and that is the most important thing in my opinion when you want to become profitable
trader It's not that you know,
you saw a breakout and he said oh you go back and then there's like kind of like
Wishy-washy kind of hindsight bias thing going on.
It's like no This is what happened and I realized that okay This is actually important
for this company and now I can take those ideas And move it forward and all of a
sudden his business just got better and I think that is so important That you mentioned
that hutch Yeah, uh shout out to margin. He found that uh,
but we talked about it. Yeah We built it forward, right? Yeah, so so Yeah,
more more more more a pub on the team, right? Uh,
but if we're running out of time,
I want to do we have time for some for these questions here?
I I got some guys that messaged me some questions. Let's do um, okay Okay,
cool Sean you want to open up? I think we're good for time. If uh,
if you want to uh,
one more question jordan I was just gonna ask a super quick question about uh,
some of your um, uh,
The other sources that you've learned from because obviously,
you know besides pa But maybe if you can just post you know If we're a rush for
time right now,
maybe you can just post in a group some of the best sources that i've taught you
Yeah Uh, I don't have a lot of resources for for that. I mean, um,
I I think dude I think that I think that everything that you guys have put forward
in the uh, I I went back and read laws of trading by gustin again Um,
I got it on audiobook this time. Um, dude,
that's a incredible book Right when you're talking about business when you're talking
about building trading as a business, dude,
he talks about uh Uh tech debt soft like coding debt.
He talks about transaction costs. He talks about dude.
He talks about everything in that book Freaking incredible book.
I I it's it's really gonna I think that you guys have a lot of great resources here
I mean and just like I mean going down the youtube hole of eun sinclair, right?
Like going like,
you know getting these names they already have like a like a a stamp of approval,
right? And just just just dig deeper, right?
Just be curious about those things and then you know,
this is cheating this is cheating because I found these guys through pa but like
There there are there are fucking smart guys in this group like really smart guys
um and that know how to code that know how to That know how to like like eric eric
eric spent some time as a professional poker player Right,
like a lot of guys don't know that right if there's anybody to talk about positive
ev and and and uh, And betting edge. It's him. You know what I mean? Like So,
I mean there's there's really smart guys in this group steve's, you know,
steve's smart kyle smart daniel smart Um,
you know all these guys i'm sure i'm missing 20,
but you know all those are the guys that I talk to a lot What's that?
For now for now in there. Yeah,
pranav pranav will be smart when he gets into his teenage years. Yeah Yeah,
so anyway, so okay i'm gonna i'm gonna hit these questions real quick Yeah,
that's what I told these guys how to answer them Um,
if anyone else on the live right now has questions drop them in the chat.
We'll get to them as well Yeah,
so marcos wanted to know Metrics and criteria for selecting trades.
I think I pretty well hit that right like Like all that I went over it at the beginning
So marcos if you didn't see that you're still recording right sean? Yep.
We're good. Yeah Okay,
so I went over that at the beginning So if you didn't catch it go, uh,
I went through pretty much every single step that I go through Um,
and that's what that was like a lot of these questions So it's kind of just metrics
and criteria I do want to i'll circle back to that criteria and then i'll hit this
one question by arnold. Um,
He said I see sometimes your summary of trades and you take trades that don't have
a lot of volume The reason I don't take those is because i'm scared that the spread
will be too big and i'll be stuck in that position Uh, so it's a good point.
Um, so when i'm looking at liquidity, okay,
so liquidity is a bigger topic I'm looking at volume and i'm looking at spread Okay,
so those are different, right?
One one leads into the other sometimes if it's low volume,
there will be wide spreads, right? That's isn't always the case though.
So you need to look at both of them. Okay,
sometimes there's a lot of There's a lot of volume,
but the spread is still kind of wide, right?
So be careful there I don't avoid wide spreads. I know that Sean,
it's probably going to hit me with a wet noodle after this,
but I don't avoid wide spreads I also I don't sort Um,
I don't sort based on total option volume.
I go to the chain So a lot of guys a lot of guys when they're looking for earnings
trades They will sort in the terminal for total options volume And they'll say anything
below this i'm not even looking at it I look at those and then I go to the chain
and I see that at the money actual volume in my brokerage Okay,
so and then I size out the position I say,
okay How big am I going to get into this position based on my risk tolerances?
And then I see what percentage of the volume that i'm going to be If i'm going to
sell like three or four contracts and there was a hundred traded i'm good i'm fine
I feel comfortable with that, right?
But I also have a year under my under my belt of fill execution and earning straights,
right? So if you're not comfortable with that then,
you know stick to the higher volume, uh, but I like I told jordan. Um,
Like I told jordan Uh, I like to I like to play in that middle market.
I'm not selling vol on nike I'm not selling vol on fedex.
Those were two that happened today, right?
That's just something that I've found that like a lot of people are watching those
names And I just don't feel like I have an advantage there So i'm gonna play in
those middle market go look at the tickers that i'm selling, right?
Some of those companies you don't know the tickers off the top of your head And
I went and looked at the volume and they were fine and I got out of it just fine
That's another reason that I don't take wings is because I don't want to fool with
wing wing liquidity That's hard to say wing liquidity.
I I don't want to fool with it. So I sell that the money, right?
So that I can get out better. Um, so Uh,
I I I understand where my edge is and and where I want to play and in the market
I found myself like a little niche and then I built everything around it to to to
capitalize on it. So Uh, we got some uh, cool words coming out of this.
Uh podcast. Hey, we got uh, Meek, we got wiggly. Um,
i'm surprised to see what else is going to be coming out of here Yeah,
I brought the bottle my whiskey bottle over here so that I could keep filling right
as I talk Yeah I thought you were grabbing your nose there. Yeah. No, no. No,
it's a bottle. Yeah, it's a bottle Uh,
so what does your research process look like that was from braun braun,
I think I saw braun uh chat Do do I feel like I I answered that?
dude You drop drop something in here if I if I answered that I feel like I did I
think for sure Went in pretty much quite a lot of detail there. Okay. Okay. Uh,
yeah. Okay. You got already. Okay good. Uh,
so Can you automate any of this this is another one of braun's questions can you
automate any of this man I would like to um It's kind of like those guys that like
the manual process of their coffee in the morning,
right the pour over like I like You know,
I like the process of going through it really feeling out the market.
I have I have learned a lot in the manual process Me and daniel have kicked back
and forth daniel has worked on it.
I have not about uh Sorting these tickers and then being able to kind of port them
over to the terminal to see what's in the terminal what's not because um Because
not to point out the terminal's weaknesses,
but the earnings date feature does it doesn't work very well, right?
So what I do is I go to a website called earnings whispers And I just go down the
calendar.
It's never failed me Maybe I missed something and I don't know it's failed me,
but it's never failed me on earning states I think it's a great.
I think it's a great resource. So that's what I use there. Um,
And practically none of this is automated for me. It's all manual.
Um What are your plans for upcoming lull and earnings a lot of whiskey i'm gonna
be drinking a lot Um, no, I mean it seriously though. I uh,
I take time during earning seasons to um I take time during earnings scenes to read
uh to process I you know,
try to do one-to-ones with jordan talk through things um Uh,
just to process to a new edge new strategy Um, you know,
I do other things right more one-off type trades or whatever. So, um, Yeah,
so I I do other things I see a pranav made an appearance. Thanks, dude,
like right at the end here not listening to anything Uh popped in a really really
funny question, so it's all good How old are you? Uh, do you uh Yeah, yeah,
do you do you play lead up to event braun? I don't man. Um, uh,
jordan used to have a Feature,
what did you call that jordan the lead up vol like what the vol of the forecast
vol? Yeah Yeah, so the forecast of earnings vol we used to have that feature.
Um, I I personally didn't love it. Daniel loved it. Um,
he liked to he liked to fool around with it and everything Um,
I I don't I really don't play lead up and vol I like the event.
I like the rush Right. I like to be in and out in a day. Um,
Uh percent wins and losses I hit this earlier Um, but yeah,
I think this season so my long vol was about 70 percent win rate Uh short vol was
about 80 percent win rate. I think that is high.
I think short vol win rate's going to come down um So and maybe i'm just scared
about the mac truck that's coming my way right the five standard deviation move,
uh, It's fine. I mean it'll happen right? It'll be a bad day. But uh, but I uh,
I know that um I know that Uh,
I know that I am capitalizing on risk ignition And if anybody doesn't know that
term read aaron brown's book red blooded risk Uh, jordan recommended it to me.
It's a fantastic book risk ignition is all about capitalizing on your risk Knowing
when the risk is going to happen right knowing when the bad thing is going to happen
But makes you sure when it goes good that you're capitalizing on it Um,
so that's what that's all about. Um, Anything else in the chat?
I think I hit all these Yeah, there's a couple here. Just give me one second.
Okay. Um, man. I love this man. This has been great so far Yeah, dude.
I've had fun So red's just uh asking how are you checking to see a stock's biggest
historical move And is that only for earnings dates? Yes. Yeah,
so earn it biggest earnings move big biggest earnings move ever, right?
So I am i'm going it's in the it's in the terminal.
So you go to the earnings tab bottom, right? it's a uh,
it's like a um bar chart of uh, Uh bar chart down in the bottom, right?
Um and uh, And uh, yeah,
just just like hover over the bars with the standard deviation moves Right,
and you'll find the biggest the biggest move ever You can also go into the moves
tab and just hover over them and figure out what the percent move was there You
can find it just there just to add to that reds. We look at the last 16 Uh,
so it's not like forever and ever but the thing is it's like we want to be stay
relevant, right?
Something that happened six years ago to a company or during the financial crisis
of the company. It's not really relevant today So that's uh,
I just want to point that out Yeah, red you're right.
It it does only go a couple years back.
That's what jordan was just saying Yeah,
so we want to make sure that we're we're relevant to what the company the company's
doing Oh, so, I mean if you want to go farther back and and scrape that data,
you know, I wouldn't fault you for it You know, I would just yeah, uh,
I I yeah, but that's that's what we look at.
It's been successful It's more than two years, right? Uh, three or four, uh,
three or four.
No greg just saying you only look two years back That's about three or four in the
terminal there.
So we got another one from trent Said when looking at historical moves for earnings
Do you weigh in the more recent events more than the further dated one?
We'll assume within the information you can see in the terminal If so,
how much more do you weight them? Yeah No,
I don't because I know that jordan has filtered out the last few years Um,
I know that he's filtered out the last few years And so I take all of that into
account, right? If I was looking at 10 years of data, i'd probably do that,
right? I'd probably be like, okay.
Well this happened 10 years ago What's happened in the last two years,
but we have pretty relevant data, right? Um,
and so I just I keep it to that Pranav said hutch be honest with us.
Do you take a shot of whiskey before each trade? Uh,
I do not um Usually at work So I don't I don't do that It's a good idea My wife
my wife,
did you hear my wife in the background she goes but it's a good idea You should
probably do that I think when we heard hutch's daughter saying daddy daddy.
I think she was coming over with a bottle of whiskey to yeah Yeah, yeah,
yeah Do we have any questions guys?
Super insightful lives Neil pnl members have any questions This guy don't be shy
Hutch is uh, hutch is a nice guy Yeah, dude,
except for if you're pranav Exactly, right?
Uh marco said how long do you take to investigate each trade? Yeah. Yeah,
that's a good question so um So during earning season any pretty much any time that
i'm not working during the day i'm working on I'm working on uh earnings,
right?
Like i'm i'm working on i'm working on sorting through companies thinking about
things Um,
so I mean I I spend I spend a lot of the day um Doing that uh for each trade specifically
it depends on the trade, right? If it's just a normal earnings trade,
man It it it only takes me five to ten minutes to go through the that ticker right
and kind of think about it If and if it like if I totally sort it out in the first
couple like filters or whatever Then I move on it takes me like 30 seconds,
right? um,
but you know if it's something that takes takes time to think about it,
you know five ten minutes and then I I really sort it out and then so So I also
work with a couple other guys too.
They're looking at the same data that I am right?
And so i'll post a list right i'll be like hey,
these are the things that I like I kind of feel like weren't Talking about right?
Um, so I work with my team these guys that I think are really really smart,
right? Um, and we talk about the tickers and hey, I didn't like that one Hey,
I didn't see that one, right?
and so we go kind of go back and forth that takes 20 or 30 minutes and then You
know,
and then we start talking about structures that takes a little bit structures takes
a take a long time, right?
You want to make sure you're covering the move you want to make sure that you're
selling good vol You want to make sure the chain is right with the data and i'm
verifying things at that point, right? So,
I mean sometime but it depends on the trade for pre-releases Dude,
so much time i'm reading i'm reading news releases I'm going through the investor
relations page making sure that they've never released before If I go two years
back and they have a release that looks like a pre-release i'm reading it It's probably
two to three pages of business jargon Which is in a ton right? But um,
if you do that two or three times a day, right?
It takes a little bit of time So pre-releases take they take time, dude.
I i've spent For that coles trade like to build the conviction Uh,
we dude we took hours,
you know talking about it Um building out structure making sure the vault the event
ball was there that the market was pricing it in all that stuff Took a long time
We got a question from uh from big dan here. Do you ever? Terminal looks good,
but the structure slash risk stress in thinkorswim doesn't Right,
so it's like the trade looks good you stress it out and you're like, uh,
maybe not actually or uh, vice versa Yeah Jordan,
do you want me to answer this? Yeah, yeah,
you you you say it And i'll be i'll be the one to say like sometimes there's flaws
in the data, right Let me look at you know,
2 000 tickers and or 1500 tickers and you know It's especially on the less liquid
names. Sometimes it could be a little bit shaky.
Yeah So I think one one thing specifically um is uh So that was so so yes,
the answer is yes Daniel asked that because he knew the answer right? Uh,
and and this is important to talk about and that's why I asked it right is you need
to verify your data That's a part of hammering out your edge, right?
Is I think this is what I think this is what it says Right.
I need to go and make sure that my brokerage is saying the same thing, right?
So one thing that I found,
uh kind of uh kind of trips up our data source a little bit and jordan,
you know I'm sure that you'll get better about this in the future. I Honestly,
I know you will you're constantly getting better at your data. But um,
but the term structure is a blend of tenors Okay,
so the tenors is expiration dates Okay,
so like so like if you have weeklies if you have weeklies On on a on an options
chain and you have a you have a 1 a 8 a 15 Right,
you have like every week you have a friday expiration Right on those tenors.
Um his His his uh,
his first dot right there on the term structure is going to be a blend of those
first two or three tenors Okay,
so so if you see a super steep Backwardization go to your go to your chain your
options chain and make sure that you're seeing that drop of fall from the front
week To the second week to the third week, right? um,
so so make sure you're verifying your data, um,
and then also um I will play around with straddles versus strangles to to make sure
that i'm covering Both upside vault like upside move and downside move Okay,
so sometimes you'll sell vol on something with high put skew Right,
and the puts are really expensive.
The calls are pretty cheap And so you're covering way more move on the downside
and you're not covering anything on the top side Okay. Well,
what if it rockets to the top side? You need to know that right?
You need to know that you're exposed to the top side So then then i'll play around
with the strangle. Maybe i'll go really far out in the calls or whatever,
right? um, so yeah Um, so yeah, the answer is yes,
and that's that's why Do you think your kids portfolio is outperforming neils?
No, I think neil's killing it.
He's not saying anything He's playing with grandma's money and he's doing earnings
date arbitrage. I think he's killing it I think he's doing pretty well,
too At least from what his grandma tells me he's doing pretty good Yeah,
grandma grandma just renewed contract she hasn't she hasn't uh,
she hasn't asked for her capital back so that's good. Yeah,
exactly Although that that that did sound a little suspect um So I guess sean we'll
wrap it up here I I can't believe we had 20 22 people stay all the way for an hour
and a half I think you're gonna start running these lives,
man People are staying out to chat with you, you know,
usually we're at 12 by the time nine o'clock comes around.
So Um anything else you want to add there? Much. Thanks, man.
This was unreal Unbelievable. Oh, yeah Dude, I had a ton of fun.
I really did I'm, uh, i'm glad that I finally got to the status,
you know that you guys brought me on I felt like I felt like that was a big,
you know moment in my career. So It's a long time coming.
It's been a long time of time, man. So Cool all right. Hey guys,
we're gonna wrap it up there post the live up tonight. Uh right after this so,
uh,
You know everyone else should watch it as well anyone who wasn't here Definitely
definitely re-watch for sure Thank you very much. You guys appreciate it.
Yeah See you,