Yes. We'll see. Okay, guys. So in this, in this lab,
we're going to be talking about constructing a portfolio.
And basically how we can improve ratio, meaning how we can improve our return,
our risk-adjusted returns. I know, right? Yeah.
You guys, you have to deal with that thing. I'm not talking about Jordan.
I'm talking about this line. Sorry about that. It's coming back.
Coming from the light up there. How we can improve our risk-adjusted returns,
which is our sharp ratio in a portfolio, right? So example,
let's say you want to,
let's say you want to build your long-term portfolio or you want to build a portfolio
that wants to outperform the market. Well,
you maybe can do better by not just buying equity, let's say S&P,
but maybe by buying S&P and bonds and leveraging that. Okay? Because usually,
you know, when S&P goes down, you know, bonds are usually going down as well,
right? So that's kind of offsetting your loss.
So therefore you can get leverage. And we're gonna talk all about that today.
We're gonna show examples. We're actually gonna build out a portfolio,
optimize it. You guys are gonna be able to see the weights through time.
It's gonna be very, very cool. I already have the back test already built in.
And thanks to Pulumi, he was helping me with this.
And the assets are chosen by Steven. So we're gonna go through this one by one.
But first, we're basically gonna start off very simple. Okay? So,
first thing we need to know. Is- Yeah, I'll figure it out. Okay.
So the first thing we have to understand, guys,
and so this is gonna be a longer line. This is gonna be probably a full hour.
But it's gonna be very informative. And you guys are,
I think you guys are gonna get a lot of value out of this one. So,
first thing we need to think about is our Sharpe ratio. Okay?
Sharpe, and I'm sure we've all heard this before. Oh,
I guess it's kind of hard. I think it's better on their end. Yeah. Okay,
that's good. Okay, so we got first thing about our Sharpe ratio.
And what our Sharpe ratio basically is, is our return. Okay? Yeah.
Maybe you have to- It's fine, it's fine. Yeah. Let me know, guys,
is it good or not good? No, no, lens is perfectly clean. All right, it's good.
I think it's good. Okay,
so the Sharpe ratio is equal to our return over our risk. Okay?
Our return over our risk. So, let's say, for example,
like usually in the market, so the S&P, for example, has a Sharpe ratio of 0.5.
Okay? This is the long-term Sharpe ratio of the S&P 500. Okay?
So what this means is, for every dollar of risk, for every dollar of return,
okay? You are, or for every dollar of risk, you are getting 50 cents. Okay? So,
for example, your, and risk here, is calculated as our standard deviation,
our volatility. Okay? So, a quick example. Our volatility might be 30%,
and our return is 15%. Okay? So that would be a Sharpe of 0.5. Okay?
Let me just get an eraser.
So, let's do exactly what the S&P usually is, right? The S&P, on average,
returns 9% a year.
Okay? 9% a year. And the volatility, on average, over the last, let's say,
10 years, is about 18%. Okay? So, our return is 9%, our risk is 18%,
our volatility. And so, therefore, we have a Sharpe ratio of 0.5. Okay?
Now let's look at a different example. Okay, let's look at ACB during the boom.
Okay? So ACB, let's say the return was, let's call it 100%. Okay?
But our volatility, we're gonna use a theoretical example, and, you know,
this is probably not too far off, is 300%. Okay? So here's ACB Sharpe.
Okay? We make 100%, but for every,
but we are basically getting a Sharpe of 0.3. Okay? 0.33.
So what does this mean? Well, what this means is,
we can get more leverage here, we can buy more S&P. Okay?
Let's say we go 10 S&P, we go S&P times 10, or let's say times 20. Okay?
So we get the same risk profile, but now our returns are much higher. Okay?
So we can think of the Sharpe ratio is normalizing our returns by our risk.
So now we're all in the same playing field. Right? So if you say, for example,
you might look at a fund, and the fund is, returns 25%. And you say, well,
that's pretty good. But when you look at his risk, he's doing, let's say 50%.
Right? So his Sharpe is only 0.5. But there's another fund out there,
who's returning, let's say 15%, but his risk is only 0.5. Right?
So now he has a Sharpe of three. So a Sharpe,
greater than one, is considered very good. Okay? And the high frequency guys,
I've seen Sharpe up to 10.
Okay? I've seen a Sharpe up to 10.
Any questions so far about this? It looks good.
We'll answer questions at the end. Okay. Okay. So,
how can we improve our Sharpe ratio? So let's go about talking about that.
Let me start with, why do we really care about Sharpe? Okay.
So the reason we care about Sharpe, and it's not the best,
it's not the best metric, because for example,
do we really care about upside volatility? Do we really,
if our portfolio is going like this,
do we really care about this? Right? So Sharpe ratio actually considers,
the up volatility as well. So there's other metrics called,
let's say the Kalmar ratio. Okay. The Kalmar ratio,
which basically looks at, our return, over our, max drawdown.
Okay. Our return over our max drawdown.
And this is usually a better metric to use, but you know,
the standard in the industry, is usually the Sharpe ratio.
So we're going to be talking about that for now. All right.
And it's the most easy to understand. Return over volatility.
So super quick, but is the return only like 5%? Oh, I think, okay, sorry guys.
If you guys are having your own conversation right now, we're going to,
I'm going to get back to all those, those questions later. Yeah.
We'll save the Q and A for the end. Okay. So how can we, how can we,
how can we do better? Right? So imagine we have,
how can we improve our Sharpe ratio? Well, imagine we have stock one. Okay.
Imagine we have the S&P. Okay. SPY.
And SPY gives us a Sharpe of 0.5. Okay. S&P gives us a Sharpe of 0.5. Now,
this is good. This is not bad. Right? This is what usually most investors get.
And then after transaction costs, this usually drops down quite a bit.
So even though this is, this is okay. Right.
And we always try to improve on this, of course. And that's the alpha, right?
Outperforming this on a risk adjusted basis, it's your alpha there.
So what we can do is, we can actually add an asset. Okay. Let's say TLT.
Okay. That let's say also has a Sharpe of, let's say 0.5. Okay.
But these are not correlated.
Okay. We'll say correlation is zero.
Okay. So we have, SPI, TLT, each having a Sharpe of 0.5,
but correlation is equal to zero. And so what this means is,
our portfolio is going to look something like this. Okay.
So let's say this is SPI. Going to use, and here we have TLT.
Okay. So when S&P is going through a drawdown,
our return on TLT is usually going up. Okay. And so our portfolio return,
now looks something like this.
Okay. So we have reduced our volatility, but our return stays the same.
So return, stays the same. Okay. So it's constant.
Okay. We'll say, we'll say our trade was return. It stays the same,
but our volatility, oops,
declines. Okay. So return stays the same,
but our volatility of the portfolio drops.
So meaning our Sharpe ratio increases.
And so what does this mean? What this means is we can add leverage.
We can add leverage here to this portfolio now. Right?
To get the same amount of risk as the S&P. Our new portfolio,
we can add more leverage, meaning higher return.
So now we're on the same playing field for the volatility of the portfolio,
because when you add leverage, you get more volatility. Right. When we add,
right.
So you could add enough leverage to bring it up to the same volatility as the S
&P. Exactly. Right.
So now you have S&P level volatility with a greater return because you diversified
with uncorrelated assets. Exactly. So now we have a higher Sharpe ratio,
meaning we get more leverage, meaning we get a higher risk adjusted return.
Okay. Same risk, higher return. Yeah. Same risk, higher return.
So how can we go about doing this now? How can we really graph this out?
And this is what we're going to call the efficient frontier.
Okay.
So here we're going to have our return.
Okay. And here we're going to have our risk.
Now let me ask you guys a question. Where do you guys want to be on this graph?
Where do you guys want to be on this graph here?
Exactly. Top left net. We want to be right up here.
We want zero risk and a very high return. Now, unfortunately,
this is not usually the case, but what we call here is the efficient frontier.
Okay. Looks something like this.
So let me ask you guys a question. Give me some stuff that is risky.
Give me some risky stuff here. Give me some anything.
And we're going to plot this on the graph here. So I'll start this out.
S&P 500. Actually, maybe I'll start out like lottery tickets. Lottery tickets.
This is going to be, I guess this would be...
It'd probably be down here, wouldn't it? Like low minimal risk. Yeah,
but the return is negative though. So maybe it'd be down here, right? Yeah,
it'd be off the graph. It'd be off the graph.
So like something like lottery ticket would be down here.
Where would the ERP be? Yeah, it'd be down here. A VRP? ERP.
Equity risk premium? Yeah.
Equity risk premium would be somewhere like right around here.
And then where would the VRP be? All right, around, let's say,
we'll just do arbitrary number. Right,
and then VRP would be a little bit higher here.
So we're trying to draw that line actually right now.
So we have the ERP here. Let me just label it. Okay, so ERP.
And we have maybe the VRP, a little bit more risk, a little bit higher return.
It's right here. Good. We'll call it VRP. We have gambling down here.
Okay, what else? What else do you guys have? What else would be out here?
Let's grab some more stuff here. Crypto, crypto. High risk,
high return potentially, right? Right up here.
What else we got?
Tesla. Tesla. Whoa, okay. Risk, really high return up here.
But really high risk. This is like all the way over here.
I can't go off the screen, so we'll go up here.
What about selling far out money puts? Would that just be the VRP or no? Yeah,
yeah, that'd be- Close enough, right? Yeah, well,
yeah. Selling far out money puts. It would probably be like here. Yeah.
Because it'd be in line with the VRP, but with huge blow up risk. Well,
it depends if it's leverage, right? If it's no leverage,
it'd be like somewhere here. So this would be the cash secured puts. Yeah.
What else guys? We'll do one more.
ACB. Oh, okay. High risk, no return. Yeah, yeah. That's down here guys, yeah.
That's down there. Okay. So now we have all these different items graphed,
okay? Now we can actually create a portfolio where,
so let me see if I can explain this properly.
So we have all these different types of equity,
all these different types of trading strategies, methodologies, assets,
whatever it is, right? All up here. Maybe we should put one more on there,
like gold or something. Okay. So gold is usually lower risk. And like,
I would say it's under a ERP.
Okay. So now here is all our different, now we can have a thing with this guys.
We can have so many different combinations of portfolios. Right?
We could have one combination, let's say 99% ACB and then 0.1% of the rest.
And that would be right over here, right? So this is 99% ACB.
Okay. Then we can have another one. Oh wait, cash. Cash is a good one.
Cash is no return, no risk. Right? We can have one that say is 100% cash,
right? And, or let's say 50% cash and whoops. So this is cash. Sorry guys.
Okay. We can have one that's 50% cash and 50% SPY.
And we would lie right around here. So we would call this,
let's say portfolio two. Okay. So here's another portfolio.
Now the thing is guys, there is an optimal portfolio. And when we say optimal,
we mean we can create a portfolio with all of these and give us the best risk adjusted
return. Okay. And it's not just one portfolio, actually.
We can actually make multiple portfolios. And all those portfolios,
those optimized portfolios are going to fall along this line.
Okay.
So for example,
we're going to do a couple of examples here so you guys can understand.
One optimal portfolio might be VRP, 33% VRP, 33% equity risk premium,
33% gold and 10% Tesla. Okay. And that's going to lie right around here.
Okay. And by combining these, because they are not correlated perfectly,
we can increase our sharp ratio. Okay. So basically this line right here, guys,
has the same sharp across the board. Okay.
The same sharp ratio is across this line. Okay.
But it's just how much risk do you want? How much return do you want?
But you're indifferent if you're here versus here.
You're taking on the same unit of risk for the dollar return as this one. Okay.
So far, so good. I don't know if you guys have any questions. It's all good.
I'm going to end the chat. Right. So this is the, let's say this,
so we have all these assets here and this line is our best sharp ratio.
Let's say, I don't know, let's say given these assets,
we can create a portfolio that has a sharp ratio of one. Okay.
Given all these assets right now,
we have a sharp ratio that has a portfolio of one. Okay.
Now let me ask you guys this question.
What's going to be the weighting of gambling in any of these portfolios?
Probably very, very, very small, right? Most likely zero,
but it could have a very small weighting if it's negatively correlated to some of
these names. Okay. So we can make thousands of portfolios.
Some of them are going to lie here,
but the best ones are going to lie along this line. Okay.
And these are the portfolios we want to be in. Okay.
Now this doesn't have to be portfolios though. Right.
Or this doesn't have to be assets. These could be strategies. Right.
And this is how we think about in terms of portfolio management is, well,
I'm a portfolio manager. Let's say I got a few traders under my belt.
Let's say I got Neil running earnings calendars.
I got Hutch running earnings vol. I got Steve B running some long vol.
We got R.E.A. running long vol. We got R.E.A. running long vol.
And so I allocate money to these traders and I'm allocating the money so that my
Sharpe ratio is going to be the highest in the total global book.
Okay. So far so good.
Okay. So now that we understand this, let's actually do an example. Okay.
Let's actually do an example that Pulumi and I worked on and Steve B gave us the
assets for. You guys, I hope this really makes sense to you guys.
Once you see this in real time in action, building a portfolio.
Let me share my screen and we're going to jump into it.
Okay.
So here's what we're going to do here, guys.
The first thing we're going to do is,
so what we did here is we basically made a portfolio. Okay.
We gathered some assets.
It's like we built some assets here and we gathered XLP, XLU,
GLD, SLV, USD CAD and USD Aussie. Okay. So we have five assets or sorry,
six assets. And we want to basically say, okay, well,
what is the best portfolio to make here? Given these assets we have,
what is the best portfolio to make? And how has the return been? If we've,
let's say consistently changed our view as the world moved forward. Okay.
And I know it's going to be a little bit of a tricky concept,
but we're going to dive into that. You guys are going to see the returns.
It's very, very interesting to see.
Okay. So here we go, guys. So first thing we do is we got the tickers.
Now we're going to build out the portfolio.
Okay. So here we go.
So what we're doing here, guys, first thing we're doing, we're going to,
we'll go through this step-by-step so you guys can see what's going on.
So first we're saying, we're going to do a long only portfolio first.
We're going to say the maximum of our portfolio,
we have to basically be 95% to 105% invested. So if we have a portfolio,
I'm going to need a marker. Yeah.
And an eraser. Yeah.
So if we had, if our portfolio is, let's say a hundred, a hundred that,
or let's say it's $10,000, or let's say we have 10K. Well,
at every given moment, we want to be,
we want to have 95% of our portfolio to a hundred percent,
105% of our portfolio invested. So that's 9.5K to 10.5K. Okay.
That's the first constraint.
So far so good.
Then our second constraint here is going to be that every single asset that we have
there has to have at least a minimum,
minimum weighting of 2% and a maximum weighting of 60%. So no portfolio,
so no asset in our portfolio can have less than 2% weighting.
So if we have 10K, we can't have a portfolio,
we can't have any asset that is less than 200. Okay.
We have to be invested by more than 200 bucks in each asset.
And we can't have an asset that is more than 60% of our portfolio.
So as a portfolio manager, I can't allocate 70% to Neil Gang. Okay.
It's too much. So 60% is the max I can allocate to Neil Gang.
And how'd you pick two in 60? Oh, just arbitrary number. Yeah. In real life,
we do some more, more complex. Yeah.
There'd be a way to actually optimize that. Yeah.
Okay. So here we go. So we got that now. So let's run those.
Okay. And now what we're going to optimize for is our Sharpe ratio. Our mean,
right? Our risk, our return over our risk.
Okay. And now this is a really cool part guys.
What this is going to do is it's going to create thousands of portfolios,
right? 1% ACB, 99% cash, 98% cash, 2% ACB.
It's going to create thousands of these portfolios and we're going to try to find
the best one.
Okay. So we're just going to take a second here, guys.
Bloomy, it was running a lot faster, man. What's going on here? Here we go.
So let's extract the weights. Okay. So you can see right now in our portfolio,
the optimal weight would be 17% invested in XLP, 2% in XLU, 14% in GLD,
2% in silver, 4% in USD CAD and 55% in USD Aussie dollar. Okay.
So you can see that right here, right? This is equal weight.
The yellow line is equal weight.
And you can see we're way overweight on USD Aussie dollar. Or USD CAD.
I know this is on USD CAD. So short CAD USD.
Okay. So now what we're going to do here, guys,
is we're going to do something really cool. Okay.
We'll do something really cool.
Yeah.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go back to 2007.
Okay. And what we're going to do is in 2008, okay.
We are going to look back on all the data from 2007 to 2008. Okay.
And we are going to say, what is the best portfolio?
Given these historical returns, what is the best portfolio? Okay.
And then from 2008 to 2009, we are going to hold that portfolio. Okay. So 2007,
2008, we're going to create the portfolio. In 2008 to 2009,
we're going to hold the portfolio. Okay. In 2009,
we're going to look back and say, okay, well, what was the data?
What was the best data here? Okay.
And we're going to make the new portfolio and then we're going to hold that again.
Okay. We're going to keep doing that all the way until today.
And actually guys, sorry, sorry, my apologies. We're actually doing,
we're actually rebalancing quarterly.
So right over here. Yeah, thanks man. Thanks dude.
Use the thick part of the line. Okay. So right over here, okay.
We're going to look back and say, what is the best portfolio?
We're going to look back 252 days, 252 business days.
And then we're going to move in time one quarter. And then the next quarter,
we're going to look back 252 days and we're going to rebuild the new portfolio and
hold that for another quarter. Okay. So we're going to rebalance quarterly.
So here we go. Okay.
So that's the training period and the rolling window and then the rebalance on the
quarters. So there's no look ahead bias.
And I think you guys are really going to like this next graph.
Let's give it a second to load.
All right.
Okay. Blue, what are you saying blue? What's going on? There's nothing wrong.
Oh, oh, thanks dude. Okay.
So right now we're going to chart the weights through time.
So you guys are really going to like this one. Okay.
It's going to be a new graph for a lot of you, but it's a very nice one.
Okay. Kind of cool. Kind of cool, right? So what's going on here? Well,
the purple area, right? So on the left axis, guys, we have our weights. Okay.
So for example, you can see in the beginning of the time, right?
Let me blow this up a little bit.
So you can see here in the beginning, we weren't usually,
we didn't have a lot of USDCAT exposure, right? But you can see as time grew,
we started adding more and more USDCAT, right? Imagine guys,
this is one period, okay? Each bar is one period of our portfolio.
Each section represents how much of our portfolio is in,
how much of that asset is in our portfolio. So you can see in this period,
the first period, right? We had a lot of XLP. And then in about four quarters,
we started to take out XLP and we started shifting into more USDCAT, right?
And this is how it changed over time. So very cool graph, right? Very,
very cool graph.
So let us keep going here.
Okay. So now what we're gonna do is we are going to graph this, right?
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna create the equal weight portfolio.
So if we didn't optimize. So what was this portfolio if we didn't optimize?
And then we're gonna say, well, what was our portfolio after optimization?
Okay, so pretty cool. Pretty cool. The black line is our strategy,
it's our new portfolio, okay?
And the red line is if we equal weighted each asset, okay? So you can see,
let me just plot the table annualized. You can see,
so we can get our Sharpe ratio. Okay, you can see we doubled our Sharpe ratio,
right? Right here, annualized Sharpe ratio. You guys can see that.
We almost doubled our Sharpe ratio, right?
Our adjusted return was about the same,
but our risk went down substantially from our optimizations.
Okay, so this now is, we're running a Sharpe of 4.2, and this is not bad,
right? This is not bad. Now,
what we could do, for example,
is if we wanted the same risk as the equal weight portfolio,
but we could increase this, we could, let's say, go two times our portfolio,
right? And we would increase our annualized return, right? So let's say 5%,
5.2%, and we would have our annualized entry deviation of 5%, or sorry, of 12%,
okay? So far, so good. So we're gonna introduce shorting.
Let me know what you guys are thinking.
Lumi, so far, so good.
For those of you that don't know,
Lumi is the York Trading Club portfolio manager,
and he does this a lot of the time. So we had a nice call earlier today,
and he shared with me some code.
Okay,
so let us go back here now. And what we're gonna do is,
we're gonna introduce shorting, right? And that's one way, guys. So, oh, shit.
Remember when we had all the portfolios here? Let me go. Ah, it's okay.
Remember when we had all the different assets here? Well,
we could actually move our efficient frontier like this by introducing shorting.
Okay, so that's what we're gonna do.
So Dan's saying, does doubling your risk equal doubling your return?
That's a very good point, Dan, and the answer is no. That's a very good point.
But it's almost a yes. Okay, it's almost a yes, but the answer is no.
Okay, so we're going to introduce shorting.
So now with our portfolio,
we're gonna say the minimum we can have now is negative 0.6.
Pulumi, what did I have here again now?
I think we just didn't have anything. Okay, let's do this now.
So here we go.
Okay, so,
hmm, sorry, guys, one second.
Oh, man, I should have saved the code. Yo, Pulumi,
what did I do differently here now? Oh,
there it is, guys. You see that? No one saw a little dot, right?
I was telling Sean the other day, I was doing some code. I spent three hours,
I was looking, I was like, why the hell is this not working?
Turns out I forgot a D. I forgot a D in some word. Today.
In 8,000 lines of code. Fuck that.
So let's do that again, guys.
Let's give that a second to load.
Yeah, one little dot.
Imagine guys trying to find that in like thousands of lines of code. Like,
I'm surprised coders don't have the shortest lifespan. I think they do.
I think they do. It's just, it's a relatively new thing, so, you know. Exactly.
Just haven't seen it yet. That's a good point. Okay, guys,
so look at our new holdings right now, right? We got 56% XLP,
and we actually introduced a little bit of leverage, right? 56% XLP,
negative 14% XLU. 12% GLD, basically no SLV. USD CAD, short,
and long USD Aussie. Now, if we take a look at this super quick, guys,
what's happening here, right?
The market's basically saying that there's some alpha,
or the optimizer is basically saying there's some alpha holding XLP over XLU,
right? And once we own gold, well, there's no real point in owning any silver,
okay? So that is what this portfolio is telling us.
And we can chart the weights, and you guys can see that, right?
So let us run this portfolio.
Okay.
Oh, man. I did something wrong here.
Okay, guys, well, basically, oh, man, we did this earlier, too. It was so good.
Oh, man. That's a shame.
So every time you wanna do something in real time,
terminal's a perfect example, guys.
Palman, you around?
No time for bathroom breaks, dude.
So everything looks fine. Yeah, everything does look good. Oh, man,
that's such a shame.
Okay. Guys, I have to figure that one out. But basically, when we did this,
we basically increased our sharp to 0.52, and our return was 0.03.
So we were able to increase our total portfolio by improving on our,
by adding in shorting to our portfolio, right?
And what that also allowed us to do was increase leverage, right?
If we're- Try running one more time. Okay. If we're long XLP and short XLU,
well, we can kind of increase our leverage.
Was it the add constraint, Blumi? I can't remember.
Did I have to remove the weight sum constraint?
It's saying remove it.
Sorry, guys. Give me one second here. We did figure it out earlier today.
Here's the code for it. I got the code right here, Blumi.
Let's see what we did.
No, we had it in there, bud. Nope, no, we didn't.
You took out the weight sum.
I have a hashtag there.
Okay, let's just give it one more shot, guys.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's a shame.
Sorry, dudes.
Oh, this is... I mean, this worked. I don't know. I don't think this is...
Yeah, I don't think this is ideal.
I think there's a little bug that we did on the shorting one. But anyways,
let's take a look at this, guys. When we introduce shorting here, right?
You can see that.
So the black line is our strategy and the red is the equal weight.
So you can see that our drawdowns go down significantly, right?
Our P&L looks fantastic here.
And this is usually what happens when you induce shorting into a portfolio,
right? If you think that stock X is gonna outperform stock Y, well,
you can get a lot of stock Y and short some stock X and have a really smooth portfolio.
So you can see here, right? Our Sharpe ratio increased quite a bit to 0.57.
Okay, this is similar to what we got, to what we got for me.
So we increased our Sharpe ratio now two and a half times, guys. Right,
we went almost two and a half times our previous Sharpe ratio.
Dan, I just wanted to go back to one of Dan's point. Dan,
the reason why we don't see the efficient frontier go like this and we see it kind
of curve off like that, Dan, is because as we increase the risk, like you said,
right? It doesn't necessarily, it starts to taper off, right?
Because of that leverage factor that you were talking about.
Okay, so we'll stop there, guys.
That's just an example of how you can optimize a portfolio. I'm not saying,
you know, optimize an R, but the whole point here is,
is once we can add diversified strategies, diversified assets into a portfolio,
well, all of a sudden we can run something now that is, you know,
gonna outperform the market, right? On a risk-adjusted basis,
which we can get leverage to and increase our total return.
That was actually one of Renato's questions was,
can we do this with diversified strategies? 100%, right?
That's a portfolio manager. A portfolio manager is running multiple strategies.
Or if I'm a huge portfolio manager, let's say Goldman,
I'm like head of the derivatives desk, right? Well,
I got traders under me who are all running their strategies and I'm allocating to
them.
I'm allocating money to each trader and all their trades are in the global book.
And I think that's the best way to do it, right? Super, you know,
super simple example is shortfall, right? You got shortfall here and we got,
let's say long fall here, right? Well, these are negatively correlated.
So if these are both good strategies and they're negatively correlated, well,
now our P&L is gonna look a lot smoother.
Yeah, if you had a good long fall and a good shortfall strategy, you run both,
you weight them appropriately, your P&L doesn't chop around.
Jack is saying, so is that the same concept with the leverage strat? No.
So a little bit, Jacko, right? You have two portfolios, right?
You have ETN one and you have ETN two and both have some negative auto-correlation.
And because they're leveraged, they tend to go like this, right?
So if you short both of these and these are negative one correlated, well,
now your stream is gonna look very smooth on the way down. But as we know,
there is some very fat tails for the strategy that don't come around very often.
They come around actually very seldomly, but they are there.
And Dan says, doesn't Dalio leverage up his all weather fund? I'm sure he does,
right? Usually you'll see guys go up to two times leverage, right?
So you're running, let's say 10K, Dan, let's say,
or let's say they're running $1 billion, okay, at the all weather strategy.
Well, their assets under management right now are gonna be 2 billion. Okay,
they're gonna control $2 billion worth of assets with a $1 billion portfolio.
And they're gonna have multiple, under here,
they're gonna have multiple strats or multiple assets and strategies, right?
That's gonna increase their Sharpe ratio,
which is gonna allow them to leverage, right? You can't leverage ACB,
right? You can't leverage this, but you can leverage SPY, right?
Because it has a lower return, a lower risk parameter,
and you can obviously leverage that.
So Dan saying, why does leverage decrease return in ETN strat,
but increase return here? Okay, so Dan, it's a really good point. So with the,
these ETNs, so these ETNs, Dan, are, they don't have positive expectancy,
right? And the reason is this, these things are negatively auto-correlated,
and they have negative expectancy, right? So it's, it's,
being long has negative expectancy. Right, being long has negative expectancy,
but it's not, and like, again, as you can see on this graph here,
when we draw the, I think that's actually a really good question, Dan.
It's a really, really good question.
So remember when we drew that graph, Dan, right?
And we said the efficient frontier looks like this,
right? It doesn't scale,
okay? And that's because of that leverage factor, right? As we,
that 10% down is not the same as the 10% up, right? Now,
if the ETNs had positive expectancy, right?
If the ETNs had a positive expectancy, then it would be,
it would make sense to buy them both.
Does that make sense, Dan? Right,
but because they're both going down like this,
we can make money by holding them, right? And it's, it's, you know, like,
the way to think about it is, you wouldn't buy 3x ETN1 for the long-term.
Right. You wouldn't buy and hold it for the long-term.
You wouldn't buy and hold ETN2 for the long-term, right?
Actually, okay. Actually, I got a really good way to explain this, Dan.
I got a good way to explain this, Dan. You got, you got NASDAQ, okay?
You got NASDAQ,
that, and you have the leveraged ETF, TQQ, okay? Well, TQQ, right?
The ETN actually does really well. It does very, very, very well.
And that's because QQQ has a positive expectancy, right?
So this is going to do very well. But what about SQQQ,
right? Well, this has negative expectancy, okay?
And because of the insane leverage,
right? And the choppiness, right? The auto-correl,
the negative auto-correlation,
this strategy should make money. And the actual thing is, Dan, we see NASDAQ,
for example, actually trend. We see NASDAQ trend most of the time.
So for that reason, this pair right here is not a good pair, usually.
This is usually not a good pair to trade. But if we have a pair like,
let's say, DGAS and UGAS,
where the vol is all over the place, and UNG doesn't move anywhere,
it just goes like this, well, now this is gonna play out, okay?
But even on a sharp ratio of three, Dan, right? Think about it like this.
On a sharp ratio of three, you still can't put your full account on here,
because there is a point where you will drop down to almost zero, right?
And then what? Then you're never coming back up, no matter how much.
So that's why. It's the insane leverage here. Even on a good strategy, Dan,
if you had the amount of leverage that these ETNs have,
you wouldn't be able to make money.
Are we at 155? Okay, so,
oh man, these chats are getting so busy now, man. It's good. Yeah, it's good,
it's really good.
Okay, guys, if you have any questions right now, post them in right now.
I'm just gonna be watching the chat. Any questions? So Ko is asking,
can we just be short SQQQ and long TQQQ?
No, you can't be short SQQ and long TQQQ, right? If, like, TQQ,
you make money when it goes up, right? And SQQQ,
you lose money when the NASDAQ goes up, right? So,
can we just be short?
Koa, okay, I don't know why I can't see this right now,
but you cannot be long one and short the other. You gotta be short both.
Are you exposed to the same thing?
Oh, yeah, okay, Tico, sorry, man. I don't know why I couldn't see that there.
What happens if NASDAQ goes down? What if NASDAQ goes down, right?
You lose on both sides. Oh, you're gonna lose on this,
and you're gonna lose on that.
So Jack is saying, how do we optimize portfolio with multiple strats? So,
obviously, the answer is you have to run it through a computer.
You have to pull the data, see what you get, and do it.
But there's other ways around that, right? You can also think about, well,
what is your strategy, right? That's why we usually break it down to two.
Is it a long vol strategy, or is it a short vol strategy?
If it's a long vol strategy, right? And you can look at your P&L, right?
You can say, okay, well, my expected return from this long vol strategy is,
let's say, 10%, right?
And it's negatively correlated with my short vol strategy that's making,
let's say, 50%. Well,
maybe there's a weight I can do here where I'm probably gonna be long,
you know, most of the short vol strat,
and then I'm gonna have some of that hedge to back it up, right, example.
Buying equity, buying,
and then buying deep out-of-the-money puts with a very small percentage of your
account just to give you that kicker.
So Hugh just saying, what is expectancy?
Expectancy is basically what you expect to make, right? What do you expect?
What's your expected value in the trade, right?
It's like when you go to a blackjack table,
your expectancy is negative two cents per bet. Every time I bet on average,
every time I bet a dollar, on average, I'm gonna lose two cents, okay?
That's what expectancy is.
If both go down, Jed says we drink. Yeah. That's it,
and we got a little mattress for you here, Tico, as well. Exactly.
So with that said, guys, it's nine o'clock.