Okay guys, so in this live, we're actually gonna be looking at a pre-release.
So what is a pre-release, right?
And remember this week we're talking about unique opportunities, right?
So Opportunities that don't happen all the time. It's not systematic, right?
An algo can't capture it You know a systematic trader can't capture it.
It's something that's unique, right?
Merger and acquisition unique Pre-releases so pre-release is basically an earning
a stock comes out before the earnings event and says Here here's my numbers Here
are my numbers. Here's here are most of my numbers Going into the event.
So I'm gonna announce it before the event.
I'm gonna issue a press release Okay.
Now the beauty of this is that Not always vol drops or vol changes.
Imagine this guys what drives the stock around earnings event? It's the news.
It's the new information hitting the market So if This news already comes out pre
prior to the the the event Then you would expect once the news is out volatility
should drop but sometimes the news comes out and volatility doesn't change So that's
what we're actually gonna look at today and we're gonna use all the software all
the technology that we have available to us To go over it. Okay,
so So what I did guys I'm gonna share my screen Hold on one second guys Okay
Okay, so Okay, guys,
so what I did was I searched for the next upcoming earnings of the upcoming next
upcoming Earnings dates for different companies that are on the list and one of
the companies was PPG. Okay, so there's this function in Bloomberg. Okay,
it's called guide.
This is a really good one from Bloomberg okay,
so There's a function in Bloomberg called guide and what it does basically is it
tells you?
when a company it tells you when a company releases its Events when it tells you
basically when does a company talk about its earnings? Okay.
So for example this company had earnings on Let's say let's look at last year.
So PPG last year had earnings 1017 and they did a four-year guidance Okay of revenue.
They dropped their guidance for revenue Okay,
so they said we continue to expect full year sales growth to come down And they
also said they're for full year So full year meaning the next year the guidance
for that in that year. Okay,
that's what drives a lot of the vol We are going to adjust our our earnings.
We're going to adjust that down So Bloomberg actually sorts that out for you and
you know, you can see what's going on Okay,
so PPG has earnings coming up next week next week on Monday,
I believe Monday or Tuesday of next week.
Now what happened was on October 8th They came out and said PPG projects strong
third quarter financial Guidance, okay, and they explained so if we you know,
we can click on the article and it'll bring us to the article here Okay,
we're basically they're saying that the revenue is going to increase by 5% And their
earnings per share is going to be in the range between $1.90 and $1.94.
So they have just given out information One week before their earnings event.
So not much is going to change between that event, right?
Now they didn't give up. They didn't they didn't give full year guidance Okay,
but they did give us the earnings numbers for this quarter Okay within a tight range
190 and 194 so volatility is gonna be Dropped a lot.
Okay Now we actually don't have Bloomberg, right? You know the guys on here.
We don't have Bloomberg. So what can we do? Well, we have on the new terminal.
Okay on the new terminal we can go to News and sentiment. Okay,
so we type in PPG at the top and right here you can see on October 10th October
8th, sorry PPG projects strong third quarter financial results,
right and they it basically summarizes The upcoming quarter. Okay,
they basically gave you a gave us an example of what we should expect.
The earnings was pre-released now another thing that we have here,
which Bloomberg doesn't have is we have access to The implied move.
So how did this affect? With all how did this affect the earnings event?
So just the earnings ball. Yeah,
this is the earnings isolated This is isolated earnings volatility. Yeah,
this is just the implied move.
This is just the implied move over the last year Okay,
so you can see guys right so October 7th It went from four point three five the
implied move four point three five percent Down to three point three nine percent
on so once the information was released vol dropped Okay,
but guess what it picked right back up Okay.
So now we're in a situation where it was almost as if the news was never released
Right volatility should have come down.
Let's say You know probably down to three percent right from four and a half to
three percent and now it's all the way back up Right.
So this is a situation we can take advantage of now by selling ball around this
earnings announcement We should not see this stock move, right?
One thing that you know They could come out and say is we are gonna have a crazy
full year guidance now that would move the stock But remember guys we have more
information now Volatility should be less Right.
Let me ask you guys this question. Would you rather sell vol?
Knowing this quarters earnings or not knowing this quarters earnings Right,
we obviously wanted to sell vol. Well,
we obviously prefer the more information So we're getting the information but the
vol is not dropping here and you can actually see guys Volatility is still higher
than when it was pre COVID.
So not only do we basically have all the information we don't have we also have
Implied move still bid so check this out guys Let's go Okay,
so you can see last quarter. For example,
they announced on October 17 and prior to that they had their their last quarter
earnings But there was nothing in between This quarter. Look at this guys.
This is a one-time situation where they are releasing information to us Right before
the event and what was the move for that event the actual move to want to look up
on our terminal? Which one?
For this one where they released information before as well, right? No, no,
they previously yet. Have they pre released before? No, no, no, they have not.
Okay. I thought it was there. Yeah, so Right. Oh, hold on this over here.
Okay,
they did something similar here actually Let's go take a look at what happened.
So this was the the 10 18 2018. Okay,
so let's take a look guys You go to historical moves.
Okay, we go to 2018 10 right here guys.
Look at that 2018 10 here was the move 1.25% Is overstated as well as that 2.8 and
I'm moving 1.25, right? So,
you know that probably came that probably wasn't even the jump that was probably
an intraday move, right? So,
you know here is an advantage we can take we can we can we have an advantage here
Markets not repricing because it's a one-time thing Right because of this one-time
thing it did reprice probably didn't reprice enough It did reprice but we can come
in over the top.
Okay?
Yeah, you like that Neil 20 quarters. You know,
you we had a 2018 number in here.
What this is 2018 See me 2016 Fuck oh, yeah. No. No, look. Oh,
what the fuck is gonna have it sorted by month by accident Guys beta beta Very cool
as well. How would you have done if you bought calls?
How would you have done if you just bought puts? So how do you like that guys?
Yeah, and so You know,
we're we're working away on the terminal I'm gonna come out and you guys can even
see like how IV changed every time So on this date,
for example implied volatility the day before went from 25 to 18 Okay,
and there's gonna be more stuff coming guys. This is just a little teaser Okay,
there's gonna be a lot more stuff coming so That is one certain scenario.
I wanted to show you guys another scenario Where this happened a while ago.
Okay, so I took this trade it was on VR NT Mm-hmm,
and they released this is like maybe two a year and a half ago.
They released a full-blown report prior to the event Okay full-blown report about
everything You wait,
so let's slow down perhaps like how can we use that information for that last trade?
You can solve all right thing about it for now you You have more information thing
will this print up? Okay,
you're in a scenario where you don't know what's gonna happen You don't know information
and you want to sell vol Implied move is greater than the average move. Okay?
now You know, you're happy selling that ball. Now.
Imagine I told you Pranav these guys already released their numbers an Implied move
didn't change. Would you be more confident or less confident selling that ball?
Yeah, we can be more certain in our in our bet. Right,
right You can be more certain you can you know,
even if the implied move is let's say near the average You can say well,
I still think this is overpriced. Yeah,
Neil it or Pranav that doesn't mean you take five lots Okay. Yeah, right.
That doesn't mean that the company doesn't come out and say Full full your guidance
is gonna be this now there are situations where that does happen and it's you as
a trader You know, these are one-off situations that actually happen.
I'm gonna say 50 times during the season Okay,
you guys got to find these right and I don't know if Pulumi's on the event. No,
I don't think he's here Pull it up No, no, no Lumi.
So Pulumi and I about a year and a half ago This is all we did.
All we did was look for companies every single day Companies that would pre-release
just sell ball sell ball sell ball sell ball. It was good.
It was great It's a it's a very good thing.
One issue is I'm sure you guys can already know this it's time-consuming It's really
really time-consuming So, you know, I've moved into other things Got,
you know found other strategies that were less time-consuming similar Similar payout
so I moved into those right but these are strategies that come to Every time if
someone in the group said hey this pre-release I'm always selling ball there There's
not one situation where I'm not selling ball, right? You know,
they're not they're not always winners Fortunately,
I haven't had a losing one doing this but you know, the risk is still there.
So you can't go you can't go too wild Mmm Andrea so how do I look for this?
I literally went through each individual name prior to this live on the earnings
calendar and said and looked at every single one Until I went like this,
for example, I went like this.
I went to the guide function. I went Apple,
right? Oh, no release. Okay, I did I did Amazon.
Okay, no release next Okay. Oh shit.
Yeah so that you can see that's time-consuming Right,
you can see it's very time-consuming imagine doing that in the terminal right you
do right imagine we do that in the terminal Oh,
they're gonna see the lag Right imagine did that a terminal imagine I did Apple
right and then I did okay nothing there and they did Amazon Kyle's asking is the
terminal news Bloomberg News It's not it's not Bloomberg News,
but it is a very good. It is very good provider Yeah,
well the press releases like you can think about this is all stuff on their website
Yeah. Oh, yeah, the press releases are just from the website.
So it is this is what Bloomberg has Yeah,
it's the exact same as Bloomberg same thing as Bloomberg So that is That is basically
these one-off trades where you can,
you know You can look for these things these pre releases and pack on some heat.
So let's take a second here to talk about Remember,
so this is about capturing these one-off opportunities,
too So the average trader looks at this and what do you think the average trader
thinks when they says other people trading earnings around PBG Maybe they're buying
a call buying a put right?
What do you think going through their head when they see news like that?
Well a lot of the time they would say Wow PPBG Increased revenue.
I'm gonna be buying the call into earnings because they're gonna announce that they
prove beat revenue. That's probably one, right? Yeah,
exactly or Maybe they don't really care Right,
maybe maybe they're still looking at how the price actions moving around this How
did how did the market react on the chart? Gotcha? Yeah,
so like okay So like for example,
someone might see a break out on PPG pre earnings and be like I'm gonna buy a call
Meanwhile someone like us will be like this vol is way overpriced news is already
in So the reason I bring this up guys is remember Remember the same things we said
over the last couple.
This is the power of knowing your product Knowing how volatility moves and what
drives high volatility low volatility how volatility should react to different types
of information coming out How it reacts around earnings events?
this is the power of knowing this stuff because the average person will see the
exact same thing as you and Make the different decision and more times than not
the wrong decision Whereas you you know,
especially the guys in like silver now who are thinking about risk exposure and
all of this type of stuff You come in and you think about how should this option
be changing? Relative to the information that's provided,
right?
So see this is so this is the thing of it's not just enough to see the information
We got to know what to do about it, right?
And this is over the last four weeks all these lives kind of coming together to
make a really good trade here.
Yeah Right and then you can see for example,
like how does How is the implied move reacting right?
How is this earnings vol reacting to this event, right?
If you imagine guys about in Tesla came out and said hey guys,
we're gonna have a pre-release and they pre-release their earnings Vol is still
gonna say so bid Going into that event and you as a trader can be like, okay.
Well,
look at this right implied move hasn't changed It's way higher than usual and information
is already out. I got to be selling vol here.
Okay And this is this this is you having an informational advantage Right,
you're having informational advantage here and I truly believe we are probably the
smartest earning group out there Okay, so The more information we have around,
you know, an earnings event is basically an information event Right,
that's all it is who has the most information to make the best decision Right.
The stock is reacting off of this brand new information coming into the market So
we need to be as most informed as possible at least more informed than the average
person we need to size appropriately Okay So yeah, Kyle's a good question.
Why would the implied move not reflect the pre-released information?
It's not like it's a secret. That's right. It's not a secret.
It's not publicized either Right. So how many people are looking at this?
Right. How many people are looking at this?
I don't know anyone in this field who does this Think about how capacity constraint
this is what like what's PPG?
10,000 3,000 options traded a day 5,000 options traded a day Right.
This thing is no one That I know is looking for press releases.
They are usually systematic vol traders Right.
Look at all the earnings guys you see on Twitter cop.
How many of them are looking at this? Right,
and this is a market So if the if big money's not flowing behind this right and
the average guy is not flowing behind this sure it repriced It did reprice right
just like when we looked at yesterday with US. Oh,
it did reprice Let's go back to PPG Hey guys One thing that I have to finish fix
with this terminal is lag time.
So that's one thing I'm having a really hard time with is the speed Okay So unfortunately,
but that's what that's why it's not out right now Yeah,
we need to fix that because we want to port everything over to this So we want it
to be up and running for you guys.
We're aiming for next week like early next week Sorry for the delay guys,
but you're used to that by now, you know, we always a couple days,
you know Give us a couple more So Kyle, it did reprice it went from 439 to 339.
It dropped a 1% implied move number,
but now it's back up Right back up to 4 now so You know,
it probably first off it probably didn't reprice enough, right?
This should this should have dropped to probably 2.5 percent,
but there's still gonna be a risk premium baked in It's like this new cop.
It's like this if if I'm a hedge fund manager and I own PPG and I have to hedge
my shares Whether earnings is coming up whether I know about this information or
not. I'm still gonna be buying protection, right?
So there's systematic reasons that you know,
it won't go down or structural reasons that it won't go all the way down Right.
So this is you, you know,
even though you know people know about this It's still not gonna drop all the way
right and imagine this Kyle imagine Apple came out and said here are our numbers
and they still gonna have the earnings college So look so we have all the information
coming up the next day.
Let's say a week down the road Would it make sense that there's no implied move
baked in? How much do you think the implied move would be?
I bet you would still be high People are still gonna be buying the options hoping
for a good earnings call People are still gonna be buying protection in case of
a one-time, you know A one-time, you know,
the the CEO breaks down on a conference call They're still gonna be buying protection
for that people are still gonna be taking bets. Sure.
It might not be as high Because maybe the market makers are more willing to sell
vol But at the same time this is another systematic thing where a market maker is
gonna sell vol And he's not a market maker is not gonna be look it's just gonna
be his computer selling vol right or providing liquidity The computer is not reading
the prospectus or it's not reading, you know,
what's What's happening with this with this out with this? news release Right.
It's probably pricing it based on average moves based on current demand.
So the amount of money flowing into this Because of that article is very little
relative to all the other money Steven I don't think so.
Not that I've seen I've never seen a company that pre-releases all the time There
are companies that offer that release Monthly revenue statements like target.
I go to target here.
Okay, maybe it's not target.
I saw one maybe Oh Walmart does it?
Okay,
there are retail companies that release monthly revenue statements store sales statements.
That's that's You know,
that's nothing special So Marcos is asking what to do when there's no confirmed
date There's a whole other field of stuff you can do in that. Yeah,
right you can bet on the date When is the date gonna be?
Think about that one Marcos try to come up with an idea of how you could figure
that out Yeah, and some of the guys are actually trying to do that.
I should just go off a call with Neil prior to this You showed me some stuff.
So try and come up with some ideas.
Remember creativity guys trying to flex it a bit and Let's uh,
let's chat about it when you come up with some ideas,
you know saying eBay Okay, so guys look at this.
Let's see what the fall was for this.
Let's check eBay.
Yeah, I go in the terminal Yeah, where was it? Oh, yeah Just run it again.
Oh We did this on eBay I think is what Neil's saying.
Yeah, let's see earnings. I can't remember.
Yeah This is gonna take 10 years to load This is a delay that we're talking about
guys,
this is the new terminal you guys are gonna be 80 by the time it loads Yeah,
Neil, it's been crazy,
dude So guys take a quick power nap We back Back after the break terminal alarm
clock will wake you up. Yeah Kyle finger on the trigger Okay, Sarah. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay guys, so perfect, right? Actually, let's go Okay,
so here we go guys look at this right 20 Where are we 20? Oh 728 right here.
Okay There's no move implied move was 7% The actual move was three and a half percent.
Okay, check this out eBay eBay released guidance, right?
eBay prior to the event one month before the event they came out and said oops on
on June 4th Okay,
they came out and said here are next quarters or numbers Okay,
bring a ding-ding Could have sold some vol would have made some good money And let
me show you guys cuz I got I'm trying to remember remember we're looking at that
thing for Costco last year So guys, this is not rigid, right?
There's there's different forms of this that can happen, right?
It's like remember guys like take this and think about it,
right think about other things like this, right?
So remember we're looking at Costco and we thought that in their July Earnings that
they had given their year guidance,
but then they were saying they were gonna give their your guidance again in December
Mm-hmm.
It's like they've already given it Everyone's pricing in that they're gonna give
their your guidance in December,
but they gave it in July So what the fuck right like these are the kind of opportunities
that are one-offs big money Or easy money, you know or reliable money.
It is maybe a better way to put it. It's low-hanging fruit. Mm-hmm Right,
but then you gotta be careful low-hanging fruit as well. Yeah,
so maybe poison Yeah, you know still by the wings just know that you know,
you should be going with a little more confidence Mm-hmm,
like treat the same but it's a good trait,
right and you can go with confidence. Yeah and a little more size Okay,
so you guys have any questions about that? Now the one thing though,
it's tedious, right? It is tedious. How many of these are there?
There's lots No, there's probably 50 every quarter.
So cows saying they released pre so, let's see.
I don't see it. No Kyle Don't see it.
No preliminary third-quarter revenue.
I'm not I'm not seeing anything regarding I'm not seeing anything regarding information
prior to the event No, I think today's release. Yeah,
they gave out future revenue numbers like Basic numbers of the future. Yeah,
here's all the here's all the numbers they gave out, right?
Here's all the numbers that they gave out today But imagine Kyle they gave these
are numbers out yesterday Right stock would have dropped Then you could solve all
today Pranav, how can you get access to this data?
The closest you can get right now Pranav is through the new terminal where all you
would do is you just go to news and sentiment and They'll tell you right there.
Okay They'll tell you right here all the press releases regarding You just go you
look up a list of like companies releasing this week And you just go one by one
by one by one by one until you find them just bang it out and it's gonna be You
know, it's gonna be super tedious, right? That's uh,
and you would look it'd be it's ranked by data, right?
perhaps so you'd be like, okay,
I'm looking for pre releases after September 20th. Okay.
There's only one after September 20th here on to the next Marcos had a good question.
I'm gonna expand on it a little bit Jordan who should talk about this So he's like,
you know, what should we be looking for?
Is it if IV comes back up or does not drop and then there's a good trade?
So I think what we need to talk about here is familiarizing ourselves with how IV
moves Right and start looking at stocks through implied volatilities Right.
What do you think should happen Marcos? Right,
what should happen after this news comes out? Well,
the IV should come back down So let's say the IV didn't come back down Then there
would be a trade because we understand that with this new information Which reduces
the likelihood of a jump on the event?
That there should be less volatility So we expect it to drop if we don't see it
drop then there's a trade if it starts to come back up Why is it coming back up?
Is it coming back for any reason in particular?
It doesn't change the fact this information's out So the trade just gets juicier
the opportunity might come back Now the only thing that is going to take some getting
used to for you and Jordan Maybe you can recommend some ways for people to start
familiarizing themselves with this is what if it drops a little bit But not enough
or it comes back up a bit,
but not really enough How do we know what the different levels that it rises to
or drops to signify? You know what I mean? Yeah,
like and it's things like pre levels and stuff.
But like how can they start familiarizing? We start thinking about it,
right we really got think just just Logically think about it.
I want someone to come in here and tell me quick and tell Sean quick.
How could we? How can we benchmark this? What do you guys think would be like?
Okay, this ball is too. It's too cheap now I can't sell it.
I'm gonna put the IV on the terminal Give him something to look at her. No,
let's say Yeah, no earnings tab. Yeah, what do you guys think?
When would we say vol is too cheap to sell if it information came up,
what could we benchmark it to?
You're gonna put the distribution of the implied move over this Yeah, okay.
That would nice What do you guys think no answers here?
Previous moves exactly, right?
The average move is 5% and you were gonna sell it at 8% Information just came out.
It went back down to let's say 5% Well,
this is not an average move You shouldn't have an average move here You just have
a lot more information a lot less ball should be baked into this option So it's
gonna be less than average.
So if the implied move is still average you want to be selling that right?
Well,
you can benchmark it to the average move There's just exactly right Steve,
right guys So I want to you know,
just just clarify one thing because I know we've got a lot of the new guys in here
Right now, okay. This is real trading Okay,
when I say that what I mean is we're making a really educated trade here This is
how like in the real world outside of social media and all of this stuff.
This is what's happening in Different ways different shapes and forms.
This is exactly what people are doing and it's trades like this You know where people
build up a large sum of capital they raise capital they start doing things like
this, you know Obviously as you scale it's not exactly this strategy,
but it's things like this It's evaluating something understanding how something
should be priced versus what it is right now and making a trade That people make
a lot of money, right?
Think about it like If you have no idea what something's worth or what it should
be worth. What are you trading? How you making money right?
We got to know this stuff.
And when we do know this stuff we make good trades We're basically saying this thing's
going for five bucks and it should be going for three bucks So it's a good trade
for me to sell it See what I'm saying guys You know now like if let's say the average
move is 5% and this this stuff the same thing came out and move went to zero There's
no earnings we've priced in Maybe it's too cheap Maybe they basically maybe there's
they're not accounting. They're not giving any margin for error, you know,
like so We got to think this way guys, right?
This is the lens of expected value This is really what we're talking about And when
you get in the groove of doing this and thinking like this you get a lot more confident
Kyle this is actually I'm logged into your I'm logged into your Account so only
you have that one in the bottom left corner. Okay.
No one else has that one Okay,
so that is basically the live guys on looking for yeah opportunity That's what we
got. What do you guys think thoughts comments concerns?