All right,
everyone welcome to a another lecture here from the PA household Today we're gonna
be talking about pre-releases the impact they have on so what they are and the impact
they have on earnings as well as a trade structure that Pranav and Hutch and Parth
and Parth also took for this trade right how they How they interpreted the information
and then how they acted on it.
So First we're gonna start off by saying a Pre-release.
Okay is when a company comes out and announces their earnings before the event Okay
so an example micron has earnings tonight, but Three weeks ago.
They come out and say This is what we're expecting to get for our earnings release
date. Okay, we are updating our guidance Okay,
what we're going to get for this earnings report And now we need to remember why
That might cut vol down. Okay, and of course,
we're gonna go into the website We're gonna show you what the pre-release looks
like But why would this or what impact should this have right and we need to think
about what an earnings event is Okay,
an earnings event is where new information comes into the market Okay That allows
us to price the company more efficiently Okay,
it allows us to price it more efficiently because now we have more earnings information
right a company in the long run,
okay In the long run is going to be based around its earnings Okay Or future earnings
for example Tesla, right? This is all future earnings, right?
It's trading at this because in the future one day They're expected to make hundreds
of billions of dollars Okay So a company like micron right where the earnings are
a little more stable,
right the company's really gonna follow like Walmart For example,
right at the high extreme or coca-cola It's not going to deviate from its price
to earnings right if you graphed out its price to earnings It would it wouldn't
deviate too much from it. Okay, something like Tesla.
There's no real value there. It's all future value.
Okay It's all extrinsic not intrinsic. Right, right. So but with micron,
you know,
we should see You know If a company comes out and real pre releases its earnings,
right and the company,
you know most of the companies at least follow these earnings then once that information
is out we can price it right now and Vol will drop Okay,
because now the information is out So it's not like the company's gonna come out
on the earnings day and say we're making Something way different and now the company
needs to price that in.
So I guess a question to start off with is What changes should you see in the option
chain? Right company has earnings coming up.
What changes should you see in the options if a company comes out and pre-releases?
Do you see Pranav stop stop trolling man.
So Pranav said Vega should tank but it won't Part the saying drop in future vol
vol should drop. Yeah, exactly. Let's so let's think about this, right?
Let's say we're looking at a timeline here wasn't this was not very dark. Yeah,
let's say we're looking at a timeline All right.
Let's say earnings releases here. And let's say this is a Daily vol. All right,
the market will probably be pricing daily vol to look something like this,
right?
now we're moving through time and at this point in time the company comes out and
Gives their earnings right here.
They give their forecast for the earnings like hey,
this is what we're expecting How should this line change?
What do you guys think?
It'll be an uneven boob Okay, yeah,
so Eric saying it should flatten right should should go down right so maybe we'll
end up with a line like this,
right Where yeah same as here and this maybe comes down a lot still maybe a little
bit because maybe still a little bit of uncertainty But you should see it Or yeah,
and even maybe a little bump here, right? That's the uneven boob that oh,
this is implied vol. Oh, gotcha. Gotcha.
Yeah You'd have realized vol at the moment, right? So yeah,
if we graphed realized vol you'd be like this All right,
and now we have the uneven boobs so This is this is what this is what happened with
that earnings right the company pre-released and so we got some information So let's
actually dig in and see what it looks like Mm-hmm.
Are you sure in the terminal?
Yes, the terminal The terminal. Okay.
Give me one second guys Give me a moment.
Oh I'll show it to you guys both in investor relations and on the terminal just
so you guys can be aware of What look or yeah,
what a pre-release looks like Okay, it's very important.
Just give me one second guys.
This is and a lot of the times At least what we saw micron a lot of times it's not
being fully priced in Right,
and so if it's not fully priced in Or at least in the vol right,
it's not fully pricing in the vol we can Then we can make some money, you know,
I did. Let's see Okay, here it is. Okay, so let's go to Okay,
so if you come to the if you come to the terminal Okay,
you come on to the news and sentiment tab And you go to the press releases you'll
see this right on December 1st micron updates quarter fiscal 2021 guidance Okay
and so This is what this is what we saw, right?
They came in and they said They gave a whole report on on Their new estimate of
the earnings, right? So you come on the investor relations, for example,
okay we can go to December 1st and you guys can search for that, right?
So usually like to search for Update, right? There it is.
So it searches all of them and it can find it for you now They don't always this
is a very rare thing that happens For earnings so that and that's why when you do
find them, they're usually really good to act on.
Okay,
so let's Let's show this report here So you come to the earnings page you come to
the investor relations and you're looking for the pre-release Okay,
or you're looking for you go to press releases. Sorry okay,
and if we go to December 1st right here micron updates quarter fiscal 21 guidance.
Okay, you can read the full report Just you're doing it somewhere download PDF.
Okay, you can you can you can look at the full report here Okay,
and this is where they go over What they're expecting to happen. Okay,
so yeah when we look at this, right?
What are the couple of things that people should be looking for in this report if
they wanted to spend the time to read it? What gives you edge here, right?
Is it future guidance? Is it next quarter's earnings?
What would they what do they want to look for and you you want to look for revenue
and earnings per share? Okay,
so you can see right here today announced or in and let's say this is where the
real alpha comes in is Certain companies will act to certain things.
So for example with Netflix,
you know Knowing the earnings per share knowing the revenue is gonna be good.
But what really matters with Netflix is the net Subscription count how many more
people came in then people went out, right? So that's really important So,
you know as you get better with these trades like depending on how specialized you
want to get with earnings You can you know,
you just become better and better and better and start looking for things specific
to the company Well,
what is really gonna cut down the vol or what's gonna increase the vol, right?
So and in pronounced case is there gonna be a is there some Delta bet to write what
you know You guys can reach out to put off.
He wrote a really good article about it okay,
so today today announced that it is increasing its revenue gross margin and EPS
guidance for the first quarter of fiscal 2021 Okay,
which ends December 3rd 2020.
So they are giving us revenue gross margin and earnings per share guidance one month
before the earnings event 30 days before the earnings event.
We're getting all of this right,
and so You're gonna have you got to stop that yeah,
we're gonna we're gonna block you here,
okay So this is what we're looking for right is there some type of information on
earnings per share revenue and guidance and You know in this case profit margin
right gross margin.
Each company's gonna be different each company's gonna be you know,
yeah Really really dependent on on the specific company,
right if we see Tesla come out with earnings per share guys We don't really care
about that But we care about is how many cars they're selling or what's the new
and what is the new industry that they're trying to get?
Into right that's really gonna drop vol because on a Tesla announcement.
It's not what they have It's what Elon says they're gonna have is what is gonna
drive the vol, right? So if he already says hey guys,
we're coming up with this battery thing.
We're gonna be talking about it on our earnings day Well now that's gonna drop vol
substantially as it's already being built in to the price or it should So in this
case what we do is right we find out okay, well,
you know They gave us quite a bit of information here.
And this is severely gonna impact realized vol but what we noticed was What we noticed
with micron is that so okay So here's the thing right implied move 5.8 average implied
7.3.
So the markets already pricing this lower right average move 7% And you can see
right vol has been coming in so we can look at let's say applied move So you can
see like it's near the lows, right? So people aren't stupid.
They're coming in They swing they're seeing this information and they're acting
on it, right and they're dropping that vol They're dropping that volatility,
right? So as a trader, we have to understand that okay,
the markets can be efficient most of time But you know what?
They probably didn't drop vol enough All right,
they didn't drop volatility enough. So for that reason, you know,
we were able to come in and why I didn't come in but many of the guys in the group
came in and Decide to sell some volatility.
So how would you know if it's enough? Yeah,
that's a That's a really good point there You know what?
And I honestly don't think there's there's a hard rule for that It's depending on
how much information they're gonna give out So in this case if they get out the
gross margin the earnings per share and the revenue You should expect vol to drop
substantially maybe 50% of what realized volatility should be right in this case
It's it's trading at 6% implied Averages at 7.2.
Like it definitely didn't come down enough, right?
And so for that reason I would always be taking that trade except for today.
I was a little busy doing some other stuff He was napping at the close So that is
That's what the pre-release is.
You guys have any questions about the pre-release?
Otherwise, we're gonna jump into the structure Okay Okay Awesome,
so we're gonna go into the structure of the trade. Oh Shoot.
I don't want you doing this.
I have no clue You're not a bunch of Is there any way to predict pre-releases?
Not that I know of Not that I know of right a lot of the company's gonna do it in
a different situation So for example,
a company might do it because their earnings are gonna be so bad right,
they're gonna be so so bad and they don't want this big one day to come and the
Company gets cut in half. So they're gonna release or it's so good, right?
The the release is just so good that they're going to uh help help give guidance
or Um in like, you know scenario like this, for example,
it's there's it's really hard to figure out How much this company's gonna make?
Because of kovat, right?
Maybe maybe their volatility of their returns is a lot higher And so for that reason
The company might come out and say well, you know what? Okay,
we're gonna help guide our investors and give them a little bit of information as
we get closer Okay um so Let us initiate a screen Let's take a look here Okay,
so let's see what happened to micron So pancake right big old-fashioned pancake.
Uh,
looks like it's going to open up around 80 um but uh Let's take a look at the structure
Okay so What we could have so the stock was trading at 79 per nav was slightly bullish
But we're going to stick with the 79s for now that that's the position he took That
is so the stock's trading was trading at 79, right?
So we want to look at 79 strike Okay, and this is this is our main trade,
right? Our main trade is this Selling the straddle. Okay.
Sean talked about it on the live today if you guys want to go and revisit that Here's
our main trade now,
you know with these earnings trades the thing can get cut in half So it's usually
prudent to go out and buy wings And I actually didn't uh suggest selling the straddle.
Uh, I wasn't aware of the pre-release And I forgot to do the research for it.
So I was actually saying lean long ball potentially. Oh, gotcha. Gotcha.
Gotcha Well, thank god.
No one did because I actually didn't show I showed like a one three two in a vertical.
Oh, nice Nice. So I saved my ass. Yeah, we got Okay, so,
um The straddle is trading at six dollars I'm probably going to go out 10 to 15
dollars out for my wings And I want to make sure that i'm not i'm not going to pay
too much, right? So one way to do that is first. This is our main.
This is our core position, right?
The first thing we want to do is stress the position what's going to happen tomorrow
after the announcement,
right and we can see here Let's go to the pa terminal All right,
we go to the volume sites We can see that Tomorrow volatility should open up at
around 41 for the 10-day options Okay, you can see that through the blue line.
This is the non-event volatility, right?
Let's quickly go over what's happening there This is just the implied vol over the
the different days to expiration and then what we do is we take out the event vol
So this is if there was no earnings There was no earnings vol would look like this
Because there is earnings they look like this relative to each other.
So we're trading the 10-day We should see vol go down from 64 event passes vol should
go down to around 41 So we got to drop vol 23 points here okay,
so We're gonna drop vol 23 points Okay,
we're gonna move time one day So here's what the straddle should look like tomorrow,
right? now you know Uh in this position,
right we're going to be making anywhere between you know 1700 You know 1700 and
and 2500, right? So what we want to do is really just offset.
We're going to spend some of that and offset it. Um By buying some wings,
right?
so something maybe like And these wings are going to be worthless tomorrow Right.
So if we go let's say 12 out, right? We'll go with the 91 91 and we go 12 down.
That's 67 So we'll pay 71 cents for these wings And now here is what our trade looks
like Okay And so I think this is the trade that most of you guys have on Hutch has
something different is a strangle in the back Right.
This is what this is the trade per nav has for tomorrow.
So You should be making more than a dollar per nav tomorrow 100 bucks Okay Should
be making a little bit more than a hundred dollars tomorrow,
buddy Hopefully between 150 and 200 if you don't uh,
if you don't mess this one Okay So roasted this is This is um,
this is the trade structure and you guys can see um You know why we structured like
this, right? Why we're buying the wings.
We're not buying the wings for edge Right.
We're buying the wings just to protect ourself here And we have to make sure that
we're not we're not we're not going to pay too much for these right?
And in fact if I were to do this trade structure,
I'd probably go even further out for the wings Maybe something like 93 and 65 Okay,
because this is just These wings are only here to help me if there's a massive blowout
in the stock market in the in the uh in the stock Maybe one we can take a look at
so parth actually has a different position on he has a 132 Oh nice. Okay,
so that actually did very well Let's take a look at it.
So he has the 80 84 87 1 3 2 80 84 Okay, slightly off.
Yeah slightly off I would uh slightly off but Okay,
actually that might have worked out better for him because he bought protection
a little Little cheaper, right? um one thing I would say Is uh,
if you knew about this pre-release you probably wouldn't want to be uh Structuring
this thing too far out of the money. Okay,
you want to be a little bit more at the money Is it 80 84 87?
I believe so Parth, can you compare can you uh, just confirm in the chat?
Can we do this?
Okay. Yeah, we're all good. Nice All right. So,
uh this one so this should work out very nice, right?
We got uh Look at that Good job Nice right so this should this should print.
Yeah, you know, this should pay off pretty good tomorrow um,
and you're probably gonna get some drop and skew as well,
right so You're risking, you know 60 bucks All right, it's gonna pay out huge.
Yeah, right. He's gonna pay out huge man Yeah, the only thing that uh So yeah,
you didn't have a lot of risk on this trade. Um, however,
you did have this blow up potential, right?
um I probably wish I had the huge risk on the other side Yeah,
I buy the structures a little bit different buddy. Uh,
maybe something like this, right?
Maybe something like buying the 79 um Buying the 79 this is knowing about the pre
-release. Yeah.
Yeah knowing about the pre-release And even if you do know about the pre-release,
it's not very margin efficient to do those,
uh broken wings Mm-hmm So maybe done something like this Maybe I probably bring
it in a little bit closer actually maybe something around probably actually the
84 sounds or 80 Maybe 83 sounds reasonable. That's four and 285.
Yeah And it doesn't line up Okay, that's okay. Um,
and if I did know about the pre-release and I was bullish in pranav's,
um Like pranav was I actually would have structured something like this Where my
body would have been maybe let's say 81 And I would have bought let's say, uh,
the 69 so it would look something like this Right,
you can you can structure these trades.
It would be a one-two-one fly right an iron condor same thing um The way I would
structure these is you want to lean in the direction you think the stock is going
to go and You can be short vol okay,
so something like this 69 81 and uh 93 Okay for six bucks Right and this You guys
can see here Okay, it's probably gonna pay out the most tomorrow At inception.
Let me drop vol here so we can see what we are at inception Okay,
it's a little off But anyways,
you guys can see here that we are long delta at inception, right?
We want the stock to go To go up.
I'm, not too sure why it's like that,
but this is what it looks like at inception Okay,
and because it went up Right or the stock was over here.
Remember the stock was right over here So if it goes up slightly And vol drops this
is going to pay out huge Right,
so this would be a pin fly in the morning wants to see This is uh before we drop
the vol right? Yeah, this is before we drop the vol Uh,
once we drop the vol eric It would look like this in the morning Right where okay
now we're gonna make money if it pins at 81.
We're gonna make the most money at 81, right?
so these are um Being short vol and leaning deltas in uh in the direction you want
to be Do you when you're trading earnings you usually do a quick scan to see if
there's a pre-release? Um,
I think we always do that Like if i'm going really really hard in the paint on earnings
like if i'm really in the zone Then you're always i'm always right if i'm like saying,
okay, i'm gonna be doing an earnings. Um,
uh An earnings rotation in my book and i'm gonna be spending as much time as I can
on this strategy Then you know i'll be basically in the zone every single day trying
to figure out as much information trading in the zone Yeah,
reading all the reports, uh, really trying to figure it out Uh parth,
can you just clarify your question?
He's like if the implied move is six percent you're um,
uh uh You're expecting a five percent move. Why put it three percent away?
Well, if you're expecting a five percent move then that's different Right,
that's different. Yeah,
we were saying it's probably not exactly after knowing about the pre-release We
were saying it'll probably be less than that If you're expecting a five percent
move,
of course You want to you want you'd want to pin it to to wherever you think it's
going to move, right?
You want you don't put your short strike to wherever you think, uh,
it's going to move So in your case, you know That made a lot of sense.
The only thing I would have done differently is um Change the strike for that last
wing.
Yeah changes try to get just because it's not very margin efficient right um Yeah
You know,
maybe you know and maybe maybe it's a little bit more of a personal thing I've just
never been a fan of broken wing butterflies So maybe you actually take that with
a brick of salt Okay Yeah,
i'm just thinking about that He was asking why not why not why why I don't like
uh broken wing butterflies. Um Like so they're not very margin efficient.
That's the first thing I hate that massive risk to the like I hate being right in
direction So like this let's say the stock goes up,
but it goes up So much that I lose a lot of money, right?
Like that's the worst feeling ever. It's like You know,
I think apple's gonna go up And then it goes up 15 And then I lose all my money
Right. That's that's what I don't like doing. So, uh,
one three two four unbalanced flies.
Usually not my my cup of tea Koa says tasty trade likes to sell butterflies.
What do you think? Um, I think they like to buy butterflies, right?
They look like they they're always short vol I don't think they like to sell butterflies,
right? Um koa. Here's here's a short butterfly Right.
I'm super against being long vol and capping. Yeah capping your gains, right?
You're buying vol for that reason of a potential blowout Right. Why? Uh,
why why cap your gains? Are you just kind of saying?
I'm kind of nervous about it. Like don't be in the long ball position. Yeah,
like what?
So but with regards to uh, you know tasty trade liking to sell vol right?
Let's say sell an iron condor there's nothing wrong with selling an iron condor
it's like but the thing we always talk about is like If you you should be selling
it if you think vol is expensive,
but expensive is relative to fair price Tasty trade doesn't offer a way for you
to determine fair value Right.
That's why that's why you have the terminal And that's why this is special And uh
koa they they sell iron flies, yeah,
it's a synthetic it's like what we call an iron condor.
Um I was gonna say something about uh about that, but now I forget Okay,
so part saying you know this you know because of that pre-release he was feeling
you know A lot safer about doing the broken wing. Gotcha, right?
So he's still in case,
you know He wanted to have the directional risk and then cap it to the downside
his risk But he was totally okay being exposed to the upside. Gotcha. Gotcha.
I would more exposure to the upside. Gotcha.
Gotcha Um because he was already biased in that way So it's like a his break-even
was already he already had a like a break-even to the upside that was pretty far,
you know Yeah, that makes some sense. Yeah. Yeah,
that's reasonable You just have to embrace that risk. Yeah,
I might I might have done a butterfly man and put the I just might have Done a one
a one two one and put the wings really far and just put it at your strike.
So it's maybe something like uh, 75 um 75 You said 83 was it is where you 80?
84 87 Okay,
so something I would have done something like this buddy Does not trade it here
Maybe something like this Right where you're still short a ton of vol and uh You
know if you get that rally to pin strike right you're you're making money uh in
a huge way,
um In multiple different levels That's probably what I would have done just out
of the money one two one balance fly So marcos is asking.
Um What he is not getting very well is that is the strategy you're you're like implementing
All the way until the earnings from the pre-release to the earnings.
Is there anything to do in between there? You could um marcos 100 man,
I mean What you could do is this right actually so before you hop into that to clarify
So marcos what we're saying here is this was a normal earnings trade Maybe we were
just looking at like a normal earnings trade and we noticed that there was the pre
-release All right now Because of that and we looked at it and vol was still high
We were saying being even though um You know,
it was slightly below the average move.
It wasn't a ton below it And we were saying it's still too expensive and having
that pre-release there. It should move a lot less No problem marcos. But uh,
maybe that's worth an idea worth talking about. Uh,
since we have we still have a few minutes here um to marcos,
you know to maybe go down that rabbit hole is uh If we see the pre-release today
and earnings is in a month, let's say or in two weeks What can we do? Yeah,
I'd probably get short vol right the market right away right away, right?
Because we know eventually the market's going to price it in right you can see here.
So if you go to the Would you be able to see in the earnings tab the vol drop off
right away? Uh, if it does so look what happened to thing here, right? Yeah,
could you could you rely on uh, Like could you rely on this number changing?
Yes, you almost certainly could right? Uh,
and if it doesn't then you know that hasn't priced it in yet, right? Right.
So you look at the average move or the average implied and see where it's different
So check this out marcos,
right december 1st the news came out Right around here Okay,
right around when it was still seven percent implying Okay,
and it took literally like five days For or sorry almost a month, right?
It's only around jan 5th where people started saying This thing's not gonna move.
Yeah, wait a minute, but maybe around jan 5th, let's say or even let's say,
you know around christmas time People started looking at earnings for micron now,
right? Okay now, you know,
I just finished my earning cycle It's time to move into the next cycle And microns
on my list and now the market makers are really looking at micron and now they're
saying oh this thing pre-release Let's drop balls off right,
but If you noticed it a month ago,
you could have been selling ball around this Right doing a calendar spread.
Let's say Isolating that event you would have made a lot of money boatloads All
right, it dropped off it dropped off,
uh one and a half one and a half balls one and a half points Right,
not one and a half volts one and a half. You're still like 20 volt. Yeah,
this would have dropped a ton of all So that's really the topic for today guys.
Do we have any more questions about pre-releases?
And just it's just another layer to trading guys, right?
Like we're trying to find a real real edge right some a real source of alpha something
we can bet on You know,
we we're not trying to uh You know draw fancy draw fancy lines and and uh You know
and try to make a bet on that right?
We want to see some real insights and real information that the market's not that
the market's missing And we want to be as competitive as possible And one thing
to keep in mind guys is and like,
you know We should really be learning from these and not just like oh,
this is a good idea But also carrying into other strategies, right?
Think about this. These just don't happen all the time.
They're very rare Right, but when they do happen,
there's usually a good trade around them And this is another layer of how the market
works, right?
The market is for the most part efficient Right the market's for the most part efficient
and it tried to be efficient here,
right vols did drop But it didn't drop fast enough And it didn't drop enough Okay,
so these are these are like, uh small,
you know small wrinkles in the market that you can find right and they're not you
know You shouldn't be going you shouldn't be waking up every morning Opening up
your screen and saying oh my god I got found a fantastic trade,
right if that's happening something's wrong Right your strategy your idea generation
is wrong Okay,
you know every morning you might wake up and there might be a potential idea that
you're willing to bet on But it's not going to be a fantastic strategy, right?
And this is just another example of these things come up very rarely Okay,
you can build a whole strategy around this uh this thing,
but you're only going to take 20 trades a year 30 trades a year Right,
so it just we need to start thinking in terms of inefficiencies Right risk premia
harvesting risk premia or trading inefficiencies Okay Another quick example of one
I was making a trade on a stock the other day and I had to trade below intrinsic
And to trade below intrinsic value on expiration day to get out of the position
Okay for any coders out there you can now create a system that looks for these and
picks them up all the time Right.
These are wrinkles in the market where people trade below intrinsic Or you buy below
intrinsic. This is like the high frequency people do in this day Yeah,
pick that up but it was so like I was there I was sitting below intrinsic for so
long that it could have been picked up by just Like you didn't have to be a high
frequency trader. He's got to be somebody put an order in wrong There's me.
Yeah,
it was yeah I was I was trying to get out and I couldn't get filled right?
No one was there to provide liquidity like 50 cents under an intrinsic Right.
Um,
that's an arbitrage So there's all these different types of strategies out there
that can make money But it's not every day you're going to wake up and there's it's
going to be there. Okay, so just keep that in mind guys Uh, no steve.
I had to do it because I couldn't take uh, I could not take the uh,
I could not take into expiration All right, because let's say, uh,
let's say one call option for example in the money Let's say just in the money on
micron is maybe going for 50 cents But the stock's trading at 95 Right.
So let's say I have 100 of those well, you know,
that's only What's that five grand? Or 500 bucks or no five grand.
Sorry in no in uh in in uh in debits,
but it's like 500 000 notional or a million notional So another question here from
part. Thanks for all the questions man. It's uh, this is really good. Um,
He said, uh,
you know With 83.54 being his upside target um you know i'm not 100 clear on it,
but uh So he's basically saying like if it moves like kind of like the average like
middle range of like four percent Should I be putting my uh?
My body right at that Okay,
so 83.54 being the upside target should m mu move the 5.75 Uh,
so so would that mean that the 71 81 91?
Would be better So that the middle is at around four percent Did you do you have
a couple drinks before this live part?
Yeah,
assuming you did your math right yeah If it moves in the direction you think right
don't forget the implied move number is uh,
absolute value that's up or down Oh, I see what you're saying. Yeah,
so the implied move, uh, what was it six percent? So six percent times uh,
eighty dollars is 48 so 480 times Plus 79 is 80.
So yeah 83.54 is where the implied move is right and remember though if it's to
the upside That's not the market's not saying it's going to move there Right the
market's not saying tomorrow. This is where it's going to move Okay,
what the market is saying is this?
On the whiteboard. Yeah The market is saying this Here's the stock right now.
Okay And here's all the potential prices tomorrow Okay right now it's trading at
80 Okay, and here is let's say uh 84 Okay, and here's 76 Okay,
and these are the implied move numbers Okay, this is implied move.
This is down the implied move and this is up the implied move.
Okay What the market is saying is just is this is what the earnings should look
like With frequency being on the y-axis.
Yeah and frequency on the y-axis The most likely scenario is going to be an up or
down move around this amount Okay Now this is we're gonna get the highest probabilities.
The mode is going to be here right the most frequent But you know,
sometimes we're going to have probabilities here Sometimes we have probabilities
here. Sometimes we have probabilities here, right?
So it's still very very possible, right?
But this is just where the mode of the distribution is Okay Awesome.
Awesome Okay So so I guess that is the end of tonight's live If
you guys have more questions about pre-releases, let's chat about in the group.
But also It might be worth taking a look for them, right? You know,
we got earning season right now coming up You know,
we're gonna make sure hutch watches this one.
He's gonna love this live um And pranav. I'm pranav.
Do you want to say hi to that? You want to say hi to your fellow teammates?
You did a really good really had a really good idea generation there and uh,
It's why we looked into micron So pranav if you're around and you want to say hi
to your fellow teammates Uh, let us know or you know,
if you want to talk about the research you did even no problem parth i'm glad to
know that uh 150 lives in we're still able to give some value Pranav's gone.
Oh, he bounced. Wow. I have a little chat with him Exactly neil Okay,
that's the end of the live everyone Irving it's good to see you out here, man.
I'm looking forward to uh,
I believe we have a call this weekend looking forward to it, man Exactly.
Steven. Steven's like,
you know that pranav's gone when the chat is orderly again All right,
we're gonna wrap it up there everyone. Have a great night.