Okay, so today's lecture is going to be on expected value.
So we all talk about expected value.
There's a little bit about it in the bronze course,
but today we're gonna deep dive into really how expected value plays out,
what we need to think about,
how it looks like in different scenarios in the world of trading and even outside
of the world of trading. So let's hop right into it. Yeah, so as Sean's saying,
like expected value is everything, right? It's,
if we have a positive expected value, it means we're playing a winning game,
means we're making money. So what we're gonna do here,
and what I did here was I simulated,
so we're looking at the top left graph over here, guys. Okay,
what I did was I simulated an expected value, okay, with 62% hit rate.
So we win 62% of the time. And when we win, we win a dollar. And when we lose,
we lose a dollar 50. So risk reward is one to 1.5, 1.5 to one.
And 38% chance we lose, 62% chance we win. Very similar to earnings. Okay,
obviously it's not perfect, but very similar. So 38% of the time, right here,
guys, remember, this is our expected value formula.
Probability of winning times how much we win minus probability of losing times how
much we lose.
And what we need to really just remember here, guys,
is what are we trying to really calculate here?
We're trying to calculate if we're supposed to win, right?
Theoretically, do we come out ahead in a game like this?
And the things that we need to consider are really two things, right?
So it's our risk to reward and our probabilities of success, right?
We can use this to break down blackjack, casino games, all types of betting.
We can use it to break down life and death situations, although it's like,
if you win, you live. If you lose, you die.
And it's like a 99% chance you live. It's like, you know, but you can use this.
You can really apply this to anything. And why do we do this though,
is also because we need to see what it looks like to play in a winning game,
right? Imagine we have no clue what a winning game looks like.
People might think winning game only goes up into the right.
So we need to simulate what does a winning game actually look like?
And because we can do that, we can get more understanding, right?
So we are gonna simulate a winning game. And in fact,
our expected value is 5 cents for every dollar we bet.
So every time I go bet a dollar, I'm gonna make 5 cents on average. Okay,
so that is our edge here. And just let's stop on that for one second,
because let's think about it. In a game where you either win one or lose 1.5,
how the hell do you make 5 cents? Well, what you do is,
you have to look at it in the long run, right? So for example,
62% of the time, you're gonna win one, 38% of the time, you're gonna lose 1.5.
If you average that out over a long, long time, on average per hand,
so if you took your total return and divided it by the number of games you played,
you would get 5 cents plus 5 cents. So on average, you made 5 cents per game,
but on each individual game, you either went plus one or negative 1.5.
So we're actually gonna play one game here. Okay,
we're gonna play one game 10 times.
So one player is gonna play this game 10 times. Okay,
so we have a 5 cent edge for every dollar we bet. So we're gonna play it.
So we're gonna play this game 10 times, okay?
And one player, okay? And this is what happens. So you can see,
we- Started with a little loss. We lost $1.80, right? We started out zero.
Or sorry, $1.50. Our first bet, we went down to negative $1.50.
Then we lost another $1.50. Okay, so now we're at $3. This is the second hand.
Then third hand, we made $1.00. Fourth hand, we made $1.00.
It kept going up and up and up and up and up. Then we lost one couple,
lost a couple, okay? And we ended up being down negative $2.00. Okay,
let's run it again.
Do you guys understand what's going on here? Yeah, if not,
we'll stop and play again. Okay, so look at this, guys. In this situation,
okay? We won twice in a row, right? We went from $1.00, then $2.00.
We won $1.00 and $1.00, right? Every time we win, we get $1.00.
And then we went on this really bad losing streak. Got smoked. Got smoked.
So do you guys get this so far? So far, we're good.
If you looked at this return, what would you think?
If all you looked at was the outcome, good or bad strategy? Yeah, dookie,
bad strategy, right? You look at that P&L graph, you go,
I don't want my P&L graph to look like that.
I don't wanna do what this guy's doing. But this is a winning game.
This is a winning game. You're in a winning,
you're playing a winning game here. Okay, so let's actually do that again.
Let's take it a little step further. Okay,
what we're gonna do actually is we're going to play this game 100 times.
We're gonna play this game 100 times,
but what we're gonna do is we're gonna have 10 people play this game.
So I think we have a little more than 10 guys on the live here.
So just imagine everyone, we'll do 11 because we have 11 of you on the live.
All of us play this game. And we play this game, we do 100 trades, okay?
So every time this trade comes up, we do it.
And we actually are able to place 100 trades, every person on this live here,
okay? So let's actually see what happens now.
Okay, look at this. So about half of us make money.
Each of these lines is a different player. Yeah,
so each of these lines is a different player. So for example,
this orange line here is Codemaster.
And then obviously this yellow line down here is either- That's Parker. Yeah,
it's either- It's Neil or Parker. Or Kyle too. Or it could be Kyle. Oh,
it's probably Kyle. It's most likely Kyle.
Okay, so each one of these is a different line. But what is this telling us?
What is this telling us here? What can we infer here, right?
And why can we actually joke about it being Kyle? Because that's luck.
It's unlucky that Kyle got, he's the one that got fucked, right?
That's why they say in trading, there's a lot of luck, right?
There's a lot of noise and very small signal. So this game has a lot of luck.
And, you know, so let's say 100 trades, this is half an earning season, okay?
Now let's actually bump this up. Let's play this game.
Let's play this game for two earning seasons.
So we've got 11 of us here, okay? Play the whole earning season.
Play the whole earning season.
Come on, brown line. Okay,
now take a look at this. Four of us get absolutely loaded, okay?
Four of us actually make 40,
we start off with a dollar and we end up with 40 bucks. Okay,
some of us actually hit 50 bucks. So some of us get rich.
On the other hand, some of us, another four of us lose. Actually two,
two lose a lot. A few of them are floating around break even, right?
This guy does okay. He does 10 times, 10 times better than me.
10 times is money, right? It's pretty good. You know, this guy breaks even,
this guy breaks even, but two of us lose a little bit of money, okay?
We go in debt. So this is half an earning season. Sorry, this is two quarters.
Now, if we did a full year cycle, okay?
We did a full year on a strategy that has a 5% edge, okay?
Very similar to earnings. Very, very similar to earnings,
okay? Almost all of us make money here and we're all playing the same game.
Every single one of us is playing the same game.
Some of us get absolutely rich, right? We're just- A hundred times your money.
A hundred times our money. But some of us get extremely, extremely wealthy.
On the flip side, some of us get unlucky. And look, in this case,
brown lines at the top. Kyle comes from being the underdog to top dog.
Now look at what's happening over here, guys.
Look at what's happening in the first 100 hands, okay? It's really noise.
It's really noise. And a lot of us are floating around break even here.
And we can say as well that these guys that are up here are higher than average.
They got more than what was made, right?
Maybe we're only supposed to be around here. This is our expected value, right?
Is maybe to be up 10 hands or 10 times our money or 15 times our money.
But people are all the way up here. Other guys are down here.
And obviously you guys are gonna see that if we increase this number, right?
Everybody makes money. Every single one of us is gonna make money.
Just give it a second to load. It usually takes a little while.
Because we're running quite a bit of hands here, right?
We're running basically a life cycle of earnings. You know,
earnings until five, 10 years of earnings.
It's just gonna take a second here to load, guys.
Just a little sludge break.
Can't believe I drank a whole stein of this garbage.
Well, there we go, right? Everybody makes money, okay? But in the short run.
Doesn't always happen that way. Doesn't always happen, right?
And this is why it's sometimes hard to stay with a strategy even though it's a winning
game, right? Like for example, if I told you guys for certain, I said, hey,
let's play a game. And we're gonna play this game exactly.
None of you would say no to it. None of you. And if you do,
there's something wrong. You're not understanding probabilities.
You're not understanding expected value. However,
it doesn't mean you're gonna come out right away a winner.
Even in the short run. It takes a while for edges to play out.
And if we have a bad earnings season like we had now, like we had last quarter,
it wasn't a great season, that's for sure, right? Tons of blowouts.
That's gonna affect our P&L, right? The quarter before that was unreal.
It was an unreal quarter.
And this is why simulating these games where we actually know for certain,
for a hundred percent certainty, we should come out a winner.
We even at some point come out losers, right? In a full earnings season,
two of us here lost, right? Three of us here lost.
And two of us came out breakeven, just a little bit better than breakeven.
But it doesn't make it a bad game, right? It doesn't make it a bad game.
You're still playing a winning game.
And now what we need to really think about, right?
So what this really paints a picture of guys is that you can't just look at the
outcome. The outcome matters. If you're not making money,
you need to be on top of things. But what do you need to be on top of, right?
That's the real question here is, do you need to be on top of like, oh,
my psychology? Do you need to be on top of, you know, I missed the breakout.
It was actually, it was a false breakout.
What do you really need to be on top of here?
What you need to be on top of is your expected value. Is there still edge?
Do you still actually have an edge in this game? Is this still a winning game?
So you look at things like at a surface level,
your risk reward and your probabilities of success.
What is your confidence in this trade? Where is that coming from? Right,
the most important thing is to really,
really know what goes into your expected value. Why like, so for example,
in this equation, if you look up here, we put in a 62% chance of winning.
It's hard to find a game that has a 62% chance of winning. Right,
but what we balanced it with, right? Because earnings is maybe close to that.
We balanced it with a one reward, 1.5 risk.
So you lose more when you lose than you make when you win. Right,
and this is how you'll typically see it play out.
If there's a huge probability of winning, right?
So you can go and sell out of the money it puts. You'll have an 85, 90,
95% hit rate, but your risk reward is like one to a hundred, right?
When it does blow out, you lose it all. And when you plug those numbers in,
you find out you have a negative,
or only maybe very slightly positive expected value with blow up potential,
right? So that's how we really want you guys thinking about this.
This is how a professional trader looks at this game. They don't just look,
you know, go back to running it, like run it out like a hundred times. Right,
or just copy the whole thing down. Yeah. This one here? Yeah, all the way down.
Look at me guys, I'm coding now, right? If you just see this, right?
Or if we do, do I just change this to a one? For what?
If I just want one player? Yeah, just take away this. Okay.
Let me just run this one more time, guys.
We can just run this one actually right here. Yeah, just like that line. Okay,
yeah. Oh yeah, I see what you mean. Right, if you see this,
looks like a bad game. Someone shows you this, it's awful.
Remember we told you about the guy in that Tasty Trade group,
what was his name? Denny, not Denny, the one with the post COVID journal.
Oh yeah, Daniel Sung. Yeah, Daniel Sung. He was a rising star on Tasty Trade.
He was big in this Facebook group we were in.
He was keeping a trade journal post COVID where he was selling zero day to expiration
out of the money options and collecting pennies.
Why did he have to do post COVID?
Because the reason he had to do post COVID is he was playing a game with negative
expected value.
And when COVID happened and we had that huge downturn in the market,
he lost his shirt. So now he needs to sell courses to get his shirt back.
But that's why we can't just look at a snapshot.
What he's showing there is a snapshot where it does well.
The market is only going up right now.
Selling puts makes money or would have made money historically over the last five
months or 10 years. Yeah, but because we never had a down day.
But what you're getting there is, the way we can think about it, guys,
is like this. If I change this to 10,000 plays, let's say.
You wanna do the one guy? Can I just run this whole thing? Yeah, that's good.
Right? So let's say that this is the graph here. What Denny did,
let's say is this.
He showed you this. Why is it such an ugly color?
What these guys are doing is they're showing you this. Right? Look how it did,
but they're not showing you this. But as sophisticated traders,
we need to look at the whole picture. We need to ask these tough questions.
You know, we gotta think about it. And if we only look at a small sample size,
right? Let's say this is 100 trades.
And let's say this is 100 trades. Well,
two very different pictures of the same game. What do you believe?
And this is why we can't just look at this. We can't just look at the chart.
We can't just look at our outcome. Because you see number one,
and you think it's the worst strategy in the world. You see number two,
and you think you're gonna be Jeff Bezos next year. When in reality,
when you look at up here, when you look at all this,
when you look at the code that goes into it,
when you look at the expected value,
instead of when you look at what the game really is,
rather than just what the outcome has been, you can say,
this is a game I wanna play. This is a game where I'm supposed to make money.
That's the way we need to be thinking about our trades.
Am I supposed to make money here? Given my risk to reward,
given my confidence in the trade, what the hell is my outcome supposed to be?
Am I supposed to make money?
And that's why it's so important to understand why you should make money,
right? Why should we make money selling vol on earnings? Well,
if we didn't make money selling vol on earnings,
that would mean buying vol around earnings,
which would make it an unbelievable trade. Because remember guys,
if you can diversify a long vol strategy that makes money,
you have the holy grail, because everything is a max risk.
And if you can diversify that max risk, you can make a ton of money,
ton of money. Now, should the market pay you for that?
Does it make sense theoretically, right? It doesn't, like everyone would do it.
Then the other thing is, well, whose money are we eating here?
Whose lunch are we eating here? Who's gonna be buying these options? Well,
if retail traders are predominantly long options,
if hedge funds are predominantly long options, if you can't,
if the barrier to entry for selling options is higher than the barrier to entry
for buying options,
it doesn't make sense that buying options around earnings should make money.
It doesn't make sense. And if it did make sense,
we'd all be rich extremely quickly, because we can leverage.
We can leverage on a long vol strat. We can't leverage on a short vol strat,
okay? So we have to think about that, but guys, we will go through drawdowns.
We just came off an amazing quarter. It only makes sense. You know,
Neil's on this live. You guys can ask Neil.
Every single trade Neil put on last quarter was a winner, right?
So it's tough. Like even that guy that I showed you, that Kay Seidel,
he did his first earnings season last quarter, and it was amazing.
It was amazing. He hyped it up, talked to his group, posted it everywhere.
And then this quarter, he went ghost. He went silent, okay?
And we all know the reason, right? He doesn't buy wings. He was selling vol,
and he got absolutely crushed,
okay? Oh, sorry, it wasn't Kay Seidel, actually.
It was the other guy from MacroOps, MacroOptions or whatever. Okay,
so now that we have that,
a couple of questions here in the group we're gonna chat about.
So Renato, you're asking us to run it with a one-to-one risk to reward.
So- Sorry, I'm struggling. Neil, I've done about 5,000 trades over about three,
four years. Renato wants us to run it with a one-to-one risk to reward.
So here's the thing. We can do that. You can just click clear. Okay.
We can do that. It's gonna be skewed though,
because the odds of you finding something with a one-to-one risk reward where you
have a 62% chance of winning is gonna be really hard.
And we're gonna show you what your expected value is for that, right?
You'll see why it'll be really hard. Yeah, so let's put this in. Okay,
so every time we're gonna win 62% of the time,
our risk reward is gonna be one-to-one and we're gonna lose 30% of the time.
Well, that makes our expected value 24 cents for every dollar you bet.
So imagine you bet $10,000. On average, you should make $2,400 per trade.
Even if you lose 10,000, on average, your expected value is 2,400 per trade.
So let's go and run that. So we're gonna run that just 100 times. Okay,
and we're gonna have the same 11 guys here. Maybe there's 12 now. There's 13.
So all of us are gonna play this game.
Better luck this time, Kyle. Well, you guys are gonna do great, right? Kyle,
you're okay. Kyle is taking the brown color. I'll take the dark blue line.
Jordan, who are you? Okay, I'm gonna do green. I'm gonna do dark green,
light green, dark green. Okay, Neil's the light purple line.
Andreas is the yellow line.
Look at that. Just in 100 games,
everybody makes not just a little bit of money. Look at this.
Some guys made 50 times their money in just 100 games. You and Kyle. Yeah,
that's right. That's right, buddy. We're back on top, right?
That's next earning season. But look what happened, guys. In the short run,
look what happened in the first 25 hands, right? Actually,
even the first 40 hands, right?
Two guys here were losing money in a game that was like you're never gonna find
anywhere. They were still losing money in the first 40 hands. Okay,
so- Is this only 100 hands? This is 100 hands. Everyone got rich.
Everyone made money, right? So with these- Wait,
can we change it to one-to-one? Yeah. So here's an example, guys. You know,
and this is obviously not for the more advanced guys.
I know you guys already know your shit, but for the newer guys here,
that's why when you see someone come and say, hey, listen,
I have a 90% hit rate with a one-to-one,
let's actually run that and you guys will see. Okay, so we're gonna go.
Unless his name is Jeff and his last name is Bezos. Okay, so 90% hit rate.
Okay, imagine we had a 90% hit rate, one-to-one risk reward.
You actually, no one in this group even went through a drawdown.
So if someone's saying, listen, I do a 90% hit rate, one-to-one risk reward.
You only need to do five trades for you to say, is this guy legit?
Only five trades. So for example,
if you're in Aristotle's group and Aristotle's claiming, I don't know,
even 85% or 90%, whatever it is, with two-to-one risk reward,
then you only have to take his trades two times, three times in order to say,
okay, is he legit or not? If you are losing money after two or three trades,
he's not legit. He's lying to you, right?
And these are just quick- It's just numbers. It's just numbers, right?
They always say men lie, women lie, numbers don't, okay? This is just,
you can just say, hey, listen, Aristotle,
you say you have 90% hit rate with a one-to-one risk reward.
Why is it after 10 trades, I'm down 30% of my account? Well,
you know what he's gonna say. Risk management. Yeah, mentality, psychology,
risk management. You got greedy. You got greedy, right? It's not,
you should never lose ever if you can find that kind of money.
Like you could put a monkey in front of the computer and just tell it they hit the
button and you should make money.
And the reason why these games actually don't exist, okay,
is because if they did exist, someone would take advantage of it. Now,
I don't wanna say they don't exist because they do,
but they do where the barrier to entry is extremely high. For example,
insurance. Insurance, you and I can't go and start up an insurance company.
We can't do it. Sean, can you go start an insurance company tomorrow? We can.
Yeah, we can't go do it, right? We can't go and start up a bank.
We can't go and do these things where the premiums are extremely expensive relative
to the payouts.
However, anyone can open up a brokerage account.
Anyone can go and look at a chart.
Anyone can go and start selling vol around earnings. Well, not anyone,
but a lot of people. Anyone can go and buy vol around earnings.
So for that reason, if there was a strategy that was extremely profitable,
remember, we're living in a world of competition.
We're living in a world where you are playing against extremely smart people,
not just the people in Aristotle Group, not just Sean and I.
You're playing against- Ewan Sinclair. Ewan Sinclair, Aaron Brown, right?
Firms. And if they have, let's say,
20 guys that come into a room every single day and say, hey, listen,
let's test this strategy, right? So for that reason,
you're never gonna find something that is a huge expected value.
But that doesn't mean you can't get rich. Big difference.
You don't need a huge expected value. Exactly. You just need unexpected value,
a positive one. It's like what Aaron Brown says. Aaron Brown says,
if you wanna get rich, all you need is a 3% edge. That's it.
But people don't look at that and they spend their whole time looking for these
strategies that have a 80% win rate, a 75% win rate, a 90% win rate,
and they never end up making it because they were looking too far ahead.
They're being too ahead of themselves.
It's like, what's another example we can use for that? Like, it's like,
look at even in the world of business these days,
most of the new tech that you see coming out is incremental changes to what already
exists. It's not every,
you don't need to always search for the blow out of the water,
the fucking lottery ticket, right?
There's money to be made in incremental things and very,
very small edges and very small changes. You know what I mean? Yeah,
and I think Stephen had a really good point here as well. He's like,
remember guys, when oil was negative $20 a barrel,
Sean and I couldn't go into the barrel yard and say, hey, give me some oil.
I wanna put a thousand barrels of oil in my backyard in our little 300 square foot
balcony, right? We can't do that. We can't do that.
So that's a huge barrier to entry. We should have bought some barrels, dude.
I mean, I think they do like a thousand barrels.
You have to buy a thousand barrels. That's one contract.
So Sean and I can't go and do that.
You guys can't go and do that. You're gonna have a storing facility.
You gotta be able to, whatever the whole process is, I have no clue,
but it's a high barrier to entry.
So the people that can do it and store it will get paid for it.
And those are extremely profitable plays, right? But we don't need that.
We don't need that to get rich. And also guys,
those people that are doing it have a business, they have employees,
they have overhead, they have a ton of overhead, right?
You wanna keep your overhead low and just find a small edge and play it over the
long run. And most importantly, understand your edge.
If you don't understand your edge,
how the hell are you gonna live through a drawdown?
If I wasn't saying to you guys, guys, listen,
selling vol around earnings events has a long-term positive expected value.
You guys would have given up. A lot of you would have given up, right?
It's one thing you can do is reduce your risk, right? I know,
I always talked to Neil about this when he was starting out with us.
You can't just have a $5,000 count in trade earnings because it's hard,
it's really difficult, right? You have to go to smaller names.
You gotta really work your way up there.
You gotta go really small and work your way up.
But that's hard because a lot of the companies are $150 stocks, right?
So remember, another thing about having your expected value play out,
the most important thing actually,
after finding a positive expected value game is managing your risk.
And that's the whole Kelly Criterion thing we talked about. Right,
so even if we're playing a game,
like let's say earnings that has a winning expected value,
but our risk is too big, you're gonna end up losing. So this is what makes,
for example, selling earnings a little bit difficult.
It's a little harder for the average person.
But buying a vol around earnings is easy.
So when you guys build out these strategies,
you really have to think these through, okay? Why should I make money here?
The first thing. Then obviously, if you can test it, that's very important.
But even more importantly, is understand why the edge is there.
Then build out a risk structure where it's like, okay, well,
this is how much risk I have to take per trade. If I go any bigger than this,
I'm gonna make money. And a good rule of thumb is,
if you don't know how much risk you should be betting, bet small.
If you don't know how much risk you should be playing, bet small.
I can't say that enough, okay, guys?
Exactly. Actually, negative gamma. I had no clue that Lotto Max was plus EV.
I'd actually love to hear that, because I'd like to go- Buy some tickets. Yeah,
have some fun with it, man. If you want to post it in Trader's Chat,
that'd be sweet, dude. Nice little trade we'll have going here.
You know, it's- I'm on a 15-year drawdown,
but I have a positive expected value. But you're gonna hit it.
I'm gonna hit one day. Yeah. And it's funny,
because even when you have a positive expected value in a game like that,
you might even go your whole life without hitting it, right?
But you only have to hit it once. But you only have to hit it once.
So all of a sudden, it's positive. Yeah, and we have 12 guys playing that game,
right? As you guys saw,
some people actually make money and some people lose money.
And you can't look at the guy and be like, you're better than me,
you're smarter than me, because they're playing the same game.
They're doing the same thing. That's why there's so much luck.
And if you talk to any- I'm sure you guys have heard this many times.
If you talk to anyone who's made a lot of money in the world,
they'll tell you a lot of it was luck, right? You need the skill.
There's no question.
No one's gonna get extremely rich without putting in skill,
unless they hit the lottery, or they inherited it.
But if you wanna go from nothing to something and work your way up,
you need that skill. But there's a lot of luck along the way.
You met the right person at the right time.
A good deal came up at the right time,
which gave you your first boost to get into the game. Yeah,
but you had the skill to recognize the deal. Yeah, exactly.
It's like, there's a saying about luck. It's like- I just dropped my water.
What is it? It's like,
being lucky is opening yourself up to luck and putting yourself in a position for
lucky things to happen, right? So for example,
everyone else saw the deal that was a good deal that showed up.
You're the one who took it, but you didn't take it because you're Joe Schmo.
You took it because you studied whatever industry that is.
Yeah, exactly. Dylan, exactly, man. Luck is nothing more than preparation,
meeting opportunity. Exactly. That's exactly what I was trying to say, man.
And you know you're prepared when your expected value is positive.
Amply prepared. Yeah.
I hope you guys got some insight there in strategy development and what reality
actually looks like, what rich actually looks like.
So I'm just gonna quickly do it again, guys. If you can find,
so if you can find a strategy, let's say, where you can trade on a daily basis.
So we'll actually have some fun and go through a couple of strategies.
If you can find a strategy that you can trade,
let's say like a Delta One product,
like a stock product or a Forex pair or whatever,
let's say you can trade on a daily timeframe. Actually, let's go,
let's have some more fun because I know there's a couple of scalpers here.
Let's say you can trade 10 times a day. So in one year,
3,650 trades. Okay, actually, sorry, 2,500 trades, one year. Okay, one year.
Okay, and let's say 60, 40,
one-to-one, one-to-one, 60, 40.
Okay, and this is what a lot of us,
this is what a lot of us are used to when we first get into trading. All right,
this seems reasonable. Hey, you know what? I'm 60% right, no problem.
One-to-one risk reward. Easy, easy. It's easy.
I can trade this on a daily timeframe, scalping some pips. This makes sense.
This makes a lot of sense to me.
So look at this. Everyone makes money in one year. Everybody. You should make,
and most people make between 2,000 and 3,000%. Yeah.
Most people make 20 times their money in one year. That's the average.
20 times the money in one year. So we need to ask ourselves this question,
right?
If some of you out there are scalping pips,
and let's say you had a long period of time.
Let's say you've been doing this for three months.
You need to really ask yourself, why is my expected value not showing?
Why is it not making me money? Okay? Because this seems realistic.
I'm gonna win 60% of the time. I'm gonna lose 40% of the time. Right?
I'm more right than I'm wrong most of the time. Right? You know,
it's just a little bit, I'm just a little bit smarter than being wrong. Right?
I'm just a little bit better than 50%. Well, and you can see right here, right?
You should never be losing after a year. Right? And you can actually see after,
oh, you know what? This is actually, guys, this is only a hundred games.
This is only a hundred games. This is only 10 days of trading.
I forgot to run it here.
Look at this. You make 600 times your money.
Okay? You make 600 times your money running it for one year.
So we really gotta ask ourselves, does this make sense? So important,
so critical, so critical. These are the reasons why these trades don't exist.
No, sorry. They do exist, but you're rarely gonna be able to act on them. Okay?
You're rarely gonna be able to act on them. High barrier to entry, for example.
Dude, I was running it a hundred, I did a hundred times.
This is what happened when I did a whole year.
Oh, so you make 600 times your money. 600 times your money. One to- One to one,
60, 40. Okay. Okay, so what do you guys think about that? Yeah,
what do you guys think about this? Because this is something, I know,
at least for me, when I was first started trading, 60, 40, one to one,
that seemed super doable. It seems super doable. Super doable.
So what do you guys think about this? Like, are we crazy?
What do you guys think? I wanna know your opinion, your real authentic opinion,
because we gotta talk about it. We got 20 minutes left on the live.
We got a whole group here of guys who are passionate about trading, you know?
And a lot of people think 60, 40 is real. It's realistic. So let's,
one to one risk reward. So let's talk about it. Let's get it out in the open.
And I'm gonna actually end the live, the recording here. Okay.