Hey everyone and welcome to our video on structures So just like in the stock market
when you think the stock is going up You buy the stock and when you think the stock
is going down you can short the stock Well,
the same is actually true in the options market if you think implied volatilities
Overestimating the future realized volatility. Well,
you want to be able to short volatility Conversely if you think that options are
cheap,
you know implied volatility is cheap relative to the future volatility Then you
won't be able to buy volatility But you can't go into the market just like you can
in stocks and go and buy volatility or sell volatility There's no asset that says
for example Apple Volatility where you if you don't like it,
you can sell it and if you like it you can buy it We don't have this in the market
But what we do have is options and because options are volatility products We can
use them to take a view on Volatility.
So how can we actually structure a trade that takes a view on this? Well,
this is where structures come in bronze.
We're gonna focus on two structures a straddle and Iron condor Now
don't you worry if you are unsure what a straddle is or an iron condor is We are
going to go through it in depth throughout this course You're also going to be seeing
it come up over and over again and you're gonna be seeing your fellow traders talking
about these trades frequently so a straddle is long Volatility Meaning you like
volatility.
You think volatility is cheap The iron condor is short volatility Now
with both these structures We don't want to take a view on The underlying stock
or the price or the direction?
We want to just take a view on volatility So we need to structure these products
Where they are neutral on Direction one thing to keep in mind guys as you go and
learn from other sources as well Is that you will see people saying iron condors
are the best strategy or straddles are the best strategy?
the truth is These are not strategies These are tools to take a view on volatility
Think about it if you are electrician if you have a nail to hit you're gonna use
a hammer not a screwdriver The same goes with options market if you want to sell
volatility. Well,
you're gonna short an iron condor If you want to be buying volatility you want to
be buying the straddle So these this is what these positions look like Let's say
Apple Is trading at $200 a share What you would go and do is you would go into the
options market and buy the $200 straddle and it would look exactly like this where
if the stock Where the point of the straddle is?
200 and let's say down here is 220 and down here is 180 on the y-axis we have our
P&L What this means is if the stock Breaks out into this region.
Let's say 220 or breaks down into this region we'll say 180 we start making money
and As the stock continues to go up we make more and more money and as the stock
continues to go down We make more and more money.
So we don't have a view on direction But what we do have is a view on the size of
the move and As you guys know the size of the move is another word for volatility
So what this straddle is telling us is that the market?
Expects the stock to stay within this range So this is stocks at 200 the markets
expecting it to hang around here somewhere Okay,
let's call this 205 Let's call this 195 and On this point over here 205 so the market
is expecting the stock to stay within this $10 range But when we buy this straddle
what we are saying is that it's going to go beyond this range In fact,
it's going to be either down here Below 195 or it's going to be up here Above 205
So you guys can see that when volatility expands We actually are going to make money.
So that is why we say a straddle a long straddle not a short straddle a long straddle
Is long volatility now,
let's head over to iron condors the way an iron condor looks is actually The straddle
but instead we're selling it.
So it looks like this But that's not just it we actually go out and buy further
out of the money options To cap our loss. Now.
I'm sure you're asking like why do we decide to buy the wings? Well,
let's go back over here when we buy the straddle we have unlimited potential for
gains If a stock declares bankruptcy We're the stock is going to go all the way
down to near zero and we are gonna make a lot of money If the stock gets bought
out the stock will go up a hundred percent and we're gonna make a ton of money We
have unlimited gain potential here Now if we're short the straddle We have unlimited
loss potential This is not prudent risk management to have unlimited loss potential
So what we decide to do is buy our wings to cap our max loss So the P&L for this
will look something like this Where we expect the stock to stay within this range.
Let's say this is the 195 and this is the 205 We expect the market to stay within
this When we go out of that region We start to lose money We are betting on volatility
going down.
We are short Volatility also with this item condor We are directionless meaning
we don't care if the stock goes to 205 or 195 or 197 or 199 as Long as it stays
within this range between 195 and 205 so we are using this item condor to take a
directionless view and bet on volatility if Volatility is less than what the market
implied Realized volatility is less than what the market implied This iron condor
is gonna make money and this straddle is gonna lose money So depending on your view
of the market you can decide which tool to use No tool is better than the other
You will see a lot of the time where people say short volatility is always better
or a long volatility is always better There is no better in options There is only
what is your view and what tool do you use to take your view on the market?
now I know a lot of you come from the Delta one space or the directional space and
This I'm sure is very foreign to you But let me tell you something Options are a
volatility product in order to master options We need to understand that they are
volatility products and how to actually trade them Strictly on volatility in the
future We are actually going to bring direction in to our trading strategies and
that's going to be covered in silver Stick with me throughout this course and you