So everyone, on tonight's live, we wanted to, you know,
Jordan and I spent some time thinking about it, and we thought of a way that,
if you have a small account, I shared with you guys a couple of weeks ago,
my small account challenge, where I said, you know,
the way I grew an account from, you know,
a couple thousand bucks to a couple bigger thousand bucks, you know,
from three to eight was by taking really high conviction trades,
putting a ton of risk on the table, cutting losers short, letting winners run.
And it's a good strategy. It's a good strategy, but to really, you know,
if you're fresh into the options game, or, you know, like, you know,
maybe a couple months in, you're not gonna learn a ton doing that,
and you're not gonna be finding those trades yourself. Right,
a lot of those trades that are high enough conviction that you would be doing that
would come from the group. So it's not necessarily like, sure,
you might make some money today,
but you're not building yourself into the person that makes money for a long time.
And that's, what you get that from is by trading a lot,
by finding your own ideas and then trading them with frequency.
The problem with that is that you have to pay to play, right,
trading costs money. You pay commissions, you pay the spread.
And if you're trading, you know, a $2,000 account, let's say,
you're gonna get eaten alive by those commissions. So what can you do to learn?
What can you do to make money and learn?
And that is what we are gonna talk about on today's live. It's a top,
it's actually a silver topic, but I think, and Jordan will talk about this,
we might bump this down a bit because I think it's so valuable.
Tonight's topic is Gamma Scalping and Delta Hedging and particularly Gamma Scalping
as an actual account strategy.
Any intro comments, Jordan? No, I think it's, I guess, actually, intro comment.
This is actually how I learned.
So when I first started trading, just to give super quick background there,
when I first started into options,
the way that I learned was by buying straddles, so right off the bat,
limited risk, okay, buying straddles and Gamma Scalping.
That was the way I learned, right? At the end of the day,
if you don't have money on the table, it's hard to be motivated to learn.
You don't really learn the nuances, like spreads, like commissions,
like drawdowns, right? Like market impact. Risks, Greeks. Exactly,
and so the cheapest way,
the cheapest way to learn this is try to find under priced vol,
buy straddles and Delta Hedging or Gamma Scalping.
And I would go on the Bloomberg Terminal every day, scan, like,
so this is maybe four years ago,
scan for stocks that were cheap in terms of volatility.
This might be buying stuff into earnings.
You guys can reach out to Pulumi about this as well.
We spent a lot of time on it. Buying stuff below its first quantile. Yeah,
just buying something that I thought was cheap. And then Delta Hedges, right?
And this is probably the cheapest way to learn options, in my opinion.
And you can make money. And you can make, I mean, hey,
there's nothing better than you wake up in the morning and the stocks move 10%,
right? It's anti-fragile.
And we're in an environment now where vol's maybe picking up a little bit,
starting, you can feel some stuff boiling. Well,
Gamma Scalping might not be a bad thing.
So the beauty about long convexity is you're never gonna wake up in the morning
and say, shit, you know? That's what we wake up in the morning and say.
Exactly, exactly. Most of the time you're gonna wake up in the morning and say,
well, whatever, right? But sometimes you're gonna wake up in the morning,
holy cow,
right? So it's the best way, in my opinion, to learn. Learn options, you know,
and also make some money. And what's really cool about it,
so it involves buying and selling shares. In the US,
you can trade shares for free, right?
So you get to save a good bit of money on those commissions. Whereas in Canada,
like even with IBKR, you pay a small fee for shares, right? Yeah, dude,
you're always paying. Pay like a buck, right? Yeah, a buck, yeah. Minimum.
Right, so you don't have to pay that. Yeah, Marcos, but we're in Canada.
Thinkorswim's five bucks in and out. It's crazy. And sure,
like I think it's actually probably the best way, the best intro into vol. So,
you know, I'm really happy Marcos just posted there. Like sometimes it's,
you know, and just from like what I know from Marcos, he's very, you know,
he's got some good alpha in the directional space.
But getting into vol sometimes, it might be a little tricky, right? Especially,
you know, you see Sean and I always talking about being short convexity.
If you decide to buy volatility, right, which everyone can do,
and Delta hedge that, it's,
I think it's a super good introduction to trading volatility.
So let's start this off with, what is gamma scalping? Okay, yeah,
maybe we'll start with gamma scalping. Okay,
we'll talk about gamma scalping and then we'll just do a quick PA scan and then
run a strategy. Yeah, yeah, it's like, you know,
not everyone here will be familiar with that as a strategy, right?
So let's talk about first actually, what is gamma?
So gamma is basically the rate of change of Delta, right?
So how much your Delta is gonna change for every dollar move in the stock price.
So, okay, just to make it like as simple as possible.
So your Delta is your exposure to the stock price. Yes.
How much money your option makes or loses as the stock itself moves. Correct.
And what gamma is, is your sensitivity to, so the, let's say this, you know,
if the stock moves $1, you get paid $1, let's say.
But if the stock keeps moving that way and starts to move quicker, well,
you're gonna actually get paid out more. And that's the gamma effect. Correct.
So gamma is that rate of change in how much you get paid for the stock moving.
So basically the difference between the stock moving like 1%, 1%,
1% versus like a 5% on the last day, right?
The pay off of that one move is different. Right,
think about buying a way out of the money call option. You think about Tesla,
you buy a $2,000 call option and expiring tomorrow, expiring tomorrow. Well,
if the stock moves up a hundred bucks today from 800 to 900,
you're gonna see zero change in the P&L of your call option, okay?
But imagine that stock continues to go up and now it's at 1,000. Well,
all of a sudden from 1,000 to 1,100, you're gonna be making a ton of money.
And that's that gamma exposure, right?
It's your Delta's changing through time or through spot.
Sean, can I share my screen? I wanted to show them something. Yeah, sure.
Should we get? Yep.
So we come over to the terminal here.
So one thing to keep in mind guys is that when we are a gamma,
an option is basically priced if you were to gamma scalp it.
If you were to get, so let's say option is priced at 30 implied vol. Well,
what the market is saying here is if you gamma scalp this,
you would break even, okay? So we're going to show you what I'm talking about.
So let's say the stock's trading at a hundred.
We've got a stock trading at a hundred dollars. Actually,
let's use a real world example.
Steve, something you're looking at. What's the ticker?
DLR. DLR.
So Steve's looking at DLR and he is, in this case, let's say he's long vol.
Okay, he wants to be long volatility.
And Steve, you give me an option with $5 strike. Say, come on, Steve.
I just have to, it's only a dollar wide strike, Steve.
What do we got? ATVI. Okay, thank you, thank you.
Okay, so let's say we're trading ATVI. Okay,
and we're trading these weeklies here.
We're trading these weeklies here. Well,
these options are priced at 27% implied volatility. Okay,
they're priced at 27% implied volatility.
And what that means is if we were to delta hedge this, right,
we would break even because the stock should realize 27% implied volatility.
Okay, so let's say Steve's looking to buy this straddle here.
Okay, so if we were to delta hedge this, we would realize 27% implied vol,
which is what the market's saying. Okay,
the market's saying this stock is gonna realize 27%.
Let's head over to the terminal here. Okay, and let's price this out.
So a lot of the time, guys, we're pricing options. Okay,
a lot of time we're pricing them. So that expiration is March 19,
or sorry, March 12.
Okay, and so 27 vol. Stock's trading at 102.25,
and we are buying the 103 strike. Okay, so the straddle price, right,
the call price is 229, and the put price is $3. So 5.29 for this straddle.
Okay, $2.29 plus $3, $5.30 to buy this straddle.
But let's say we think volatility is gonna be 40%.
Okay,
that straddle today should be worth 7.80.
Okay, it should be worth 7.80 today, but it's trading for 5.30.
Right, so what we need to do is buy this option, buy the straddle,
and then delta hedge or gamma scalp.
What do you think, Sean?
I think it's good.
So I think quickly, Jordan, if you can try to explain why we have to do that.
Like, okay, so if it's gonna realize 40% vol,
why don't I just buy the straddle? Isn't that what we say?
If we think vol is cheap, buy the straddle. Why am I doing this scalp? Dude,
it's a brilliant question. To be honest with you,
I've always asked that question when I was starting out as well.
And so let me- Whiteboard?
Okay, so here's actually the beautiful thing about options, right?
It's something that we don't talk about much in Predicting Alpha,
but it's actually one of the beautiful things about options, okay?
We're looking at a stock here, ATVI, that's being priced at 27, okay?
And it's going to realize 40.
And this is where the stock is starting at, okay? Now,
the thing with the stock is it could realize 40 vol multiple ways, okay?
In fact, there is infinite paths, okay? So for example,
this stock could realize 40 vol like this,
okay? It could realize 40 vol like this.
It could realize 40 vol like this,
okay? There are infinite ways at which this could realize 40 vol.
It could also realize 40 vols like this,
okay? And so what delta hedging does, or gamma scalping, the same thing, okay?
What this allows us to do is it allows us to convert realized volatility into,
or sorry, implied volatility into realized volatility.
So whether we get this path, we get this path, or we get this path,
as long as it realizes 40 vol, we're gonna make money.
Because- As long as it realizes more than 27. Right, right, sorry. Yeah,
as long as it realizes more than 27, we're gonna make money.
It takes away the directional component,
okay? Do you wanna maybe show it day by day maybe,
and how hedging your delta there- Gotcha, gotcha.
Makes the directional component not matter. Okay, so we're gonna go,
we're gonna do one where we don't delta hedge. And also guys, keep in mind,
every path we took there, so when we buy the straddle, okay?
Our expected value is, in our case, 27 minus 40, it was the $3.50.
If we place this trade 1,000 times,
our expected value would be that dollar amount. But on one give and take,
it might not. So let's do that example here. So here's day one, we start here,
okay? We buy this option, 27 vol. Tomorrow, it goes up.
And 40 vol divided by 16, plays plus here. Oh, you know what, Jordan?
I think I actually have a really good way to show this. Can I try to- Yep, yep,
yep, yep. Can I try to show the screen? Okay, let me,
I'm gonna have to use some big brain power here. Just so you know,
2.5% vol a day, 2.5% move is a 40 vol. Yeah, yeah, yeah. No,
that won't be necessary for this if my brain works. Nice.
So let's say here's where we are today, okay? We buy this option for 27 vol.
We are anticipating it to be about 40% vol, okay?
So let's say we get that two, sure, that 2.5% move up, Jordan, okay? So we get,
so let's call this our, let's say, you know, this right here, right?
This line where this dot is right now, this is our starting point, right?
So we're on day one right now. We're at our starting point.
And then in the first day, it moves up 2.5% to here, right? So this is day one.
And we'll say this is like the end of day one. So we'll call this two. Well,
when we, at this point, if we hedge our deltas, it's like us doing this.
And now we are back at that line again. You see what happened there?
We reset our position. We're back in line with this. Now let's say on day two,
it goes down 2.5%, okay? What we do then is we come in and we hedge it again,
and we keep in line with that. We're staying delta neutral here.
And we're getting to capture these gains from these moves, right?
And then let's say day three, we get, you know, a 4% move up,
you know, we're gonna come in here and we're gonna,
maybe made that a little too big. And we're gonna bring it back down here.
Come with me, come here, come on. I really like that.
I really like this diagram, dude.
Any questions about this, guys?
And also just to add on to Sean is that if he doesn't delta hedge,
he has delta exposure. So in the first case,
he wants the stock to continue to rally. And if it doesn't, well,
then he's gonna lose. So he's increasing his variance, but he's increasing his,
you know, winners and losers.
But instead what he's doing here is he's removing that exposure,
right? So think about this. Like on this first,
when I delta hedged this first one here, I locked in a plus 2.5 move, right?
So I got paid as if the stock moved 2.5 as an absolute move. So, okay,
here's what we're doing.
We are removing positive and negative moves and just having absolute moves.
That's basically what it is, right, Jordan? Yeah, that's exactly what it is.
Right, does that make sense? So imagine this, imagine a stock went plus 2.5,
imagine a stock went plus 2.5 on day one, and then it went on day two,
minus 2.5. Oh my God, why am I, something's wrong with me here, dude. 2.5,
that would be a total percent move of zero and you wouldn't get paid if you just
held the straddle. But if we delta hedged here and we delta hedged here,
what we basically do is we remove this sign and we remove this sign,
leaving us with a total move of 5%.
Yeah, cool, I could do that. Cole's asking,
can we do that like an example with shares? I think for a hypothetical,
it might get a little messy. I think we can do them pretty quick. Okay,
you wanna do it? Yeah.
So here, Teeqo, here, I'll just, you know, show me your screen. Yeah,
you can share your screen.
Of course, Teeqo, we'll always talk about Tesla.
I actually love how every time Teeqo asks a question, we use a Tesla reference.
Yes. Okay, Teeqo, so we buy the straddle, okay? Think about this, okay?
Here we go. So here's day one that Sean talked about, right? Here's day one.
Honestly, gamma scalping Tesla is probably a really good idea. Yeah,
especially on the cheaper, the near-term stuff, it's pretty cheap right now.
Okay, so Teeqo, let's say we start here, okay? And Tesla, it's so funny,
I almost called Tesla Teeqo. Might as well, it's interchangeable. And so,
Teeqo, Tesla drops 20%. It drops 20%, okay? And now it's trading over here.
And we have just made $65,000, okay? We've just made $65,000. Now, okay,
in this case, I'd probably close it,
but imagine we still had a bunch of gamma left, okay? Which,
imagine we still had a bunch of gamma left. Tomorrow,
if we wake up and the stock goes up further, we make a ton of money.
But if it comes back down tomorrow, well, now we're gonna lose money.
So what we can do is we can lock in this game. We can actually lock this in.
The way we lock this in is flattening our deltas.
So now we have no directional exposure. So Jordan,
do you wanna maybe put a price slice there and then flatten your deltas and show
how that changes the instantaneous? Yeah,
so one thing to keep in mind is the shares aren't gonna be here at this price,
so it's gonna be a little bit different, but- Oh, actually, no,
you should be able to adjust the bid you're putting in for the share. Okay,
let's see. Shouldn't you? We will find out, sir. Exactly, Cole,
you'd buy shares there. Right, so Tesla comes down, it's at 665, and we say,
okay, we need to buy some shares here to remove our directional exposure.
And lock in our game. Exactly, well, okay, so what's that? 665,
we're gonna buy shares. But how many do we buy? Well, we need to buy 650,
right? That's our delta. So let's say we buy 650.
We have a negative 650 delta and each share is a positive delta,
so we want that to be at zero, so we'd buy 650.
And so now you can see here, well, if the stock, because we're long gamma,
so we still want movement. So if the stock falls back down to, let's say, 800,
well, we're gonna make a ton of money, right? We're gonna be up $69,000,
okay? And because we're long gamma, we want movement. If the stock rallies,
if the stock continues to drop, well, we're still gonna make money.
So let me ask you guys this question. How do we lose money?
The stock falls down, we make, yeah. The stock falls down, we make money.
The stock rallies, we make money. How do we lose money?
Marcos is saying no volatility. Tell me more, Marcos. Tell me more.
Do you need to know more?
Expires worthless,
beta. Marcos, I need, who said that? Who said that one? Marcos? Perfect.
Sylvan, quickly, second place also said beta. Exactly, right?
There's no free money here. Okay, there's no free money here. Every single day,
we can see right here, our position is gonna lose $1,000.
Okay, so- That's too many words. For that gamma,
right? We are paying for that gamma to have that exposure of, okay,
if the stock moves up and the stock moves down, we're gonna make money, right?
And so it needs to move up and down by a certain amount.
And it has to move actually by the amount of our theta,
how much we're gonna lose. Yeah,
it basically has to move more than the implied move,
right? Remember, we bought at 27, expecting it to move more than 27.
If it moves less than 27 implied vol, we lose.
And what's that number? Well, our daily break-even is 27 divided by 16.
That is 1.8%. So as long as the stock moves by more than 1.8% tomorrow,
we're gonna make money. Okay, if we lock that in.
By the way, guys, read what Red's saying.
He's sharing some good points in the chat. But Jordan, I guess,
I think people are starting to understand it.
We'll take some questions at the end, but how do we turn this into a strategy?
Because one thing that people need,
traders would need to keep in mind is I need to be able to buy and sell shares.
So when you were, okay, let's assume for a minute,
you have a thousand dollar account, just a nice round number.
How much should you allocate for a straddle?
And how much should you allocate for shares?
Like what ratio of your account should you have available for hedging to efficiently
run a gamma scalping strategy? Dude, super great question.
So usually you should have 50% of your max deltas in capital, okay?
You wanna- In non vol terms. Okay, so in this case, right?
So we're gonna do one more, okay?
What is the max amount of shares that we would ever buy in a one lot?
What would be the maximum shares we would ever need?
100, Koaw got it first. Justin, you said that really skeptical. You said 100?
You don't get the points, man. Perfect, so if we, if our delta,
if we're all the way over here, guys, we'll check that out, right?
Our delta is 100, it's negative 99.
I usually leave 50% I would need in gunpowder, okay? So 50%,
so 50 deltas on Tesla, right? So because you guys can see here, right?
Like when we get to 50, right? We're usually closing out the position.
We're starting to run out of gamma. So I need 50 deltas.
So 50 times $600 is 30 grand, okay? And 30 grand, cause I'm using margin.
I don't know how, I think it's a 50% in the States.
I would need 15,000 in gunpowder. So I buy this straddle for 66. Oh, sorry,
I buy this straddle for 10 grand and then I need 15 grand behind. So Jordan,
another question for you here. We sort of, as a rule of thumb,
say trade stocks that are liquid and above $15 in price.
So that might put some people, you know,
hypothetically someone's got like a $600 account. They're just trying to learn.
That might put them in a bit of a tricky spot. So for a strategy like this,
does that rule that we've sort of said to sort of stick with change?
It doesn't.
And I actually want to ask the guys this question to see who's on their toes today.
What would be the characteristics of a stock that would offer the most leverage?
So obviously you have a small account. You're gonna need leverage, right?
There's no ways around that.
So what characteristics of a stock would offer the most leverage? Who's got it?
Steve's got it. I know he's got it. It's for sure. Danny's saying a 3X ETF. 3X,
okay. Come on, Danny. You're better than this. Absolutely not. Steve,
what's the answer here, bud? Wow. Wow, Trent. Oh, my man. Trent,
if you can expand on that, that'd be great. That is the right answer.
That is the right answer.
Because they are less risky? Okay, it's not that they're less risky.
It's that you can buy them, right? The gamma is gonna be extremely low.
So you can buy these things for extremely cheap, right?
And because it's basically, it's something, the market should just say like,
if it's something really low vol, right? Well, if nothing happens,
you're not gonna lose a lot. But if something does happen,
you're gonna make a boatload, right? So the low vol,
you're gonna have very low gamma. Oh, so my apologies.
You're gonna have the highest gamma, the lowest theta, right?
The rent ratio is gonna be the lowest. The lower the vol,
the lower the rent ratio. So let's, for example,
and just to show you guys here super quick, let's take a look at Tesla, okay?
We'll go to Tesla, we'll go to Tesla March, okay? And we'll buy a Straddle.
Actually, we won't go March, my apologies. We'll go March 19th.
We'll take a look here, okay? And the rent ratio, so our theta, 1100,
and our gamma's five, okay? Now let's go over to Coke,
okay? So 1100 to five, and here it's 252 gamma to 40 thetas, right?
The leverage is extreme, right? Imagine, for example, a 10% move in Coke.
That'd be huge. Your payout would be massive. In Tesla, it'd be a normal day,
okay? So your leverage is huge here.
And so to answer the question there, Sean,
what you need to do is you need to go and find these low vol,
potentially huge moves, right? Potential big moves, low vol.
So Red's saying, we want a gamma scalp,
but it looks like the implied move is smaller than the average move.
Tasty Trade would say, you know, I'm not saying this is Red's opinion,
he's just sharing, Tasty Trade would say,
only consider doing this if IV rank is under 30.
So there's this big misconception, and Sean and I did a live on this,
or a video on this, that buying low IV rank, or sorry,
selling low- Selling high IV rank. Selling high IV rank works, right?
And this is actually the opposite of what we see. Usually when IV vol is high,
realized vol is even higher, right?
Think about selling implied volatility during a market crash.
Think about- Or on GameStop. Or on GameStop, right? If the stock moves 50%,
you're done. You're toast, right?
So what we usually see is implied vol doesn't get as high as realized vol when it's
high. And when it's low, it's usually at a premium. So here's a quick example.
A lot of hedge funds, what they'll do is they'll sell the VIX,
and this is very popular in like the vol arm space in hedge funds.
They'll sell VIX futures when VIX is in contango, right?
Meaning that VIX is downward sloping. The future curve is downward sloping.
And they'll buy vol when it's upward sloping. Okay,
so kind of opposite to maybe what tasty trade might say.
In this case, right? You wanna buy vol when it's cheap,
relative to what you think it's going to be. Yeah, and so what we'll,
obviously this involves forecasting future vol a bit.
This is where the terminal becomes your best friend, right?
So we're gonna get into that in a minute.
But before we move into the terminal and some filtering you can use to find stocks
that you may want to do this on, right? Because I think,
like I've been thinking about it. I think for,
if you're relatively new to options and have a, you know,
on the smaller side account, I think this is an,
and especially if you're from the US,
this is something definitely worth looking at.
So Jordan. Yeah. Straddle or strangle?
Yeah, so strangle more advanced. Let's see if Trent can get this one. Trent,
max loss on a Delta head strangle. What is it? What do we got dude?
And Steve. He needs a minute. He's analyzing the trade right now. Okay, sorry.
No, hold on guys, guys. Max loss on a Delta head straddle. Who's got that one?
Okay, but then we'll go into the strangle.
Max loss. So let me, let me open these up. What are the guys saying there,
Trent? Co is saying the spread, the width. Okay, so the width, okay.
Or one full leg.
Okay, so my apologies guys. What is the max loss on a Delta head straddle?
Let's start simple. Max loss on a Delta head straddle.
Theta, the lowest point in the graph. Thank you. The debit, the debit you pay.
That is the max loss. Now let's take a look at a strangle.
Is the max loss on a strangle the debit you pay? Who's got the answer there?
Is the max loss on a strangle the debit you paid? Assuming Delta hedging.
Width of the strikes. Width of the strikes.
Steve's saying it's more than the debit. Why, why Steve? Why Steve?
Why would it be more?
He's like, that's what I got, man. I was hoping you would roll with it. Yes,
that's actually what he's like. That's what I got. Okay,
so the max you can lose on a straddle is the debit you paid. Okay.
Now imagine this guys.
Imagine this. Imagine you buy the strangle. Okay. And it moves to 729.
Moves to seven. Actually, let's go a little wider here.
Let's say it moves to 700 on the strangle. Well, now you're short,
you're short 200 Deltas. Okay, so you buy 200 shares.
Now imagine if the stock moves down. Okay, so you buy 200 shares.
So let's go buy 200 shares.
So you buy 200 shares at 681.
Well, now check this out. What if the stock goes to 600 and then gets pinned?
Right, then it gets pinned. And so now you're decaying with theta, right?
You're stuck over here. You're decaying with theta.
And you just lost a ton of money, like a ton of money, right?
And I actually know a guy who's on the floor of the Siebel trading crude.
And he was in a huge position on a Delta 10 strangle.
And stock moved and he got pinned. Or it's not the stock, sorry,
the commodity moved and he got pinned to the strike, right?
And this is the worst case scenario for you.
So trading strangles are a bit trickier, okay? For a couple of reasons.
One is you can get pinned, in which case you can lose a lot of money, okay?
Second case is there's other Greeks involved, right?
There's third order Greeks that are happening that might kind of throw you off balance.
So I started with straddles, really wide, really tight strangles, okay?
Stock's trading at 97.50, maybe do the 195 strangle. When you get wide,
you know, sure you get a ton of leverage, but you gotta be very careful. Okay,
it's more of an advanced, you know, like no need to rush it here. Yeah.
You know what I mean? So for the purposes of this live, straddle. Straddle.
Right, this is for learning purposes, straddle, all right? Straddle.
Stick with the straddle for now. As you get better,
if you choose to pursue this further, we'll talk about strangles.
Small account challenge for gamma scalping, straddle. Jordan,
how many days to expiration? You know, given,
we want the learning experience here.
We want this to be a profitable learning experience.
How many days to expiration to minimize the choices someone has to make,
and they can focus on the good stuff. How do they pick it,
or what would you recommend? I'd recommend two.
I recommend trying longer data stuff, 90 days, 120 days.
Try playing with that Vega, right? Cheap way to play with the Vega.
And then, you know, 20 days. 20 days to expiration, 15 days to expiration,
play with the gamma. And as you're doing that,
you should be asking questions about it in the group,
and people can help you out. Like,
clearly there's a few guys in here who know their stuff when it comes to gamma scalping.
Jordan, next question for you. How often should you be hedging it?
Do you set a threshold for hedging? Do you, you know,
if you're in the States and you have, you know, unlimited trades, more or less,
you know, say you're trading something super liquid, do you sit there all day,
scalp, scalp, you know, scalping your pips? What do you do? Hedges to close.
Hedges to close. And Sean, I'm going to say this, man.
I'll promise everyone on this live here.
If they buy a 20 day straddle and they Delta hedge every single day,
they will be a completely different person when that straddle expires. Wow.
That's a, it's a big claim. Yeah, it's a big claim. It's a bit,
it's a good claim though. So you're saying hedge at the close.
Why are you saying that?
So there's obviously, you know, better ways to hedge,
but that kind of like incorporates a second strategy or you got a Delta one strategy
and a vol strategy. You know, just pick a, you know, just hedge at the close,
right? Or pick a threshold. So there's two ways you can do this.
Pick a threshold, which is, okay, after a hundred Deltas, hedge.
Or at the close, hedge.
All we're doing here is we are removing our directional exposure.
There's no reason to get too excited about it. Maybe set it as like,
if your Delta represents 1% of your account hedge or hedge at the close.
Obviously stick to one. So don't, don't, don't, don't like be like, oh,
you know, I'm doing this one today and this one tomorrow.
Stick to one and just do it for, you know,
you guys aren't going to lose a lot of money. I think- Yeah. Yeah. Maybe,
maybe, maybe do that. Hedge at 1% of your, of your account.
Up to you. It's arbitrary. Yeah, it's arbitrary. For now, just,
I guarantee you guys, just give it a try.
You're not going to lose a lot of money. Buy what's cheap vol to you.
Delta hedge it. You're not going to lose a lot of money. Worst case scenario.
Best case scenario, the stock blows out. And please just, you know,
remember this live and it's your yacht party.
I'll share my Venmo with you and you can send me some money. Yeah.
Just subscribe to my only fans. If you, if you hit the jackpot.
All right. Danny's saying, I'm going to give it a try for fun. All right, man.
Let's see it happen. You better,
you better be giving us the daily updates in the chat. Daily update, man. Okay.
Got a couple more questions here for you. And Danny,
if you're going to be giving it a try make sure you ask your questions.
And post the results. Post daily results. Like day one, Delta this. Track it.
Yeah, track it.
When do you close the position?
So I would close it. So it really depends on your gamma, right?
If the stock's all the way up here we don't have any gamma left. I'm out.
Right. So that's going to be,
you know before we put on any position guys really think about, well,
what are the possibilities? Right?
Like this is something that Sean and I are trying to get you guys to do in silver
which is the tree diagram.
Before we even put on this position we should look at this graph right here and
say what could happen tomorrow? Right? So for example,
we stress it to tomorrow, one day and well,
what do I do if the stock goes here? Right?
What do I do if the stock goes here?
What do I do if the stock goes here or here? Right? And usually we say,
okay by a certain gamma amount, I'm out. Right? If the stock is,
let's say up here I'm out of the position.
And you can also look at that theta amount as well. Right?
You can see our theta drops from 1800 at the money to 900. Right?
It's the position is done. So, you know,
we want to get back into that new position now where, okay, ball's cheap.
Let's get back into the, at the monies. Right?
And that's one thing about the strangles,
you know going a little off the road here take a look at the strangles. Right?
Look at this, look at this guys. Check out that theta. Okay.
Check out that theta there. You guys see that theta number?
What do you guys notice about that theta number? Who's got it? Who's got it?
What do you guys notice about that theta number on the strangle versus that straddle?
Higher. Increasing. Perfect. Like it, so it actually, it's a,
it's a lot more constant.
So if the stock moves here or the stock moves there you're going to have that constant
gamma. Right? But as a straddle, as the stock moves, you deplete your gamma.
And what the gamma means is basically your sensitivity to the movement. Right?
So check this out guys. You know, super exciting, super good life.
I'm pumped up. You guys are pumped up. This is good stuff. Right?
So take a look at this, right? Let's say the stock moves up here. Okay.
Let's say the stock moves to 950. Right? Or watch this.
Watch this.
Okay. Oops.
We're going to sell. So we're over here at 950. Okay. We need to sell.
How many do we need to sell?
400 at 950.
So let's take a look at this. Look at that exposure guys. Right?
Look at that exposure. It's like a straddle. Right?
We still have a ton of gamma.
So that is the beauty of the strangle as well. Right? Is we get this constant.
We get this gamma across a huge time, a huge width. Okay.
But it's also can be more risky. But there's no free lunch in this game.
You want more, you want more risk or you want more reward?
You got to take on more risk. Okay.
So Jordan,
we're going to hop into the terminal in a second and actually talk about, okay,
well, how do we find the right trade to be doing this on? Right.
But before we do that, Red had a question. He said, Sean,
you were saying that gamma scalping resets your position,
but Jordan was saying that gamma gets depleted. Can we resolve,
can you resolve this, you know, things button heads. All right, Sean.
All right. Square up. Red, you're the best. Okay.
So, so gamma scalping, I think what Sean meant there is delta. Okay.
So when you flatten your delta, okay, your gamma can get,
your gamma can get depleted, right? You have no gamma here. Okay.
You can see that by the blue line, the purple line, that convexity, right?
You see that convexity here, right? Let me just super quick.
So Red, check this out. Okay. If I were to draw a line here, Red, a flat line,
a tangent line back to, I see you're kidding me, man. Dude,
just use the straight line tool. I don't know why you try and do this. Okay.
Here we go. Here we go. Okay. Okay, okay. Red, let's go back to,
to first year calc. Okay.
Is this calc? Yeah, yeah, yeah. This is, maybe, maybe second.
Maybe advanced functions. Yeah. Is it the tangent line? It could, it could be.
I don't know. Oh my God. Derivative, I guess. Okay. Okay. Here we go.
Here we go.
Okay, Red. So you see that convexity there, right?
You see how it's not straight. It's not linear. It has like that convexity.
And as long as we have that convexity, we're long gamma. Okay.
Now let's go over here, right?
If I draw a tangent line somewhere at some point, there's no convexity.
So what happens is as long as we have that gamma, delta hedging,
all it does is take that directional exposure away. That's all it does.
So now we get back to whatever point we are.
Remember when Sean was showing that like a tree diagram?
If, so take a look at this. Okay. Take a look at this. Sorry, Sean.
This is the one. This is the one that's going to set away. Okay.
So you can see here, right? I draw this diagonal line here.
And right over here is where we are going to be delta neutral. Okay.
In this position here, let's say. Yeah. So when I did that reset,
it's like putting you as that tangent line now. Exactly. Exactly.
So if you look like Jordan, show them like where they are right at the bottom,
draw a tangent line at the delta neutral spot. Well, Inception.
So I know I'm actually going to go delta neutral here.
I'm going to flatten the deltas right here. Do it. So right here,
you can see that we are 500 deltas. Okay.
We need to be long 500 deltas to flatten.
Check that out now, Red. Right. You see that now?
Now we don't care what happens, right? As long as it moves,
right? We basically took this line and we did this.
We took that line, Red, and we did this.
That's it. We tilted it. As long as we're that gamma, we have that convexity.
So Jordan, one last thing before we hop into the terminal.
I said that this is a great way if you have a small account to, you know,
grow it. Is this limited to small accounts? No,
this is limited to market makers. You know,
market makers are doing this on a daily basis. Right. So what would you say,
like, if you were to, if someone were to say, like,
why should I do gamma scalping? What would you really tell them? Okay.
So I just want you guys to know, like, I do this all the time. Okay.
If I'm long volatility, if I'm long volatility,
and usually I'm not long volatility on a 10-day option,
I'm usually long volatility on a 30-day, 40-day option.
If the stock moves up 7% in a day, and I still have gamma,
Jordan, I can take the risk if I want to, if I want to increase the variance,
nothing wrong with that, or I could just remove that risk.
Okay.
So it's all you're doing is you're removing the risk of the directional bet.
If you think the stock is going to rally still, well, don't remove it.
You know,
if the stock goes up and you still think it's going to go up and you're long gamma,
why would you hedge your deltas?
Hedging your delta and gamma scalping is taking away that risk.
It allows you to convert implied to realized volatility and learn about how to trade
volatility. And, you know, and not just learn about it, actually trade it.
Do the thing. Do the thing, do the thing, right? Like, I'm always hedging.
I'm always hedging my deltas, right? I'm usually concerned about my thetas,
right? So I'll take out my deltas, I'll take out my thetas,
and now I'm just left with, let's say, you know, in that case,
I'm talking about relative value. Yeah, my view on,
I'm assuming relative value,
my view on one option's gamma versus the other option's gamma. So Jordan,
I think at this point, because it's nine o'clock, guys,
I want to thank you for sticking around so long. You know, I hope the content,
it's not because you fell asleep. Because you're pumped.
Because you're pumped up, right? That's why you're still here at nine o'clock.
So Jordan,
now let's get into the moment that a lot of people have been waiting for.
They've been sitting here saying, goddammit,
when are they gonna show me how to find a trade for this?
Let's hop into the terminal, Jordan. Yeah. And show how to filter for this.
Until next time. We'll see you guys. And that will be in part two. Okay, okay,
okay, okay, okay. So let's go volatility trader, right? We're in volatility,
and we're gonna go to the volatility analyzer. And we're looking for cheap vol,
okay? So one thing is,
is we need to know that our IV versus our forecast is cheap, right?
So implied vol divided by the forecast is 0.1. What do you wanna look for?
Something under 0.9? Yeah, so maybe, yeah, you know what? Honestly,
I'd go 0.99,
because sometimes you can find these like fundamentally cheap ones. Okay.
So for example, there's actually so many examples,
but I'll just give you one super quick that I did a long time ago.
Foot Locker back in 2017. This is when I was learning about gamma scalping.
They had a court case coming up. And for some reason,
market wasn't pricing it in. It was a pretty big court case.
And so I bought vol, you know, the stock shot through the roof,
and it was a good trade.
And then the court case got thrown out the next day and nothing happened. Yeah.
Okay, so IV versus forecast, we want that below one, right?
We want the implied volatility higher than what we think is gonna happen. Well,
throw on your price and option volume filters first. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
We always gotta, you know, we gotta, you know, best practices here.
We gotta make sure there's some volume and we gotta make sure that it's not a penny
stock. Exactly, exactly. You know, I'm usually gonna like to trade over,
we like to trade over 20 bucks here. And now implied volatility, okay,
we're resigning here. Implied volatility, I'm gonna want below, okay,
I'm gonna want below 50 here.
Okay, I'm gonna want cheap vol.
And then I also want IV rank. I'm gonna have IV rank below.
So it's gonna be above a certain threshold, right?
Because if the stock's not realizing anything, implied vol is gonna be too low,
right? And it's basically gonna be RVs down here, IVs up here. Okay,
and we want, I'm gonna say IV below 50. Okay, and now look, we have 20 stocks.
We just filtered for 20 stocks. All right, so let's say for example,
and you know what? We're gonna filter by IV versus forecast.
AKAM, okay? AKAM. It's the first one, right? So IV versus forecast, 0.77,
right? Very cheap. Actually,
is there any stock that you guys see right off the bat that you guys wanna talk
about? Go through them. Okay, so we got WFC here, okay? We got STZ on the list.
Isn't that Constellation? Yeah, yeah, the Constellation brand.
We got Constellation brand on the list.
TSN, XRT, XRT, TAP. What do you guys see? What do you guys like? Marcos,
I know you like this stuff, Marcos. Is Marcos still around? Yeah,
Marcos is still here. Nice, nice. KHC, I remember trading earnings on the KHC.
Okay, we got two for MTCH. I think those on page two. Okay,
okay, MTCH, okay. So average option volume, 13K, pretty liquid.
We're looking good. Yeah, implied vol versus forecast, 89.
We can see that the implied volatility 30 day is 45%. I have it ranked 37.
Looks, this actually looks great. Looks great. Who came up with this one?
This one looks really good. Koa and Danny. Okay, nice. So you come here, MTCH,
and, right, we're gonna buy a straddle. Or, you know what?
Because I know you guys love a little bit of leverage, we'll do a strangle,
okay? No, no, do the straddle. Just do the straddle just for,
we need this to be like the step,
and people are gonna watch this again to get the steps. So let's do straddle.
The one issue is we don't have the 160, 250 strike. So we're gonna do the 165,
160, super tight strangle. Couldn't you start with a little delta hedge?
I guess, yeah. Actually, really good point, Sean. Really good point. Okay,
so we're gonna buy the 165 straddle. Now take in, guys.
The delta here is 47 and 53. So right off the bat,
we're gonna be short negative six deltas.
Okay, and negative six times 100, and our negative 0.6 times 100 is 60 deltas.
So here we are. We are short 60 deltas. And so that's not a lot of deltas,
right? So basically what this is saying is you're short 70 shares.
You're short 70 shares. Can you handle that variance? I'm sure you can, right?
Everyone in this chat can handle 70 shares of variance.
So we come in here and the stock moves up, let's say 3% tomorrow.
We're gonna be long 257 deltas.
So we're gonna have to come in and sell some shares.
We're gonna have to sell some shares.
Make sure you're trading something that leaves you that 50% threshold for hedging.
Yeah. Make sure you have that.
Yep, there you go, right? Now we hedge 250 shares. The stock goes down,
we make money. Stock goes up, we make money.
If the stock passes with time and doesn't move, we lose money. So I guess,
Jordan, a couple of questions just to end off the slide.
Bringing it back to when we close this out.
So obviously you're gonna hedge your deltas.
You're gonna pick a threshold here.
You're either gonna do it maybe every time your delta number is 1% of your account
value. Maybe you're gonna do it at the end of the day.
You're gonna pick a threshold, stick to it and hedge. Now,
questions you gotta ask. When are you right and you take it off?
When are you wrong and you take it off, right? At the end of the day,
if this is a big loser, maybe you wanna get out of it. If it's a big winner,
maybe you wanna get out of it.
What are these metrics that we should look for to exit? Yeah, so super quick,
I would say, put these trades on.
You guys are gonna figure that out for yourselves, in my opinion.
That being said, the losers are gonna be extremely, extremely, extremely small,
okay? If you trade this small size in terms of debit. So let's say,
for example, this is $1,670 to buy one of these, okay?
If that's too much for you, don't trade this, okay?
So pick a debit that you're comfortable with. Now,
you're not even gonna- And you can actually choose that with like the stock price,
pretty much. Yeah, and the thing is,
you are not gonna lose this full debit because you're gonna be delta hedging,
okay? So you're gonna make back some money. So pick, let's say, a debit,
times it by 50%. So in this case, 1,670 times 50% is 800 bucks.
If you're okay with losing $800, this is perfect. Okay,
so you're not gonna lose a lot of money, first off. So closing this out,
I wouldn't even say worry about it. Just keep delta hedging, keep learning.
Keep learning about this as you do it. You're not gonna lose a ton of money.
In terms of taking it out, you guys will know this as well, okay?
You're gonna wake up one morning and the stocks rally 10%, okay?
You just close the damn position. Red's got a question here. He's saying,
should I have a profit target on the entire straddle strangle or individual targets
on either side? Yeah, when you enter this trade, Red,
you are buying the straddle because why? Why are we buying the straddle?
Really important question. Why are we buying the straddle?
He says he wants like a sharp move. Okay, it's more than that,
it's more than that. Okay, we're buying the straddle. Or he's saying gamma.
Well, we're buying the straddle because we think it's worth more. Yeah.
Because if we delta hedge, it's worth more.
So we have an expectation of what this is worth, right?
Before we even buy the straddle, we value it.
This straddle is worth $20 to us and I can buy it for 1670 right now.
So when I realize that 300 bucks, I'm out. Exactly, Sylvain.
Sylvain's saying the vol's cheap. Exactly, the vol's cheap.
And so when finally, right, when we realize what we expect to realize, I'm out.
Or if I buy this position right now and tomorrow I realize 400 bucks on a 16,
on 24, I buy it for 1600. I think it's worth 20. I think it's worth $400 more.
And tomorrow the stock moves 400 bucks. Most likely I'm out. But you know,
that's for another talk of when we reevaluate. But most likely, we're out.
But we got the move we wanted to onto the next one.
Exactly, Red. Yeah.
All right, guys, that is going to conclude this live. That is Gamma Scalping.
I highly recommend anybody looking to learn vol seriously for you to the space.
If you're trying to grow a small account, this is what to do, right?
Spend a lot of time thinking about it. I think this is,
I hope you're as excited as I am to see this brought to the Predicting Alpha members.
I'm amped. Jordan, we should totally have, for the strategy scanner,
we should have like a Gamma Scalp thing.
We should. Pip Scalper. Pip Scalper. We're going to have a cheap vol one.
Can we call it the Pip Scalper? We can call it the Pip Scalper. Okay, good,
good, good.
All right, everyone, we're going to end the live there. I hope you enjoyed it.
And we'll see you all tomorrow. See you guys.