Okay, guys, so in this video,
we're going to be talking about bankroll management, okay?
And why bankroll management is actually a make or break in your trading.
If you don't have bankroll management,
you can turn a winning strategy into a losing strategy. Okay?
And that's why it's so important. And today in the group,
we actually saw it for the first time.
We actually got our first taste at a five standard deviation move in the group,
right? CRM.
This is by far one of the biggest earnings blowouts I've seen since I started trading.
And a lot of the time, we don't think our max loss is actually possible, right?
None of us here has seen our max loss until today.
And it can actually destroy you,
it can cripple your account if you bet too big.
So that's what we're gonna be talking about today, bankroll management,
and how this can actually, you know, make you a profitable trader,
assuming you have a good strategy. Okay?
And how it will cripple you if you don't have this. Okay? Win or lose,
if you don't have this, you will never make it as a profitable trader. Okay?
And we're gonna go over why in detail,
and I think you guys are gonna get a lot of value out of this. Okay.
So let's jump into it. We're gonna be playing a game here.
I'm gonna give you guys a hypothetical example,
and I want you guys to take a guess on what the answer is.
And the winner of this is going to, like we said, get a one-on-one tomorrow.
So let's play a game, okay? We are going to the casino, and let's call it,
you know, some type of new blackjack game. Okay?
We go to the casino with $1,000 in our bank account.
We're playing this game where when we win, we win 1.2. And when we lose,
we lose whatever we put down at the casino.
And we have a 60% chance that we win. So that means a 40% chance that we lose.
Okay? Imagine we took a trade here. Our winners are 1.2 times our losers,
and we win 60% of the time. How much of this $1,000 should we bet? Okay?
To stab at that, guys, put your comments down here,
and we'll take a look at it towards the end.
So what we're gonna calculate here, guys,
is there's actually an optimal bet size.
There's actually the perfect amount to grow your account.
If you bet more than this, you don't do well. If you bet less than this,
you don't do as well. Okay? And this is what we call the Kelly Criterion.
So this is what we use. Now, it can get very advanced,
but this is actually very simple.
And this is what a lot of professional gamblers use all the time.
It's actually the basis of risk management and option trading.
So that is the Kelly Criterion.
What the Kelly Criterion tells us is if we want to optimize our expectancy,
meaning if we want to make the most money in the long run,
how much should we be betting? And that is what the Kelly Criterion is.
So the formula for that is the probability you win, okay,
times the odds that you win. Okay, we're going to call that B, plus one,
minus one, divided by the odds of you winning. Okay?
This formula is going to maximize our long-term gains, right?
It's going to make sure we don't go bankrupt. Okay?
So we're going to plug in these numbers into here and find out who is the closest
to the winner. Now, this is the Kelly Criterion, okay?
Probability of you winning, the odds of you winning, plus one, minus one,
divided by the odds of you winning, the odds on your bet. Right?
So the odds on our bet here was 1.2. Okay? We win 1.2 times our losers.
We bet $100 and we lose, we're going to lose 100. But if we win,
we're going to win 120. Okay?
So we're going to plug it into this formula and we're going to see who wins here.
So we have probability of us winning, 60%. The odds that we're getting are 1.2,
plus one, minus one. Okay? Divided by 1.2.
So this is going to be 0.6 times 2.2, minus one, divided by 1.2.
So 0.32 divided by 1.2. 0.27.
0.27. Yeah. Okay. So on our $1,000 account, is it 0.027 or 0.27? 0.27. Okay.
So on our $1,000 account, okay, we should be betting $270 per bet. Now,
this number right here is going to optimize our long-term expectancy.
We have to bet $270 every time. Okay?
Some people will come in here and they'll bet too much. Okay? Not good.
And some people will come in and bet too little,
and that's not optimizing their bank. That's not optimizing their expectancy.
Okay? Now that we know this, so you guys, so far so good,
this is how much we should be betting to optimize our bank.
But what does this mean? What does this mean? What does this $270 mean?
So this, by the way, guys, is called our Kelly fraction. Okay?
That's our Kelly fraction.
Okay? This is optimizing our bankroll without the risk of blowing up. Okay?
Now, let us, let us, oh, sorry, guys, you still, yeah, okay.
Now let us go into an example of why we need to know this and why it's so important.
Okay. Okay. So we said our Kelly score equals 270. Okay?
I'm going to draw a couple of scenarios here.
And by the way, guys, we have an expected, we have a positive expectancy,
right? Our strategy, okay? Expected value is equal to 0.6 times 1.2, right?
Minus, this is all from bronze, minus 0.4 times 1. Right?
That's our expected value. So we go 0.6 times 1.2,
0.72 minus 0.4 equals 32 cents. Okay? For every dollar we bet,
we're going to make 32 cents. That's our expectancy, our long run expectancy.
For every dollar I bet, I'm either going to, on average, right?
I'm either going to win $1.20 or I'm going to lose $1. But on average,
I'm going to make 32 cents. Okay? So I'm going to draw a couple examples here.
So imagine we sit down at this game. We sit down at this game. Obviously,
we're going to become rich. We're going to become filthy rich, right?
If we can sit at this game forever and ever and ever,
we're going to become billionaires.
So let's graph this out. Let's graph out our play. So here is time zero.
And here is money one. Okay? This is our bankroll.
We're going to call this our bankroll.
Okay? I'm going to draw a couple graphs for you guys.
So let's say we come to this game starting at $1,000.
Okay? So on our y-axis, we have our bankroll. Okay? And then here,
we have the number of games we played. So let's say we start with zero.
And then by the end of the year, we've played 5,000 games. 5,000 hands. Okay?
And our first graph looks like this.
Okay? That's our first graph. Our second graph looks like this.
Okay? We're going to do four graphs, actually, guys. Make it a little more fun.
Our third graph looks like this.
And our final graph looks like this.
Okay? So these are four different people playing this game. Okay?
We have four different people playing this game.
We're going to call them Marcos, Ram, Lavelle, and Dan. Okay?
These guys are all playing this game.
I want you guys to tell me how much each person is betting at this game.
So remember, we have $1,000. Okay?
And we're going to talk in terms of Kelly fractions. Okay?
So we know Kelly of 1 is 270. Okay? I want you guys to tell me,
what Kelly fraction is this guy betting at? So you can scale from, let's say,
0.1, means 10% of Kelly, all the way up to, let's call it 2 times Kelly. Okay?
So you're betting 2 times the Kelly fraction. And right now,
we're playing a game that is a long run. The more we play,
the more money we make. Right? It's a long-term expected value game.
The more games, the more money. Okay? So first one. Blue guy.
What Kelly fraction is he betting at? Okay? Let's see what we got here.
So what Kelly fraction is this guy? We have this crazy, crazy P&L graph,
and it goes all the way up here. What fraction is he betting at?
So Koa's saying 2. Marco's saying 2. Okay? So 2. How about this guy?
He's got a smoother P&L. It goes right here. What's this guy betting at? 1.5.
Okay.
Okay. How about this guy right here? This guy in the green.
So he's got a really smooth P&L. What's he doing? He's doing 1.
Kyle's saying 1. Okay. And how about this guy? How about this guy?
It looks like he lost a lot of his money. What happened to him?
Pranav's saying 0.5, 0.69. Okay. We're going to call it.
What are you guys saying here? 0.5, 0.3. Okay. Awesome. Awesome.
We're going to go with 0.5.
Okay. Guys, I got to tell you something.
You guys had this flipped. Everyone had this flipped. Okay.
Kyle's saying negative 1. Okay. Let's talk about this.
The guy who lost all his money, you know what he did? He bet $280.
He bet $280 at that casino. He bet over 1 of the Kelly Criterion.
He bet over 1. He loses money in the long run. This guy up here,
he did 1 times Kelly. Remember, Kelly optimizes your bankroll.
It optimizes your expectancy given your bankroll.
So this is always going to be the highest out of all different combinations.
Okay. So this is the highest. The next highest is not full Kelly, right?
So this guy right here, he's betting $270. This guy right here, he's betting,
let's call it half Kelly. Okay. So he's betting 140. Okay. And this guy,
he's betting a quarter of Kelly. So he's betting .25 Kelly,
which is about 80 bucks.
And this guy down here is betting, we're going to call it $300.
Because in the long run, if he bets more than this number,
he turns a winning strategy, a very profitable strategy. Imagine this, guys.
Imagine every time you bet, you got 32 cents for every dollar.
Imagine every time you bet $10,000, you got on average 3,200 back.
That's the strategy right here.
And this guy does phenomenal because he bets Kelly.
This guy does good because he bets half Kelly. This guy does okay,
but he didn't maximize. But look, his P&L is very smooth.
And he bet quarter Kelly.
This guy who maybe he didn't understand bankroll management,
he lost all his money.
Okay. And why is this the case? How can this be possible?
How can this be possible in the long run? Well, if you think about it,
if he's betting, let's say $300.
Okay.
Let's go with a bigger amount just so you guys can make sense of it.
Imagine he's betting 500 bucks. Okay. It's only going to take him two times.
He only has to win. He only has to lose two times in a row to go down,
to lose his whole bankroll. Right. And if we know some mathematics, we win.
Sorry. We lose, right, 0.4 times 0.4. That's 50 points. Right.
We lose two times in a row, 16% of the time. Right. And if we do that again,
6.4% of the time. Right. We lose three times in a row. And four times in a row,
by the time we go bankrupt, it's about 1% of the time.
But the way that Kelly Criterion is built is that it's unlikely for us to lose four
times in a row without at least us getting a head start. Okay. We only lose,
you know, at the initial start 1% of the time. Okay.
So that is how Kelly Criterion works.
It helps us avoid maximizing our bankroll as well as avoiding bankruptcy. Okay.
Okay. So that's, that's on the whiteboard I want to show you.
Then I was just going to show you guys a,
an example on my computer super quick. So I know,
I know the guys that read the Yoon Sinclair book, I did the same thing as well.
I skipped over risk bankroll management.
And actually Yoon Sinclair didn't introduce me to Kelly Criterion,
but I've read somewhere else. And then I realized he did a lot of work on it.
So he, in this example, he does the exact same thing.
He shows us what I just showed you. Okay. And, you know,
if there's any mathematicians,
you guys can go in and learn a little bit more about the math.
The black line here is Kelly. It's full Kelly. It optimizes your bet,
your bankroll. This line down here is half Kelly.
He's betting half the optimal size.
And this where the guy eventually goes bankrupt is twice Kelly.
Two times the Kelly Criterion. Okay. So that is what happens, right?
This is our dollar P&L. So this is why bankroll management is so important.
Because if you're betting,
so let's actually take it back to an iron condor example.
Now we're actually going to do it right here, right here on the live.
So let's do an iron condor example. Okay. So here we have an iron condor.
Okay. Now let's say when we win.
Now the thing that's a little bit different with trading is that there's no binary
outcome. It's not like you either win or you lose. You could be over here,
right? Or you can be over here. There's lots of different combinations.
And this is actually where Hune Sinclair has done a lot of work.
He's done a lot of work on this,
on turning that Kelly Criterion and expanding on it for option trading.
So if you guys want to learn more about it, math is pretty intense.
It's in his book. Okay. So we're going to use this hypothetical example.
Now we're going to say when we win on average. Okay. We're going to use like,
let's say this line. Okay.
So let's say we put on this iron condor and we say when we win,
we're going to win 500 bucks.
Okay. And when we lose. Okay. We're going to lose. Let's say this is,
I don't know. Let's say our max loss is a thousand.
Okay. Now we know a lot of the probabilities, right?
We know that one standard deviation, 60% of the time, right? 68% of the time.
We're going to, we're going to make money. We're going to be somewhere in here.
Right. And, you know,
I was just talking to Kyle earlier yesterday or something.
His hit ratio was 1.29. Okay. So that is almost 68% of the time. Right.
For his earning trades.
So we know that we're going to make money about 68% of the time.
You're going to be somewhere in here. 33% of the time or 32% of the time,
we're going to lose money. Okay. But we're going to lose big, right?
This is just like an earnings trade. We're going to win 500 and we're right.
And we're going to lose a thousand when we're wrong. Okay.
So now we have probabilities. Now we have our, our, our PNLs. If we're right,
if we're wrong, and we can throw that into the Kelly criteria.
So we're going to throw it into the Kelly criteria.
Okay. So 0.68.
0.5. Plus one, right? The odds are half for every thousand we lose.
We make 500. Minus one over 0.5. 0.68. Times. 1.5. Minus one.
Divided by. 0.5. 1.02. Minus one. Yeah. Over 0.5. 0.04. So in this example,
we cannot bet more than 4% of our bankroll. If we bet more than 4%, guess what?
We lose money in the long run. Okay. So I know that's shocking guys.
And this is why we always say, you know, keep it to 5%. Right.
Keep it to 5% for these earnings trades.
And the reason we do 5% is I think we have a little bit higher expectancy here.
Okay. A little bit higher. And our, our win loss is usually not a two to one.
It's usually one to 1.5. So we usually say that 0.05. When you start going,
let's say 10%. 15%. Even though you're in a winning game,
you are going to lose all of your money. Now. You know, you sometimes,
you know, you hear Sean, I say. If you find an edge that big. That big. Well,
imagine. We had. 0.80 here. Imagine we had insane confidence, right?
This number right here. This P. This is our confidence level.
How confident are you? If you're confident in trade you,
that means you think it's going to happen.
If you don't think it's going to happen, this P value goes down.
And in trading, if this P value goes down. What happens to be.
What happens to be if you're, if you're making a trade right now.
And P goes down. B has to go up. If you, if peace, okay.
If P is your confidence, if you're, if you're not confident on trade,
what does that mean? It means the risk reward has to be huge.
Otherwise you're not going to take a trade. If you're that's why our one,
three, two flies, for example, we're not confident. Always.
We don't have a directional view, but guess what? This B value is 10 to one.
This B value is 10.
Right? So this is how we start to figure out, well, you know,
how should we make a trade here? What kind of, you know, how,
how can this math right. Integrate into our trading. Into our betting.
At the end of the day, guys, we're betting here. We're we're bets. We're,
we're, we're creating these bets and we have to manage them properly.
It's so important. And perhaps saying, if I bet 271. Instead of two 70.
You go back up in the long run. I know it doesn't say,
I know that might sound crazy for now. Now,
obviously it's not going to look like exactly. Right away. Yes.
It's not gonna happen right away. But in the long run. It's going to happen.
This $1 per nap is going to screw you. Okay. And that is. This is not,
this is not theory. This is not theory. This is math. Okay.
This is what actually happens. You lose in the long run. Betting $1 more.
So guys. Here's the harsh reality. Here's the harsh reality.
If your account size is $1,000. And you are doing an earnings trade. Okay.
What does that mean? What does that mean? If your account size is $1,000,
you're doing earnings trade. You can't have a loser. Okay.
Bigger than that.
Okay. You cannot have a loser. Bigger than this. Your risk on the trade.
Cannot be bigger than this number. Okay. If you're doing an earnings trade.
Yeah. If you have 5,000. Your max risk. Cannot be 250.
Cannot be bigger than $250. Okay. And what does that mean? Well,
it just means that you can't trade everything right now.
That you can only take certain trades. Okay.
And there's another thing you can do. Is you can create your own strategy.
Which either increases P. Increases your confidence. Or increases B.
Increases the risk to reward ratio. Okay. And this number.
So if we actually plug it in with instead of 500 and 1,000.
Let's say we did like 500 and 750 or 600. Which is more realistic.
This number goes up. So 6.66. So in reality, you know, you can't be making.
You can't be putting on the line. More than 60 bucks.
For every $1,000 you have in your account.
Okay. That is. That is the reality of trading. And I know it's hard.
I know sometimes I might be like, holy shit. Like that's crazy.
This is the truth. You know, there's people. There's, you know,
as the saying goes, men lie and women lie. But numbers don't.
Numbers don't lie. Okay.
If you're just flat out doing the earning strategy.
You can't bet more than this.
If you want to create your own strategy around earnings.
If you have a certain idea that, you know. Is going to increase either P or B.
Now you can bet more. And this is not just for earnings.
This is for every strategy out there. Okay.
So now the lecture is over. I'm just going to go and answer some questions.