Yeah, if we actually start breaking it down here step by step marks,
like somebody got a haircut It's so funny man. Sean Sean did it for me.
I Do a good job.
It's all right I think if if trading doesn't work out and if predicting alpha falls
through I've always got a backup career as a barber Yeah, you know what? Yeah.
Hey, but if you look at Sean's head, you know who did this this guy this guy.
Yeah Who did a better job?
Yeah It's like it's kind of it's kind of insulting if they would say That I did
the better job. Well, because I mean my hair my hair. Oh, yeah That's funny,
okay, maybe stick with options Thanks, Dan. Okay guys,
so we're gonna jump right into this Let me Make sure we're all good here Okay,
so I'm gonna share my screen and we are gonna get started here.
We'll give it We'll give it one more minute here just for the guys to trickle in
No, we make sure we get the chat open and stuff. Yeah Okay,
let me just grab my charger super quick man, okay Yeah,
we're gonna get started in one second here just give some time for people to trickle
in Jordan's got to grab his charger and Then we're gonna get started Really cool
trade breakdown. I think it'll be really insightful.
We're really excited to go through this with you Okay,
sit down wrap bring this around I Will get this all plugged in okay,
so I'm actually gonna start out by Going through going to show you who you and Sinclair
is just so we can So we can all be on the same page. Yeah,
why like sure it's not our trade,
but why the hell should we listen to this guy? so Okay,
so you and Sinclair is waiting for his picture to load So you guys can you guys
can see who we're gonna be chatting about.
So he's a funny-looking dude a It's kind of a funny-looking guy.
He's actually Australian and Really smart guy.
He's partner at the firm Talton Capital.
He used to work as a serious trader for Bluefin Before going out on his own to become
a professional to be a partner in the firm So he went from trader to partner in
the firm and he's been trading options for you know,
probably over 25 years really smart guy has his PhD and Absolutely dominated the
the option space.
He's decided to give a lot back to the the options community and he's written a
few Really good bucks.
You really good book really good books so we're gonna go through one of his trade
breakdowns and You know how it played out how he managed his risk and the whole
the whole play-by-play so you guys can see What an eight-figure trader does and
when I mean eight-figure trader I don't mean he's making a hundred and fifty percent
a year on you know,
a million dollars or five hundred thousand bucks What I'm saying is he manages a
lot of money And so he might make you know,
25 35 40 percent a year on his on his capital So with that said let's jump right
into it. So guys pay really good attention here. Okay,
this is very important You know,
it's it's it's really critical to learn from an in-depth Example so I recommended
this book to almost everyone in this in this group here It's called volatility trading.
It is a little bit Difficult,
it's pretty math intensive is a little math intensive For that reason we're gonna
we're gonna break it down here.
Are we all good guys? Looks good Maddie saying great book. Okay, perfect.
Thanks mark. Hey mark. Hey, great to see you here, man. Okay,
so This is gonna take me about I'd say 30 minutes to get through 20 minutes to get
through but this is a real-world example so in this chapter,
we are going to Break down a volatility trade that you and Sinclair did.
Okay from you know a predetermined plan to Consistently re-evaluating the position
so that our exposure is a reflection of our current thoughts Okay,
and we always say if we don't want to be in a position we get out of that position
And then finally they exit the trade and they go through an in-depth analysis of
what happened pre-trade analysis So the pre-trade planning analysis is usually the
most important part of any trade this is especially true for volatility trading
aka option trading as Our edge will only be accumulated slowly and noisily Without
a good plan in place.
It is very easy to second-guess ourselves during the trade So we're gonna have a
strict plan.
We have to understand the plan So Apple was a darling of the markets.
This is June 25th,
2007 Apple was a darling of the market positioned at the confluence of the fashion
and technology industries It could seemingly do no wrong and its share price increased
more than a hundred and twenty five dollars per share Over the previous five years.
It had rallied on a split adjusted basis from eight dollars and fifty seven Which
was an increase of over one thousand percent Compared to the market where it only
moved fifty four percent So what he's saying is this stock was in the news people
were loving this stock Everyone was buying it and I don't know if you guys remember
he was talking about the Mac versus PC commercials Those were fantastic.
I don't you guys remember those but the iPhone was scheduled for launch Okay,
and this is you know, obviously a brand new product comes in market.
There was a lot of hype around there So June 29 was expected to be the catalyst
for another explosive burst right June 29th was the launch of the iPhone Apple was
a perfect example of the stock that people that many people expected to rally and
rally big Conversely,
the hype was attracting the standard number of contrarian types who were predicting
a huge flop This is the sort of situation that can easily result in overpriced options
as directional traders bet on large moves Bidding up the value of both the puts
and the calls Remember we said guys that 99% of option traders use options to buy
calls and puts to take directional views Though so that is what was happening here
People were buying and selling buying calls and puts to take directional views on
Apple and by doing that It was there was no one selling everyone was buying so it's
increasing the demand and there was no not enough supply So July implied volatility
has been going had been going progressively morbid for several weeks meaning it
was increasing rallying from the mid 20s to the high 30s After some discussion and
eyeballing the data We'd arrived at a consensus that the forecast of realized volatility
over the next three weeks Would be 29% and the July implied volatility was 41% So
if we go back to our graphs here, let's see if he posted the Okay,
so he's saying that the forecast of realized volatility is gonna be 29% That's what
he's forecasting. But the implied volatility was 41% Okay,
so this gave an edge of 41% Right in the way.
He calculated that was just simply it's this 41 minus 29 Right,
which is giving us 12 and we take 12 and divide it by 29.
Okay, so we've got 41% He thinks the realize is gonna be 29 implied is 41.
The normal spread for Apple was around 20 to 25 percent Meaning usually there is
a bias of 20 to 25 percent. But in this case, it was 41 percent Okay,
and then to put it in the overall context the S&P 500 Basically the vault the VIX
index right the volatility of the S&P 500 was only 31 percent higher than the forecast
volatility So here he shows a few of the volatility measures of Apple So the realized
volatility remember in the predicting alpha terminal we have the time series graph
of the realized volatility Here, maybe should I show that right now or just?
Yeah,
so here are all the different types of volatility models He's looking at so the
Garmin cloths volatility the Parkinson the close to close This is what he's looking
at right and we don't need to understand what these are We actually take care of
this in the terminal So he has all his different types of volatility here And so
what he did was he had all this these different models these different types of
volatility estimates So for example The yangzang was 31 the close to close was 28
and what he did was he took the average of all of these different estimates Which
gave him an estimate of 29 percent?
So that was his forecast of realized volatility at this point We were reasonably
confident that we had an edge in the spread between implied and realized volatility
both on absolute and relative levels We also had a clear catalyst that has caused
the spread and which and which we thought was being overplayed by the popular media
We decided to go short Apple implied volatility Now this is exactly I don't know
if you guys already seen this. This is exactly what you guys do right,
we We forecast volatility then we understand why volatility is there and then if
it makes sense we take a trade So during the so before we continue guys because
we're gonna go into Placing the trade.
So do you guys have any questions about what he's doing here?
Because then we're gonna jump into The actual actual the actual trade you have 30
seconds any questions?
How did he develop his forecast? Yeah,
so What he did was he basically took How much the stock moves so different models?
So let's say for example the yangzang actually We'll look at the close to close
because this is gonna make a lot of sense to you It's what's in think or swim the
close to close is basically how much the stock moves Every single day.
So let's say he looked at the last 20 days and he said well on average the stock
moves 10% Right,
that would be a volatility of 160 right 16 times the average daily move That's gonna
be your close to close volatility. So in this case Dan Daniel,
we got 28 Divided by 16 is about 1.5 1.7 percent.
So over the last let's say 20 days The stock Apple was only moving one point seven
percent a day So which we had a close to close volatility of 28 So this is just
one input then he would do something like the yangzang model the Parkinson,
right? We have the garch just like in the terminal.
So that's how he came up with these forecasts and then he averaged them all then
he averaged them all because each one has a little bit of a different view on the
market and if you take the Average of you know,
the crowd usually get a good estimate of the future.
Is there any questions about that? We're gonna we're gonna move on here.
Looks like we're good.
So here we go. Here's the trade starts During the afternoon of June 25th.
We started to sell we sold a 12 lot of July 125 calls at five dollars and ten cents
and bought five hundred shares at 124 so we basically sold it at 41 percent forty
one point two percent implied volatility So remember we talked about Selling an
option and then buying the shares selling a call like we did on I know for example
Where we sold the call we bought some shares against it and that's gonna create
something that looks like a straddle later How did he okay and then Daniels asking?
Hedging deltas. Yes. So let me just quickly show you guys here.
I gotta load it up Shouldn't be that bad. Okay,
well while that's loading we're gonna continue So later as the market broke we sold
50 of the July 125 straddles so you guys are familiar with this.
He sold the 125 straddles for $10 and 70 cents and then he also hedged his deltas
and Sold some shares against it at the end of the day.
We were short $1,450 worth of Vega now, this is a silver concept.
So I'm not gonna go too much in depth on this But what this basically means is that
if the stock the implied volatility went down one one point he would make $1,450
so this was giving an expected profit of roughly $16,000 so we had his expected
value already pre-planned Before he entered the trade or as he entered the trade,
but this number I'm telling you right now was already pre-planned Okay,
our hedging band don't worry about this.
We don't need to worry about this He hedged is he was figuring out his hedging his
risk management strategy here So we calculated it you know his all his Greeks his
haircut on the position meaning his margin on the position how much he has to post
up and His daily P&L now right away when he's making these trades he has transaction
costs He has a you know trade the cross the bid-ask spread.
So right off the bat.
He's down $121 just like you guys saw in the live when I was trading as soon as
I entered a position I'm already down a bit the next day Apple opened up slightly
higher at 123.97 in line with a slight rally in the overall market and the stock
dropped later in the morning We sold 50 more shares, I'm sorry,
we sold 50 more 125 calls and Under hedged them slightly to stay within our Delta
band.
Don't worry about that Our total expected P&L was now $20,000 and our hedging band
widened to 1,000 shares again.
Let's not worry about that that that silver concept So this was a very quiet day
in the market No hedging required and when he says hedging he means no Delta hedging
No hedging with the shares. No buying and selling the shares.
You can see his P&L now Yeah,
so his P&L for the day was five thousand three hundred thirty-eight.
His total P&L was three hundred and eighty-five So because there was a quiet day
right and we're short volatility Then if there's nothing happening today,
we are gonna collect our theta and not pay anything out.
Okay,
so he made five thousand three hundred thirty-eight on the day which put him up
to three hundred eighty-five So June 28th the next day another very quiet day Amazing.
He's short volatility. He's just collecting the premium here.
Let's see if this is up Just so you guys can see maybe see what's actually happening
here June 29 2007 There was a slight rally in the stock and some general choppiness
as iPhone related chatter seemed to be having some effect We had to buy 400 shares
on the rally Okay, so stock went up he had to buy 400 shares Yes, so Dan,
these are unrealized P&L because he still has the position It becomes realized P
&L once he closes out the position.
Okay,
so on this day he lost $823 and so his total P&L so far is six thousand and the
margin required for this position eighty four thousand So so far for example,
he's up about eight percent on his position in two days in three days There was
practically no movement at all. So July 2nd,
there was practically no movement at all in the stock Volatility softened considerably
to 34 and we tried to buy some back at the bid We were not filled so implied volatility
came down Right, and he's betting on it coming down.
So that's amazing for him So what he tried to do was he tried to buy back those
shares for a good price meaning at the bid right at the lowest price and Why is
he doing this guys well remember when our implied versus realized spread Collapses
we want to get out of the position so originally He had a forecast of 29% and an
implied of 41 huge edge But now it started to shrink So because you don't have that
big edge anymore. You want to take some risk off the table?
So he that's what he tried to do but in the market We don't just get filled at the
price. We want we get filled at the price the market wants Well,
look at our little our little buddies here.
You're like a little chipmunk that comes and hangs it. Oh, wow Okay,
so So we try to buy back he couldn't because the market didn't want it and so what
happened was his P&L now is now 7,500 bucks.
He's almost up 10% on the position,
but he still holds it July 3rd this morning We decided to liquidate the position
if at all possible Implied volatility at softened we had realized a good portion
of our expected P&L and we had a few other positions in our book This case this
gave us an issue with lack of diversification.
We had to be more risk averse particularly with the July 4 holiday coming up Further
we expected volatility to soften before the holiday which would make our liquidation
easy Even if we had to lift the offer We bought back our shorts at the average implied
volatility of 29.
So you see what happened here guys his edge completely disappeared now forecast
29 implied volatility 29 No more edge. Why are you in a position?
There's no more edge here. So we decided let me close it out Okay,
and what's happened? What else is going on here?
Is that in his book right in his portfolio?
He has more short volatility positions,
so maybe he had let's say short Amazon Volatility. Well,
he doesn't just want exposure now To short like by having short Apple in short Amazon.
That's a correlated position So he's saying you know what?
I gotta take some off the table now and my edge is gone So I'm liquidating at any
price even if I have to lift the offer Meaning even if I have to cross the spread
I'm taking it off Because the edge is gone there's too much risk now so total P
&L for this trade $18,000 his expected value is 20,000.
He made 18,000 almost his full expected value that was a profit of 20% in a week
20% in one week.
Okay, so he made 23% So do you guys have questions about that?
Because now we're gonna do the post trade analysis So that was the during that was
the that was the during the trade now, we're gonna do post trade So,
let me just quickly Open up thinkorswim here so you guys can see what he actually
has on.
So this is a position that you had on Okay, it's an iron condor,
but he's naked So it's a straddle and when he was hedging his deltas what that means
is the stock went from 362 to let's say 350 all of a sudden now he has a Directional
bias, right? Just move this up.
He has a directional bias now.
He wants the stock to come up Not go down and he starts losing money if the stock
goes down. So what he did was he shorted some shares Right.
Let me just show you what that looks like super quick.
Okay,
so you can see now Over here right without the shares Without the shares we want
the stock to go up, right? We don't want it to go down Right,
we make $5,000 at 361 and we lose $6,000 at 333.
So we want the stock to go from 350 So we hedge our deltas and now look we don't
we don't care if the stock goes down or up as long as it stays Here,
so we remove that directional bias and that's what he was doing Firefox there.
Yeah. Oh, yeah, there it is.
So let me just answer some questions here Okay How much capital would he have needed
for this play So in this case,
he needed 84,000 to make the 20 $20,000 but you for example might only need $8,000
to make the $2,000. Okay,
so it's it's it's all relative When you say a profit of X percent in options is
that on the total equity of the option of individual trade So Dan this in this case
scenario it was on his Margin requirement.
So if it costs you $10,000 to Make this trade.
Let's say it's cost you $10,000 to buy Apple and then Apple goes up a thousand bucks
You would make 10% so it's on the margin required.
So let's say you buy a butterfly for 20 bucks and the butterfly goes to $25 Well,
that's 20% gain or sorry 25% gain 5 divided by the amount you have to put up which
is 20 That's gonna be 25% Okay So, okay. Let's see. What else we got here.
Okay, when you say okay, yeah,
Danny Daniel's asking What could have what could he have done if the stock started
to move to the upside with the stock still work as a hedge?
Yes So Danny see how we have to short some shares and you guys were seeing me do
this all the time last week See how we had to short some shares when the stock went
down Well, what if the stock went up right? What if the stock went up here now?
We want the stock to go down instead of up.
So what we need to do is buy the shares And now look right now.
We don't care where the stock goes Okay, so he's just removing his Deltas.
That's all and What was the approximate entire portfolio risk I'm Not a hundred
percent. I'm not a hundred percent sure here mark.
He doesn't really he doesn't really talk about the the whole portfolio He just talks
about the margin on the position.
So I'm not too sure about that Doesn't this also happen when holding an iron condor
if the stock moves down too much? Yep, exactly So with an iron condor,
so let me show you super quick.
How you doing Sean being fantastic. Yeah. Yeah, it's good Okay,
so here's our iron condor We still have that if the stock goes down here if the
stock goes up to here We want the stock to go up or sorry.
We want the stock to go down Not up so we can hedge our Deltas here by buying some
stock and there you go Right now we now we are directionless Again,
so same thing happens Okay,
so And that'll be talked about more in silver Yeah And and just so you guys know
like it can get costly though to hedge so you don't be hedging all the time you
Want to be hedging is as infrequent as possible How do we calculate how many more
stonks to buy to hedge again So you would look at your Deltas and that'll be calculated
for you on on your brokerage Okay,
but we're gonna move on to post trade analysis Okay. So in seven days,
we made 18,000 on average haircut of 76 K thus giving us a return of 24% We lost
money on three days But on the first of these we were incurring cost by actively
crossing the bid-ask spread in the options And on the second day,
we were happy enough to sell more on the offer at the as the implied volatility
slightly went more bid So this is what you guys saw in my portfolio when I was trading
Live for you guys, right?
You saw me incurring a lot of costs at the beginning to put on these positions and
then you usually have to hold these positions For a few days Right.
So for example, I know is finally starting to come in So this is you know,
we always have to keep in mind of our transaction cost we can't forget about them
They're so important. We don't want to be trading frequently,
especially in the option space when the bid-ask is not one penny If you look at
the stock market or the Forex or whatever,
it's gonna have a very very tight bid-ask spread But in options,
it gets a little bit thicker Okay.
So what next he says this trade was unreasonably successful meaning most of the
time It's not gonna work out where almost every single day.
He didn't have to hedge It was just it was a really good trade, right?
Usually it's not gonna work like that.
If every trade was like that everyone would be rich, right?
But this is an example of a good trade a good breakdown, right?
We made almost exactly what we hoped for and did it in seven days Instead of holding
that and so instead of holding the position until expiration Okay Having to hold
until expiration is gonna expose us to more risks, right?
Our gamma is gonna start to increase We're not just looking at implied volatility
anymore. Our gamma is increasing Okay,
so our decision to exit was perfectly timed as 9 a.m.
Eastern the next day the stock began a strong rally to close out 127 This would
have not worked out well for us implied volatility rose to 43 and we would have
lost money hedging our short gamma This would be inevitable regardless of our specific
hedging policy as a daily range of the size would imply volatility about 110% Okay.
So what he's saying is we would have lost on implied volatility and the stock movement
okay, however,
if we did hold to expiration we still would have had remained profitable and Here
he breaks down the trade. So on this day,
he lost 120 then he lost 5,000 then he made 385 7,000 etc.
And you can see how his P&L looked through time.
So he entered the position here He went up luckily. He exited right here.
But the next day he got smoked and then he came back up Okay,
so this is what it would look like So here he's gonna talk a little bit about what
actually was was really what was he really thinking?
We do these trades on the premises that implied volatility is incorrect over the
lifetime of the option It's the average volatility that's important or the realized
volatility We can afford to have a few bad days The actual close to close realized
volatility was 30% over the life cycle,
which was very close to his 29% forecast Okay,
so we were unlucky because we had a large move that took us away from our short
strike.
So meaning Here's his short strike Okay right here the 362 he had a large move That
took him down here Right.
So we had to hedge the position if he stayed right in here and time for the past
right as time passes He makes money, right?
So that's why guys when he said there was no there was no hedging the stock didn't
move All he did was Collect data the purple line moved up a bit Okay,
then he talks about this We should never get stopped out of a trade just because
we have lost money.
We exit trades if we no longer like them Losing money while deeply unpleasant should
never be the sole React should never be the the criterion for exiting Right just
because you're losing money doesn't mean you exit the trade the stock the trade
could keep going against you but if your initial idea is still intact keep the trade
on right a Basic cliche is always have a stop but this is overly simplistic and
it doesn't take into account the dynamics of the trade This is one thing I don't
agree with you is that I think we should have a ultimate stop where we say we are
We are wrong Okay,
we expect high volatility be transient So stopping ourselves out after every high
volatility burst is not a good idea Right if we think implied volatility is high
at 40 and it goes up to 43. Well, it still looks good to us Right.
So we need to we do understand that so instead of a stop based purely on P&L Which
I agree with we have a plan based on our edge evaluation and our initial trade size
Trades going bad shouldn't be too painful if they are kept small enough Okay,
so just quickly summary an old trading adage is to plan the trade trade the plan
Look for situations where implied volatility differs significantly from your forecast
both for Pacific stock and in context of the market Evaluate the fundamentals that
causing this this spread Do your research? Yeah, do your research?
execute the trade appropriate size and hedge it properly and then hold until your
your edge is either realized or your volatility forecast changes and Then continually
evaluate risk in context of your overall portfolio If you sell Apple and you sell
Amazon and you sell Microsoft,
you probably all you have one big trade You don't have three different trades.
So that is the breakdown Okay,
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna actually ask you guys questions now to see
how much you absorbed So you want you want to send that out?
Yeah so That's a question from while ago We actually instead koa if you if you still
have a question about how we forecasted the vol Just ask it again because we answered
that when Danny asked it Yeah,
so let us know if you have any more questions about that But for now,
we're gonna hop right into our little test here.
So just we have three questions Question one run for one minute. Good luck.
Okay. Let me see how many guys we haven't alive today.
We'll give another 30 seconds Okay,
15 we got 15 so I'm gonna wait for for you guys to get in here Wait for a couple
more Come on guys get him in.
I mean we got we got you got test your knowledge here.
Give that one more second.
Okay?
I press and pull right Okay Okay, so most of you guys got it, right?
Fantastic IV was greater than forecast, right?
He said the implied volatility was 41.
The forecast was 29 And he understood why the trade why it was bid Because everyone
was looking at the stock it had a catalyst coming up and everyone was being directional
It was pushed on the news.
He said right and that this was in 2007 So nowadays we are gonna say, you know,
it's pushed on the stock boards Cool raise his hand Yeah,
he said where's the test?
So it should be popping up on your screen as a part of the zoom Are you are you
on mobile? Maybe it may not pop up on mobile Okay. Yeah,
so it's it's showing up for desktop users I'm not a hundred percent sure where you
would find the pole on mobile Try clicking around the screen.
It's a it's a pole that we've launched Okay, okay.
There's only a couple questions call.
I wouldn't worry about it for this one It's only three questions for the next round
do it for the for the next life. Okay, stop sharing, right?
Yeah All right pole number two Another 60 seconds and meet this for a second.
See if our little buddy will come.
Oh, we can't see that So what the full question? That's okay Okay,
we got eight answers waiting for a few more guys nine ten eleven. Okay,
twelve perfect Okay, sweet. So Almost all of you guys got it, right?
Share results. Okay, so pretty straightforward, right?
He understood why why ball was expensive He planned his risk management and he estimated
expected value.
So there there's nothing really to be There's nothing really to be you know Shaken
up about what now we enter remember we want to take psychology out of trading as
much as we can because we're not good At psychology. No one is right.
Maybe maybe some people are I wouldn't I shouldn't say that Why go the hard route?
Plan everything out before you enter the position If something wild happens you
are you knew that this could this could happen if it does happen.
I'm out Right,
so you come in here knowing everything about how you think this trade is gonna break
down all possible scenarios The stock gapping up 30% What do you do then?
Right? You need to think about these things before you enter the trade Okay,
and because of that he was confident going into the trade and now all of a sudden
psychology is nothing It's something but all of a sudden it's removed a lot.
You're not you're not you're not guessing. Oh, maybe it's gonna come back Oh,
you know, maybe it's not gonna come back.
It's like no I pre-planned this am I being greedy if I stay in? Yeah,
you know am I being fearful if I get out you don't have questions like that anymore
exact next question Okay,
or last question and then I'm gonna go in the terminal super quick and show you
guys some of the features that we just Looked at here.
All right. Good luck guys. I think this one's let's see Okay, yeah,
this is this is a good one,
okay a few more of you guys to come in waiting on two more,
all right,
and We're gonna end the poll right there So it wasn't that he had a directional
view on Apple instead It was that he didn't have a directional view on Apple.
So we wanted to remove that exposure Right when we're looking here,
for example,
I'm think or swim the stock went down here Let's say to 349 all of a sudden he has
directional exposure He wants the stock to go back up and he didn't want that So
he decided to trade the shares to get rid of that exposure So I'm glad I'm glad
Almost all of you got it,
right but keep that in mind With options we have the beauty of or in trading not
just an option with the beauty of Getting exposure to the risk we want and removing
the exposure.
We don't want and that's what he did He didn't want directional exposure.
So he removed it Okay So now I'm just gonna quickly jump into the predicting alpha
terminal if you guys have any questions raise your hand Or drop them in the comment
box drop them in the comment box.
We're gonna quickly go over this What info did he need to calculate that 20k expected
profit? Yep.
So all he needed was his implied volatility and His forecast of volatility once
you do that all you do is so it's right here so Here's his implied Okay,
his forecast was 29 and then he has to multiply it by this is something in silver
So if you're you know, if you're bronze, don't worry too much about this.
He multiplies it by his Vega exposure Okay,
so how much exposure he has to Vega?
So for example on this trade right on this Apple trade,
let's go back to To today on this Apple trade we have $850 of short Vega exposure.
Okay,
so in our in that case we would do 850 times the difference So that's how he came
up with that It's like I noticed yeah,
I got it after we changed that password I sat there for so long trying to remember
what it was Really? Yeah, I couldn't remember it, but he figured it out. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay,
so a couple things here guys first thing is for the forecast of volatility We do
something very similar to what you did where we take a bunch of different factors
different models We add them up.
We take the average of them and then that comes out right over here so for Apple,
for example,
our forecast is thirty two point five eight and The implied is thirty three if this
was let's say 42 we could be selling volatility Okay,
then the other thing is you can see Historically how much Volatility Apple's hadn't
passed just like you did right where he showed He showed the volatility of one year.
Well,
we did the we have something very similar on the on the terminal What has the historical
volatility been a year from now a year ago, right?
So You know if so right now you can see implied volatility as high as 86 Imagine
or sorry realized volatility is 86 Imagine implied volatility was 300 would that
make sense? No, so we would sell options there. So this is the historical Okay,
so these are the few features that you know,
you used in his analysis that we actually have in the terminal.
Okay, so Daniel said if we wanted to do a quick forecast from the TOS platform,
how could we do that? Do you mean forecast of volatility? Yeah,
I think that's what he's talking about. Okay,
so In that case you would use Yeah In that case you would use
this Okay, historical volatility right there. Now, that's the close to close,
right? That's one of the forecasts the issue with this is it's not great Right.
This is not the greatest model ever. And in fact, it's it's very naive.
So you would say for example The implied vault the historical volatility of Apple
has been 33% in the past Meaning it's probably gonna be 33% in the future.
Now that is very naive So I wouldn't be too keen on using Just this alone You got
a good question from Chegg's.
So he said why doesn't the market calculate volatility like we do?
What do they do differently that causes the mispricing? Okay,
so first off Chiggs There are people that do exactly what we do right you did it
for example Right.
There are other guys that I've learned from that do the same thing that we do as
well The problem is and also what you mentioned is that a lot of option traders
don't price volatility They don't trade volatility Right.
How many times do you see people say I own Apple?
So I'm gonna buy some puts to hedge They don't care what the price is or I own Apple
So I'm gonna sell some calls to get a covered call and get some income They don't
care about the price of those calls Right,
or I'm gonna buy an Apple call pre earnings because I think Apple is going up After
earnings they don't care about the price of the call again, right?
So for that reason the market is not looking at the world through implied volatility
But we are looking at the world through implied volatility.
That's all that's only that's the only difference most of the world is looking at
the is looking at the market through a directional bias and For that reason we can
find edge in Volatility because there are the world of volatility is much smaller
So I hope that answers that question there What they do people do price it like
we do and they some people even use more advanced techniques Can we do any other
questions? I think that was a good little walkthrough. I you know,
I hope you guys There was I think it was a Q&A or was that that was it?
We finished it wasn't there I think there's one up here. Let me see.
I think that's the old one. Okay.
Yeah Mark says I was away for a bit But what are your thoughts on not Delta hedging
but instead using the parameters of the risk profile to define your risk?
Instead of Delta hedging. Yep. Yep, Mark. I Think that's you know,
because Delta hedging is expensive and obviously you know that So if you're not
going to Delta hedge Then you would you'd probably have a hard stop somewhere,
right? Like if the stock goes, you know, the stock goes Ten percent down.
I have to close out my position But yeah,
I mean There's nothing wrong with not Delta hedging as like I said,
it is pretty expensive So you would say for example Then you also have a directional
view though, right Mark.
So like let's say stock goes down to 380 all of a sudden You are long you you you
are You are short shares So,
you know you at that point you have to say well if I'm not if I'm if I'm bullish
on Apple You probably don't want to be in this position anymore.
So I Know I'm not sure. Did I answer that question mark?
Yeah Okay, so the only time Honestly mark, I actually I probably don't do it.
I like I'm probably the worst directional trader you're ever gonna meet Like for
example our Spotify trade I Close it out. Literally.
I bought it at the top close it at the bottom and it rallied all the way back up
We would have made 15,000 bucks just on that butterfly.
It pinned to our short strike a day later a day later.
Unbelievable So I'm honestly I'll be straight up with you.
I'm not the grace Directional trader so as soon as I get too much Delta,
I'm gonna close it out But I know there are definitely people that do right but
then but then what you're really trading is instead of the implied versus realized
Spread you're you're trading the terminal distribution.
What is what is the stock today versus where it's gonna be in the future,
right?
You're at you're trading the end point So if you think for example Apple is gonna
is in support and resistance right now Do you think it's gonna stay within that
range?
Then you probably swing Delta hedge you just hold this position But you know,
I'm sure you're probably much better directional trader than I am mark So I wouldn't
I wouldn't be taking advice from me in that sense.
So if there's no more questions,
we're gonna wrap this up We're gonna go into the after dark for 15 minutes.
Yeah, we'll go hang out Yeah,
see if you guys want a couple new guys tune in here really happy to see you here
If you look in the discord, we have a category called after dark.
It has a text channel and a voice channel We're just gonna pop in there hang out
for a bit if you guys have any more questions for us Marco said do you ever trade
direction? I do trade direction, but it's not in the sense of Outright Delta.
So Delta just means direction and we're gonna cover all this in I think we're doing
a bronzer. No,
it's in silver Yeah So I don't usually take outright directional bets Because like
I said,
I don't have an edge in it and it's not that I don't have it like an edge in it
It's also the fact that I haven't spent the time I've seen what it takes to be a
profitable directional trader and It's pretty mind-blowing I've seen some of the
guys who work at some big funds that are doing some very cool data science stuff
with direction and It's definitely not an easy game.
I think there's a lot more money to be made in the vol space And so for that reason
I tried to remain directionless However,
there are some times where I do pack on some Delta Yeah,
so for example in the unbalanced flies on unbalanced fly exactly Danny had a question
that we should address Yeah, Mark,
so you like you like we know each other pretty well now and like, you know,
I do trade one three two flies they are they do have direction,
but They're also very sensitive to The skew right so we get like these really nice
risk reward trades and they're usually more of a risk reward trade than a directional
trade Yeah, I do. I do trade directional. Sometimes I try to find a small edge,
especially around earnings events But even then it's I'm definitely not the best
directional trader Danny had a question about the what did we mean by the risk parameter
in the brokerage? So like we're talking about this Okay, right.
So you just want to say like, what do you mean by risk brokerage? Okay.
So so what Mark was saying is Do you ever just put on this trade and then don't
Delta hedge and instead have like a risk parameter where you know If the stock goes
below a certain threshold, you're out of the position, right?
Just like what we do in iron condors,
right when you guys are trading iron condors for bronze so Yeah,
that's exactly what he's talking about. But for me,
I usually like to hedge my deltas And yeah,
so that'll be in silver by the way for all this is a bronze live. Yeah,
we got into some silver concepts Yeah, we did. I think it was good. Yeah Yeah,
so You can have a hard stop right where if it touches the wing we're out So I will
do that I will do that sometimes Because Delta hedging is pretty expensive.
But most of the time I do like to hedge my deltas Okay, guys,
so that's the life that's the life we're gonna end it there and we'll see you in
the after dark for a bit Awesome. Peace out Yeah,
exactly It's funny because like because you didn't sinclair just basically said
like, you know, don't don't don't do But I think they're I think you know,
it's good to have a hard stop When you're wrong,
right know when you're wrong and and put it put it in there. Okay guys,
I'll talk to you in a bit Thanks mark Yeah,