Why do we look at the world in implied volatilities when we're option traders?
Why do we do that? Why do we not look at it through prices?
Okay. Why is it that as an option trader, you guys come in here,
a lot of the new guys come in here and right off the bat,
they have to start looking at the world through this implied volatility lens.
You know, why are we doing this? Wouldn't it make more sense to just use price?
What do you guys think?
I think Neil fell asleep, man. He's either freaking out or he fell asleep. No,
he just doesn't know the answer.
Okay,
so what do you guys think? Wow, no answer. All right, go for it. Okay,
I'm gonna have to share my screen and we're gonna jump into it.
Is he asleep or alone or with someone? No, no, he's asleep. It's Neil, man.
It's with someone.
Okay, so here we're gonna go to an option price calculator, okay?
And I want you guys to think about this for a second, okay? Neil,
so the question is,
why do we look at the world through implied volatilities and not price?
So I want you guys to imagine this, okay? So first off, 99% of retail traders,
99% of traders look at the world through price in terms of options.
The professionals always look at it through implied volatility.
Why is that the case?
Okay, so imagine we're looking at... Actually,
let me pull up thinkorswim as well. Okay,
imagine we're looking at a stock that's trading for 100 bucks.
It's trading at $100 and we're looking at the 105 strike call option.
Now, if that 105 strike call option was $3 or $2 or $8,
would we be able to make decisions off of that?
What do you guys think? While I sign in here,
let me know what you guys are thinking.
Because I feel like even with some of the guys here, Kyle, Neil, Steve,
I feel like I still have to ingrain this in your heads.
Right, Renato? We can't just... We can't make a decision.
If I'm looking at Apple, okay? And Apple's trading right now at $115.
And I look at this call option for 120 and it's going for $3 and 70 cents.
What does that mean? Right, Sean always says, learn how to price your asset.
Is it cheap or expensive? Is it fair value? Do you know,
right? We can't gain any information from $3 and 70 cents.
Do you want to say something? No, keep going. Okay,
so now let's see why we want to look at it through implied volatility lens.
Well, the first thing we need to think about is, how are these options created?
How are they replicated, right? How can we actually value this asset?
And the way we can value this asset is through volatility. Okay,
options are a volatility product. Let's go into option calculator here, okay?
Stocks trading at 100. We look at the 105 strike call.
Days until expiration is 30.
Okay, dividend interest rates are zero and implied volatility is 30%. Well,
that implied volatility level. Okay,
so the implied volatility meaning what the market is expecting to happen corresponds
to $1.56 call option.
Okay, so now you're probably thinking, well, Jordan,
what the hell does volatility of 30 mean to us? Right,
it doesn't mean anything either. Well, we can actually see,
we can actually graph volatility through time, right? And we can see, well,
how has this thing moved, right? Now we're being able to see,
is this cheap or is this expensive, right? If we look at,
let's take a look here. Let's see how we can take a look.
So we're looking at Apple, let's say.
And what I'm going to graph is the historical implied volatility. Okay,
just by itself.
I'm going to expand it. Yeah, so here's the implied volatility for Apple.
Well, now let me ask you guys this question, okay?
So first I'm going to ask you this.
So I'm going to graph, actually,
I'm going to graph this option.
Okay, so this is the, what was this? This is the November 20th contract. Okay,
November 20th contract. At the money call. Just out of the, well,
right now it's out of the money. Okay,
so let me actually go a little bit longer out here, guys.
I can only go back five days, it looks like. Okay,
let me ask you guys this question right now. Is this price,
so right now it's trading at $2.40. Is this cheap or expensive?
What do you guys think? It's trading for $2.40. Is it cheap or expensive?
Okay, here it is right here.
Okay, and this is what it's been trading at the last five days.
Cheap or expensive?
Koaw is saying cheap. How come? Why Koaw? Marco's saying it depends.
I like that answer better. Kyle's saying, I don't know. Right?
I like that answer too. Yeah, we really don't know.
We really don't know because this option, for example,
maybe it was at the money here and now it's out of the money. Right, well,
obviously it's going to go down,
but that has nothing to do with the stock price. Well,
it has nothing to do with the stock price, but it has nothing to do with,
right, it's...
It has nothing to do with fair value. Right, it was at a different price here.
The,
let's say Apple over here was trading at 120 and now Apple's trading at 115 over
here. Well, obviously this call option is going to go down,
but that means we have to have a view on the price, not on the option.
Right? On the price of the stock, on the price of the underlying. Now,
let's take a look at implied vol, okay?
Actually, we'll look at SLV because that one, oh shit.
It's so fucking funny, man. Always happens. Should've held it.
Always happens to me, man. Okay. Okay, guys, I swear to God, these things,
I don't know who draws these, okay? I swear to God, they're not me.
Must be Chris. Chris must be taking over my computer. Okay, so we can see here,
right, guys? Let's take a look. Time frame set up.
You pinned up our strike too, man. I know, right? Should've held it, man.
Isn't that crazy?
And just to keep you guys in the loop, back in, right, back in July,
Sean and I were selling the 23s straddles on silver, November expiration.
And what do you know, guys? Pins to our strike, okay? Not the first time.
Won't be the last time. What else do you know, guys?
We fucking sold it like a month ago. Yeah, we sold it on the first breakdown.
Okay, so we can look at this graph right here, okay?
Without even doing any data statistical analysis,
we can look at this graph here and be like, okay,
this is expensive relative to history.
Okay, relative to history,
this implied volatility is probably extremely expensive and is almost certainly
gonna go down in the future, right, which it did. Now,
obviously timing it perfectly is difficult, right? So for example,
we might've been, and we were, right,
we were selling vol here and it went all the way up to here, right? But,
you know,
we were able to manage the position and eventually it turned out to be a profitable
trade, right? Came all the way back down and then we exited around here.
Now, the whole purpose of this is, this is how we can view options, okay?
And it's not just the level of implied volatility, okay?
That's the most important thing as well, okay?
It's not just the level of implied volatility,
it's also for the surrounding options. And what do I mean by that?
Well, we look at Apple here and I wanna compare,
let's say the 120 call option and the 125 call option. Well,
the 120 call option is $4 and 5 cents and the 125 call option is $2 and 50 cents.
So why don't I just sell a whole bunch of these 120s and buy a whole bunch of the
125s, right? We have to be able to compare these options locally, okay?
So there's a globally and there's also locally and this is on a local plane here,
okay? So we can see, okay, well,
this option is trading for 47 and a half percent and this option is trading for
47.13%. Now, what if this option here was trading for, let's say $1, okay?
So right now it's trading for $1.80. Imagine it was trading for a buck. Well,
we wouldn't be able to tell if it's expensive or cheap but we can because we use
implied volatilities. This would be 47 and a half and this would be 35,
right?
So we could do something now where we could buy this at 35% and sell these at 47%,
right, and make money.
And that is why using implied volatilities and looking at the world through implied
volatility is crucial in option trading and why you won't see market makers or professional
option traders quoting in price. They'll always quote in implied vol, right?
And I'm gonna try and explain it a little deeper here as well or just in a little
bit more of a simple way maybe.
You make money on an option, right? Let's say you were to buy a call,
not just when the stock goes up,
but when it goes up within a given timeframe past a certain point, right?
Remember the characteristics of what really an option is made up of, right?
You need to have a view on how quickly it's going to move as well, right?
And what we know volatility means is it's the size and speed of these moves,
right? It's almost like you can use,
similar to the way we use volatile in other words,
like Jordan has a great example with a drunk guy walking down the street,
right?
If we were trying to measure how drunk this person was just by asking him how many
beers he had,
we might not get a great read because who knows it might be a seasoned alcoholic.
He's had seven beers, but that's just a typical Tuesday afternoon for him.
He hasn't even got to the evening yet or maybe it's someone who's never drank before
and seven beers should put them in the hospital, right?
So we can't really judge it like that.
But what we could maybe look at is we could watch this person walk and see how they
stumble, right?
Maybe if this is the case, if this is the sidewalk, right? And we'll say,
this is the road, there's like cars driving here now.
Maybe the person walks like this,
right?
Maybe he's walking like this,
which he's got a good buzz going or maybe he walks like this.
Maybe he's pretty sober, who knows how many beers he had,
maybe he's pretty sober or maybe he's walking like this.
Guys, I don't know if you know this, but that's Neil after one beer.
That's Neil.
That's Neil, yeah.
But you guys get what I'm saying, right?
So volatility can help us explain things that price cannot, right?
Because at the end of the day, the option is not just about where it moves to,
it's about how quickly it's moving as well, right?
Volatility is the size of these moves.
And the implied volatility is what is the market saying those moves are going to
be? Now, if we looked at an option on Apple versus an option on Amazon,
both of them at the money, they're going to be drastically different prices,
right? Imagine the option on a penny stock versus the option on $2,000 Amazon,
right? The Amazon option might be like a few hundred bucks,
whereas the penny stock one is 10 cents.
Does that make the penny stock one cheap?
How are we supposed to compare these things and be like,
what are these options telling us about these different stocks?
The only way that we can do it is by having an apples to apples comparison to them.
And that's why we can use something like this, like volatility, right?
What if we looked at the volatility measures for each of them and we see that,
you know, sure the Amazon one, right?
Is maybe let's say $200 and the penny stock one is 50 cents.
But in terms of implied volatility,
maybe the Amazon one is saying this and the penny stock one is saying this.
All of a sudden we see that this penny stock one is telling us that the market thinks
this thing is going to move like crazy.
Whereas the Amazon one is telling us that it's actually implying that Amazon isn't
going to move much in the future, right?
Now you can see how once we move it to implied volatilities,
we can start looking at things relative to one another and start to make judgments
about what would need to happen in the future in order for this to be a profitable
or unprofitable trade if we bought or sold, right?
In order to help us make a better decision about what's this thing worth,
right? You know, anything you want to add there? Nope. I think it allows,
implied volatility allows us to look at the world on the same playing field,
right? Everything is lined up. Exactly. Right? Of course,
an Amazon call is going to be $50 and, you know,
a small cap stock is going to be or a small price stock is going to be $2.
You can't say this $2 one is cheaper than the $50 Amazon.
A lot of people actually look at the world like that, right?
We have to always look at implied vol,
okay? And Neil, do you actually want to share your story there?
I can't remember. Like, did you roll down the hill and then the goat hit you?
Is that how it worked? The goat nailed you with the picture up with its horns?
Okay. Anyway, so... And guys, at the end, after the live is done,
I'm going to go over some implied correlation stuff super quick.
I just realized I have Chris Cidio up here. I really got to stop. But anyways,
we... I thought we talked about this, man. Yeah,
we can go over the implied correlation post he just tweeted about for the more advanced
guys. Okay. So stocks trading at $100, $105 call price, okay?
Days until expiration, $30. Volatility, $30. Now,
look what happens when we change the price of implied volatility.
When we change implied volatility, okay?
So when we go from $30 to let's say $40,
the call option is going to go from $1.56 to $2.60. So if we think that today,
fair value or volatility in the future is going to be 40%,
that call option should be worth $2.60 today.
But because the market is saying it's only going to move $30, it's only $1.56,
right?
By having our own forecast of what volatility will look like in the future,
we can now say, is this cheap or expensive? And we can do this for any option.
Because it's no longer about the price of the option,
it's about what that option has baked into it.
And the measure we can use that's baked into the option to compare them all is implied
volatility.
Yeah, I know. Good thing you're going to the gym, man,
or you probably wouldn't be on the slide right now.
That goat would have gone through you, man. Yeah.
So that is why we look at implied volatility, okay? Now, the next thing is,
well, how do we find these opportunities?
Where would we find opportunities where options are going to be over or underpriced?
So the way you want to think about it is, this is actually coming off of,
I've always had this idea, but I think Yoon said a lot nicer.
You can take advantage, for example, of risk premiums, right?
We always talk about this. Where is the market?
Where are people not willing to go? Right? So for example,
people don't want down and out put exposure.
And I guess before we hop into that, like something that should be said is,
it's not like you're just going to look at an option chain and it's going to be
like, all of them are 40 implied vol,
and you'll just see one that's like 20 implied vol. You know, the market,
something that people have to always keep in mind is,
the market is not perfectly efficient, but it's damn good, right?
So there will usually be like a reasonable explanation for why something would be
expensive or cheap. Now there's times where it's not. And when we see those,
we take advantage of all of them, right? Like BCLI, right?
We were in this trade right now, where you want to pull it up.
That's a good example. Right? Go through that. Because like, look guys,
here's the implied vol. The stock's a lot less liquid, okay? Look at this.
This is going for 185% and this is going for 262%, right?
Now a naive person might come in here and be like, arbitrage opportunity. Well,
the reality is this brokerage here is not giving you fair,
it's not quoting you the fair price, right?
They're using mid as an implied vol fair value.
So you might come in here and say, okay,
I'm going to sell a boatload of these and buy a boatload of these, right?
You might do, let's say a ratio spread here, right? Let's see,
1250 and what was it? 1750,
right? You might come in here and say, well, Jordan,
I'm going to sell a bunch of these, right? I'm going to sell vol at 260.
I'm going to buy vol at 185 and it looks great,
right? Look at this guys, it looks fantastic. You know, we're going to,
we basically, we get to, we're not going to lose money below,
if we hold to expiration below 24 bucks, right? And on the downside,
we're obviously going to make, you know, the 1050 bucks.
The difference more or less. And you might say, okay, well, you know,
if this was priced, for example, so you guys can see right here, right?
Let's price this out. So here, 185 implied vol, okay?
This one looks pretty liquid. You can see the bid ask spreads pretty tight,
not super tight, but pretty tight, okay? But look at this one over here.
What if this was priced at 185 vol? How much should this be worth?
So right now, for example, the brokerage is quoting us a mid of $1.15, okay?
So let's go to our option calculator super quick.
Stock is trading at $10 and 20 cents.
And we're looking at the 1750 call is until expiration 25 and volatility 185,
okay?
So this option would go from $1.15 to 42 cents. This is the real fair value,
right? The real fair value is 42 cents, not $1.15, right? If it was $1.15,
we'd want to sell these as much as possible.
And the only way we were able to do this is through the lens of implied volatility,
not through the lens of the price,
okay?
Look at this one, right? This one's the mid here is $2.50.
It's trading at 450% implied vol. You know,
someone might come in here and be like, this is awesome. This is an awesome,
you know, an awesome sell. I'm going to get this for $2.50.
They start buying these, right? They start accumulating these at 185.
Then they come and start selling these and they realize I can't get this for $2
.50, right? Because they weren't looking at the lens of implied vol, right?
This is an arbitrage opportunity, right? Look at this, guys.
We can sell this for $2.50 and we can buy this for $1.20.
Arbitrage. There's nowhere on this graph where we lose money, okay?
And that is why this will never happen, right? You know,
this exact thing will never happen. I've never seen it.
You guys probably won't ever see it. Who knows?
But maybe leave a resting order. Some new book will come in and hit you, right?
So, you know, these are,
if we don't look at the world through implied volatility and we only look at price,
because I've seen a lot of the guys in the group, for example, be like, hey,
how can I lose money on this trade?
Because they were looking at it through price.
If you're looking at through implied vol,
you'll realize that the world's a lot different.
And that's how the professionals look at this game.
Kyle, down and out means, so if we're looking at the option chain, okay?
We're down. So we go down in strikes and we're out in time.
So down and out might be, let's say, a 200-day Delta 5 or Delta 10 put,
okay? Yeah, out in time, way out of the mind. Yeah, that's a down and out.
Basically betting on this thing going to zero in the long run.
Marcos is asking if we ever look at volume. We don't look at volume.
In the sense that a lot of other people do. Yeah, you know,
and that being said, Marcos, you know, you've been with us for a while now.
You know that we don't know everything.
And so I've heard of stories where guys would, you know,
find these small cap stocks. They have a huge print,
an aggressive print on the ask for, you know, let's say 5,000 contracts.
And you can tag along with those, right?
And that's actually a retail strategy that big institutions can't do.
That being said, I think you need to do a lot more.
It's a lot harder to do that than said.
Yeah, because now you're in the queue.
Ko is saying 5 cents versus $5. Did I just say something about that? No,
he's just looking at this.
Oh, the bid-ask spread. On the 20, on the 22.50. So someone, right,
is willing to buy this for 5 cents and someone's willing to sell this for $5.
There's basically no market there. There's no market here, right?
So you need to come in and be able to price this.
Now you can't price this without looking at implied vol, right?
You can't just come in here. Imagine you, imagine this Tico.
Imagine you come in here and you're like, okay, mid is $2.50,
I'm going to buy it for $2.50. You would be paying 450% implied vol.
And this is actually guys, what retail people do. Okay,
I'm convinced even though there is, you know,
there is something happening on this expiration.
I'm convinced some group posted about BCLI because of the volatilities through the
roof. And these are the guys buying these options,
right? We got to think about it. It's a cheap, like how in heaven's name,
let's wait, where are we, December, right? We sold the 18, right? Yeah,
you know,
how in heaven's name is this going for 390% implied vol on the downside,
right? These are things where, look at this guys,
the stock has to go to zero in order for us to lose money.
Like people are betting on bankruptcy here, right? And not just that,
it's like, well, there's, the stock doesn't go instantly to zero, right?
There's still, you know, a net liquidation value, right?
There's still value to shareholders here. So whoever's betting this,
betting on these things,
it's crazy.
And I think one thing that has to do with it is because the price is so low.
So if this was, let's say a $500 stock,
I don't think we would see 380% implied vol, to be honest.
We'd see maybe a lot less, like 200%.
And Koa is saying we should try and find all of these. Yeah, Koa,
you should start researching this, man. When we have time,
we'll be looking into it a lot as well.
But obviously time is of the essence for a lot of other things right now.
But guys, let me ask you a question, right?
Who the hell would want this payoff? At one point it was trading for two bucks.
Who would want this payoff here, right? This is wild.
This is a wild payoff to me, right?
Stock trading here.
I mean, hey, it could happen. You know, they could get paid off.
Your risk is like, it's like one-to-one risk reward for like,
for you betting on bankruptcy. Like in what world does this make sense?
Would it make sense to like structure a vertical here if you bet on it going down?
Yeah, it'd be a lot better. Right, like sell, you know. Even then, right?
It's still not good. It's brutal. It's absolutely brutal.
At least you're making money a little before. Yeah,
at least you're making money a little bit down here. But these, you know,
if we can't look at the world through implied vol,
we're never going to be able to see these opportunities.
Okay. Right. You know, I'll use the example I use for statistics and trading,
right? So any of the new members here who's been through the first week,
it's what I say to you guys when we talk about basic stats.
Implied volatility is the language of options.
You need to be able to speak the language to make money, right?
Like you wouldn't move to a foreign country where, you know,
the first language is different and not learn the language. You know,
good luck getting a job, right?
You need to learn the language of the game you're in to be competitive.
And that's what this is.
Yeah, like look at this structure, man.
You can't lose money on the downside and you're good all the way up until 30 bucks.
It's free money. Until they say we found the cure for coronavirus.
And it goes all the way. And they're like a mining company.
They're not even a... Yeah, I imagine they're a gold mining company. Come out,
guys, we found the cure. Deep down near the core of the earth.
It was sitting there in a vial for us. Yeah, I think it is a biotech stock.
So you always got to be careful of these, right? Yeah, brainstorm,
sell therapeutics. But it looks like the bet is it to go into zero. It's not,
no one's betting on this thing going to the moon. Look at the implied vol here,
right?
It might be worth financing a way out of the money call with our free money we're
gathering on the downside. Right? And like you guys know as well.
What are the odds these people are right? And you know, it's actually really,
actually really interesting about this trade,
which is why I think it's like a phenomenal trade.
And this is also how you guys can,
how we can look at the world through implied vol.
The implied volatility is actually higher to the downside.
So what do we know about skew? This is, you know, for the,
we're going to talk about this maybe tomorrow or Wednesday,
but what do we know about skew? Well, if implied vol is higher on the downside,
right?
That means that the market actually thinks the most likely scenario is to the upside,
but the volatility is to the downside. Now,
does that make sense for a biopharma stock that the volatility is to the downside
and the most likely scenario is to the upside? No. Right. It don't. It doesn't.
The scenario we should see is volatility to the upside.
And a trickle down if nothing happens. Right. Right. It's,
it's burning cashflow, burning cashflow, spike. But right, right now,
what the market's saying is making money, making money, smash down. It's like,
wait a minute. It's like, this isn't Apple.
That's not how these companies work. Yeah. So, you know,
I think this is a great trade overall.
And it's, it's, it's gonna be really exciting to see it play out.
I know a couple of guys are saying he bought a cheap November call to cover his
upside risk. Yeah. Yeah. So I think we're not, we're not going to strangle.
Yeah. He's actually in this position here. So we're not, Renato is in this,
right? So, and then he took some of the money and bought a,
I believe it was a November 35, right? So here we go.
So you guys are going to like this trade, right?
So Renato bought the Novembers. So this is him right here. Okay.
So right now he spent, so here's his, here's his core position. Okay.
Here's his core position. Now this company could release something huge.
We don't know.
Markets saying that there is going to be some type of big move coming up.
So let's say it does jump to 50 bucks, right?
Renato doesn't want that exposure.
So what he did was he spent 35 cents or 25 cents to buy some out of money calls
just to remove that blow up risk. Okay. Just to remove that blow up risk.
And that's actually very, very important in this game.
Okay. So do you guys have any questions about implied volatility?
A general idea of why we use implied volatility and we're getting into more advanced
stuff throughout the, throughout the week.
And then we'll just chat about implied correlation towards the end there.
Cause I know some of the guys would like that.
Actually, Kyle and Neil, let me know if you guys are still here.
Otherwise I will, or Steve, let me know if you guys are still here.
Otherwise I will skip out on an implied correlation.
I think they're still here. Okay.
Oh, Raph. Raph, what's going on man? And Lawrence is here. Lawrence. Hey,
Lawrence. I know you've been dodging me about those trade breakdowns, man.
I'm following up with you this week. He has, eh? He's been dodging me. Okay,
guys. So no questions about implied volatility. That's it.
All right. Let's move on. Okay. So I'm gonna stop the live. Yep.
Let's stop the live. Okay.