Ok guys, now that you understand what a backspread is,
we are actually going to take that backspread one step further and create a butterfly.
Now a butterfly is the exact same thing as a same strike iron condor.
So remember an iron condor,
we have a short put and a short call at the same strike,
and then a long put and a long call as our hedge.
Well a butterfly is actually the exact same structure and there is no difference
between the two.
So we are actually going to build out a butterfly through a vertical,
a backspread, and then into a butterfly.
And I am sure some of you are already seeing how this is going to work.
So to recap, here is our vertical spread.
When we cap it off and sell another call, we get a ratio spread.
Now what we can do here is we can buy another call that is further out of the money.
And that is going to cap our loss. So we have created a butterfly spread.
An example would be, this is the 200 call, this is the 210 call,
we are selling two of these, we only have one of those.
And then we are buying the 220 call, and we are buying just one.
So this is going to be a butterfly spread.
Now a butterfly can be used for many different things,
just like an iron condor. Remember,
a butterfly is an iron condor with the same strike.
So they can be used in many different scenarios.
One scenario is to be short volatility.
If we think that the stock is not going to move that much, let's say the stock,
let's say Apple,
is trading at 210.
Well, we can buy the butterfly, so we are buying the 200 call,
selling two 210 calls, buying one 220 call,
and as long as the stock stays within this range, we are going to make money.
But that's only one way to trade butterflies. And this way,
the butterfly is short volatility,
because we are short two call options that are at the money, or near the money.
But there is another way to trade butterflies, and that is to get direction,
to get delta, and to trade into skew. So remember, with the backspread,
we like to trade them when there is high skew. We bought an at the money,
we sold an out of the money put,
and then we sold another out of the money put to create the backspread. Well,
we can actually do the same thing with butterflies,
if we don't want this unlimited risk. So let's take a look.
Apple is trading at 210, and there is a lot of skew on Apple,
a lot of put skew. So what we can do here, is we can buy the 210 put,
sell two of the 200 puts, because the skew is high,
maybe the implied volatility here is 30, and here it's 35.
So these are very expensive. And instead of having unlimited risk,
we can actually buy the farther out of the money put to cap our risk off.
Now obviously, because there is steep skew, this put,
let's say is going to be 40%, is going to be very expensive.
So we're going to be giving a lot of our edge back to the market.
But one thing we are going to get is a debit, meaning we have limited risk.
So by giving up a little bit of edge, we get more margin efficiency,
and we get a limited downside, which is just the debit we paid.
Maybe this spread costs us $3.
So our max loss on this trade is going to be $3.
And what we have with this fly now, is we are actually directional.
So if the stock moves down, we're going to make a lot of money,
and if the stock moves too far down, we're going to start losing money.
So the way I like to trade these butterflies is when I think the stock is going
up or down, and I like to place the fly into the direction of the skew.
And then I also think that the skew is very expensive.
Now the way I like to trade these flies is I like to place them in the direction
that I think the stock is going. So if I think, let's say, Apple is going down,
then I'm going to buy one of these flies.
But another reason why I'm going to buy them is because the skew is expensive.
So if I'm directional, and there's skew in my direction,
I'm going to want to buy this butterfly.
And this butterfly is going to offer me a fantastic risk to reward. In fact,
this butterfly right here might be giving me 1 to 10,
where I risk 1 to make 10. So this is where and why we use butterflies.
Now let's talk about three things. Risk management, days to expiration,
and which strikes to pick. So in terms of days to expiration,
what's going to matter is your view on either volatility or direction.
What you're going to see is, if you go really far out in expiration,
your red line is going to look like this.
Let's say the stock's trading right over here,
meaning that even if the stock does go down,
you're not going to make a lot of money.
But if you trade a fly with 10 days to expiration,
what you might see is something that looks like this.
Meaning, if the stock does go down, let's say tomorrow,
your instantaneous P&L is going to be positive.
You're actually going to make money. And so if I do have a directional view,
which I usually do when I trade butterflies,
I'm going to be trading these a lot shorter days to expiration,
definitely under two weeks.
If it has more than two weeks,
I'm not going to be able to take advantage of the extra delta I get when the stock
goes down. Now what about risk management? Well, for risk management,
it's very simple. These butterflies usually give you a huge risk reward.
So the way I like to think about these is, if I'm wrong,
I'm not going to lose a lot of money. But if I'm right,
I'm going to make a lot of money.
So I usually think about these almost as a lottery ticket,
where if I don't win, that's okay. If I do enough of these though,
eventually my positive expected value in the trade is going to show itself.
Lastly, we're going to be talking about which strikes to pick. Well, again,
this is totally up to you. If you want to be short gamma or short volatility,
then you want to do something where the body is going to be at the money.
And if you want direction,
then this short strike is going to be in the direction that you want.
So if you're bearish, this is going to be below 210. The width of the strikes,
you really have to play around with them because there's no one size fits all strikes.
The wider you go, the higher the room for error. The smaller you go,
the smaller the room for error.
As this butterfly is going to start becoming very, very narrow.
So I hope you guys understand what a butterfly is and when to use it.
These are a very popular strategy that I like to use because you have max risk,
which is the debit you pay, and they're very versatile.
You can use them to be short volatility, or you can use them for direction,
or you can use them to trade into skew.
So I hope you guys found that video insightful,
and I'll talk to you in the next one.