Okay, guys, so in this video, in this lecture, in this workshop,
we're going to be talking about our Tesla trade, why we shorted vol today,
and why we shorted a strangle over a straddle. Okay, so those,
that's what we're really gonna be talking about breaking down this trade in depth.
And also all the other nuances that come with it.
And then going really deep into like,
why strangle versus straddle and like the differences between the two and why we
picked one over the other. Especially because a lot of the time, guys,
we're gonna hear in this space, like a strangle is safer than a straddle,
right? How many times I think we got John on here, right? John, perfect.
We got John here. You know, how many times tasty trade tells us right,
a strangle is the safer straddle, right?
A delta 16 strangle is a much better and safer trade than say doing it at the money
straddle. And so this is actually not the case,
it's actually the complete opposite. And so in this in this video,
we're gonna be chatting about that, right? Why is it the complete opposite?
And you know, when I first found this out as well,
it was brought a lot of insight insight to me. And, you know,
I hope you guys find that insightful as well.
So share my screen.
Alright.
So first off, why Tesla, right? Why are we shorting vol on Tesla?
So let's see what's going on here. And by the way, guys,
the terminal should be good to go from now on. No more. No kinks. Yeah,
no more bet. No more messy bugs. But you know, as soon as we say that,
there's a there's a bug, there's a bug.
Okay, so pull this up. So guys, look at the implied vol 30, okay?
It's actually it caught a bid today. So as you guys know,
I'm been short vol right around here. And today it caught a huge bid. Okay.
Now, Tesla, Tesla has been recently, you know, put into the S&P index.
And it seems like if we go to the if we look at the implied volatility and spot
correlation,
we can see that every like there's a slight correlation right between when,
when the spot change, okay, when when Tesla goes up,
implied volatility increases. Okay,
you guys can see that this is very interesting by the slope of the line, right?
Usually, let's say if we're looking at the S&P, okay, we're looking at the S&P,
when when the S&P goes down, I vol drops, or I vol increases.
And when the S&P increases, I vol drops. But for Tesla,
we're seeing the totally, we're seeing something totally different. Okay.
And that's what's happening. The last two days, Tesla has been rallying,
it's gone from 600 to 650, and it's rallying overnight. Okay,
so for that reason, right? We're seeing this increase in implied volatility,
we're seeing this increase in the option prices.
Now, we need to come to a conclusion. Is this overpriced?
Or is this underpriced? Okay.
And one thing that is driving this news is that Tesla is going into the S&P 500.
Now we need to think about this as from a trader's perspective,
is this changing the overall business?
Should this change the volatility of the overall company? Right? And you know,
Sean, I think the answer is no. Right? In fact,
we think this is going to drop vol.
There's extra liquidity coming into the market now, right?
It's a bigger company, right? As the company grows in size, vol needs to drop.
Right? It's harder to go from 100 trillion,
or let's say half a billion to a trillion, than it is to go from, let's say,
500,000 to a million. Right? So as this company grows in size,
vol needs to drop. And so what we're seeing is the complete opposite.
Vol is increasing. Oh, by the way,
Tesla's also just announced they're raising 5 billion more.
I've heard about this. Yes. So, and they even might be introducing, I think,
$100 billion worth of shares. If you want to just confirm that, Cole,
I think they're going to be releasing,
they're going to be providing a whole bunch of more liquidity into the market,
if you can just confirm that.
So, you know, some news coming out with this company, and, you know,
it's driving iVol, right? It's driving up the price of these premiums.
People are saying, oh my God, this thing's unreal. It's going to the moon.
Right? And, you know, a couple of people in our chat also believe it,
rightly so. Right? They've been right. No, Tico? Congrats.
We can't say he's been wrong. He's been absolutely spot on. Right?
So all this money coming into Tesla, driving up the price, driving up the vol.
We've got shorts who are short the shares, covering with call options. Right?
If they're short the shares, how are they going to hedge?
They've got to buy some call options. Right? So,
and it's been driving up the vol like crazy. So what we can see here now, guys,
we're going to start breaking it down in terms of the option prices and the volatility
for these option prices. Well, let's take a look, right? Here we have,
so remember we were talking about the volatility cone yesterday?
We're going to drop, we're going to drop the max, we're going to drop the min,
and we're just going to look at the third quantile, the first quantile,
the median, and the max, and the current. So remember, most of the time,
vol is going to be within this range. Okay? But it's way above right now. Okay?
It's at the 20 days at 100, the 30 days at 95, and the 45 days at 92. Okay?
So the market's telling us something is off. Right?
There should be a ton of vol. And we don't, we actually don't,
we actually don't agree with them here.
We think vol is going to eventually drop down into this range again. Okay?
And here's one of the reasons why. Look at the realized vol, guys.
I'm going to head over to Relative Value to look at this.
Okay, so we're going to plot the implied vol 30 and the realized vol 30. Okay?
And the ratio.
So let's take a look here. Right? Let's take a look at this top graph here.
Well, look at the realized vol. It's only at 65. The eyeball, the realized vol,
how much it's actually moving has only been at 65,
yet the implied vol for the 30 days at 95%. Okay?
It's extremely big given how much this thing is actually moving. Right?
If we look at today, for example, it's only been up 3% or 2%,
yet vol has increased drastically. Right? And when we compare those ratios,
when we compare the implied volatility relative to the realized volatility,
what's actually happening, we can see we're approaching almost all-time highs.
Okay? Besides these like little pops here, okay,
besides this little pop and this little pop,
we're approaching almost all-time highs. Right?
We're almost getting back up to this 1.5 ratio. Right?
And what does this tell us? Well,
it tells us that one of two things are going to happen. One,
implied vol is going to drop, or two, realized vol is going to increase. Right?
That's the only thing that's going to drop this ratio back down to its mean.
And what we're saying is,
the realized vol is actually not going to be increasing.
There's too many things that, there's too much liquidity in this market.
Maybe we'll stop for one second there.
Maybe we can talk about why this spread would drop back to its mean.
What is the relationship between implied and realized that would make it mean reverting?
Really good point. Really good point. So remember,
if implied vol is above realized vol, right,
if it's too far above realized vol,
then people who are selling options are going to earn a ton of money.
So they're just going to come in and sell more and more and more.
So what's going to happen is, eventually,
the spread between implied and realized is going to collapse. Right?
Either realized vol needs to increase, or implied needs to decrease. Otherwise,
they're just going to keep earning all this money all the way through.
So to try and make it simple, it might be too simple,
but you could almost think of it as like a cat and mouse game,
where they're kind of like always chasing each other, implied and realized.
Yes. Right? If the spread gets too big, it comes back together in some way.
Because if implied just stays higher than realized,
and it's not like insider trading or something, well,
sellers are just going to crush. They're just going to make a ton of money.
Right? So it's always, the market's always trying to be efficient as possible,
right?
The implied volatility should be in line with the realized to some degree.
Yeah. And then, you know, and we see that here, right? And it's not,
this is not just a phenomenon with Tesla, it's a phenomenon with any stock.
I need to change it at the top there. Oh, yeah. Okay. It's a phenomenon. Here,
you know what? We'll just keep Tesla here, actually, for now.
You have to check the box. Right? It's not just a phenomenon with Tesla,
this is a phenomenon with any stock. And it makes sense why. Right? Like,
we really,
the reason we pause here is to understand why this IVRV spread sort of does this
thing where one will be higher than the other,
then they come back together and then one will be higher than the other and they
come back together. Now it's not like they move exactly like that,
but as you can see on this graph, it kind of does. Right? So when we, when we,
you know, we try to model the volatility, right?
And we look at a whole bunch of different models to try to forecast what the volatility
of Tesla will be in the future. Right? And if we think,
if we really think about this,
forecasting volatility is very similar to forecasting the temperature. Okay.
Today's temperature is going to be similar to tomorrow's temperature. Okay.
And the same,
the same thing happens in the volatility space and the option space.
Okay.
Forecast. So, so when we look at our forecast of vol, right,
our forecast for the next 30 days going forward, we think it's going to be 77%.
Okay. And, and this forecast is taking into consideration, well,
the mean reversion of volatility, right?
How up moves are different than down moves in volatility. Right?
And so we have a 77% forecast for the next 30 days,
yet the options are implying a 95%. Right? So this is too big. Okay. So that,
that is our analysis right now with Tesla. Option volatility,
options in general are too expensive.
Okay. Okay. So, and, and just a, just a quick SKU analysis here for you guys.
You can see that the out of the money calls are still crazy bit.
And I actually,
Steven had a fantastic point about how SKU should actually change. Okay.
Think about it like this. You are in the S&P 500 now. When stocks sell off,
well, the ETFs have to unload the shares.
That's going to drive down the price of the shares.
So we should now see put SKU, not call SKU, right?
But we're still seeing this call SKU.
And what Steve's looking into is selling a risk reversal,
selling those out of the money calls,
buying an out of the money put and hedging the shares. Okay.
So if you guys want to learn more about that, please reach out to Steve.
He's got a really good analysis for you. Yeah. So Jared has a good point here.
He's like, what about the influx of share purchases from fund managers on 21st?
Yes. So that's already going to be priced in, right? If we think about it,
Jared, it's like Tesla went from $300 billion to $600 billion on the news,
right? Or $350 billion to $600 billion just on the news, right?
And we can see this. So one beautiful thing that we have is data, right?
So we can actually say, okay, well,
what happened when other stocks were included? CRM, Yahoo,
what happened when these stocks got included into the index?
And you're going to see that on the announcement, right? Well,
everyone is going to be like,
this thing is going to be included into the market.
I should buy it before all these funds have to buy it. Right.
And so what happens is we start bidding up the price, bidding up the price,
bidding up the price. I'm going to hold Tesla.
Think about it from the trader's perspective. I'm going to hold Tesla. Okay.
I'm just going to rise. And now Sean comes in and says, I need Tesla.
I need Tesla shares. So now I'm going to provide you liquidity.
I'm going to sell, I'm going to sell, I'm going to sell, unload,
unload everything to Sean. Right. So that's what,
that's what it means by being baked in. Okay. Right. Like, uh,
and another way you could think of it,
it's maybe not as good of an example with where you went with it, but, uh,
let's go back to the weather example for a second. Right.
So today's weather is a good indicator of tomorrow's weather. Right. You know,
it was sunny today. It'd probably be sunny tomorrow, but let's say there,
you know, there was a huge hurricane down. We're in Toronto.
So let's say in down South,
there was like a huge hurricane and it's moving North tends to happen.
We usually get the tail end of hurricanes that happen like Florida,
for example. Well, if that hurricane, you know, starts arriving tomorrow,
the weatherman is going to think that there's rain tomorrow and we're going to be
aware of it. Everyone's gonna be aware of it.
And the forecast for tomorrow's weather will now incorporate the fact that there's
that impending big thing coming.
And also I was actually talking with Marcos about this yesterday.
I don't know if he wants to keep a secret,
so I'm not going to say it on the live,
but Marcos has some really good idea about positioning,
how funds are going to be basically positioning different positioning their equity
book. Now the S&P 500, how that's going to be positioned going forward.
And you know, there might be some other trades available.
So if you guys want to reach out to Marcos as well,
he's got some really cool structuring ideas that he's working on.
Let me just make sure we got some of the questions here.
So Jared, really good point. I actually don't have an answer for that,
but I did see a really good YouTube video on it recently.
It's actually on chat with traders. I really like this guy's name.
I can't remember his name now.
Something Narang. Oh yeah. Yeah. Your buddy. Yeah. I don't know.
I can't remember his first name. I actually saw that online. Rishi Narang.
It just came out two days ago. Check it out. Okay. It's actually,
he talks about this stuff and Marcos,
you're actually going to really like that video.
He talks exactly about what we were chatting about last night.
Okay. So anyways, overall, we want to be selling options.
We think they're overpriced now. That's great. Unfortunately,
we can't just say, okay, well, we're going to, we're going to sell options.
We actually need to go and do it.
And how do we structure the trade and express our view? Okay.
So let's open up thinkorswim. So just to clarify, guys, we want to sell vol.
And what's our view? Like, what do we think is going to happen?
Is realized vol going to be low? Is IV going to come down?
What do we think is going to happen?
We think that implied volatility is going to drop down to our forecast. Okay.
It's going to drop down to about 77%, which is also, you know,
inside this quantile, right? Somewhere just inside this quantile,
we think vol is going to drop. And actually in the long run,
I think vol is going to drop quite a bit down to 60,
but that's for a different day.
Okay.
Here's our, here's our GME guys.
Yeah. Here's our GME, right? If vol drops, what do I have it stressed to?
We have a stress to the negative 30% here, but we'll see tomorrow. Anyways,
we should, we should all be good tomorrow. Assuming it hangs above 14, 14, 25.
We're good guys. We're good. Too much stress.
Too much panic going on in the group.
Okay. Jared had a good question. He's saying,
I think Tesla could hit 800 by the 21st.
I assume you have to Delta hedge to offset that risk. Jared,
if it actually moves 800, I don't know what I'm going to do. Okay.
If it does go to 800, I'm going to be very upset. That being said,
if it does keep moving, I am going to have to keep hedging my shares,
but obviously from my position I have on, I wouldn't be, I wouldn't be,
I wouldn't be short vol if I thought I was going to 100, 800.
I really hope that that's not the case, Jared.
Okay. So how do we do this? Well, a couple of things guys,
which we actually chatted about this on our live yesterday with GME that if we look
at Tesla, okay, actually I sold the February. So let's go back to February.
If we look here, we can't sell an at the money option here.
We could sell an at the money option here, but it's not neutral.
It's not neutral in direction and at the money option here is 60 Delta minus 40
Delta, right? So we're actually short, sorry,
we're in short 60 Delta and long 40 Delta here.
We're actually short 20 Deltas and we can just take a look here guys.
And that was, that was a, if you guys weren't on our live last night,
that was because of the volatility of the stock.
High volatility stocks usually have Deltas above spot price.
So we actually want this thing to go down at inception. Okay.
So if you're going to sell a straddle here and you want to be neutral in direction,
you can't just sell them at the money. Okay.
You'd actually have to go up in price,
right? Something like, let's say 690. Okay. And now we're,
we are a Delta neutral. Okay. Now the beauty of the options is you can do,
if you want to be short Vega, you can structure lots of trades, tons of trades.
So in this case, right,
the way I structured it was actually a Delta 40 strangle.
So let's price it out.
Oh no.
Dude. Why am I? Why is that? It's not even. Good job. Oh,
it's this cronium thing. Does anyone know how to get rid of chromium? It's a,
it's a, I think it's a virus, eh? Yeah. Yeah. You have a virus. I don't know.
Wow. This is the first time. What the fuck? Wow. Guys.
I actually can't believe this brand new Mac breaking down live stream.
Short Apple. Okay. So we got the new M1 chip now.
Tico will tell you all about it.
So I decided to put on a Delta 40 strangle. So this is the position I have on,
but actually I think in this example,
because we're going to be talking about strangles versus straddles,
I'm going to go a little bit wider just so you guys can,
can really grasp the point. So we're going to do a Delta 25 strangle.
Some good questions in there. I think chromium is a virus. Yeah.
Koa just looked it up. Come on, Koa. Don't scare me like that mid-live, dude.
Okay. So let's look at the strangle here, guys.
So here is our Delta neutral strangle.
Now we are taught that this is more safe. Okay.
This is more safe than a straddle. Now I think really to understand this,
we need to actually look at it from the long side.
Okay. We need to look at this from the long side. So here's our straddle,
right? Now here's our strangle because we're out of the money. Okay.
And this is really important guys, because we're over the money on a strangle,
you're more sensitive to implied volatility. Okay.
So we are a lot more sensitive to implied volatility. And Jared, you probably,
you know, maybe thought about this as well, just because, you know,
a tasty trade hasn't put, you know, at least in my mind,
when I was first starting out, that strangles are safer,
but let's really think about this. Okay. Well,
what do they reduce your exposure to that makes them say it's safer range,
right? The range, right? It's like, okay. Our range is bigger, right?
And our break evens are bigger. So therefore it's safer.
And that's a really good, really good point there, Sean.
But the actual fact guys is that think about it like this. Okay.
I want you guys to think about it in terms of Delta.
What is going to give you more leverage on a 10% stock move and in the money option
or an out of the money option, right? Well,
that out of the money option is going to go from 5 cents to 5 bucks, right?
And the same goes for implied volatility. If implied volatility increases,
we actually add a second derivative, okay? A second order Greek,
and that's called, it kills me to say it, VOMA, okay?
What it means is as implied volatility increases,
the wings actually increase faster. Okay. Just like,
you know how our Delta guys for our directional bet, right? The wings.
So let's look at one option here just so we can really understand this thoroughly.
I think it's so, so important.
Yeah. We're going to go for a, we're going to look at this 38 day option.
The worst lag this computer has ever experienced. Ever. I can't believe this.
It's crazy. Oh my God. Okay. Let's look at this option here guys. Okay.
At first. Okay. Let's take a look here.
So at first we don't have a lot of Delta exposure. Okay. Look at our Delta,
right? It's a hundred. It's a hundred Delta. Look at this exponential increase,
right? As we hit, as we hit the curve, it starts increasing rapidly, right?
And that's why they say Delta doesn't kill traders, Gamma does.
Because you sell this way out of the money option and everything is good until it
actually starts picking up, right?
You don't care what happens if the stock moves like this,
but once the stock gets going, you're in big trouble. Right? Okay.
And that's that, that's that, that increase in Delta. As you get to the wings,
volatility is going to be exactly the same. Okay. Let's take a look.
Let's increase vol here guys. Let's see what happens.
Do you hear that? Yeah, it's crazy. I don't know what it is.
Don't worry about it. Just keep chugging along. It must be the virus. Okay.
So let's increase vol here guys. Okay. Watch what happens here.
We're just going to increase vol 10 points. Okay. And look at this. We go from,
I guess it tests us so much, but so if we go,
let's look at our P&L at 1000 here. Okay. Or you can even add spot.
Too far out. Okay. Let's look at our P&L here at, uh, right here at 900. Okay.
When we increase vol, let's say 20 points. Okay.
We didn't take note of what it was before. Oh, okay. Sorry guys.
Give me one second here. We're going to go to add the money.
So at the money P&L, when vol increases 20 points is, what is our P&L?
Is $8,000. Okay. 8,000 bucks.
So by increasing vol 20 points, it's all good. That's the term. Logging out.
Okay.
By increasing the vol 20 points, this thing,
this thing increases 10 grand from an option that only cost us 10,000 to put on,
it's going to double up in value. And that's simply because of this,
this exposure to the wings, right? This VOMA, right?
The wings are gonna get more expensive a lot quicker. Okay.
So let's actually go back here and show this in real time. So watch this guys.
Okay. I want you guys to take a look at this. So we're gonna do two things.
Okay. We're gonna look at one.
We are going to look at, um,
two different strategies. Okay. Two different strategies.
First is the straddle. Okay.
And our Vega exposure on the straddle is going to be 1,663.
You guys see that 1,663 and we're going to create a strangle with the exact same
Vega exposure.
So something to clarify, I think is we want exposure to Vega.
That's our number one thing, right?
Our view is that the level of implied volatility is going to decrease.
But I think like to understand the point,
we've got to go from the long side first. So here we have two positions.
They have the exact same Vega exposure. Okay. Exactly the same.
This one has 1,700 and this one has 1,650. So $50 difference.
Now let's increase implied volatility by 25 points. Okay.
And we're going to go a little bit much here just to, to, to really,
to really express the point. Okay. So we paid $16,500 for this position. Okay.
$165, 10 lots, 16,000, sorry, $165,000 for this position.
And we made 40 grand. So we paid 165 grand and we made $40,000 on 25% increase.
Okay. Now let's look at the strata of the strength.
We go, we pay a 14 times 52 is 50,020 is 70,
we pay $70,000 for this position and we make $43,000. Okay. We pay 70 grand,
we make 43. That is more than 50% of our,
more than 50% increase when the other one only made 25%. Right.
That leverage factor. It's that as, as Vega increases, okay.
The wings actually increase quicker. Okay. And that's called,
there's a third derivative called VOMA or second derivative called VOMA higher derivative.
So let's go back to our position.
So why do we want to go and sell the strangle instead? Well,
for that exact reason,
for that exact reason, if we're right, okay,
we are going to get the most exposure. Okay. If we're right,
as Vega comes down, the wings are going to come down even quicker, right?
And that's what we want the exposure to is that we are taking on more leverage.
Okay. We're taking on more leverage.
We're taking on more sensitivity to that implied volatility. Okay.
So that's why you would choose a strangle over a strata is if,
do you want more, do you want more risk? Right.
Do you want more exposure to that, to that, that decrease in volatility?
And there's actually another reason why as well, is that volatility inside the,
the, the wings is going to remain constant Vega inside the, the, the strikes,
sorry, is going to remain constant.
So those are the reasons why we're taking the short strangle versus the short straddle.
Let's say you decide that a strangle is the way to go.
You understand why you're taking it. How far, how wide do you make it? Yeah.
That's a really good point, right? So think about it like this guys.
So a lot of the times we need to think in terms of dollar gain versus implied vol
gain, right? Example,
you could sell a way out of the money option on Tesla at 120 eyeball for a dollar,
right? And if vol drops, you gain a dollar, or you can get more Vega exposure.
When vol drops, you make quite a bit of money.
So you always have a trade-off between implied vol versus dollar, right?
So implied vol gain versus dollar gain.
I usually like to go between Delta 40 and Delta 30 just because, well, one,
I get a little bit, a little bit sensitivity to that, that third order Greek,
right? If I'm right.
And then also because as long as the stock stays within that,
within those strikes, I'm going to have the same Vega exposure throughout,
right? Yeah. Steve. So the Vega doesn't remain constant.
It actually changes just like how Delta changes, right? Vega changes as well.
And it actually never changes at the money. It only changes in the wings.
Yeah. Jerry, I used up all my VP today, man. I couldn't, uh,
I couldn't get any more Tesla on. And uh, I'm sure for you in the state,
do you guys get portfolio margin in Canada? We don't.
So these things per lot cost me 50, 50 K to put on Terrence saying,
does making this an IC pose the Vega? Yeah, it does. Right. Unfortunately,
you know, you go out and buy the wings here, right? Think of it like this guys,
right? If we're looking at the Vega, Theta Vega, right? Here's our Vega.
So we're selling, let's say 84 Vega here, or let's say we're selling,
let's say 80 Vega on the wings. And then we're going to buy out,
they're buying 40 Vega, right? So if you want the same exposure,
you just need to increase your position.
But now you have the third order Greeks working against you.
When implied vol drops, guess what's happening?
Your wings are dropping quicker.
Your wings are dropping quicker. But if you go really far out, well,
now we're talking the dollar terms that it's dropping. Doesn't really matter.
Right? Think about it like this. Let's imagine we had,
let's say a 3000 strike and you bought those wings. Well, sure.
Implied vol is going to drop like crazy,
but you're going from 10 cents to zero while you're making $20 at the money,
right?
So we're always in that trade-off between dollar return and implied vol return.
Yeah. Right. Right. And you know,
that's why sometimes you look at the skew for example,
and you'll see like way out of the money calls are so bid and it's like,
it's not worth our time to go, you know? It's like your commissions slippage,
how much are you going to make here? 10 cents? Yeah. You know,
we could always sell those way out of the money Delta two options for 300% implied
vol to make two cents. It's not worth it. Not worth it.
So wow, that was a, I didn't realize I ranted that hard. Wow.
Any questions guys? Yeah. Jared saying,
how does the vol drop effect of vertical? Depends where you place it. Right?
Check this out. Jared.
Let's say we're looking at Tesla. We'll do the 38 day.
If I'm buying a digital, right? If I'm buying a digital here, let's say one,
a little bit of lag today. Okay. So here's my digital.
Okay. Well changing the vol is not going to do anything.
It's not really going to do anything because I got no Vega. I got no Vega.
My Vega is eight bucks, but watch this. Let's see what we do.
This at the money wide vertical,
but all of a sudden I got a ton of Vega now, right? Well,
I got six times more Vega. Okay.
So depending on where the option is placed is really going to depend.
So Coa says, why not sell the December 24th vol should drop.
So basically how'd you pick your expiry? Yep. That's a really good point. Cool.
Let's go back to the term.
Marcos really upset right now because he doesn't like the, uh,
I actually think it might be less than 30 minutes. Yeah. Double check it.
And he's like, I told you, I told you guys, I told you guys.
And then we have one last question for Marcos there that I think is really good
as well. Okay. So, um, so,
um, I wanted exposure to Vega. Okay. I wanted exposure to if implied vol drops,
I don't really have gamma. The stock moves up 10% stock moves down 20%.
It doesn't really matter too much. What matters is the level of implied vol,
especially for a long graded option. And that's what I really cared about.
Okay. Okay. So what we have is, uh, what we have is what we have is the width.
Okay.
I'm going to show you this and I'm going to break it down for you in more in depth.
It's not testing.
Yes. So longer dated. Okay.
Longer dated means more sensitive to the implied volatility level. Okay.
When shorter dated means more sensitive to the realized vol. So check this out.
I think that this option is going to drop 15 handles. Well,
let's take a look at our Vega. Let's just go to the option calculator, right?
Okay. Let's price an option at TECO where let's say we're looking at the, uh,
at the February options. Okay.
And let's look at our Vega or watch this TECO as we get closer to expiration,
right? So here we are now, as we get closer to expiration, our Vega drops.
So our sensitivity to implied vol drops, but look at the opposite,
look what happens on the opposite side. Okay.
Our sensitivity to the actual movement of the stock increases. So we have this,
uh, we have this trade off here and I was just talking to Ned about it.
Near dated stuff.
We are concerned about that sensitivity to the underlying stock.
Is it going to move or is it not going to move? If it doesn't move,
we don't care about implied vol as long as it doesn't move.
But for the longer dated stuff,
it can move all at once as long as implied vol drops or it increases from the long
side. Okay. So that's your trade off there, right? There's no better,
there's no better here. It's what do you think is going to happen?
Yeah. Yeah. Thanks Jared.
We should make a PA terminal keyboard. We should. That'd be cool. Okay. Uh,
just answer Marco's question here. That was really good as well.
Where are we wrong? So, uh, Marcos, are you saying,
when do we say we're wrong or how can this be a bad trade? I guess,
I guess they're both, they're both one in the same.
So, um, this is really tough, right?
This is really tough because as implied vol increases,
I'm going to be more and more, you know,
thinking this thing is going to be great.
This thing I should be selling more and more just like today, right?
I was already in a position implied vol increased and I sold some more. Um,
so where I'm going to be wrong is if the stock blows out, if it moves,
let's say 15%, I'm wrong. I have to close out the position.
I have to keep hedging. My, my, my Vegas is going to dry up.
So if we go back to the analyze tab,
I'm just going to do a, not when it hits 800, if it hits 800,
we can't be wishing that into existence, man, you Tico, you,
you basically influenced Jared to think this thing's going to 800.
Now what's going on here, guys,
you guys can hold off seeing 800 for a couple of months. Come on, guys.
Let us make our money. Then you make your money. Exactly. Come on, guys.
We're Tesla bros. Now, by the way, Jared, you're typing to all panelists.
So if you want everyone else to see your message,
you do all panelists and attendees.
Um, Marcos. So one thing, one thing that we, uh,
that we note is that realized vol and implied vol are correlated. Remember how,
like we say to implied vols up,
realized vol comes or from realized vol down implied vol comes down with one of
the two, they, the spread closes. So I'm going to be wrong, right?
If this thing, let's say moves a lot closer to my break.
Even I got basically my Vega starts to run dry, right? My,
I start to lose a ton of Vega out here, right. Versus when it was over here.
Right. I lose a thousand Vegas down here. And at that point, I got to say,
okay, I'm wrong, right? I don't have a position on anymore.
That really expresses my view, right? Sure. I'm short Vega, but I'm,
I have a ton of risk on, and so I'm going to have to close out the position.
Okay. I was saying, so if all does not drop in time goes by, well,
if all doesn't drop in time goes, okay. I see what you're saying.
So that's going to be a really hard one because like,
if we look at our silver position, right.
We had the position on for like two months and then it took two months for it to
pay off. Right. And sure. It was a great return,
but was it the best use of our capital?
Because it took two months to take to really come through.
And that's a really good, that's a really good point, Marcos.
And although I should have thought about this,
shouldn't have thought about that entering this trade.
I'm going to actually think a lot more about that after you mentioned it,
but that's a very good point, Marcos.
I hope everyone understood what Marco is saying is that if we do sell ball and what
if just nothing happens? Well, okay. Well, first off, right. First off,
if nothing happens, we're going to make a little bit of money,
but because our Vega, our theta is so low,
we're not going to make a lot of money and it could be a really bad use of capital.
Yeah. Unless it stays pinned at the current price and we hold it to expiration.
It'd be a huge winner. It'd be a huge winner. But it's also like,
it's also like our capital could have been somewhere else for so much that.
Okay.
So no more questions. If anyone has, sorry, if anyone has any more questions,
if not, there's no more questions. We will end the live here. By the way,
we had a great turnout tonight, everyone. Dave, good to see you. Joe.
Awesome. Awesome. Awesome. Really good. Leon. Leon and Lawrence. Lawrence, man.
And Mark. Hey, what's going on, Mark? Awesome.
Awesome. If I knew Mark was here, I would have, I would have really,
I would have done a whole PowerPoint.
Okay. So that will be the live for tonight, everyone.