Alright guys, so in this live,
we are going to be talking about filtering for put spreads in the Predicting the
Alpha Terminal. We're also going to be briefly talking about put spreads,
when to use them, when not to use them,
how to be able to quickly find them in the terminal,
and then going into execution. The reason why this live is so important,
and I'm happy to see,
especially the members that came into PA using put spreads here,
is that the terminal has a lot of power,
and there's a million different things that you can do with it.
But the easiest way to get started using the terminal is to use it to start applying
data to the decisions you're already trying to make.
If you're out there trading put spreads right now,
you can improve upon what you already do simply by adding this new layer of filtering
to the trades that you're looking at.
So what we're going to be going through is,
there's going to be really two sections to this live. The first section,
we're going to keep it really straightforward.
How do you use the terminal to find trades where you can be systematically looking
at using put spreads? If put spreads are your go-to tool,
here's how you can find trades to be trading put spreads on that are optimal.
Like the perfect,
a few filters you can apply that create sort of like the perfect storm for put spreads.
Sorry, go on. At least from the volatility standpoint. Yeah,
from the vol standpoint. We obviously,
you got to have a directional view as well,
which the terminal doesn't forecast direction, it forecast volatility.
But from that standpoint, that's usually the component that's missing.
Usually you have your directional bias without the view on volatility.
Now you can add that second piece to the puzzle.
The second half of the live is we're going to go into the components of our filter.
Why did we care about skew?
Why did we care about the level of implied volatility, for example?
Why do we care about these things?
So that is what this live is going to look like. And then maybe we'll finally,
at the end, structure out a bunch of them. Exactly. Yeah. Okay.
So as we go along, make sure to leave your questions in the chat there.
I'll be keeping an eye on the chat.
If it's extremely pertinent to what we're talking about at the time,
we'll answer it. But if not,
you can expect it to be answered at the end of the live,
or maybe at the little break between sessions.
And maybe even before we share a screen, I thought I'd give a little story.
When I was first starting into trading and how put spreads were really the ideal
thing for me, right? So it was around the election time, 2016,
and implied volatility was very high going into the elections.
And I was also bullish on the market.
And so the trade that I did was I sold an out-of-the-money put spread, okay?
I sold an out-of-the-money put spread.
I sold about the Delta 30 and bought the Delta 16 about 20 days out.
And I collected a premium and the vol dropped, stock rallied.
And I thought this was the trade, right? It makes a lot of sense.
I think the stock is going to go up,
and if at least it doesn't come below this price, I'm going to make money.
Right? And so it's really like the perfect storm for a retail trader.
And we always got to remember where we came from, right?
And try to put ourselves in those shoes to really understand what other people are
thinking of when we're talking about these put spreads, okay?
So just to make sure everyone's on the same page, if the stock, or here,
why don't we just put one on just so everyone knows that we're all on the same page,
okay? So Boeing, I was just talking to Pranav about this,
we think Boeing is going to go up. So we might come in and sell, for example,
it's trading at 207. We might come in and sell a 195, 185 put spread, okay?
Pretty typical from a trader standpoint, right? Here we are. Okay?
Boeing is trading right over here right now. And if Boeing continues to go up,
we're going to make some money.
And if Boeing doesn't go below a certain threshold, right,
we're still going to make some money. Which would be right here,
which would be over there. This is a pretty standard approach for a put spread.
Now, the thing about a put spread is it's actually very versatile, okay?
Depending on how wide we make the strikes, where we put the strikes, okay,
how far out in time we put the strikes, we will have different exposures,
right?
The beauty about spread trading is you can customize it to have a ton of different
exposures.
So let us take a look at this very particular one here, super quick,
just we'll take a look at a basic risk profile before we start to,
just so we can get a sense of what they're really expressing before we go and scan
for it, okay? So if we look right here, okay, we look down here,
we can see a couple of things, okay? We're long delta,
meaning we think the stock, we want the stock to go up, okay?
We're also long theta, meaning we want time to pass, right?
If time passes and nothing happens, we're going to make money,
and we're short vega. So if volatility drops, we're also going to make money,
okay? And that is the characteristic of this particular short credit spread.
So why don't we go in and start scanning for these, okay? And in the comments,
as we're going over to the PA terminal,
I want to ask you guys the question of what do you think we might scan for,
okay? What do you think we might scan for given this vertical spread, okay?
And we're going to, as you guys write down your comments there,
we're going to head over to the terminal and figure it out.
So we're going to head over to volatility insights tab. And this tab,
as you guys know, it has all the volatility characteristics.
All we're going to focus on right now is this top section up here, right?
This right here is what we're going to be using. This is the area,
it's basically just our scanner.
It allows us to filter all the opportunities out there to find ones that meet a
particular criteria for us.
So for the purposes of finding the trades to put spreads on,
this is where you're going to look, okay? So you just come to the terminal,
you go to volatility insights. Okay. And honestly,
this is Sean's bread and butter, I thought he was going to take it away here.
So we showed what our risk profile was, right? What we benefit from,
from time passing, from volatility dropping, from stock increasing.
So right off the bat,
we're going to need the most important thing of this put spread right now.
And as we can see quickly here from this put spread,
that our biggest risk is this Delta factor.
Meaning we need the stock to go up and we need the stock to go up.
So before we even put on this put spread,
our view needs to be that the stock is going to go up.
Whatever fundamental reason we have, it's got to be there. Okay.
And that should be sound. Now,
we're not really going to talk about the Delta view, but briefly,
that view of Delta needs to be sound. Okay.
You can't just say the stock is going to be breaking out,
so I'm going to buy this, sell this vertical spread.
You need something more sound, something more reasonable. Okay.
Something that might actually have an edge, right?
You need to have an edge in Delta. Okay. If you don't have that,
this trade is not the best trade to place. Okay. So that's the first thing.
Now obviously, you might be able to use this,
the scanner for your own Delta view. For example,
if you want to scan for call put ratio,
maybe you think that the more calls than puts being bought,
that the stock is going to continue to go up. Okay. So you might use that,
for example.
Another thing you could use is the skew, right? Which is basically,
this is a different topic for a different lecture,
but this kind of tells you where the market thinks the stock is going to go.
Okay. Most likely. But what we're really going to focus on first is volatility.
Okay. So we are going to make money if volatility drops.
So the first thing we want to see is that IV is greater than our forecast.
Right. So we might scan for this being greater than one. Okay.
Maybe we'll do like 1.5. Okay. Right off the bat,
we narrow it down to 400 stocks. Okay. So IV greater than our forecast.
What we also might want to see is that there's some implied volatility. Right.
So we might say, let's go over 35. Right.
There's got to be some juice in this thing.
And then the last thing that I like to scan for is IV rank above 50. Okay.
This at least tells us that it's above the median. Right.
That this thing probably could come down. Right. Oh, I'm sorry. That was... No.
You want this as well? Yeah. Yeah. In a second.
We'll first talk about the vols here. So actually, maybe we'll go above 60.
Okay. So now we have...
Right now we filtered for basically Sean's bread and butter daily live. Right.
It's the IV greater than forecast and implied volatility pretty high.
And there is some, at least some volatility. Okay.
So that's from the IV 30 that we just scanned for here.
The other thing I like to do, like, you know, you don't really need to,
you know, you don't have to do this, but I usually like to,
because it's a spread, right, we want to see some type of volume, right.
Some type of liquidity. If there's no liquidity, right. The more,
the more legs you have on a trade and the less liquid,
the more edge you're giving away. Okay. There's no two corners around that.
The less liquid, the more legs, the more you're paying commission, slippage,
et cetera.
So we want to have some type of liquidity there,
and you can just scan for that in average option volume. Now, so far, okay,
we've scanned for high volume and high volatility.
We've narrowed it down to 30 stocks. Okay.
So all of these are potential candidates.
Now something else that's a little bit more on the complex side about these vertical
spreads is that they're different strikes. Okay. They're not the same strike.
They're different strikes. And so because of that, right,
we go back to think or swim here because we have different strikes,
we are buying and selling at different implied volatilities. Okay.
And just so you guys, you know, just so you know, I'm not going crazy here.
You can see that we're selling this at 48.2%, right?
We're selling this with this 195 and we're buying this one at 49.65, okay?
So we're selling at 48 and a half and buying at 49 and a half. Now,
we can actually scan for, okay, those volatilities, right?
We can actually scan for something where the out of the money put that we're buying
is cheaper than the at the money put we're selling. Okay.
And that is going to be in our skew factor. That's going to come down to this.
Yeah. Oh, you know, I'm probably going to scan for, I'm going to scan for,
I'm going to use skew rank here. I'm going to use skew rank.
And what I'm going to scan for is it's below 50. Okay.
So that means that the skew is less than the median. Okay.
So we're going to take a look at an example here. Okay. So right off the bat,
we have Pinterest. Okay. We got Pinterest right off the bat.
So let's take a look here.
And just before I actually move into thinkorswim, does everyone see Pinterest?
Is everyone okay with us using Pinterest here? So this is our scan.
This is our scan, right? So before we move on,
let's maybe do a little checklist here. Yeah. A little recap.
We'll do a recap and a checklist. I'll show you what I mean.
So let's look at what we did here. Firstly,
first thing we do is we apply our filter that we, you know,
pretty much do every time. Liquidity. Right. Price and liquidity.
And we didn't do price this time, but you know,
see it over 15 bucks and make sure it's liquid.
That's filter one is to make sure we have, you know,
it's within the realm of something we should be trading.
The second filter is our vol filter where we put,
we want to see the IV versus forecast high.
We want to see some implied volatility and we want to see the IV rank up.
Right? So then once we've applied those,
we are looking at ones that fit our volatility criteria only from there.
We know that we want to make sure that that out of the money put that we're buying
is not extremely expensive relative to the closer to at the money put that we're
selling. What we need to look for that is we need to filter for skew. Right?
So what we'll do is this quick, right?
You guys can take a little screenshot of this if you want.
Number one is the liquidity and price filters.
Number two is volatility filters,
which would be IV versus forecast greater than one. IV greater than 35.
And IV rank greater than 50. All right.
And then the last one here we're going to put is IV rank greater than 50.
There now we have skew filter, which would be skew rank above or below 50.
If we just come back up here quick. For liquidity filters,
option volume above 6,000, let's say, and price above $15.
Any questions about these? This would be the PA vertical scan. Put spread scan.
Put spread scan. Yeah. Sorry. Short put spread scan. Jared's asking,
when are we getting the put spreads button? Jared,
we were keeping that a secret. It was a surprise coming this week.
You ruined it, man. You're letting the cat out of the bag here.
Soon enough, you'll be able to do this with the click of a button.
Or not. Or not. Jared doesn't know what he's talking about.
Jared's drinking again. Yeah. Jared's drinking again.
Okay.
So will you be able to alter the scan? So Mark,
the way we're going to be doing it is we're going to have a homepage button or a
homepage tab that's going to have a bunch of different strategies with preset filters,
and it'll pull up the top 10 for it, let's say.
So whether it's like put spreads or covered calls or whatever you might want to
be doing. But then you'll be able to see what those are,
and you'll be able to adjust your own filters in the vol insights page.
Actually, guys, just a quick thing from Mark. For the more advanced guys,
I'm not going to be talking about too much,
but reach out to Mark about trading long debit vertical spreads.
I learned something from him in the summertime where you can place these trades
where you think volatility is insanely high and they're skewed in one direction.
Because as long as you get some type of movement, you know,
imagine a stock's random, right?
As long as we get some type of movement in that direction, it usually pays off.
So reach out to Mark for anyone who wants to trade long debit spreads,
or we'll do another live on it down the road.
But he's got some good ideas for those. Okay.
So I'm assuming everyone has their screenshot of this. Actually,
I'll just save it, and we'll throw it up in the group after.
Blessing's asking, do we have any concerns about days to expiration?
So Blessing, remember, the vertical spread, which towards the end,
we're going to put a whole bunch on, they can have different exposures, right?
They can have different risk factors.
So if you're putting a vertical spread further out in time, right,
you're going to be very sensitive to a drop in implied volatility, okay?
But that also depends on how close you're putting the strikes.
So it's not that we're concerned about days to expiration,
it's that do we want to put something on that expresses a certain view? Okay,
so there's never a time where it's like, I'm worried about this, right?
Because at the end of the day,
you can just – It's just a knob we can adjust to tweak what our view is.
Exactly. Right?
We're not going to focus on that too much for this live, to be honest,
Blessing,
because this is really tailored for – if you look out in the educational space for
options right now, a lot of people talk about put spreads.
So a lot of people are coming in here doing put spreads right off the bat anyways.
As they're learning, they're doing put spreads,
and we feel an obligation to make sure that people who are trading something that
maybe isn't in the Bronze education are still making the best decision possible
for what they're trying to do. And this is really for that person. And,
you know, if you learn about put spreads,
we'll do more talks about them in the future, et cetera.
This will help you fit whatever you choose to end up doing. And don't forget,
guys, from that screen that Sean showed, the scanner, most importantly,
is you need to have a long delta bias. Okay?
You need to have some type of long delta bias.
And we're not going to chat too much about, like,
what would make something a good or bad long delta bias.
Everyone has their different reasons,
and we're not necessarily the best delta traders either.
So, Mark, do you mind maybe elaborating a little bit about that, Mark?
Are you saying because, like, an iron condor is basically just, like,
two different spreads combined? I'm not 100% sure what you mean there, Mark.
If you can just maybe elaborate a little bit, then I'll mention it. Okay.
So now that we have that spread, we have Pinterest that came out on the list.
Okay? Now, this isn't on the top of the list. We could, let's say, filter.
So we're filtering for IV versus forecast right now.
And you can just turn the knobs there, whatever you guys are looking for.
So we're going to use Pinterest right now. I feel like it's a good one to use.
And let's say we have a bullish bias on Pinterest, right?
We think Pinterest is going to go up. Well, what we could do here,
we're going to structure out a couple here. We could come here 37 days out,
let's say, and sell an at-the-money, right?
Sell an at-the-money vertical strike.
And then let's say buy a little bit further out, maybe, let's say, 55. Okay?
Or why don't we say 60?
Okay, so here is this put spread.
All right? And also remember, guys, depending on this, you might, let's say,
do between a 55 and a 60 put, right, is going to give you more delta exposure.
It's also going to increase your rega exposure. Okay,
so we're going to do a couple here. So we're going to do the 70-60,
and we're also going to do the 70-50. Okay?
So let's look at the 70-50 first, right? Someone might come and say, hey,
you know, this is terrible risk-reward trade. Well,
it's not terrible risk-reward trade.
It's just expressing something maybe a little bit different. So in this case,
right, you're going to see here that our delta is 316.
Let's store it to one lot. Oh, yeah, okay, let's do one lot.
Okay, so this delta is 31. So it's like you own 31 shares. And this one, okay,
is 18. So right off the bat, the difference between these two, first off,
is that you're more bullish. Right, so how bullish are you on Pinterest? Now,
what else is a little different here? Well, look at our theta and vega, okay?
Theta is 7 here, and it's only 3 here. Okay,
so we're not as sensitive to time with this one. And lastly, look at our vega.
It's negative 3 when the other one was negative 7. So this one,
we're more sensitive, okay, to volatility collapsing. Now,
one mistake I see a lot of the time that traders do,
and I wouldn't say it's a mistake, but I think they put it on unknowing,
is they do these extremely, extremely tight spreads way out of the money, okay,
or even at the money. I guess at the money is not bad,
but I'll see sometimes traders do something like this, okay,
because they don't want to lose, so they'll sell way out of the money,
and they're going to do it super tight, okay? And they're going to say, okay,
well, as long as that thing goes up, right?
And this is really what we want to be thinking with these spreads, okay?
Look at our exposures here, right? Our exposures are almost nothing, right?
Go to a 1 lot here. Sorry, we're at a 10 lot, okay?
Our exposures are really nothing.
There's nothing really exciting going to be happening with this spread,
win or lose, right?
And so I think it's important that when we do these spreads,
we do them with conviction.
We do them with a real desire to want to put this trade on, right?
It's got to be meaningful, right? So doing something like this,
I don't know how to say it,
but it's like I would never do this in a million years.
I guess that's the best way that I can explain it.
Do you have anything to say about this one? I think you summed it up. So,
you know, depending on the different put spreads, right?
But let's also take a look here, guys. Remember how we scanned for that skew,
right? Let's take a look.
We're selling here at 88 and buying at 87 on this one, okay? Now,
that's not a huge deal. And, you know, because we're buying further out, right,
it's, you know, a couple points difference is not big. Sometimes we'll see,
though, people do this on the S&P 500, okay?
And look what happens when we do this on the S&P 500.
Look what happens here. You end up selling at, let's say,
a 17 vol and buying at a 22 vol, right?
So this put spread is not going to give you a great risk to reward.
So that's why we scanned for that skew.
And there's actually a little bit more in-depth reason for it,
but we're actually not going to talk about it on this live.
So do you guys have any questions about this? And key thing to know, guys,
like when it comes to developing a directional view,
there's a lot of different ways you can go about doing it, right?
Like, you know, one thing you can maybe think,
if you're selling something a little bit longer dated,
you think the macro environment is good. Well,
if you're trading something that's correlated with the S&P, well, there you go,
right? You know,
you don't need to have a directional edge that you think this thing's going to go
to the moon.
You need to be more confident that this thing's going to move up and down.
So Mark has a really good point here, right?
A lot of time we need to really just understand these structures, right?
Because sometimes let's say you might sell a put, right?
And then next thing you know, you're, you know,
you're buying it out of the money put to offset that down the road, right?
Let's say the stock's going down and you say, okay, you know what?
I got to hedge something here. Maybe I'm going to buy an out of the money put,
right? If we look at, let's say a market maker's book,
he's going to have a ton of different spreads on, right?
And he's going to try to look at it through one lens. Mark,
I think that's what you're trying to get at. I'm not 100% sure. If not,
maybe you can make a little post about it. You know, try to read.
Definitely in depth for this slide, but yeah,
definitely too deep for this slide,
but that would be a whole live in and of itself.
And that's actually one probably worth talking about. Yeah. And I actually,
I actually recommend it. You do reach out to Mark for these types,
these types of spreads.
I've learned some stuff from him over the summer regarding it. And Mark,
thank you in advance for your generous donation of time to everyone who will DM
you.
So, but is everyone understanding when to use a put spread,
when not to use a put spread, right?
We would use a put spread when we have high,
when we think implied volatility is too expensive.
We think the stock is going to go up and we think,
And we're not paying too much for those out of the money wings that we sold for
at the money, right? That is the skew.
The difference involves between the strikes. Okay. Now,
once we have that view on, we can make a solid trade.
And just given the time that we're at now,
I think it actually makes sense to do a part two tomorrow where we talk about the
components. Yes. Okay. So,
and let me just show you guys super quick what the skew does. Okay.
How the skew affects it. So let's say for example,
we're going to do two trades here. We're going to do a three 80. Okay.
We're going to sell them at the money call spread. Okay.
So S and P has a ton of skew. Okay.
So we're going to sell an at the money call spread here. Okay. So here it is.
And we're going to get $5 and 12 cents for it.
Now what we're going to do is do the exact same thing on the put side,
$10 wide, exactly the same. Okay. And look at the difference.
One is going for $5 and 12 cents and the other is going for $2 and 84 cents,
right? Here is the exact same thing. We're going to three 80, $10 out.
We'll look at that difference. Okay. Look at that difference.
And the reason is on this call spread that we're looking at here,
we're selling at 17 and buying at 14 on the put spread.
We're selling at 17 and buying at 20. Okay.
And that is going to make all the difference. So this is the,
this is how we want to look for these spreads. Okay.
Does that make sense to everyone? What do you guys think opinions?
Okay. Mark, I might have to actually learn this one from you.
So if you don't mind maybe in traders chat, if you can write a little,
if you can write a little message about it in traders chat,
I would love to read it afterwards. Yeah. And, and yeah,
that's exactly what we're saying, right?
Like and tomorrow's live, we will go in depth on that. Okay.
Cause that we like, we really, you know,
I don't want to give you a one liner and then make it confusing.
We'll just go in depth on that on tomorrow's life. Last thing is asking,
can you please repeat the criteria? So let's do this. Here it is again.
These are the filters we're going to use.
We want to make sure it's liquid and have a good price.
We need our vol filter and we need our skew filter down the road.
Hopefully not too far down the road. This is going to be available to you.
Boom. Like preset done. You just look at it and be like, here's the top five.
If I wanted, if any of these fit my bullish view,
these are the best ones to be doing it on.
And I think blessing also asked, you know,
the probably the most important question, right?
The most important question is, you know, Sean touched on as well,
is how do you build a directional bias or how do you,
how do you build that directional edge? And you know what guys,
it is a directional edge. You can make a ton of money with,
with a directional edge. So we really, it's, it's difficult to build one out.
It's there.
It will be a whole, a whole lecture on building out directional edge.
Personally, Sean and I, we don't look at charts. Okay.
But rarely are we trading a Delta,
but there's nothing wrong with trading Delta. Okay.
It's it's just something that Sean and I are not, let's say the best app.
All right.
Okay.
So we are going to continue this tomorrow on tomorrow's live where we actually are
going to go into each of those filters and really explain them.
The main one we're going to be focusing on is that skew element. All right.
Because at first glance, you're going to be like, wait, I don't get it.
Something tricky here. We're really, really dig into it.
And I literally picked this topic for you. I'm so happy that you liked it.
And on our next call, I, I hope to see how you're using it to, to, you know,
make great trades. And, and make sure to bring Alan.
I don't know where he is today. Oh, I'm sure. Come on. I don't know.
He's got to be there. It's one of his favorite topics too.
Oh, he was with the boys. Okay.
Make sure you make sure he's out here tomorrow and I'll upload the recording tonight
so that he can watch it.
He's definitely gonna be watching it tomorrow night tonight, but you know,
when it, when it wakes up tomorrow afternoon, he can give it a watch.
All right. Have a great night, everyone. See you guys. See you around.